<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,165.63,136.49,280.75,15.15;1,201.75,158.40,208.50,15.15">Query Reformulation for Clinical Decision Support Search</title>
				<funder ref="#_rGU98gG">
					<orgName type="full">US National Science Foundation</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,110.84,199.13,68.08,10.48"><forename type="first">Luca</forename><surname>Soldaini</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Information Retrieval Lab Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Georgetown University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,187.74,199.13,69.69,10.48"><forename type="first">Arman</forename><surname>Cohan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Information Retrieval Lab Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Georgetown University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,267.40,199.13,69.96,10.48"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Yates</surname></persName>
							<email>andrew@ir.cs.georgetown.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Information Retrieval Lab Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Georgetown University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,346.47,199.13,75.40,10.48"><forename type="first">Nazli</forename><surname>Goharian</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Information Retrieval Lab Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Georgetown University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,431.42,199.13,69.74,10.48"><forename type="first">Ophir</forename><surname>Frieder</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Information Retrieval Lab Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Georgetown University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,165.63,136.49,280.75,15.15;1,201.75,158.40,208.50,15.15">Query Reformulation for Clinical Decision Support Search</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">A3E5346633D49FB40738CDBE9DF7B5D3</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:08+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>One of the tasks a Clinical Decision Support (CDS) system is designed to solve is retrieving the most relevant and actionable literature for a given medical case report. In this work, we present a query reformulation approach that addresses the unique formulation of case reports, making them suitable to be used on a general purpose search engine. Furthermore, we introduce five reranking algorithms designed to re-order a list of retrieved literature to better match the type of information needed for each case report.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>One of the tasks a Clinical Decision Support (CDS) system is designed to solve is retrieving the most relevant and informative literature for a given medical case report.</p><p>The unique formulation of case reports poses a serious challenge for general purpose search engines: case reports are much longer than traditional queries and present a narrative structure.</p><p>Our system, initially disclosed in <ref type="bibr" coords="1,220.30,521.58,10.91,9.57" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, uses a combination of query expansion and query reduction techniques to address the unique formulation of medical case reports when used as queries. Because many of the medical and health-related terms in each case report have one or more domain-specific synonyms, we expand queries to ensure that the retrieval process would not suffer from the limited vocabulary coverage. Rather than relying on a thesaurus, we decided to use pseudo relevance feedback (PRF). The advantage of using such technique is that it is able to expand the case report not only by adding relevant medical terms, but also by incorporating many health-related expressions that are also used in related literature to the original query. That ensures that medical literature that is relevant to the original case report but uses different vocabulary is correctly retrieved. As PRF is not domain specific, we combine it with a health terms filter based on Wikipedia, which prevents query drift by removing terms that are not relevant in the context.</p><p>Our query reformulation approach does not directly take into account the generic question type (diagnosis, test, treatment) provided with each approach. To ameliorate that, we studied the task of providing the</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Case reports</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Search Engine Pseudo Relevance Feedback</head><p>Health Terms Filter Search Engine most relevant literature to a given type as a reranking task on the retrieved results. Different reranking methods were tested, both supervised and unsupervised.</p><p>In summary, our contributions are:</p><p>• A query reformulation technique that combines a domain independent approach with a technique designed for the health domain;</p><p>• A comparison of five different reranking techniques aimed to promote articles that match the type of information needed for each case report.</p><p>An improved and expanded system designed to address CDS search based on this work appeared in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,538.09,407.76,10.91,9.57" target="#b5">[6]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Methodology</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Preprocessing</head><p>The dataset was indexed using ElasticSearch<ref type="foot" coords="2,271.12,505.85,4.23,6.99" target="#foot_0">1</ref> v.1.2.1, a search server built on top of Lucene<ref type="foot" coords="2,496.78,505.85,4.23,6.99" target="#foot_1">2</ref> v.4.8. The following fields were indexed and used for document retrieval (unless otherwise stated): article title, article abstract, and article text. Finally, the default implementation for the divergence from randomness retrieval model <ref type="bibr" coords="2,132.81,548.45,11.52,9.57" target="#b1">[2]</ref> was used.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Query Reformulation</head><p>Our query reformulation approach combines PRF with a health terms filter that removes non-medically related expressions from each case report before submitting it as a query to the search engine (Fig. <ref type="figure" coords="2,541.67,625.35,4.24,9.57" target="#fig_0">1</ref>). This strategy ensures that the original query formulation is expanded by adding many affine terms while preventing query drift.</p><p>Our PRF model is inspired by "IDF Query Expansion" (IDFQE) method proposed by <ref type="bibr" coords="3,478.78,97.11,10.91,9.57" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Our system executes as follows: (i ) a case report q of length n is issued as query to a search engine S; (ii ) of the set of documents D q = {d q,1 , . . . , d q,p } returned by S, the top k are tokenized and used to build the root set R q = {t | t ∈ d q,i for some i ∈ {1, . . . , k} or t ∈ Q}, which consists of the set of all the terms in the top-k documents or in the case report; (iii ) for each term t j ∈ R q , a boost coefficient is determined according to the following formula: b j = log 10 (10 + w j )</p><p>where w j is computed as suggested in <ref type="bibr" coords="3,241.58,198.43,10.91,9.57" target="#b0">[1]</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,242.52,222.20,311.88,33.71">w j = α• I q (t j )• tf j + β k k i=1<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where I q (t j ) = 1 if and only if t j ∈ q (i.e., term t j is in the case report q) and I d q,i (t j ) = 1 if and only if t j ∈ d q,i (term t j is in the case report d q,i ). Once the weights have been determined, the set of m terms {tc 1 , . . . , tc m } with the highest boosting coefficient are selected as candidates for expansion.</p><p>Rather than using a medical thesaurus to determine which terms are more suitable to expand the original query, we rely on Wikipedia. In detail, we estimate for each term tc l its likelihood of being associated with a health-related page on Wikipedia by evaluating the odds ratio between the probability of tc l appearing in a health-related Wikipedia page P over the probability of tc l appearing in a non-health related Wikipedia page P :</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="3,192.78,399.27,361.62,25.64">OR(tc l ) = Pr(P is health related | tc l ∈ P ) Pr(P is not-health related | tc l ∈ P )<label>(3)</label></formula><p>Each tc l in the candidates list {tc 1 , . . . , tc m } is added to the original case report if its odds ratio OR(tc l ) is greater than a threshold δ. Each term in the reformulated case report is finally boosted by its boosting coefficient b j .</p><p>To compute the probabilities in equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="3,269.24,486.71,4.24,9.57" target="#formula_2">3</ref>), a Wikipedia dump from November 4, 2013 containing 2,794,145 unique entries was used. Pages with an information box containing at least one of the following medically-related fields were designated as health-related: DiseasesDB, eMedicine, MedlinePlus, MeSH, and OMIM (24,654 pages). The remaining pages were designated as not health-related.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Re-ranking</head><p>We approached the problem of identifying whether a retrieved document described a treatment, proposed a diagnosis or suggested a test as a reranking problem. In other words, given a list of search results, our system should rank higher those papers whose type aligns with the one in the query. We tested four different reranking strategies, as well as a fusion reranker that combines them via an unbiased voting scheme algorithm.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.1">Supervised SVM Reranker</head><p>Upon observing that vocabulary in medical literature varies based on the goal of the paper (presenting a treatment, discussing a diagnosis, proposing a test), we decided to test whether such property could be exploited in a supervised setting.</p><p>To build a classier to distinguish between different types of biomedical articles, we asked three annotators to read 400 medical papers<ref type="foot" coords="4,186.56,183.50,4.23,6.99" target="#foot_2">3</ref> each (1120 in total, as a 10% overlap was ) and indicate whether they were discussing a treatment, diagnosis, test or none of them. Since it is not uncommon for a biomedical article to be more relevant to more than one category, we allowed the annotators to indicate more than one type for each paper. The agreement between the annotators on 40 overlapping question was 0.43 measured by Cohen's kappa <ref type="bibr" coords="4,130.69,239.65,10.91,9.57" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p><p>We used a one-vs-rest SVM classifier with a linear kernel; for each paper the following features were considered:</p><p>• term stems, stopwords and numbers excluded;</p><p>• MetaMap<ref type="foot" coords="4,130.93,312.21,4.23,6.99" target="#foot_3">4</ref> concepts in the title and abstract.</p><p>Only a portion of MetaMap concepts belonging to selected semantic categories were considered by the classifier <ref type="foot" coords="4,97.75,346.09,4.23,6.99" target="#foot_4">5</ref> ; this approach has been shown more effective by previous work <ref type="bibr" coords="4,410.42,348.04,10.91,9.57" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p><p>Once the retrieved documents {d 1 , . . . , d n } are classified, the system groups them together in clusters {c 1 , . . . , c h } by using the affinity propagation algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="4,336.32,381.91,10.91,9.57" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. Clusters are then ranked by number of articles that were classified in the same type category of the case report. In other words, given a case report q of type T , the following list in produced:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="4,188.79,433.52,365.61,10.63">{c r | ∀t &gt; r, typecount(c r , T ) &gt; typecount(c t , T )}<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where typecount (•, •) is defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="4,189.45,482.54,364.95,10.63">typecount(c r , T ) = |{d j | type(d j ) = T ∧ d j ∈ c r }|<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Finally, the reranked list of retrieved results is produced by concatenating the list of articles in each cluster.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.2">Biographical Reranker</head><p>Since the appropriate treatment, diagnosis or test for a patient often depends on their age, biological sex or race, we hypothesized that articles that contain similar biographical information to those in the case report are more likely to be relevant. Therefore, for each case report q, we rerank the list of documents retrieved by the component of our system described in section 2.2 based on their biographical affinity with q.</p><p>The system proceeds as follows: (i ) age, race and biological sex are extracted from the case report<ref type="foot" coords="5,526.77,95.16,4.23,6.99" target="#foot_5">6</ref> ; (ii ) the same type of information is extracted from each retrieved biomedical article; a document receives a point for each matching biographical information<ref type="foot" coords="5,290.15,122.26,4.23,6.99" target="#foot_6">7</ref> ; (iii ) for each paper, the original ranking score of each document is linearly combined with the points count; (iv ) finally, documents are reranked based on the new score.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.3">Seed Terms Reranker</head><p>In section 2.3.1 we mentioned how we observed that the goal of a biomedical article seems to affect its vocabulary. The reranker presented in this section exploits such observation; however, instead of a classifier, it uses a list of 55 selected seed terms (5 for treatments, 3 for diagnoses and 47 for tests) to determine whether a document matches the type of a case report.</p><p>For each retrieved document, the occurrences of terms in the document in the appropriate set of seed terms are counted; such value is then normalized by the length of the document and combined with the initial document score returned by the search engine. Finally, documents are reranked based on the new score.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.4">MetaMap Similarity Reranker</head><p>This method reranks the retrieved documents based on their similarity with the query in terms of MetaMap concepts.</p><p>For each search result retrieved by submitting a case report q, the system uses MetaMap to extract UMLS concepts from its title and abstract. The concepts are matched with those extracted from the case report. Finally, documents are reranked based on their original score and the normalized number of detected matching concepts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.5">Fusion Reranker</head><p>We combined all the previously described approaches by building a voting-based fusion reranker. The rank assigned by each method to a document is considered as a vote; the final rank of the document consists of the average of the ranks determined by the other four rerankers.      </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head><p>Results for each run are shown in table 1 and figures 2-4. We reported inferred average precision, inferred nDCG, R-precision, average precision after 10 results are retrieved (P@10), and precision when k documents are retrieved (k = 5 to 1000). We included results for each case report type (diagnosis, test, and treatment), as well as the overall performances of each method.</p><p>Combined results (figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,181.55,360.17,4.85,9.57" target="#fig_1">2</ref>) show that Biographical is the best performing reranking method, both in precision-oriented metrics and recall-oriented metrics. We attribute this outcome to the conservative nature of this reranker, as it modifies the rank of the results if and only if there is a strong biographical similarity between the case report and the retrieved documents. SVM performed poorly, underperforming all other methods. This is likely due to difficulty of the annotation task, as indicated by the only moderate agreement among annotators (κ = 0.43). Seed terms and MetaMap show a very similar behavior. The fusion reranker does not seem to offer any improvements over individual methods as its performance is likely to be affected by the worst performing method.</p><p>Some interesting behaviors are observable by looking at the performances of the reranking methods when grouped by case report type.</p><p>For diagnoses (figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,156.88,509.21,4.24,9.57" target="#fig_3">3</ref>), MetaMap shows comparable or better performances to Biographica. This suggests that the overlap between UMLS concepts in the case reports and the concepts in the query is a good indicator of the relevance of literature to a case report for diagnostic purposes. All the methods were found to perform similarly on treatments (figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,292.12,549.85,4.24,9.57" target="#fig_4">4</ref>).</p><p>For tests (figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,136.68,570.18,4.24,9.57" target="#fig_5">5</ref>), we noticed that SVM is capable of achieving solid performances in an high precision setting (e.g., P@5), yet its performances degrades quickly as the number of results retrieved increases. This might suggest that there are some language features exploited by SVM are strong indicators of the relevancy of a paper for this type of case reports. Further tuning of the parameters of the classifier will be conducted to better understand such behavior.</p><p>Finally, as shown in figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,182.87,644.70,4.24,9.57" target="#fig_7">6</ref>, we noticed that the performances for each topic vary greatly, suggesting that some inherit differences are present between topics. Moreover, we observed that, when SVM performed comparably to other methods, Fusion consistently outperformed all other methods. This observation validates the voting strategy adopted in this method.  Topic Number </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions</head><p>We addressed search for clinical decision support, i.e., the task of retrieving relevant literature to a medical case report. We introduced a query reformulation technique that combines PRF with an effective domain specific approach. Furthermore, we studied five reranking algorithms that re-order a list of retrieved literature to better match the type of information needed for each case report.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,115.88,250.87,380.24,9.57"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Query reformulation component (section 2.2) of the proposed system.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="6,205.50,238.31,201.00,9.57"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Overall results for each method.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="6,230.55,391.32,150.91,9.57"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Results for diagnoses.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="6,227.38,544.39,157.25,9.57"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Results for treatments.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5" coords="6,242.06,696.87,127.87,9.57"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Results for tests.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7" coords="8,57.60,259.74,496.80,9.57;8,57.60,273.29,372.79,9.57"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: Inferred average precision and nDCG per topic across each run; topics 1-10 are diagnosisrelated, topics 11-20 are test-related, and topics 21-30 are treatment-related.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="7,57.60,101.01,496.80,141.67"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Inferred average precision, R-precision, inferred nDCG, and precision at 10 documents retrieved for each reranking method. The best performing reranker is highlighted in bold.</figDesc><table coords="7,171.31,101.01,269.38,104.21"><row><cell>Method</cell><cell cols="4">inf-AP R-prec inf-nDCG P@10</cell></row><row><cell>SVM</cell><cell>0.0173</cell><cell>0.0691</cell><cell>0.1015</cell><cell>0.1867</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Biographical 0.0623 0.1871</cell><cell>0.2272</cell><cell>0.3367</cell></row><row><cell>Seed Terms</cell><cell>0.0508</cell><cell>0.1884</cell><cell>0.2076</cell><cell>0.2567</cell></row><row><cell>MetaMap</cell><cell>0.0556</cell><cell>0.1792</cell><cell>0.2174</cell><cell>0.2667</cell></row><row><cell>Fusion</cell><cell>0.0394</cell><cell>0.1550</cell><cell>0.1847</cell><cell>0.1933</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,61.75,681.96,131.81,7.47"><p>http://www.elasticsearch.org</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,61.75,692.92,112.98,7.47"><p>http://lucene.apache.org</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="4,61.75,659.40,170.93,7.86"><p>randomly selected from the entire dataset.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_3" coords="4,61.75,671.00,127.10,7.47"><p>http://metamap.nlm.nih.gov/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5" xml:id="foot_4" coords="4,61.75,681.32,492.65,8.12;4,61.75,692.28,121.38,8.12"><p>acab, anab, comd, cgab, dsyn, emod, fndg, inpo, mobd, neop, patf and sosy for diagnoses, topp and clnd, for treatments, lbpr, lbtr and diap for tests.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6" xml:id="foot_5" coords="5,61.75,670.36,144.25,7.86"><p>When such information is available.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7" xml:id="foot_6" coords="5,61.75,681.32,492.65,7.86;5,61.75,692.28,255.19,7.86"><p>Ages were discretized in five buckets (0-1, 2-12, 13-18, 19-65, 65+); we say that a document matches the case report with respect of age if the two extracted ages fall in the same bucket.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="5">Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was partially supported by the <rs type="funder">US National Science Foundation</rs> through grant <rs type="grantNumber">CNS-1204347</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_rGU98gG">
					<idno type="grant-number">CNS-1204347</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="8,74.57,524.56,479.83,9.57;8,74.57,538.11,291.51,9.57" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,198.56,524.56,351.13,9.57">Searching in medline: Query expansion and manual indexing evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Abdou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Savoy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,74.57,538.11,184.49,9.57">Information Processing &amp; Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="781" to="789" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,74.57,558.44,479.83,9.57;8,74.57,571.99,479.83,9.57;8,74.57,585.54,24.85,9.57" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,248.68,558.44,305.71,9.57;8,74.57,571.99,149.88,9.57">Probabilistic models of information retrieval based on measuring the divergence from randomness</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Rijsbergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,233.76,571.99,242.96,9.57">ACM Transactions on Information Systems (TOIS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="357" to="389" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,74.57,605.86,479.83,9.57;8,74.57,619.41,479.83,9.57;8,74.57,632.96,131.88,9.57" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,365.94,605.86,128.28,9.57">On clinical decision support</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cohan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Soldaini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Yates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Goharian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Frieder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,515.08,605.86,39.32,9.57;8,74.57,619.41,475.01,9.57">Proceedings of the 5th ACM Conference on Bioinformatics, Computational Biology, and Health Informatics</title>
		<meeting>the 5th ACM Conference on Bioinformatics, Computational Biology, and Health Informatics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="651" to="652" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,74.57,653.28,479.83,9.57;8,74.57,666.83,86.66,9.57" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,124.64,653.28,210.84,9.57">A coefficient of agreement for nominal scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,344.33,653.28,204.65,9.57">Educational and psychological measurement</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="1960">1960</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,74.57,97.11,479.83,9.57;9,74.57,110.66,47.88,9.57" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,193.72,97.11,241.76,9.57">Clustering by passing messages between data points</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Frey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dueck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,443.47,97.11,31.92,9.57">science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">315</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5814</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="972" to="976" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,74.57,130.98,479.83,9.57;9,74.57,144.53,342.18,9.57" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,366.83,130.98,187.57,9.57;9,74.57,144.53,76.09,9.57">Retrieving medical literature for clinical decision support</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Soldaini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cohan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Yates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Goharian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Frieder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,174.10,144.53,162.89,9.57">Advances in Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,74.57,164.85,479.83,9.57;9,74.57,178.40,412.98,9.57" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,212.21,164.85,342.19,9.57;9,74.57,178.40,128.69,9.57">Unsupervised biomedical named entity recognition: Experiments with clinical and biological texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Elhadad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,212.50,178.40,158.18,9.57">Journal of biomedical informatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1088" to="1098" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
