<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,79.91,161.71,451.43,15.15;1,147.78,183.63,315.69,15.15">CRP Henri Tudor at TREC 2014: Combining Search Results for Clinical Decision Support</title>
				<funder ref="#_sBBDwjE">
					<orgName type="full">Luxembourgish E-Santé Agency</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_8WnHAzX">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,217.78,217.55,55.54,10.52"><forename type="first">Duy</forename><surname>Dinh</surname></persName>
							<email>duy.dinh@tudor.lu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">CR SANTEC</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Public Research Centre Henri Tudor</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>6 avenue des Hauts-Fourneaux</addrLine>
									<settlement>Esch-sur-Alzette</settlement>
									<country key="LU">Luxembourg</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,284.35,217.55,109.13,10.52"><forename type="first">Asma</forename><forename type="middle">Ben</forename><surname>Abacha</surname></persName>
							<email>asma.benabacha@tudor.lu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">CR SANTEC</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Public Research Centre Henri Tudor</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>6 avenue des Hauts-Fourneaux</addrLine>
									<settlement>Esch-sur-Alzette</settlement>
									<country key="LU">Luxembourg</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,79.91,161.71,451.43,15.15;1,147.78,183.63,315.69,15.15">CRP Henri Tudor at TREC 2014: Combining Search Results for Clinical Decision Support</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">127FFDA7A132B008C077413C8A9C73B8</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:08+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This paper presents the first participation of the Luxembourgish Public Research Center Henri Tudor in the TREC 2014 Clinical Decision Support (CDS) Track. At the Resource Centre for Healthcare Technologies (SANTEC) department, we focus our research activities on healthcare technologies. Our mission consists primarily in improving healthcare by developing methods, tools, services and solutions that can be applied by healthcare professionals, patients and citizens on a daily basis.</p><p>In this research work, we present an approach to combining search results using data fusion techniques. The focus of the 2014 Clinical Decision Support Track was the retrieval of relevant biomedical articles for answering generic clinical questions about medical records. Each question consists of a case report and one of three generic clinical question types, such as "What is the patient's diagnosis?". Retrieved articles are judged relevant if they provide information of the specified type that is relevant to the given case.</p><p>The remainder of this report is organized as follows. Section 2 gives a brief description about the CDS Task. Section 3 describes our methodology for combining search results. Our submitted runs and the official results of TREC CDS Track are described in Section 4. Finally, Section 5 draws our conclusions and outlining directions for future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Overview of the CDS Task</head><p>The TREC Clinical Decision Support (CDS) Track investigates the performance of systems that search a static set of documents obtained from short case reports, such as those published in biomedical articles, as idealized representations of actual medical records. The goal of the task is to rank the documents in the collection in decreasing probability of relevance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Document collection</head><p>The target document collection for the track is the Open Access Subset of PubMed Central (PMC). PMC is an online digital database of freely available full-text biomedical literature. Because documents are constantly being added to PMC, to ensure the consistency of the collection, we obtained a snapshot of the open access subset on January 21, 2014, which contained a total of 733,138 articles. The full text of each article in the open access subset is represented as an NXML file (XML encoded using the NLM Journal Archiving and Interchange Tag Library), and images and other supplemental materials are also available.</p><p>Each article in the collection is identified by a unique number (PMCID), which is specified by the &lt;article-id&gt; element within each article's NXML file.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Topics</head><p>The topics for the track are medical case narratives created by expert topic developers that serve as idealized representations of actual medical records. The case narratives describe information such as a patient's medical history, the patient's current symptoms, tests performed by a physician to diagnose the patient's condition, the patient's eventual diagnosis, and finally, the steps taken by a physician to treat the patient.</p><p>There are many clinically relevant questions that can be asked for a given case narrative. In order to simulate the actual information needs of physicians, the topics are annotated according to the three most common generic clinical question types : diagnosis, test and treatment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Evaluation protocol</head><p>The track received a total of 102 runs from 26 different groups. All the runs contributed to the judgment sets, which were constructed to be compatible with the computing of the inferred measures. In particular, the judgment sets were created using two strata: all documents retrieved in ranks 1-20 by any run in union with a 20% sample of documents not retrieved in the first set that were retrieved in ranks 21-100 by some runs.</p><p>Documents in the judgment set were judged on a three-point scale of 0: not relevant, 1: possibly relevant, 2: definitely relevant. The evaluation measures were computed by conflating the possibly relevant and definitely relevant sets into a single relevant set. The exception to this is the inferred NDCG measure which makes use of the different relevance grades. The measures reported by sample eval are inferred average precision (infAP), inferred NDCG (infNDCG), inferred precision at 10, 50, and 100 documents retrieved (iP10, iP50, iP100), inferred number of relevant retrieved (inum rel ret), inferred number of relevant (inum rel) and number retrieved (num ret).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Methodology</head><p>In our previous work <ref type="bibr" coords="2,414.31,435.83,11.52,9.57" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,427.33,435.83,8.49,9.57" target="#b6">7,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,437.31,435.83,7.68,9.57" target="#b8">9]</ref>, we have examined several data fusion techniques, term weighting models and query expansion models. In this work, we propose another strategy for merging search results into a list of results. We first present the document indexing and retrieval architecture (Section 3.1) and then we present our approach for combining results (Section 3.2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Document indexing and retrieval</head><p>Our indexing and retrieval framework is based on an open source search engine, which has been widely used for research in IR. More specifically, we used the Terrier IR platform for indexing and retrieving documents in the collection <ref type="bibr" coords="2,494.67,634.61,16.00,9.57" target="#b9">[10]</ref>.</p><p>The indexing aims to organize, structure and store statistical and/or linguistic information about terms and documents in the collection allowing a rapid and efficient search. During the indexing stage, stop-words are removed from documents before stemming using the Porter algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="3,113.24,187.49,16.00,9.57" target="#b10">[11]</ref>.</p><p>The document retrieval aims to match the user query and document representations in order to retrieve a list of results that may satisfy the user information need. A document D containing terms used for formulating a query Q is weighted by summing the score of each term appearing in document D:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,112.12,310.74,188.53,22.26">RSV (D, Q) = t∈Q score(t ∈ D)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where score(t ∈ D) is the query term weight calculated using a particular term weighting model. For evaluating the performance of current state-of-the-art weighting models, we chose three different term weighting models used in our experiments, namely BM25 <ref type="bibr" coords="3,213.21,411.23,16.00,9.57" target="#b11">[12]</ref>, In expB2 <ref type="bibr" coords="3,289.13,411.23,11.52,9.57" target="#b1">[2]</ref> and LGD <ref type="bibr" coords="3,124.18,424.78,10.91,9.57" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. We then applied several stateof-the-art pseudo-relevance feedback techniques using statistical measures such as the Bose-Einstein (Bo) statistics <ref type="bibr" coords="3,182.75,465.43,11.52,9.57" target="#b0">[1]</ref> in order to select most related terms for enriching the original query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Document fusion</head><p>Let L = {L 1 , L 2 , ..., L k } be the set of different lists of documents returned by k IR methods, where L i is the result list obtained by the IR method i. Formally:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,131.38,599.59,164.62,10.63">L i = {D i1 , D i2 , ..., D iz } (<label>2</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="3,296.00,599.59,4.65,9.57">)</formula><p>where z is the size of the list L i and D ij is document j belonging to the list L i .</p><p>Each IR method can be configured by a set of parameters (e.g., the term weighting model, term's properties (stopword, low IDF, term length), etc.).</p><p>When the result lists for each query are combined together, we build a set of runs of documents. Each run contains documents with the same ID (docno) but with different scores returned by different IR methods.</p><p>Inspired by our previous work cited in <ref type="bibr" coords="3,505.49,228.14,11.52,9.57" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,518.13,228.14,8.49,9.57" target="#b7">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,527.74,228.14,7.68,9.57" target="#b8">9]</ref>, we aim to define novel combination techniques based on several means.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="3,312.42,286.77,247.72,77.19">           CombH = n a -1 1 +a -1 2 +...+a -1 n (harmonic mean) CombG = n √ a 1 * a 2 * ...a n (geometric mean) CombA = a 1 +a 2 +...+an n (arithmetic mean) CombQ = a 2 1 +a 2 2 +...+a 2 n n (quadramatic mean)<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where n is the number of documents in each run and a i is the score of document D i .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">TREC CDS Submissions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Run description</head><p>We submitted five official runs to the TREC CDS track. Our submitted runs are divided into two groups: the first one includes four automatic runs and the second one includes one manual run. For each group of runs, we aim to evaluate the performance of our data fusion techniques in comparison to state-of-the-art retrieval models. The description of the five submitted runs are as follows:</p><p>• tudorComb1: query terms are only in the description field (long query). We ignore low IDF terms and run the retrieval using three IR models namely BM25, LGD and In expB2 with query expansion (top 30 terms from top 20 returned documents) using the Bo1 model. Finally, the results are combined using the CombA fusion technique (see Formula 3.)</p><p>• tudorComb2: this run is different from the previous run in the sense that query terms are extracted only from the summary field.</p><p>• tudorComb3: this run is similar to the first run except that we consider also low IDF terms for retrieval.</p><p>• tudorComb4: this run is similar to the third run with the exception that we consider query terms in the summary field.</p><p>• tudorCombm: the last run is similar to the first run but is classified as manual because we expand the original query using long forms of abbreviations and give a more important weight for terms denoting medical concepts.</p><p>We use the default term processing pipeline in Terrier: stop-words are removed from documents and queries before stemming using the Porter algorithm. For manual runs, we further removed query terms that are not present in the stop-word list but that we believe are not quite informative. For example, in the query "Patients hearing loss", the term "with" is recognized as a stop-word and is therefore automatically removed from documents/queries. We compare the combined results with the baseline results obtained by each of the three IR models namely BM25, LGD and In expB2 using query expansion (top 30 terms from top 20 returned documents) using the Bo1 model.</p><p>In what follows, we present the results of our official runs submitted to TREC CDS 2014. Afterwards, we present the results obtained unof-ficially on the small set of documents that have been judged either relevant or irrelevant.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Official results</head><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="4,339.93,200.77,5.45,9.57" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows the official results of our runs submitted to TREC CDS 2014. According to the results, we observe that there is no significant difference when using long (description) and short (summary) queries. This is probably due to the poor performance of the IR models on the underlying collection. Indeed, the baseline IR performance is very low : bpref ≈ 0.10, M AP ≈ 0.05, inf AP ≈ 0.09, inf N DCG ≈ 0.11 and P 10 ≈ 0.25, iP 10 ≈ 0.18.</p><p>We also notice that the combined results outperform the results obtained by the baseline, i.e. without combination. For example, the inf N DCG of tudorComb2 run is 0.1640 which is quite better than the best baseline LGD+Bo1 (inf N DCG = 0.1175) with an improvement rate of +39.57%. There is also an improvement rate of +38.19% in terms of iP10 when comparing run tudorComb1 (iP 10 = 0.2533) and the best baseline BM25+Bo1 (iP 10 = 0.1833). Therefore, the results show the evidence of combining results for improving the IR performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Performance analysis</head><p>We study the performance of different data fusion techniques for combining search results. Table 2 depicts the IR results obtained on the pool of documents that have been judged either relevant or not relevant. Here, we only use documents that have been judged, i.e. 29,969 documents, assuming that all documents in the collection must be judged. The results confirm that the arithmetic mean yields the best performance with P 10 = 0.2967 and iP 10 = 0.2000 w.r.t. the other means (harmonic, geometric and quadramatic). However, even if the document space was dramatically reduced, i.e. unjudged documents were removed from the evaluation, the overall IR effectiveness in terms of M AP, inf AP and inf N DCG is quite small (M AP best = 0.1803, inf AP best = 0.0168, inf N DCG best = 0.1756). Also, the overall effectiveness of our system is close to the performance of the IR model B25 in a smaller collection (only documents that have been judged). Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,116.95,515.93,5.45,9.57" target="#fig_0">1</ref> depicts the percentage of relevant vs. irrelevant documents that have been judged either relevant or irrelevant. We observe that for each query, there are a high number of irrelevant documents in comparison to relevant documents.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="5,101.92,131.01,108.39,28.76">X X X X X X X X X X X</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Run</head><p>A first analysis of false positives showed that some irrelevant documents were well ranked by our system due to irrelevant keywords. For example, the word "trip" in the query 2 1 led to 1 Diagnosis. 8-year-old boy with 2 days of loose stools fever and cough after returning from a trip to Colorado several irrelevant documents. In future work, It would be interesting to investigate whether the semantic analysis of topics could improve the performance of our system. We plan to use NLP techniques to analyze queries semantically (e.g. <ref type="bibr" coords="5,334.07,433.30,11.82,9.57" target="#b2">[3]</ref>) in order to give different weights to keywords according to their importance w.r.t. the focus of the query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>We presented our participation to the Clinical Decision Support track in TREC 2014, which is a biomedical retrieval ad hoc task. The underlying IR platform of our experiments is the Terrier search system. Our participation focused on the evaluation of several IR models for term weighting as well as state-of-the-art query expansion models. We have also evaluated several combination techniques.  The combination of search results showed an improvement of the IR performance for large document collections.</p><p>In future work, we aim to investigate the adequate linguistic features extracted from relevant documents in order to better promote relevant documents. For example, we can study the semantic similarity between relevant documents and derive an IR model to rank documents based on their pairwise semantic similarity.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="6,72.00,607.82,467.25,9.57;6,72.00,621.37,359.33,9.57;6,72.10,342.00,487.92,249.66"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Some statistics about the documents submitted by all participants. Those documents are then merged into a pool and judged by TREC as relevant or irrelevant.</figDesc><graphic coords="6,72.10,342.00,487.92,249.66" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,72.00,132.22,467.25,209.90"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>IR effectiveness obtained by each run on the TREC CDS 2014 collection. Bold numbers correspond to the best performance of submitted run while underlined numbers correspond to the best performance of the baselines.</figDesc><table coords="5,115.75,132.22,387.61,159.80"><row><cell cols="2">Performance bpref</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>P10</cell><cell cols="2">infAP infNDCG</cell><cell>iP10</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Submitted runs</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>tudorComb1</cell><cell>0.1045</cell><cell cols="3">0.0503 0.2533 0.0324</cell><cell>0.1508</cell><cell>0.2533</cell></row><row><cell>tudorComb2</cell><cell cols="2">0.1130 0.0513</cell><cell>0.2500</cell><cell>0.0335</cell><cell>0.1640</cell><cell>0.2500</cell></row><row><cell>tudorComb3</cell><cell>0.0320</cell><cell>0.0120</cell><cell>0.1167</cell><cell>0.0100</cell><cell>0.0655</cell><cell>0.1167</cell></row><row><cell>tudorComb4</cell><cell>0.0394</cell><cell>0.0168</cell><cell>0.1433</cell><cell>0.0151</cell><cell>0.0819</cell><cell>0.1433</cell></row><row><cell>tudorCombm</cell><cell cols="4">0.1070 0.0531 0.2467 0.0349</cell><cell>0.1618</cell><cell>0.2467</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Baseline</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>BM25+Bo1</cell><cell>0.1049</cell><cell>0.0502</cell><cell>0.2500</cell><cell>0.0092</cell><cell>0.1170</cell><cell>0.1833</cell></row><row><cell>LGD+Bo1</cell><cell>0.1033</cell><cell>0.0483</cell><cell>0.2433</cell><cell>0.0089</cell><cell>0.1175</cell><cell>0.1833</cell></row><row><cell>In expB2+Bo1</cell><cell>0.1163</cell><cell>0.0486</cell><cell>0.2467</cell><cell>0.0077</cell><cell>0.1017</cell><cell>0.1700</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,310.61,663.04,174.34,7.86"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Chest x-ray shows bilateral lung infiltrates. IR effectiveness obtained by each of the combination techniques on the judged documents (either relevant or irrelevant) extracted from TREC CDS 2014 collection.</figDesc><table coords="6,86.28,130.51,432.72,161.91"><row><cell>````````````C omb.</cell><cell cols="2">Performance bpref</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>P10</cell><cell cols="2">infAP infNDCG</cell><cell>iP10</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CombAVGA</cell><cell cols="4">0.1902 0.1803 0.2967 0.0168</cell><cell>0.1756</cell><cell>0.2000</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">(tudorComb1)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CombAVGG</cell><cell>0.0848</cell><cell>0.0456</cell><cell>0.0400</cell><cell>0.0043</cell><cell>0.0821</cell><cell>0.0833</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CombAVGH</cell><cell cols="2">0.1910 0.1443</cell><cell>0.2400</cell><cell>0.0104</cell><cell>0.1211</cell><cell>0.1267</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CombAVGQ</cell><cell>0.0848</cell><cell>0.0456</cell><cell>0.0400</cell><cell>0.0043</cell><cell>0.0821</cell><cell>0.0833</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Baseline</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">BM25+Bo1</cell><cell>0.1965</cell><cell>0.1846</cell><cell>0.3233</cell><cell>0.0179</cell><cell>0.1869</cell><cell>0.2033</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>LGD+Bo1</cell><cell>0.1852</cell><cell>0.1728</cell><cell>0.3133</cell><cell>0.0174</cell><cell>0.1832</cell><cell>0.2067</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">In expB2+Bo1</cell><cell>0.1955</cell><cell>0.1828</cell><cell>0.3000</cell><cell>0.0161</cell><cell>0.1737</cell><cell>0.1933</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_0" coords="7,88.59,663.68,98.85,7.47;7,333.03,133.29,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,146.84,206.21,9.57;7,333.03,160.39,100.19,9.57"><p>http://www.gecamed.lu ACM SIGHIT International Health Informatics Symposium (IHI 2012) (Miami, FL, USA, January 2012).</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work has been done in the context of the GECAMed 2 <rs type="projectName">R&amp;D</rs> project ("<rs type="projectName">Gestion de Cabinets Médicaux</rs>"), which was developed at the <rs type="affiliation">SAN-TEC department of the Public Research Center Henri Tudor</rs>, with the help of general practicioners in Luxembourg. The project is sponsored by the <rs type="funder">Luxembourgish E-Santé Agency</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_8WnHAzX">
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">R&amp;D</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_sBBDwjE">
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">Gestion de Cabinets Médicaux</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,94.42,466.08,206.22,10.18;7,94.42,479.63,206.22,9.57;7,94.42,493.18,206.22,9.57;7,94.42,506.73,50.00,9.57" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,152.08,466.08,148.56,9.57;7,94.42,479.63,206.22,9.57;7,94.42,493.18,37.78,9.57">Probability models for information retrieval based on divergence from randomness</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Glasgow</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">PhD thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,94.42,534.05,206.21,8.33;7,94.42,545.76,206.22,9.57;7,94.42,559.31,206.22,9.57;7,94.42,572.86,206.22,9.57;7,94.42,586.41,129.33,9.57" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,94.42,545.76,206.22,9.57;7,94.42,559.31,206.22,9.57;7,94.42,572.86,83.58,9.57">Probabilistic Models of Information Retrieval Based on Measuring the Divergence from Randomness</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Rijsbergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,190.91,572.86,109.74,9.57">ACM Trans. Inf. Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="357" to="389" />
			<date type="published" when="2002-10">Oct. 2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,94.42,613.73,206.22,8.33;7,94.42,625.44,206.22,10.18;7,94.42,638.99,206.22,9.57" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,113.88,625.44,186.76,9.57;7,94.42,638.99,188.16,9.57">Medical question answering: Translating medical questions into sparql queries</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ben Abacha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Zweigenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,333.03,184.82,206.22,8.33;7,333.03,196.52,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,210.07,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,223.62,206.21,9.57;7,333.03,237.17,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,250.72,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,264.27,92.43,9.57" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,333.03,196.52,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,210.07,10.00,9.57">Information-based Models for Ad Hoc IR</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Clinchant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gaussier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,376.72,210.07,162.53,9.57;7,333.03,223.62,206.21,9.57;7,333.03,237.17,206.22,9.57;7,486.27,250.72,52.99,9.57;7,333.03,264.27,21.59,9.57">Proceedings of the 33rd International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 33rd International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="234" to="241" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SIGIR &apos;10, ACM</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,333.03,288.69,51.74,8.33;7,402.95,286.85,136.30,9.57;7,333.03,300.40,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,313.95,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,327.50,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,341.05,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,354.60,133.48,9.57" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,402.95,286.85,136.30,9.57;7,333.03,300.40,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,313.95,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,327.50,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,341.05,55.81,9.57">Accès à l&apos;information biomédicale: vers une approche d&apos;indexation et de recherche d&apos;information conceptuelle basée sur la fusion de ressources terminoontologiques</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dinh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Paul Sabatier University -Toulouse</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">PhD thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,333.03,377.18,206.22,10.18;7,333.03,390.73,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,404.28,206.21,9.57;7,333.03,417.82,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,431.37,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,444.92,206.21,9.57;7,333.03,458.47,60.75,9.57" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,498.85,377.18,40.40,9.57;7,333.03,390.73,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,404.28,206.21,9.57;7,333.03,417.82,28.92,9.57">IRIT at TREC 2011: Evaluation of Query Expansion Techniques for Medical Record Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dinh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Tamine</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,392.76,417.82,146.49,9.57;7,333.03,431.37,130.31,9.57">Proceedings of The Twentieth Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>The Twentieth Text REtrieval Conference<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, Maryland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-11-15">2011. November 15-18, 2011. 2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,333.03,482.90,156.77,8.33;7,507.73,481.05,31.52,9.57;7,333.03,494.60,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,508.15,206.21,9.57;7,333.03,521.70,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,535.25,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,548.80,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,562.35,155.87,9.57" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,507.73,481.05,31.52,9.57;7,333.03,494.60,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,508.15,155.92,9.57">Voting Techniques for a Multi-terminology Based Biomedical Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dinh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Tamine</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,509.81,508.15,29.43,9.57;7,333.03,521.70,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,535.25,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,548.80,53.38,9.57">Artificial Intelligence in Medicine -13th Conference on Artificial Intelligence in Medicine, AIME 2011</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Bled, Slovenia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">July 2-6, 2011. 2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="184" to="193" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,333.03,584.93,206.21,10.18;7,333.03,598.48,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,612.03,206.21,9.57;7,333.03,625.58,190.63,9.57" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,468.40,584.93,70.85,9.57;7,333.03,598.48,206.22,9.57;7,333.03,612.03,206.21,9.57;7,333.03,625.58,32.48,9.57">Towards a context sensitive approach to searching information based on domain specific knowledge sources</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dinh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Tamine</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,374.99,625.58,61.22,9.57">J. Web Sem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="52" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,333.03,650.00,206.22,8.33;7,333.03,661.71,206.22,10.18;8,94.42,133.29,206.22,9.57;8,94.42,146.84,206.22,9.57;8,94.42,160.39,194.61,9.57" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,357.04,661.71,182.21,9.57;8,94.42,133.29,206.22,9.57;8,94.42,146.84,110.73,9.57">Factors affecting the effectiveness of biomedical document indexing and retrieval based on terminologies</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Dinh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Tamine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Boubekeur</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,220.37,146.84,80.27,9.57;8,94.42,160.39,85.61,9.57">Artificial Intelligence in Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="167" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,94.42,184.75,206.22,8.33;8,94.42,198.30,206.22,8.33;8,94.42,210.00,206.22,9.57;8,94.42,223.55,206.21,9.57;8,94.42,237.10,206.22,9.57;8,94.42,250.65,206.21,9.57;8,94.42,264.20,33.33,9.57" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,94.42,210.00,206.22,9.57;8,94.42,223.55,145.37,9.57">Terrier: A High Performance and Scalable Information Retrieval Platform</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Plachouras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lioma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,261.32,223.55,39.32,9.57;8,94.42,237.10,206.22,9.57;8,94.42,250.65,139.43,9.57">Proceedings of ACM SIGIR&apos;06 Workshop on Open Source Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>ACM SIGIR&apos;06 Workshop on Open Source Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006. 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,94.42,286.72,206.22,10.18;8,94.42,300.27,206.21,9.57;8,94.42,313.81,206.22,9.57;8,94.42,327.36,60.00,9.57" xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,188.04,286.72,112.60,9.57;8,94.42,300.27,58.87,9.57">An Algorithm for Suffix Stripping</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
			<publisher>Morgan Kaufmann Publishers Inc</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="316" />
			<pubPlace>San Francisco, CA, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,94.42,351.72,206.21,8.33;8,94.42,363.43,206.22,10.18;8,94.42,376.98,206.22,9.57;8,94.42,390.53,140.83,9.57" xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,205.25,363.43,95.39,9.57;8,94.42,376.98,206.22,9.57;8,94.42,390.53,22.75,9.57">Okapi at trec-7: Automatic ad hoc, filtering, vlc and interactive track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Beaulieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Willett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="264" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
