<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,107.66,76.93,396.67,18.04;1,73.70,99.97,464.59,18.04">San Francisco State University at TREC 2014: Clinical Decision Support Track and Microblog Track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,156.98,120.58,81.33,10.80"><forename type="first">Aayush</forename><surname>Bhandari</surname></persName>
							<email>aayushb@sfsu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">San Francisco State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>San Francisco</settlement>
									<country>California</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,246.53,120.58,96.34,10.80"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Klinkhammer</surname></persName>
							<email>jamesk@sfsu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">San Francisco State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>San Francisco</settlement>
									<country>California</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,371.95,120.58,82.92,10.80"><forename type="first">Anagha</forename><surname>Kulkarni</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">San Francisco State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>San Francisco</settlement>
									<country>California</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,107.66,76.93,396.67,18.04;1,73.70,99.97,464.59,18.04">San Francisco State University at TREC 2014: Clinical Decision Support Track and Microblog Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">750CEDD6E9D30E4328D264FC6945B6F4</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:08+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The Clinical Decision Support Track in TREC 2014 involved identifying biomedical articles that could assist in answering generic clinical questions. This paper discusses the methodologies adopted by the system, Runsystem2, that we built for answering these medical questions. Runsystem2 operates by translating a narrative of a patient's case report into a list of structured medical concepts which are then used to generate the query. The articles retrieved for the query are then reranked based on their ability to answer the three types of clinical questions studied in this track: diagnosis, treatment and test. The experimental results demonstrate that the developed system performed close to the median performance on most metrics.</p><p>Our approach to the ad-hoc retrieval task focused on on query expansion, language and re-tweet filtering, and URL boosting. Query expansion used pseudo relevance feedback based on frequency of reoccurring terms. The various filters were then applied over the results from the expanded query after which the remaining tweets were re-ranked via URL boosting. The experimental results demonstrate that the best search effectiveness is obtained when all three techniques are employed.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">INTRODUCTION</head><p>The Clinical Decision Support track ran for the first time in TREC 2014. The specific retrieval task defined under this track was that of answering Generic Clinical Questions. The goal is to assist medical professionals by retrieving biomedical articles that answer different types of clinical questions that are related to a particular patient's case report. Three types of clinical questions were included in the 2014 task: diagnosis, treatment or test. 1 http://www.lemurproject.org/indri/ 2 http://metamap.nlm.nih.gov/ We approached the problem by designing our system Runsystem2 which consisted of three main components: treatment/test score generation, retrieval, and postprocessing. Section 2 describes the steps taken to build the index from a provided corpus of biomedical articles using Indri 1 . The assignment of each document in the corpus with a score, based on the relevance of treatments or tests is also illustrated. Section 3 describes the use of MetaMap 2 and MeSH 3 for transforming a patient's narrative into a set of weighted structured queries. Section 4 describes the post-processing step, where documents are re-ranked based on the type of the clinical question/information need. The experimental results are described in section 5. The paper ends with conclusions in section 6. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">SYSTEM ARCHITECTURE</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Index Building</head><p>The 4 PMC-text bundles provided to the participants were transformed into an inverted index for efficient and convenient access using Indri. The krovetz stemmer was employed for morphological normalization. The index creation process was straightforward because Indri supports documents in xml formats. The indexing allowed documents to be identified by their filename, which were the same as the articles PMC Identification. This number also allowed easy access for viewing formatted versions online. In order to perform focused search of certain sections of a document, such as, the abstract, and the article title, which is supported by Indri, some of the fields were included in the indexing process. These fields included abstract, body, article-id, articletitle and reference-list.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Treatment and Test Scores</head><p>When studying the document collection one of our observations was that documents that specify one or more treatments for a particular medical condition may not always use the term treatment in the document. We saw similar pattern for medical tests as well. This posed a challenge for the retrieval algorithm when answering treatment and test type questions. The solution we developed for this problem made use of an external resource, specifically a list of 421 treatment names from rightdiagnosis.com, and 819 test names from webmd.com. Each name from these lists was used as an individual query with the goal of assigning a treatment score and a test score to each collection document. The fields for searching the treatment and test names was restricted to title, abstract and the body. This field restriction modelled our intuition that a document should be considered relevant to a particular treatment or test only if the key sections (title, abstract, body) mention it, and not if only the references section contains the treatment or test name. The collection documents were ranked for each treatment and test name individually, using Indri. The relevance score assigned by Indri to each document was then divided by the rank of the document to calculate a weighted score. This score decay operation rapidly dampens the document scores down the list. This was done to obtain a small but robust candidate set of relevant documents for the treatment or test name, which is then used in the final step of post-processing. The weighted scores for a document retrieved by multiple treatment or test queries were summed up to assign a final treatment and test score to such document. Documents that were not retrieved by any of the treatment or test queries were assigned the score of 0 by default.</p><p>As a last step the score calculated for treatments and tests were normalized between 0 and 1. Hence, each document in the corpus was assigned with two scores: the treatment score, and the test score.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">QUERY GENERATION and RETRIEVAL</head><p>The Clinical Decision Support Track provided 30 different evaluation topics. Each topic consists of a summary and a description of the patient's case report. We chose to use the description section of the topic to develop our queries since it contained much more detailed explanation than the summary section.</p><p>Upon investigating many biomedical articles we saw numerous medical terms occurring in pairs or triples. Words such as "heart attack" and "myocardial infarction" would make very different sense if they were to appear in a different order, or farther apart. This motivated us to convert the given patient narrative into a set of structured query terms. Upon further inspection we saw cases where instead of being pairs, two or more terms occurred very close to one another. For example the word chest and pain may be portrayed as "chest pain" or "pain around the chest region". To consider these cases such groups of terms each structured term was given term proximity of an ordered or unordered window of length 5. After generating the structured queries each of them were assigned with a weight based on a list of rules described in section 3.2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">MetaMap Concepts</head><p>Recognizing medical concepts in a patient's case report was the most vital step for our system to generate meaningful queries. We decided to use MetaMap, a tool used for mapping biomedical text to the UMLS Meta thesaurus. We employed MetaMap to identify biomedical terms and concepts from the given case report. MetaMap also provides synonyms or hyponym wherever possible and appropriate for the parsed terms. For instance, "female child" is the annotation assigned to the query term "girl" in the above example. The synonyms are specified in round brackets right after the parsed term by MetaMap. One of the most useful pieces of information that MetaMap provides are the semantic type annotations for the parsed terms. These annotations are specified in square brackets. In the above example, "sign or symptoms" is the semantic type assigned to "abdominal pain".</p><p>One of the parameters used with MetaMap during this run was -y (word sense disambiguation). The option causes MetaMap to attempt to disambiguate among concepts scoring equally well in matching input text. For example in the phrase "An 8-year-old boy fell from his bike" the word "fell" would be mapped into "fall" and categorized as the season autumn for the Meta candidate with a rank of 1. Using the word sense disambiguation feature allows, "fall" to be categorized to a much more relatable concept of "falling" for the first Meta candidate.</p><p>Another MetaMap feature that was utilized was the -negex feature that outputs a list of negated UML concepts occurring in the input and the associated strings that caused the negation. In Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,93.38,633.36,5.52,9.94" target="#fig_2">3</ref> we see the --negex output of MetaMap for the phrase "She denies diabetes and hypercholesterolemia." Any concepts that were categorized as negations were not included in the query generation process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">MetaMap Semantic Group Weighting</head><p>MetaMap categorizes every identified concept into one of the 133 available semantic types. The semantic types contain concepts such as "clinical drug", "sign or symptom", "population group" etc. The input phrases that are annotated with semantic type that are directly associated with patient's health, such as "sign or symptoms" and "disease and syndrome", were added to the query as phrasal components, that is, the order of the terms and the proximity within terms specified in the input phrase was required in a matching document. Less stringent rules were applied to the input phrases that were annotated with other semantic types. Specifically the order of the terms was not enforced and the terms could be at most 5 terms apart. Input phrases with fewer than 5 terms were added in this manner to the query. The longer phrases were ignored because typically they were not coherent concepts, and also not central to the query topic.</p><p>The semantic type was also used to assign weights to the input phrases, based on the following rules. The semantic type of "population group" was given a low weight based on the observation that they are often too generic, and thus would not contribute to answering clinical questions. Similarly "geographic areas" and "language" was also given a weight of zero. Conceptual semantic types such as "temporal concept" and "spatial concept" were give a low weight. For example, the word "right" (spatial concept) in "right arm" would be assigned a very low weight, as the main focus of the concept would be the arm and not which side the arm is in. On the other hand semantic types such as, "disease and syndrome", "sign or symptoms", "body part" were assigned the highest possible weight, as they would be very critical is determining the relevance of a biomedical article. Other semantic types that fell under health, biology and chemistry related topics were given a medium weight. Such topics include, "biological functions", "laboratory or test result" "body system", "neoplastic process" and "mental behavior".</p><p>The synonymy and hyponymy annotations assigned to input phrases with highly weighted semantic types were used to expand the input phrase. These expansions were however given one-third weight than of the original concept to avoid query drift.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">MeSH</head><p>Query expansion has been shown to be very important in improving retrieval effectiveness in medical systems <ref type="bibr" coords="4,88.42,608.04,11.77,9.94">[6]</ref>. MetaMap was able to provide expansion for a few terms but many concepts were still missing expansions. As an alternative method of query expansion, MeSH (National Library of Medicine-Medical Subject Headings) descriptors data's entry terms were used to expand the concepts with the sematic type of "sign or symptoms" and "disease and syndrome". At most 2 top entry terms were chosen for any given concept. For example the concept "syncope" would be expanded with "drop attack" and "fainting". These expansion terms were also structured and assigned with a weight that was one third of the original term to avoid query drift.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Retrieval</head><p>After generating the query based on structure, weight and term proximity, there were two other approaches taken before retrieving the documents. The first step was determining the article field restriction. Abstract and body were chosen as the two fields because they were descriptive and highly likely to cover the article's central topic. Article-Title was not included as a field, since most of the queries contained very generic terms whereas most article title contained very specific medical terms. The reference field was not included because they contained author names and article titles, which were not good representative of the patient's case report.</p><p>The second step was using filter requirements, which made it mandatory for a document to contain the prioritized concepts. Most of the highly weighted concepts representing MetaMap semantic group such as "sign or symptom" and "disease and syndrome" were used as the filter terms. Hence, any document that would not contain these terms of the query would just be filtered out. Using the above described methodology a query was generated for each of the 30 topics. The language modelling and inference network based retrieval algorithm, Indri, was used to run the queries against the collection of biomedical articles, and to obtain a ranked result list for each query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">POST-PROCESSING</head><p>Upon examining several biomedical articles retrieved for a given patient's case report, we observed that most of the articles provided some discussion about the patient's diagnosis. However, this did not hold true for treatment or test. Hence it was important to filter and re-rank the retrieved documents based on the type of the query topic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Final Score Generation</head><p>At this point all the documents that were retrieved from the query had three different scores. Indri's relevance score based on the weighted structured query assigned to the document, the normalized treatment score, and the normalized test score computed based on the methodology described in Section 2.2.</p><p>For the treatment query type, the relevance score of every retrieved document was boosted by adding the corresponding treatment score of the document. A similar score boost was applied for test query types using the test scores. The retrieved documents were then re-ranked based on the updated scores for both, treatment and test query types. For the diagnosis query types only Indri's relevance scores were used, and thus re-ranking of documents was unnecessary. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">RESULTS</head><p>The results are reported in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,227.43,360.43,4.14,9.94" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. For most evaluation metrics the Runsystem2's results are slightly lower than the corresponding median score. Although some queries resulted in a low P@10, the total number of relevant document retrieved was greater, which resulted in a slightly higher average recall.</p><p>The query-level analysis for P@10 metric shows that for most queries Runsystem2's performance is close to the median. For some queries, such as, topics 14 and 19, Runsystem2 performed better than the median, but for others, such as, topics 15 and 21, our system did worst. We analyze these queries in further detail in the next section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Query Level Analysis</head><p>The queries generated for topic 14 and 19 had very few terms in the filter requirements. The filter requirement for topic 14, "85-year-old man who was in a car accident 3 weeks ago, now with 3 days of progressively decreasing level of consciousness and impaired ability to perform activities of daily living." is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,161.03,641.04,4.14,9.94" target="#fig_3">4</ref>. In contrast, the filter requirements for topic 15 and 21 contained 4 times as many words. The filter requirement for topic 21, "21year-old female with progressive arthralgias, fatigue, and butterfly-shaped facial rash. Labs are significant for positive ANA and anti-double-stranded DNA, as well as proteinuria and RBC casts." is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,362.44,74.44,4.14,9.94">5</ref>. This suggests that too many filter requirements can overly constrain the query and thus degrade its performance. As such, the rules used to add the filter requirements to the query need to be revisited. Also, the structured query generated by our system for topic 14 and 19 contained few words with high weights, and many words with low weights. The structured query for topic 14 is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,535.75,188.32,4.14,9.94">6</ref>. We believe such a distribution of weights creates a query that is well-focused on a coherent topic (the high weight terms), and also derives support from several related concepts (the low weight terms).</p><p>In contrast, the queries generated for topics 15 and 21 consisted of many terms with high weights. The structured query for topic 21 is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,535.75,276.91,4.14,9.94">7</ref>. We believe this type of weight distribution leads to low retrieval performance because the query focus is too diffused and the central topic of the query is not clear. This suggests that it be worth revisiting the term weight assignment rules used by our system, and to allocate high weights to terms more selectively. Overall, our system is a work in progress, especially so because this is our very first time working with biomedical data and retrieval task. We have identified a couple of promising venues for improvement, and we hope to make further progress once the relevance judgments are made available. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">CONCLUSION</head><p>We presented our system Runsystem2, which uses MetaMap and MeSH to generate a structured query from a case report narrative, and utilizes Indri search engine to find the most relevant biomedical articles for a given patient summary. The documents were further filtered and re-ranked in a post-processing step to adapt the retrieval results to the different types of clinical questions. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Microblogs, such as Twitter, are becoming more popular. Their short nature, 140 characters in the case of Twitter, makes searching microblogs unique in comparison to traditional web searches. The 2014 TREC microblog track contains both a temporallyanchored ad hoc search task, and a tweet time line generation task. We chose to participate in only the ad hoc task. The purpose of this task is to retrieve at most the 1000 most relevant tweets to query Q posted before time T. This year's track uses the same corpus as the 2013 microblog track, consisting of 243 Million tweets, accessed through the twitter-tools API <ref type="bibr" coords="8,254.56,256.04,11.77,10.04" target="#b5">[1]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Query Expansion</head><p>Query expansion involves adding terms in to the original query to improve retrieval effectiveness. Our query expansion method uses a simplified pseudo relevance feedback. First, a baseline search is performed on the corpus using the twitter-tools API and the original queries. The first 20 tweets retrieved for the query are assumed to be relevant. With the help of the Twitter NLP and Part-of-Speech Tagger <ref type="bibr" coords="8,185.84,409.21,14.06,10.91">[2]</ref> the proper nouns are extracted from the pseudo-relevant text. All terms that already appear in the query are removed from this set. The three most commonly occurring proper nouns for each query, with a minimum occurrence of 5, are then inserted into the original query. A baseline search with the API is then run using the new expanded queries. We experimented with a range of settings for each of the parameters specified above, such as, the number of top tweets that are considered relevant, and the number of new terms added to the query. The query set and relevance data from the TREC 2011 and 2013 Microblog tracks were used as a tuning set to select the parameter values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Filtering</head><p>One of the recurring trends we observed was that the tweets retrieved for the expanded query contained significant fraction of tweets that were of sub-par quality due to one of the following two reasons. We developed simple techniques to identify such tweets, with the goal of removing them from the result list to improve search effectiveness.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Re-Tweet Filter:</head><p>Re-tweets are copies of tweets that were originally posted by another user. Upon inspecting the returned tweets we found many re-tweets, beginning with the text "RT@". Because re-tweets are not original content, we presume them to be irrelevant and filter them out by removing tweets beginning with "RT@". For example, a baseline run on the first query (include the query text) in the 2013 query set returns the tweet "RT @anayaseth: whole summer iz left n shortage of water how some1 cn waste water 4 playing holi" as the fourth most relevant tweet.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Language Filter:</head><p>While non-English tweets are not necessarily irrelevant, the queries are all English text. While experimenting with the 2013 track's queries, we observed a large number of non-English tweets that were ranked relatively high but deemed irrelevant. Based on this observation, we decided to remove non-English tweets. Using the Language Detection Library for Java <ref type="bibr" coords="8,349.23,405.73,12.76,10.91">[3]</ref>, developed by Shuyo Nakatani, all non-English tweets were removed from the results. Table <ref type="table" coords="8,353.33,433.35,6.00,10.91" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows a sample of the results from the retweet filter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">URL Boosting</head><p>URL boosting refers to increasing the relevancy rank of results if they contain a URL. Tweets containing URLs can contain far more information than just 140 characters and are more likely to provide information relevant to the query than a tweet without a URL. URL boosting has demonstrated consistent improvement of search effectiveness in past microblog tracks <ref type="bibr" coords="8,510.43,589.71,12.85,10.91">[4]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" coords="8,531.03,589.71,12.85,10.91">[5]</ref>. In our experiment, tweets containing a URL had their relevancy rank boosted by a factor of 1.1. We experimented on the 2011 and 2013 queries and data sets with a range of factors between 2.0 and 1.0 and additionally experimented with lowering the rank of tweets not containing URLs. Ultimately A boosting factor of 1.1 was found to provide the best results on the 2011 and 2013 queries. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Data</head><p>The data set used for the 2014 microblog track is the same set used in the 2013 track. It consists of 243 million tweets taken from the public Twitter stream between February and March of 2013 <ref type="bibr" coords="9,270.82,662.82,12.85,10.91">[6]</ref>.</p><p>The data set cannot be downloaded and is only accessible by running the query set through the twitter-tools API. The difference this year is the query set. The query set consists of 55 different queries varying in length and content. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Results and Conclusion</head><p>In this paper we have described the methods we used in the 2014 TREC microblog track ad-hoc task. We submitted four runs to the ad-hoc task with various features enabled and disabled. Table <ref type="table" coords="10,50.40,274.09,6.00,10.91" target="#tab_5">4</ref> depicts the features enabled and the results of each run. Query expansion and the re-tweet filter were both applied to all runs. URL boosting and the language filter were then applied in turn, with the final run making use of all methods. The mean average precision and precision at 30 are the official evaluation metrics for this track. We found that the run making use of all methods performed the best, with the highest MAP and p@30. Using the ER (expansion re-tweet) run as a baseline for ERL and ERU, the language filter had a more significant impact on the p@30 while URL boosting more greatly affected the MAP. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Runtag Query Expansion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Re-Tweet Filter</head><note type="other">Language</note></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="1,313.25,639.36,201.72,9.94;1,313.25,651.96,57.57,9.94"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Search System Flow Diagram for Runsystem2</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,197.69,223.98,216.46,8.96;3,57.60,246.80,241.31,10.05;3,50.40,259.52,248.50,10.05;3,50.40,272.12,248.55,10.05;3,50.40,284.95,248.41,9.94;3,50.40,297.55,248.28,9.94;3,50.40,310.15,248.32,9.94;3,50.40,322.87,248.36,9.94;3,50.40,335.36,248.32,10.04;3,50.40,348.08,248.23,10.04;3,50.40,360.79,248.19,9.94;3,50.40,373.39,248.52,9.94;3,50.40,386.11,248.28,9.94;3,50.40,398.71,248.34,9.94;3,50.40,411.43,248.24,9.94;3,50.40,423.94,248.29,10.05;3,50.40,436.54,80.70,10.04;3,131.40,79.44,351.00,131.52"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Regular output of MetaMap for a phrase Figure 2 provides an example of of MetaMap's parse and annotations for the phrase "A 15-year-old girl presents to the ER with abdominal pain." MetaMap brokes down the input sentence into phrases, which are then further divided into individual terms or pairs of terms.MetaMap also provides synonyms or hyponym wherever possible and appropriate for the parsed terms. For instance, "female child" is the annotation assigned to the query term "girl" in the above example. The synonyms are specified in round brackets right after the parsed term by MetaMap. One of the most useful pieces of information that MetaMap provides are the semantic type annotations for the parsed terms. These annotations are specified in square brackets. In the above example, "sign or symptoms" is the semantic type assigned to "abdominal pain".</figDesc><graphic coords="3,131.40,79.44,351.00,131.52" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="3,226.73,610.34,158.55,8.96;3,86.40,461.88,432.00,137.04"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Negex output for MetaMap</figDesc><graphic coords="3,86.40,461.88,432.00,137.04" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="5,331.27,577.17,194.32,9.94;5,331.20,451.44,149.28,122.64"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Filter requirements for topic 14</figDesc><graphic coords="5,331.20,451.44,149.28,122.64" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="6,50.40,493.07,176.50,8.96;6,50.40,72.00,213.24,417.96"><head>Figure 5 :Figure 6 :Figure 7 :Figure 8 :</head><label>5678</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Filter requirements for topic 21</figDesc><graphic coords="6,50.40,72.00,213.24,417.96" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" coords="7,57.60,72.00,165.00,438.72"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="7,57.60,72.00,165.00,438.72" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,45.72,225.18,238.75,93.71"><head>Table 1 : Runsystem2's search effectiveness, as compared to the median performance.</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="5,45.72,225.18,238.75,56.15"><row><cell></cell><cell>InfAP</cell><cell cols="2">infNDCG R-prec P@10 Recall</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Median 0.0316 0.1514</cell><cell>0.1257 0.2333</cell></row><row><cell>Runsys tem2</cell><cell cols="2">0.0195 0.1194</cell><cell>0.0926 0.1867 0.2792</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="8,369.40,713.94,192.62,10.91"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Table 2 illustrates the change URL boosting had on the first query. Comparison of the number of relevant results returned and the total results returned with language filter on and off (runs ER and ERL)</figDesc><table coords="9,58.80,91.98,466.83,325.63"><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>num_rel_ret / num_ret</cell><cell>num_rel_ret / num_ret</cell></row><row><cell>id</cell><cell>query</cell><cell>(language filter = off)</cell><cell>(language filter = on)</cell></row><row><cell>172</cell><cell>Merging of US Air and American</cell><cell>296/706</cell><cell>296/548</cell></row><row><cell>174</cell><cell>Hubble oldest star</cell><cell>13/867</cell><cell>13/734</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">175 commentary on naming storm Nemo</cell><cell>257/617</cell><cell>252/591</cell></row><row><cell>181</cell><cell>Costa Concordia shipwreck</cell><cell>23/733</cell><cell>22/411</cell></row><row><cell>183</cell><cell>Evernote hacked</cell><cell>274/808</cell><cell>266/468</cell></row><row><cell>185</cell><cell>National Zoo Panda, insemination</cell><cell>22/742</cell><cell>21/562</cell></row><row><cell>193</cell><cell>Bulgarian protesters self immolate</cell><cell>90/763</cell><cell>89/667</cell></row><row><cell>200</cell><cell>UK passes marriage bill</cell><cell>78/643</cell><cell>78/624</cell></row><row><cell>201</cell><cell>Higgs Boson discovery</cell><cell>280/721</cell><cell>277/484</cell></row><row><cell>211</cell><cell>Downton Abbey, Lady Mary, beau</cell><cell>16/823</cell><cell>16/782</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Query ID,</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="9,86.66,406.89,398.72,109.50"><head>Top 20 tweets relevance Top 20 tweets post URL boost relevance</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="9,86.66,426.27,377.33,90.11"><row><cell>299651936842571777</cell><cell>16.79</cell><cell>307496241623883776</cell><cell>16.95</cell></row><row><cell>307360182604820481</cell><cell>16.77</cell><cell>302903789118173185</cell><cell>16.94</cell></row><row><cell>307462808801513472</cell><cell>16.30</cell><cell>299651936842571777</cell><cell>16.79</cell></row><row><cell>307216821277310977</cell><cell>16.22</cell><cell>307360182604820481</cell><cell>16.77</cell></row><row><cell>300671001728000000</cell><cell>16.22</cell><cell>307534271374061568</cell><cell>16.44</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="9,64.46,550.11,483.06,24.71"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>The top 20 returned tweet ids on query MB171 "Ron Weasley birthday" and their relevance rating before and after URL boosting is applied</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="9,324.05,632.94,237.48,24.71"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Table 3 summarizes the query set. Summarization of the query set. Query content is an approximation. Queries may relate to multiple content categories, or none at all</figDesc><table coords="10,81.14,78.18,455.25,50.08"><row><cell></cell><cell>query length</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">number of queries with content relating to:</cell></row><row><cell>Minimum</cell><cell>maximum</cell><cell>average</cell><cell>people/objects</cell><cell>locations</cell><cell>events</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>3.76</cell><cell>28</cell><cell>13</cell><cell>35</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="10,73.82,332.97,436.04,134.34"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Run configurations and comparison</figDesc><table coords="10,277.37,332.97,230.92,24.52"><row><cell></cell><cell>URL</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Filter</cell><cell>Boosting</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>p@30</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,345.67,425.73,195.71,9.94;6,338.11,438.33,94.44,9.94" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,350.74,425.73,137.29,9.94">Medical Tests and Tools A to Z</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,500.09,425.73,41.29,9.94;6,338.11,438.33,34.51,9.94">WebMD. WebMD</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005-2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,338.11,476.25,193.04,9.94;6,338.11,488.97,211.29,9.94;6,338.11,501.57,106.39,9.94" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,338.11,476.25,193.04,9.94;6,338.11,488.97,211.29,9.94;6,338.11,501.57,73.15,9.94">MetaMap -A Tool For Recognizing UMLS Concepts in Text. Software. National Library of Medicine (NLM)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,345.67,514.17,185.24,9.94;6,338.11,526.89,53.02,9.94;6,338.47,539.49,161.84,9.94" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,352.21,514.17,169.29,9.94">TREC Clinical Decision Support Track</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.trec-cds.org/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,338.11,526.89,24.76,9.94">TREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-02">Feb. 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,338.11,552.21,220.92,9.94;6,338.11,564.81,110.16,9.94;6,338.11,577.41,219.29,9.94;6,338.11,590.13,8.59,9.94" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,342.44,552.21,79.19,9.94">List of Treatments</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.rightdiagnosis.com/lists/treats.htm" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,433.90,552.21,125.13,9.94;6,338.11,564.81,46.54,9.94">RightDiagnosis.com. Health Grades Inc</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-06-17">17 Jun.2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,345.67,602.76,206.23,9.94;6,345.67,615.48,179.65,9.94;6,345.67,628.08,148.42,9.94;6,345.67,640.80,214.17,9.94;6,345.67,653.40,70.99,9.94;10,50.40,520.84,65.10,12.54" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,404.17,615.48,121.15,9.94;6,345.67,628.08,111.53,9.94">Query Expansion Using the UMLS® Metathesaurus®</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alan</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Rindflesch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://skr.nlm.nih.gov/papers/references/query_expansion.97.pdfReferences" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Print</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,67.42,549.75,99.66,10.91;10,50.40,563.55,184.23,10.91" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/lintool/twitter-tools" />
		<title level="m" coord="10,100.40,549.75,61.76,10.91">Twitter Tools</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,67.42,591.15,202.79,10.91;10,50.40,604.98,79.40,10.91;10,68.42,618.78,187.49,10.91" xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://www.ark.cs.cmu.edu/TweetNLP/" />
		<title level="m" coord="10,149.71,591.15,120.49,10.91;10,50.40,604.98,74.14,10.91">Twitter NLP and Part-of-Speech Tagging</title>
		<imprint/>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>CMU ARK Lab</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,67.42,646.38,162.86,10.91;10,50.40,660.18,222.60,10.91" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="10,129.50,646.38,95.47,10.91">Language-Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nakatani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://code.google.com/p/language-detection/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,341.07,531.39,217.42,10.91;10,324.05,545.19,233.10,10.91;10,339.07,558.98,204.23,10.92;10,324.05,572.78,27.00,10.92" xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mccreadie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="10,508.51,531.39,49.97,10.91;10,324.05,545.19,233.10,10.91;10,339.07,558.98,204.23,10.92">Relevance in Microblogs: Enhancing Tweet Retrieval using Hyperlinked Documents In Proc. of TREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,341.07,600.42,214.63,10.91;10,324.05,614.22,228.66,10.91;10,338.83,628.01,174.31,10.92" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,397.49,614.22,155.22,10.91;10,338.83,628.02,30.67,10.91">The University of Amsterdam at TREC</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Berendsen</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Meij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Odijk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rijke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Weerkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,412.39,628.01,70.75,10.92">Proc. of TREC</title>
		<meeting>of TREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012. 2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,341.10,655.62,178.88,10.91" xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Trec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Track Guidelines</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
