<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,137.53,115.96,340.30,12.62">TUW @ TREC Clinical Decision Support Track</title>
				<funder ref="#_ekrpTEW">
					<orgName type="full">European Union Seventh Framework Programme</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_ZKwnC9b">
					<orgName type="full">Austrian Science Fund (FWF)</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,160.37,154.83,51.83,8.74"><forename type="first">João</forename><surname>Palotti</surname></persName>
							<email>palotti@ifs.tuwien.ac.at</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Software Technology and Interactive Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Vienna University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AT">Austria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,219.59,154.83,67.36,8.74"><forename type="first">Navid</forename><surname>Rekabsaz</surname></persName>
							<email>rekabsaz@ifs.tuwien.ac.at</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Software Technology and Interactive Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Vienna University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AT">Austria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,295.06,154.83,67.55,8.74"><forename type="first">Linda</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
							<email>anderson@ifs.tuwien.ac.at</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Software Technology and Interactive Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Vienna University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AT">Austria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,390.20,154.83,64.78,8.74"><forename type="first">Allan</forename><surname>Hanbury</surname></persName>
							<email>hanbury@ifs.tuwien.ac.at</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Software Technology and Interactive Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Vienna University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AT">Austria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,137.53,115.96,340.30,12.62">TUW @ TREC Clinical Decision Support Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">8EEF005824F283F5761800529920171F</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:08+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>Medical Information Retrieval, Evaluation</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This document describes the participation of Vienna University of Technology in the TREC Clinical Decision Support Track 2014. Four different search models are investigated, as well as different strategies to index the corpus and to extract the most relevant information from the topics. Our results conclude that BM25 and Vector Space Model had similar performance for P@10 and inferred NDCG.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Searching for health has become a common task nowadays. Pew Research Center estimates that 80% of the American population uses the Web to seek health information <ref type="bibr" coords="1,189.38,418.49,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. In line with this trend, various health-related campaigns were proposed. Some examples are the TREC Genomics Track <ref type="bibr" coords="1,397.09,430.45,10.52,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref> which ran from 2003 to 2007, the TREC Medical Records Track <ref type="bibr" coords="1,351.04,442.40,10.52,8.74" target="#b8">[9]</ref> running in 2011 and 2012, the ImageCLEFmed Track on medical image retrieval <ref type="bibr" coords="1,383.63,454.36,10.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,394.59,454.36,7.31,8.74" target="#b4">5]</ref> running between 2003 and 2013, and the ShARe/CLEF eHealth Evaluation Lab <ref type="bibr" coords="1,423.93,466.31,10.96,8.74" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,434.89,466.31,7.31,8.74" target="#b2">3]</ref> running in 2013 and 2014. Here we briefly describe the goals of the first TREC Clinical Decision Support Track (TREC-CDS) and the participation of Vienna University of Technology.</p><p>The TREC-CDS is focused on physicians searching for relevant information for patient care. As document collection, it uses the open access subset of PubMed Central (PMC), containing a total of 733,138 articles. The topics are divided into three main types: diagnosis, test and treatment. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="1,437.98,551.20,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows a diagnosis query.</p><p>As there was no development set available, we decided to experiment with different search models and indexing possibilities, trying to build a initial foundation for our future participation next year.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Our Contribution</head><p>In this paper, we experiment and evaluate a large variety of search models and indexing strategies, as well as ways of combining different models and indexes.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Experiments</head><p>In our experiments, we explore several different search techniques, IR-system, as well as different indexing strategies. In this section all the different configurations used will be described in details. In Section 2.1, we explain how we create three varieties of index using the MeSH hierarchy. Thereafter, in Section 2.2 we explain our query formulation method, where we make use of Metamap to retain only the most important concepts from each topic. In the Sections 2.3, 2.4 and 2.5 we briefly explain the 3 different IR-systems that we use for our runs: Run1 (Indri), Run2 (Lucene), and Run3 (Xapian). For each system, we generate 6 runs: a combination of the 3 indices methods from Section 2.1 and 2 query strategies from Section 2.2. We merge the scores of each run into a final run for each system. For Run4, we combine the documents from the previous 3 runs, as we explain in Section 2.6. Finally, we explore Word2Vec in our Run5, explained in Section 2.7.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Indexing Concepts</head><p>We take advantage of the Medical Subject Headings (MeSH 1 ) hierarchy to keep only the important concepts of each document in the collection. MeSH has an hierarchical structure for a set of terms named descriptors as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,472.84,580.20,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. The hierarchical structure makes it possible to narrow the scope of the terms. It is updated every year and the 2014 version has 27,149 descriptors.</p><p>Based on MeSH hierarchy, we create 3 types of indexes:</p><p>1. All words: we index the documents as they are, without removing and word;</p><p>1 http://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/MBrowser.html We use all 3 indexes for runs 1, 2, 3 and 4, and only MeSH-CD for run 5, as describe in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,212.89,422.56,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_1">1</ref>. For all runs, a script to lowercase and remove punctuation is also used. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Selecting Terms in the Topics</head><p>We employ NLM's Metamap (version 2013) with default processing options <ref type="bibr" coords="3,470.07,620.25,10.52,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref> to annotate all the topics. Metamap maps the topics to UMLS concepts and semantic types. There are a total of 133 semantic types, but some of them (e.g., Clinical Drug or Disease or Syndrome) are more important than others in our experiments<ref type="foot" coords="4,217.98,117.42,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">2</ref> . For example, the last sentence in the description part of Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,166.51,130.95,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_0">1</ref> is: "A 62-year-old man sees a neurologist for progressive memory loss and jerking movements of the lower extremities" from which Metamap identifies concepts such as:</p><p>- In an automatic manner, we kept only the concepts in which the semantic types are related to symptoms, diseases or treatments (based on <ref type="bibr" coords="4,438.03,258.75,10.30,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref>): man, memory loss, jerking movements, and lower extremities.</p><p>For each topic, we can:</p><p>1. use the description of the topic as the query; 2. use only the keywords related to symptom, diseases or treatments, provided by Metamap semantic types.</p><p>For runs 1, 2, 3 and 4 we generated runs both possibilities. For Run5, we only generated runs using only the second possibility.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Run1</head><p>Run1 was based on Indri<ref type="foot" coords="4,248.64,396.73,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_1">3</ref> . Indri is a search engine from the Lemur project, mainly based on Language Modeling as retrieval model. We used only the #combine operator in our experiments. Six runs were generated: three different indexing strategies combined with two different ways to formulate the queries. The runs were combined simply adding the scores for each document.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Run2</head><p>Lucene<ref type="foot" coords="4,165.35,489.97,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_2">4</ref> is a text search engine written in Java and supported by the Apache Foundation. The default search model of Lucene is the Vector Space Model (VSM), and it was used with the default parameters. As for Run1, six runs were generated and combined summing the scores of each individual document.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Run3</head><p>Xapian <ref type="foot" coords="4,166.04,571.26,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_3">5</ref> is also an open source search engine. It is written in C++ and has BM25 weighting scheme as its default. The scores of the six run created were also summed for each document.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.6">Run4</head><p>Our Run4 is the combination of all the previous runs. However, instead of using the raw scores provided by the systems, we used the position a document had in each run as its score (1/position).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.7">Run5</head><p>Word2Vec<ref type="foot" coords="5,179.07,203.16,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_4">6</ref> provides vector representation of words by using deep learning. We had to compared each word in the query with each word in the documents, in a quadratic procedure. Therefore, we used only the MeSH-CD indexing strategy and the Metamap strategy for building the queries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head><p>We detail the results for all 30 topics in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,339.34,291.12,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_3">3</ref>. There were some very difficult topics, such as 3, 9, 23 and 25, in which more than 50% of all participant systems could not find one single relevant document in the top 10. For other topics, such topic 4 and 27, the results were in general high. On average, our systems, in special the ones using Xapian and Lucene as base, were as good as the median system for both P@10 and inferred NDCG.</p><p>In general, Run1 was our worst run, performing much worse than the others. Run5 also did not perform so well, but it can be explained by the fact that only the smaller indexing strategy (MeSH-CD) and Metamap queries were used for this system. In any case, a detailed investigation of the performance of these two runs need to be carried in the future. Run2 and Run3 were our best runs, Run3 had slight better performance for P@10, but Run2 was better for inferred NDCG. Run4 was stable enough to perform relatively well even after the terrible performance of Run1. Table <ref type="table" coords="5,260.70,446.54,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_2">2</ref> compares the averaged results for all 5 runs, the median and the best system for each topic.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Runs</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>Improving search systems for health related documents is an important challenge for information retrieval researchers. In this work, we focused on creating a robust baseline system, testing different search models and indexing alternatives and possible ensembles.</p><p>Our experiments have shown that Lucene, using Vector Space Model, and Xapian, using BM25, had very similar performances. An ensemble of these two can lead for better results, and it is one of our future work. Also, investigating what caused the Language Model of Indri to perform so bad is left as an important future work.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,228.74,299.94,157.88,8.74"><head>Fig. 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1: Example of a diagnosis query</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,182.43,320.86,250.50,8.74;3,238.51,115.84,138.32,193.50"><head>Fig. 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2: MeSH hierarchy with the disease branch expanded</figDesc><graphic coords="3,238.51,115.84,138.32,193.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="4,151.70,172.04,274.14,8.74;4,140.99,183.41,227.33,8.77;4,140.99,194.82,255.15,8.77;4,140.99,206.23,273.42,8.77;4,140.99,217.63,19.01,8.77;4,140.99,229.04,308.65,8.77"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Concept: /year (per year) -Semantic Type: Temporal Concept -Concept: Old -Semantic type: Temporal Concept -Concept: MAN (Male gender) -Semantic type: Finding -Concept: sees (Vision) -Semantic type: Organism Function -... -Concept: (Lower -spatial qualifier)-Semantic type: Spatial Concept</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="6,178.09,489.80,259.18,8.74"><head>Fig. 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3: Precision at 10 and Inferred NDCG for all 30 topics.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,109.64,467.87,408.24,77.61"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Summary description of all 5 runs</figDesc><table coords="3,109.64,467.87,408.24,63.76"><row><cell>Runs</cell><cell cols="2">System</cell><cell>Indexing Variants</cell><cell>Query Variants</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Model</cell><cell cols="3">Search Engine All Words MeSH voc. MeSH-CD Whole Desc. Metamap Filter</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Run1 Language Model</cell><cell>Indri</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Run2 Vector Space Model</cell><cell>Lucene</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Run3</cell><cell>BM25</cell><cell>Xapian</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Run4</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>Combo</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Run5</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>Word2Vec</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,134.77,493.70,345.82,120.92"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results averaged over the 30 topics for each of our 5 runs, the Best and Median system.</figDesc><table coords="5,212.45,493.70,190.46,94.61"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">P10 InfNDCG infAP RPrec</cell></row><row><cell>Best</cell><cell>0.71</cell><cell>0.520</cell><cell>0.180</cell><cell>0.350</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Median 0.23</cell><cell>0.151</cell><cell>0.032</cell><cell>0.126</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Run1 0.02</cell><cell>0.017</cell><cell>0.001</cell><cell>0.007</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Run2 0.28</cell><cell>0.193</cell><cell cols="2">0.057 0.174</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Run3 0.29</cell><cell>0.171</cell><cell>0.042</cell><cell>0.152</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Run4 0.23</cell><cell>0.152</cell><cell>0.033</cell><cell>0.141</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Run5 0.14</cell><cell>0.059</cell><cell>0.009</cell><cell>0.040</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_0" coords="4,144.73,612.96,335.87,8.12;4,144.73,624.57,169.46,7.47"><p>A complete list of every semantic type can be found here: http://metamap.nlm. nih.gov/SemanticTypesAndGroups.shtml</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_1" coords="4,144.73,635.53,160.05,7.47"><p>http://www.lemurproject.org/indri/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_2" coords="4,144.73,646.48,117.68,7.47"><p>http://lucene.apache.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5" xml:id="foot_3" coords="4,144.73,657.44,84.73,7.47"><p>http://xapian.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6" xml:id="foot_4" coords="5,144.73,657.44,164.76,7.47"><p>https://code.google.com/p/word2vec/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This research was funded by the <rs type="funder">European Union Seventh Framework Programme</rs> (<rs type="programName">FP7/2007-2013)</rs> under grant agreement n o 257528 (KHRESMOI) and partly funded by the <rs type="funder">Austrian Science Fund (FWF)</rs> project number <rs type="grantNumber">I1094-N23</rs> (MUCKE).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_ekrpTEW">
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">FP7/2007-2013)</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_ZKwnC9b">
					<idno type="grant-number">I1094-N23</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,234.24,342.25,7.86;7,146.91,245.20,173.14,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,211.74,234.24,268.85,7.86;7,146.91,245.20,89.70,7.86">Effective mapping of biomedical text to the UMLS Metathesaurus: the MetaMap program</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,256.16,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,267.12,212.81,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,214.60,256.16,265.99,7.86;7,146.91,267.12,23.16,7.86">Health topics: 80% of internet users look for health information online</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Susannah</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,178.03,267.12,153.61,7.86">Pew Internet &amp; American Life Project</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,278.08,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,289.04,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,300.00,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,310.96,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,321.92,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,332.87,292.47,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,312.97,300.00,167.62,7.86;7,146.91,310.96,56.97,7.86">Overview of the share/clef ehealth evaluation lab 2014</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Liadh</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lorraine</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hanna</forename><surname>Suominen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Tobias</forename><surname>Schreck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gondy</forename><surname>Leroy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Danielle</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mowery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sumithra</forename><surname>Velupillai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Martínez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Guido</forename><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>João</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Palotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,226.23,310.96,254.37,7.86;7,146.91,321.92,277.93,7.86;7,303.85,332.87,44.40,7.86">Information Access Evaluation. Multilinguality, Multimodality, and Interaction -5th International Conference of the CLEF Initiative</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Sheffield, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-09-15">2014. September 15-18, 2014. 2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="172" to="191" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,343.83,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,354.79,333.67,7.86;7,146.91,365.75,185.18,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,453.05,343.83,27.54,7.86;7,146.91,354.79,256.52,7.86">Image-CLEF: Experimental Evaluation in Visual Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Deselaers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><surname>Caputo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<publisher>Springer Publishing Company</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Incorporated, 1st edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,376.71,342.25,7.86;7,146.91,387.67,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,398.63,333.68,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,355.49,387.67,125.10,7.86;7,146.91,398.63,185.14,7.86">Overview of the imageclef 2012 medical image retrieval and classification tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alba</forename><surname>García Seco De Herrera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jayashree</forename><surname>Kalpathy-Cramer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Dina</forename><surname>Demner-Fushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sameer</forename><surname>Antani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Eggel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In CLEF 2012 working notes</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,409.59,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,420.55,333.67,7.86;7,146.91,431.50,156.66,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,402.94,409.59,77.65,7.86;7,146.91,420.55,333.67,7.86;7,146.91,431.50,30.79,7.86">User intent behind medical queries: an evaluation of entity mapping approaches with metamap and freebase</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>João</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Veronika</forename><surname>Palotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Allan</forename><surname>Stefanov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Hanbury</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,197.16,431.50,15.46,7.86">IIiX</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="286" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,442.46,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,453.42,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,464.38,305.88,7.86" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,409.24,442.46,71.35,7.86;7,146.91,453.42,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,464.38,180.84,7.86">Tasks, topics and relevance judging for the TREC genomics track: five years of experience evaluating biomedical text information retrieval systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Phoebe</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hersh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,336.05,464.38,36.66,7.86">Inf. Retr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="97" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,475.34,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,486.30,333.67,7.86;7,146.91,497.26,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,508.22,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,519.18,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,530.13,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,541.09,301.51,7.86" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,297.25,508.22,183.35,7.86;7,146.91,519.18,33.38,7.86">Overview of the share/clef ehealth evaluation lab 2013</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hanna</forename><surname>Suominen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sanna</forename><surname>Salanterä</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sumithra</forename><surname>Velupillai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><forename type="middle">Webber</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Guergana</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Savova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Noemie</forename><surname>Elhadad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sameer</forename><surname>Pradhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Brett</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>South</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Danielle</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mowery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Gareth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Liadh</forename><surname>Leveling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lorraine</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Guido</forename><surname>Martínez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,205.02,519.18,275.58,7.86;7,146.91,530.13,276.09,7.86;7,312.89,541.09,44.40,7.86">Information Access Evaluation. Multilinguality, Multimodality, and Visualization -4th International Conference of the CLEF Initiative</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Valencia, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-09-23">2013. September 23-26, 2013. 2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="212" to="231" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,552.05,342.25,7.86;7,146.91,563.01,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,573.97,159.75,7.86" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,224.58,552.05,130.03,7.86">The TREC medical records track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ellen</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,371.96,552.05,108.64,7.86;7,146.91,563.01,36.31,7.86">ACM Conference on Bioinformatics</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Washington, DC, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013. 2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">239</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
