<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,140.78,90.31,330.44,7.58;1,122.87,108.25,366.26,7.58">UCLA at TREC 2014 Clinical Decision Support Track: Exploring Language Models, Query Expansion, and Boosting</title>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">UCLA Department of Radiological Sciences</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_ehYZwhG">
					<orgName type="full">NIH/NLM</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_smCREJM">
					<orgName type="full">NLM</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2015-01-29">January 29, 2015</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,167.76,135.92,117.82,12.66"><forename type="first">Jean</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Garcia-Gathright</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Bioengineering</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,296.94,135.92,57.38,12.66"><forename type="first">Frank</forename><surname>Meng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Bioengineering</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Radiological Sciences</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,372.75,135.92,59.71,12.66"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Hsu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Bioengineering</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Radiological Sciences</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Los Angeles</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,140.78,90.31,330.44,7.58;1,122.87,108.25,366.26,7.58">UCLA at TREC 2014 Clinical Decision Support Track: Exploring Language Models, Query Expansion, and Boosting</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2015-01-29">January 29, 2015</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">F355A37BC42AA86186BC2A296EA428B4</idno>
					<note type="submission">Preprint submitted to TREC 2014 Proceedings</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:08+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>For the TREC 2014 Clinical Decision Support track, participants were given a set of 30 patient cases in the form of a short natural language description and a data set of over 700,000 full-text articles from PubMed Central. The task was to retrieve articles relevant to the patient cases and one of three types of clinical question: diagnosis, test, and treatment. This paper describes the retrieval system developed by the Medical Imaging Informatics group at the University of California, Los Angeles. One manual run and four automatic runs were submitted. For the automatic runs, a variety of retrieval strategies were explored. Two retrieval methods were compared: the vector space model with TF-IDF similarity, and a unigram language model with Jelinek-Mercer smoothing. The performance of retrieving on abstracts alone was compared to that of full-text. Finally, a simple set of rules for query expansion and term boosting was developed based on recommendations from domain experts.</p><p>Submissions for 26 groups were pooled and evaluated by a team of medical librarians and physicians at the National Institute of Standards and Technology. The results showed that 1) the language model outperformed the vector space model for automatically-constructed queries, 2) searching full-text was more eective than searching abstracts alone, and 3) boosting improved the ranking of retrieved documents for "test" topics, but not "diagnosis" topics. Our best automatic run used the language model, full-text search, query expansion, and no boosting.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>PubMed, the National Library of Medicine's database of over 23 million citations, is an important source of knowledge in the biomedical domain. In order to leverage PubMed to provide evidence-based decision support to clinicians at the point-of-care, it is necessary to develop strategies to retrieve literature relevant to specic patients. Retrieved documents should address common clinical questions such as: what is the patient's diagnosis? What tests should the patient receive? What treatment should the patient receive?</p><p>The TREC 2014 Clinical Decision Support track challenged participants to retrieve articles from PubMed Central, an open-access subset of PubMed, given a short description of a patient case and an associated clinical question. 30 patient cases were provided, as well as a data set of over 700,000 full-text articles from PubMed Central. This paper describes the retrieval system developed by the Medical Imaging Informatics group at the University of California, Los Angeles. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Indexing</head><p>The PubMed Central articles were given as a set of XML les, one le per article. An XML parser, implemented in Python, extracted PMC IDs, keywords, titles, abstracts, and full-texts from the XML. If an abstract was not available for an article, the Conclusion section of the text, extracted with a regular expression, was used as a substitute for the abstract.</p><p>The GATE MetaMap plugin <ref type="bibr" coords="2,247.88,438.70,11.93,12.66" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,259.82,438.70,7.96,12.66" target="#b1">2]</ref> mapped the abstracts of the articles to the Unied Medical Language System (UMLS) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,259.02,452.25,10.85,12.66" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, a controlled vocabulary for biomedical terminology. The mapping included identication of concept names, concept codes, semantic types, negation status, and match scores. To prevent excessive numbers of matched concepts, only match scores greater than 800 were used.</p><p>Data for each article was stored in a relational database. Two indexes were created using Apache Lucene <ref type="bibr" coords="2,163.06,520.00,10.85,12.66" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. The rst index used Lucene's default scoring method: a vector space model using TF-IDF weighting and cosine similarity. The second index was produced using a language modeling approach, in which documents are represented as a unigram language model, then ranked based on the likelihood of the model generating the given query. Language model approaches require a smoothing method to account for terms that appear in the query but not in the document. We chose to use Jelinek-Mercer smoothing, with a lambda of 0.7, as recommended in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,179.72,601.29,11.45,12.66" target="#b4">[5]</ref> for retrieving articles from lengthy queries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Recommendations from domain experts</head><p>Two clinicians were recruited to provide recommendations for designing and improving the query construction process. The rst clinician composed ad-hoc queries based on the patient description and clinical question. For many topics, the clinician was able to recall the correct diagnosis from memory. However, we chose to assume that for "diagnosis" topics, diagnosis is part of the information need and would not be known at the time of the query. Thus, for "diagnosis" questions, the clinician was instructed not to include the diagnosis explicitly in the query. For test and treatment topics, no such constraint was enforced. These expert queries were used to retrieve a baseline set of results, submitted to TREC as a manual run.</p><p>A second clinician reviewed the rst pass of retrieval results, produced using mostly keyword-based searches. The clinician described her approach to understanding the patient cases and suggested modications to the retrieval strategy.</p><p>The two medical experts agreed independently in several aspects. First, they emphasized the importance of capturing patient attributes such as age and sex, as these contribute important information to the diagnostic process. For example, pediatric cases, women of childbearing age, and geriatic populations each have a distinct set of possible medical complaints. The experts also recommended discriminating between acute and chronic or progressive conditions, as well as including a term that specically names the clinical question type (e.g., diagnosis, test, testing, treatment, management). Both experts relied on domain knowledge to rank the discriminative value of symptoms and recognize patient features that point to probable diagnoses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Query construction</head><p>The automatic query construction algorithm was designed to approximate recommendations from domain experts. Base queries were produced from the condensed patient summaries. Patient summaries were mapped to UMLS codes using MetaMap. The base query consisted of the patient summary itself, concatenated with the list of UMLS concept codes. Concepts identied by MetaMap as being negated were not included in the query. Two types of phrases were found to cause false positive matches. "Xx-year old" caused many of the top matches to be case reports; sometimes, the only matching aspect of the report was the patient's age. The word "her" also caused articles on HER, a driver mutation in breast cancer, to be retrieved. Both of these special cases were removed from the base query.</p><p>Query expansion was used for three purposes: to focus the query on the clinical question type, to highlight the temporal aspect of the patient's condition, and to retrieve articles on pediatric care as needed. First, the query was expanded based on the clinical question associated with the case. For a test-oriented query, added terms included test, evaluate, diagnose, guideline, examination, measurement, imaging, and UMLS semantic types Diagnostic Procedure and Laboratory Procedure. Likewise, to retrieve treatment-related articles, additional terms were treat, treatment, manage, management, therapy, guidelines, intervention, and semantic types Therapeutic or Preventative Procedure and Pharmacologic Substance.</p><p>Query expansion was also used to characterize the temporal condition of the patient and whether the case described a pediatric patient. The patient summary was searched for timerelated terms. If the words hours or days were found, the query was expanded to include the word acute. If the words months or years appeared, the query included the word chronic. Similarly, if the UMLS mapping of the patient summary identied the patient as a child, the term pediatric was added to the query.</p><p>Certain query terms were boosted if they belonged to a highly relevant semantic class. Signs or Symptoms, Findings, Diseases and Syndromes, Injuries or Poisonings, Therapeutic or Preventative Procedures, and Pharmacologic Substances were boosted by a factor of 20. Population Groups and Age Groups were boosted by a factor of 50. Boost factors were chosen empirically, based on the importance of the semantic type and the perceived qualitative benet to the retrieved results compared to lower and higher boost factors. One manual run and four automatic runs were submitted, each exploring a dimension of the retrieval strategy. The runs were:</p><p>1. tfman: manual run using expert queries, vector space model with TF-IDF weighting, and full-text search.</p><p>2. tfauto: automatic run using vector space model with TF-IDF weighting, query expansion, and full-text search.</p><p>3. jmab: automatic run using language model with Jelinek-Mercer smoothing, query expansion, and abstracts only. tfman, produced by expert query, provided a baseline for retrieval performance. For the automatic runs, we hypothesized that 1) the language model would outperform the vector space model, 2) full-text search would be more eective than searching abstracts alone, and 3) boosting would improve results vs. no boosting.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.">Evaluation</head><p>26 groups participated in the TREC Clinical Decision Support track, submitting 91 automatic runs and 11 manual runs. The judgement set consisted of documents ranked 1-20 in any runs, union a 20% sample of documents ranked 21-200 in some run. Documents were judged as being (potentially) relevant, or not relevant. Evaluation metrics were: inferred average precision (infAP); inferred normalized discounted cumulative gain (infNDCG), which measures how well the documents were ranked; precision at R (R-prec), where R is the number of known relevant documents; and precision at 10 (P@10).</p><p>Evaluation metrics were calculated for each topic. For each run, the average of each metric was calculated over all topics. Averages were also calculated after stratifying topics by clinical question type. Statistical signicance was determined by pairwise approximate randomization.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Comparing submitted runs to each other</head><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,135.59,402.34,5.42,12.66" target="#fig_2">2</ref> shows each run's results for each metric, averaged over all topics. Table <ref type="table" coords="5,481.09,402.34,5.42,12.66" target="#tab_1">2</ref> summarizes signicance levels for this comparison set. As expected, tfman had the best results for each metric. tfauto and jmab did not perform as well as jmignore, conrming our hypotheses that the language model and full-text search were more eective strategies. jmignore performed slightly better than jmboost, although the dierence was signicant for R-prec only. Contrary to our hypothesis, boosting did not improve retrieval when averaged over all topics.</p><p>3.2. Comparing submitted runs to the median Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,135.09,525.68,5.42,12.66" target="#fig_3">3</ref> and Table <ref type="table" coords="5,191.77,525.68,5.42,12.66">3</ref> compare our manual and automatic runs with their respective medians over all TREC CDS participants. For the automatic runs, tfauto and jmab performed below the median. jmboost performed slightly below the median for infAP and R-prec, and slightly above the median for infNDCG and P@10, although these dierences were not statistically signicant. Our best automatic run, jmignore, performed slightly above the median for all metrics (again, not statistically signicant). tfman was our best run overall, performing in the top 1-2 over all TREC CDS participants for all metrics except R-prec.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Analyzing best automatic runs by topic type</head><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,136.82,649.02,5.42,12.66" target="#fig_1">4</ref> breaks down our best automatic runs by topic type and compares them to the median. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,165.74,662.57,10.85,12.66" target="#fig_5">4a</ref> shows that jmignore had the best performance for "diagnosis" topics, reaching statistical signicance over jmboost but not over the median. Thus, boosting was detrimental to retrieval for "diagnosis" topics.  Table <ref type="table" coords="6,116.26,358.29,4.22,12.66">3</ref>: P-values for comparisons of all submitted runs to the median. Bold: p &lt; 0.05. Underline: p &lt; 0.10. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="6,135.59,406.78,11.45,12.66" target="#fig_5">4b</ref> summarizes performance for "test" topics: for this set of patient cases, jmboost provided some benet over the median (p &lt; 0.1). As seen in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="6,418.01,420.33,8.84,12.66" target="#fig_5">4c</ref>, jmboost improved P@10 for "treatment" topics, but this nding did not reach statistical signicance.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="6,131.81,447.43,5.42,12.66" target="#tab_3">4</ref> summarizes the p-values for each comparison set, by topic type.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Discussion</head><p>tfman was an excellent run overall, demonstrating the value of expert knowledge in domain-specic systems. Two of our three hypotheses were conrmed: for the automatic runs, the language model approach outperformed the vector space model. These results are consistent with our preliminary evaluations as well as previous work showing performance gains from the language model approach over TF-IDF weighting <ref type="bibr" coords="6,405.40,555.63,10.85,12.66" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Full-text search performed signicantly better than searching abstracts alone, demonstrating the importance of using full-text in applications when available. One surprising result was that semantic boosting did not improve retrieval overall. However, boosting did improve retrieval for some metrics, particularly on "test" topics. An investigation of the best-and worst-performing boost queries revealed a few trends. One observation was that short queries containing relatively little information beneted most from boosting. Because "test" topics generally contained less information than "diagnosis" topics, this may explain the improved performance on "test" topics with boosting. For example, this "test" topics performed well: 85-year-old man who was in a car accident 3 weeks ago, now with 3 days of progressively decreasing level of consciousness and impaired ability to perform   activities of daily living. Boosting of UMLS concept "consciousness-related nding" brought relevant articles to the top of the result list compared to no boosting. However, boosting introduced further noise in this lengthy "diagnosis" topic: 2-year-old boy with fever and irritability for 5 days. Physical exam ndings include conjunctivitis, strawberry tongue, and desquamation of the ngers and toes. Lab results include low albumin, elevated white blood cell count and C-reactive protein, and urine leukocytes. Echo shows moderate dilation of the coronary arteries.</p><p>Secondly, performance was sensitive to errors in selection of boosting terms. Consider the following "test" topic (bold indicates boosted terms): 25-year-old woman with fatigue, hair loss, weight gain, and cold intolerance for 6 months. Median performance for this topic was relatively low, despite being an easy diagnosis of hypothyroidism for a medical expert. However, boosting performed well compared to no boosting. Because this topic has very little noise and all relevant terms were boosted, an article on hypothyroidism was ranked 3rd in the retrieval results. Without boosting, the highest-ranked article on hypothyroidism was ranked 16th.</p><p>In contrast, this "diagnosis" topic performed poorly: 67-year-old woman status post cardiac catheterization via right femoral artery, now with a cool, pulseless right foot and right femoral bruit. In this instance, the relevant term "femoral artery" was not boosted, resulting in retrieval of documents only generally related to cardiac catheterization.</p><p>Performance with boosting also suered when less-relevant terms were boosted. For example, boosting of "hypertension" and "obesity" skewed the result list in this "diagnosis" topic: 58-year-old woman with hypertension and obesity presents with exercise-related episodic chest pain radiating to the back.</p><p>These observations suggest that a well-tuned boosting strategy could improve the ranking of documents relevant to specic patient cases. One potential area of development would be in calculating the boost weight for each term. In our system, all boosted semantic types receive one of two boost values (20 or 50). However, our expert queries reect that symptoms have a range of discriminative power and this knowledge is used by experts to produce short, dense queries. Consider the topic 8-year-old boy with 2 days of loose stools, fever, and cough after returning from a trip to Colorado. Chest x-ray shows bilateral lung inltrates. The expert query, pediatric pulmonary infection colorado, integrated the concepts fever and cough into a single query term, pulmonary infection, whereas the concept bilateral lung inltrates was not included in the query at all. A knowledge-or data-driven scoring function that estimates the discriminative power of symptoms could be an area of further investigation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusion</head><p>This paper described the retrieval methods developed by the UCLA Medical Imaging Informatics group for the TREC 2014 Clinical Decision Support shared task. A suite of methods that included a unigram language model with Jelinek-Mercer smoothing, query expansion, and full-text search performed near the median. For a subset of the topics, a boosting strategy based on semantic type conferred some benet to the ranking of retrieved documents, suggesting that with further development it could be a viable strategy for the matching of literature to patient cases.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,213.20,310.61,185.59,12.66;2,140.25,85.04,331.50,215.63"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Overview of retrieval system.</figDesc><graphic coords="2,140.25,85.04,331.50,215.63" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,98.42,411.76,8.44,12.66;4,112.31,402.56,51.31,24.93;4,168.73,411.76,358.23,12.66;4,112.31,425.31,148.38,12.66;4,98.42,440.22,8.44,12.66;4,112.31,431.02,46.70,24.93;4,165.03,440.22,361.94,12.66;4,112.31,453.76,195.45,12.66"><head>4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>jmignore: automatic run using language model with Jelinek-Mercer smoothing, query expansion, and full-text search.5. jmboost: automatic run using language model with Jelinek-Mercer smoothing, query expansion, boosting, and full-text search.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="5,85.04,216.76,210.48,12.66;5,300.52,207.56,32.02,24.93;5,336.22,216.76,116.98,12.66;5,458.20,207.56,47.85,24.93;5,509.73,216.76,17.23,12.66;5,85.04,230.31,112.45,12.66;5,199.41,85.04,213.18,121.77"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Comparison of all submitted runs. tfman was the best run overall. jmignore was the best automatic run.</figDesc><graphic coords="5,199.41,85.04,213.18,121.77" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="6,85.04,236.34,283.25,12.66;6,371.86,227.15,32.02,24.93;6,407.46,236.34,119.50,12.66;6,85.04,249.89,56.65,12.66;6,145.31,240.69,47.85,24.93;6,196.77,249.89,318.58,12.66;6,309.33,85.04,213.51,123.42"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Comparison of submitted runs to the median. (a) tfman performed well above the median. (b) jmignore was slightly above the median, but was not statistically signicant.</figDesc><graphic coords="6,309.33,85.04,213.51,123.42" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="7,102.71,236.71,186.43,9.96;7,334.24,238.20,163.68,9.96;7,211.31,371.97,189.38,9.96"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(a) Retrieval results for "diagnosis" topics. (b) Retrieval results for "test" topics. (c) Retrieval results for "treatment" topics.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5" coords="7,85.04,392.98,289.17,12.66;7,380.35,383.78,43.69,24.93;7,428.09,392.98,98.87,12.66;7,85.04,406.53,193.77,12.66;7,198.59,250.25,214.83,114.84"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Comparison of best automatic runs by topic type. jmboost improves ranking for "test" topics, but not "diagnosis" topics.</figDesc><graphic coords="7,198.59,250.25,214.83,114.84" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,85.04,88.08,441.92,203.56"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Query terms for patient summary: 15-year-old girl with right lower quadrant abdominal pain for hours, decreased appetite, and enlarged appendix on abdominal ultrasound. Table1describes the query terms for an example patient summary. The nal query is the concatenation of the list of query terms.</figDesc><table coords="4,98.11,88.08,415.79,117.41"><row><cell>Query terms</cell><cell>Comments</cell></row><row><cell>right lower quadrant abdominal pain, decreased</cell><cell>Raw terms, stopwords removed,</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">appetite enlarged appendix abdominal ultrasound. Xx-year-old phrase removed</cell></row><row><cell>metamap_concept:Entire appendix</cell><cell>UMLS mapping, no boosting</cell></row><row><cell>metamap_concept:Transabdominal Ultrasound</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>metamap_concept:Female child ^50</cell><cell>Boosting population group and symptoms</cell></row><row><cell>metamap_concept:Right lower quadrant pain ^20</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>metamap_concept:Decrease in appetite ^20</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>+(treat treatment manage management</cell><cell>Query expansion for topic type and</cell></row><row><cell>therapy guideline intervention) pediatric</cell><cell>pediatric case</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,85.04,305.59,441.92,35.41"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /><note coords="5,128.88,314.79,220.35,12.66;5,353.09,305.59,50.86,24.93;5,409.51,314.79,117.45,12.66;5,85.04,328.34,109.75,12.66"><p>P-values for comparisons of automatic runs to jmignore. Bold indicates statistical signicance (p &lt; 0.05).</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="7,85.04,487.39,441.93,190.53"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>P-values for comparisons of jmignore, jmboost and median, broken down by topic type. Bold: p &lt; 0.05. Underline: p &lt; 0.10.</figDesc><table coords="7,160.34,487.39,291.32,152.87"><row><cell></cell><cell>infAP</cell><cell>infNDCG</cell><cell>R-prec</cell><cell>P@10</cell></row><row><cell>jmignore vs. median</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>diagnosis</cell><cell>0.846</cell><cell>0.304</cell><cell>0.284</cell><cell>0.382</cell></row><row><cell>test</cell><cell>0.331</cell><cell>0.329</cell><cell>0.094</cell><cell>1.0</cell></row><row><cell>treatment</cell><cell>0.967</cell><cell>0.652</cell><cell>0.515</cell><cell>0.773</cell></row><row><cell>jmboost vs. median</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>diagnosis</cell><cell>0.713</cell><cell>0.746</cell><cell>0.586</cell><cell>1.0</cell></row><row><cell>test</cell><cell>0.076</cell><cell>0.054</cell><cell>0.062</cell><cell>0.313</cell></row><row><cell>treatment</cell><cell>0.926</cell><cell>0.637</cell><cell>0.699</cell><cell>0.633</cell></row><row><cell>jmboost vs. jmignore</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>diagnosis</cell><cell>0.013</cell><cell>0.026</cell><cell>0.005</cell><cell>0.032</cell></row><row><cell>test</cell><cell>0.251</cell><cell>0.100</cell><cell>0.714</cell><cell>0.521</cell></row><row><cell>treatment</cell><cell>0.655</cell><cell>0.800</cell><cell>0.574</cell><cell>0.496</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work was supported by <rs type="funder">NLM</rs> <rs type="grantNumber">T15-LM007356</rs>, <rs type="funder">NIH/NLM</rs> <rs type="grantNumber">R01-LM009961</rs>, and the <rs type="funder">UCLA Department of Radiological Sciences</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_smCREJM">
					<idno type="grant-number">T15-LM007356</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_ehYZwhG">
					<idno type="grant-number">R01-LM009961</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="9,89.26,199.08,437.70,12.66;9,95.95,212.63,431.01,12.66;9,95.95,226.18,101.25,12.66" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,365.61,199.08,161.35,12.66;9,95.95,212.63,329.37,12.66">Getting More Out of Biomedical Documents with GATE&apos;s Full Lifecycle Open Source Text Analytics</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Cunningham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Tablan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bontcheva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,434.61,212.63,92.36,12.66">PLoS Comput Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1002854</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,89.26,248.69,437.70,12.66;9,95.95,262.24,412.60,12.66" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,218.37,248.69,308.59,12.66;9,95.95,262.24,28.72,12.66">An overview of MetaMap: historical perspective and recent advances</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,133.07,262.24,271.83,12.66">Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="229" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,89.26,284.76,437.71,12.66;9,95.95,298.31,301.81,12.66" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,173.94,284.76,353.03,12.66;9,95.95,298.31,40.18,12.66">The unied medical language system (UMLS): integrating biomedical terminology</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Bodenreider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,144.77,298.31,103.77,12.66">Nucleic acids research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="D270" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,89.26,320.82,437.71,12.66;9,95.95,334.37,155.39,12.66" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,308.58,320.82,214.16,12.66">Lucene in Action: Covers Apache Lucene 3.0</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mccandless</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hatcher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Gospodnetic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<publisher>Manning Publications Co</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,89.26,356.89,437.70,12.66;9,95.95,370.44,393.47,12.66" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,183.46,356.89,343.50,12.66;9,95.95,370.44,37.70,12.66">A study of smoothing methods for language models applied to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Laerty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,141.45,370.44,244.30,12.66">ACM Transactions on Information Systems (TOIS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="214" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,89.26,392.95,437.70,12.66;9,95.95,406.50,431.02,12.66;9,95.95,420.05,171.76,12.66" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,203.50,392.95,259.25,12.66">A language modeling approach to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ponte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,470.40,392.95,56.56,12.66;9,95.95,406.50,431.02,12.66;9,95.95,420.05,96.46,12.66">Proceedings of the 21st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 21st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="281" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
