<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,103.92,75.53,387.55,12.58">Fusion of Retrieval Models at CLEF 2008 Ad-Hoc Persian Track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,261.48,106.56,65.84,9.02"><forename type="first">Zahra</forename><surname>Aghazade</surname></persName>
							<email>z.aghazadeh@ece.ut.ac.ir</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of ECE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tehran</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wollongong</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dubai</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,257.82,118.02,74.80,9.02"><forename type="first">Nazanin</forename><surname>Dehghani</surname></persName>
							<email>n.dehghany@ece.ut.ac.ir</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of ECE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tehran</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wollongong</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dubai</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,262.56,129.54,65.85,9.02"><forename type="first">Leili</forename><surname>Farzinvash</surname></persName>
							<email>l.farzinvash@ece.ut.ac.ir</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of ECE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tehran</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wollongong</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dubai</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,265.32,141.06,59.88,9.02"><forename type="first">Razieh</forename><surname>Rahimi</surname></persName>
							<email>r.rahimi@ece.ut.ac.ir</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of ECE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tehran</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wollongong</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dubai</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,252.30,152.52,85.42,9.02"><forename type="first">Abolfazel</forename><surname>Aleahmad</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of ECE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tehran</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wollongong</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dubai</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,274.80,164.04,45.78,9.02"><forename type="first">Hadi</forename><surname>Amiri</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,252.54,175.56,80.35,9.02"><forename type="first">Farhad</forename><surname>Oroumchian</surname></persName>
							<email>farhado@uow.edu.au</email>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,103.92,75.53,387.55,12.58">Fusion of Retrieval Models at CLEF 2008 Ad-Hoc Persian Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">F1B89418C2D4EBA4193D29AC7A0F8B67</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:18+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Information Search and Retrieval</term>
					<term>Retrieval Models Information Retrieval</term>
					<term>Information Fusion</term>
					<term>Persian Text Retrieval</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Metasearch engines submit the user query to several underlying search engines and then merge their retrieved results to generate a single list that is more effective to the users' information needs. According to the idea behind metasearch engines, it seems that merging the results retrieved from different retrieval models will improve the search coverage and precision. In this study, we have investigated the effect of fusion of different retrieval techniques on the performance of Persian retrieval. We use an extension of Ordered Weighted Average (OWA) operator called IOWA and a weighting schema, NOWA for merging the results. Our experimental results show that merging by OWA operators produces better precision.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>With the rapid growth of the volume of the data, improving the effectiveness of information retrieval systems is essential. Many approaches and methods have developed to exhibit better retrieval engines <ref type="bibr" coords="1,437.94,508.86,10.61,9.02" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. In this study, we try to use the idea behind metasearch engines in order to improve the results of Persian information retrieval. We consider each retrieval model as a decision maker and then fuse their decisions with an OWA operator in order to increase the effectiveness. This work has been done as our first participation in the CLEF evaluation campaign. For the Ad-Hoc Persian track we submitted eleven experiments (runs): UTNLPDB3BB2, UTNLPDB3BM25, UTNLPDB3DFR, UTNLPDB3IFB2, UTNLPDB3INEXPB2, UTNLPDB3INEXPC2, UTNLPDB3INL2, UTNLPDB3PL2, UTNLPDB3TFIDF, UTNLPDB3NOWA and UTNLPDB3OWA. Our main goal was to study the effect of fusion operators and whether fusing retrieval models can bring additional performance improvements. The collection that is used in this study is a standard test collection of Persian text which is called Hamshahri and was made available to CLEF by University of Tehran <ref type="bibr" coords="1,464.17,623.88,10.61,9.02" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, [3]. In section two, we present a brief description of the retrieval methods that have been used in our experiments. Previous experiments have demonstrated that these methods have good performance on Persian retrieval. In section three, OWA operator and its extensions that are used for merging the results are described. One key point in the OWA operator is to determine its associated weights. In this study, we use a weighting model which is based on Normal distribution and an IOWA extension. There are two approaches to fuse the retrieved lists:</p><p>• Combine the results of distinct retrieval methods.</p><p>• Combine the results of the same method but with different types of tokens Runs that submitted to CLEF 2008 use the first approach and results show that using this approach dose not lend itself to a significant improvement. It seems although the retrieval methods are different but their performance and result set is similar. In another word, those retrieval methods provide the same vision of the data. After CLEF results were published, we tried the second approach and we were able to improve the effectiveness up to 5.67% and reached the 45.22% average precision on test set. Section four describes the experiments and their results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Retrieval Methods</head><p>In this work, for the purpose of fusion, we needed different retrieval methods. After studying different retrieval toolkits, finally we choose Terrier [4]. Different methods have been implemented in Terrier toolkit. Among these methods, we selected nine of them. The weighting models and a brief description of them (from [5]) are illustrated in table <ref type="table" coords="2,146.81,183.66,3.75,9.02">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table 1 -A description of retrieval methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Weighting Model Description</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BB2</head><p>Bose-Einstein model for randomness, the ratio of two Bernoulli's processes for first normalization, and Normalization 2 for term frequency normalization</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BM25</head><p>The BM25 probabilistic model</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DFR_BM25</head><p>The DFR version of BM25</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IFB2</head><p>Inverse Term Frequency model for randomness, the ratio of two Bernoulli's processes for first normalization, and Normalization 2 for term frequency normalization</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>In_expB2</head><p>Inverse expected document frequency model for randomness, the ratio of two Bernoulli's processes for first normalization, and Normalization 2 for term frequency normalization</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>In_expC2</head><p>Inverse expected document frequency model for randomness, the ratio of two Bernoulli's processes for first normalization, and Normalization  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">OWA Fuzzy Operator</head><p>This section describes the Order Weighted Average (OWA) operator, normal distribution-based weighting and IOWA extension.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">OWA Definition</head><p>An OWA operator of dimension n is a mapping, OWA: R n R → , that has an associated n vector</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,73.98,323.84,287.32,65.95">T n w w w w ) ,..., 2 , 1 ( = such that ] 1 , 0 [ ∈ j w and ∑ = = n j j w 1 1 . Furthermore, ∑ = = n j j j w b a a a OWA 1 ) ,..., , (</formula><p>Where j b is the j th largest element of the collection of the aggregated objects n a a a ,...,</p><p>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">IOWA</head><p>An IOWA operator is defined as follows: is referred to as the order inducing variable and i a as the argument variable. It is assumed that i a is an exact numerical value while i u can be drawn from any ordinal set Ω <ref type="bibr" coords="3,351.48,536.44,10.65,9.04" target="#b3">[7]</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="3,232.14,449.53,46.34,26.54">∑ = = n j j b</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">NOWA</head><p>Suppose that we want to fuse n preference values provided by n different individuals. Some individuals may assign unduly high or unduly low preference values to their preferred or repugnant objects. In such a case, we shall assign very low weights to these "false" or "biased" opinions, that is to say, the closer a preference value (argument) is to the mid one(s), the more the weight it will receive; conversely, the further a preference value is from the mid one(s), the less the weight it will have <ref type="bibr" coords="3,280.85,624.10,10.63,9.04" target="#b4">[8]</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="3,72.00,647.57,101.10,18.99">Let T n w w w w ) ,..., 2 , 1 ( =</formula><p>be the weight vector of the OWA operator; then we define the following:</p><p>.</p><p>[ ] . n µ and n σ are obtained by the following formulas, respectively: </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Analyzing the Results and More Experiments</head><p>We submitted top hundred retrieved documents for our runs to CLEF, while CLEF evaluates the results by top thousand documents which decreased average precision about 10% in average. Therefore, in future we intend to calculate our Precision-Recall charts and other measurements based the top thousand retrieved documents. The results published by CLEF for our fusion runs show that using fusion techniques on these methods does not yield to improved results over the individual methods. By analyzing the lists obtained from the retrieval methods, we observed that these result lists for these nine different methods have high overlap among them. On the other hand, fusion methods work well when there are significant differences between decision makers. Therefore, we have concluded that although the methods are different they are not significantly different from each other and basically they provide the same view of the collection.</p><p>After the CLEF results were published, we decided to investigate the second approach for fusion and look into the effect of different tokens in retrieval. For this purpose we chose a vector space model and ran it on the training set three times with three different types of tokens namely 4-grams, stemmed single terms and unstemmed single terms. To obtaining best results, we ran PL2 method of terrier toolkit on 4gram terms, indri of lemur toolkit [10] on stemmed terms and TF_IDF of terrier toolkit on unstemmed terms. Then we applied the above OWA methods and as shown in table 3, we obtained 9.97% improvements over individual runs. After that, we continued this approach and did more experiments with the CLEF test set. On the test set, this approach lead only to 5.67% improvements on the average precision over individual runs using NOWA method and 5.6% using IOWA method. Table <ref type="table" coords="5,226.39,637.11,3.77,9.06" target="#tab_4">4</ref>, figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,262.75,637.11,5.03,9.06" target="#fig_2">3</ref> and figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,313.58,637.11,5.03,9.06" target="#fig_3">4</ref> demonstrate the obtained results.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusion</head><p>Our motivation for participation in the Ad-Hoc Persian track of CLEF was investigating the influence of fusion techniques on the effectiveness of Persian retrieval methods. First we use nine retrieval methods and then fuse the results by NOWA and IOWA. The obtained results showed that functionality of these methods have high overlap and there were no considerable improvement by applying fusion techniques. In the second stage, we changed our approach to use different versions of a same method. To reach this goal, we focused on working with different terms instead of different methods. Results indicates fusion techniques works well on the circumstances which the decision makers have different views.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="5,159.72,259.02,276.07,9.02"><head>Figure 2 -</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2 -The result of running IOWA published by CLEF 2008</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="6,133.38,344.82,328.61,9.02;6,152.10,365.40,291.90,247.68"><head>Figure 3 -</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3 -Comparison of precision between NOWA and individual methods.</figDesc><graphic coords="6,152.10,365.40,291.90,247.68" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="6,75.54,615.30,444.31,9.02"><head>Figure 4 -</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4 -Comparison of precision at top retrieved documents between NOWA and individual methods.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,72.00,436.86,451.65,178.34"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>depicts the result obtained from running the above nine methods described in Table1on the training set of queries.</figDesc><table coords="2,428.32,436.86,82.48,9.02"><row><cell>2 for term frequency</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,160.92,74.46,262.40,126.92"><head>Table 2 -Comparison between different weighting models</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="3,160.92,87.36,262.40,114.02"><row><cell>Weighting Model</cell><cell>Average Precision</cell><cell>R-Precision</cell></row><row><cell>BB2</cell><cell>0.3854</cell><cell>0.4167</cell></row><row><cell>BM25</cell><cell>0.3562</cell><cell>0.4009</cell></row><row><cell>DFR_BM25</cell><cell>0.4006</cell><cell>0.4347</cell></row><row><cell>IFB2</cell><cell>0.4017</cell><cell>0.4328</cell></row><row><cell>In_expB2</cell><cell>0.3997</cell><cell>0.4329</cell></row><row><cell>In_expC2</cell><cell>0.4190</cell><cell>0.4461</cell></row><row><cell>InL2</cell><cell>0.3832</cell><cell>0.4200</cell></row><row><cell>PL2</cell><cell>0.4314</cell><cell>0.4548</cell></row><row><cell>TF_IDF</cell><cell>0.3574</cell><cell>0.4017</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,109.26,506.28,363.83,81.02"><head>Table 3 -Results of applying fusion methods on training set</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="5,109.26,519.15,363.83,68.15"><row><cell>Retrieval Method</cell><cell>Average Precision</cell><cell>R-Precision</cell><cell>Dif</cell></row><row><cell>TF_IDF with unstemmed single terms</cell><cell>0.4163</cell><cell>0.4073</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PL2 with 4gram terms</cell><cell>0.4100</cell><cell>0.3990</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Indri with stemmed terms</cell><cell>0.4100</cell><cell>0.4183</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>IOWA</cell><cell>0.5160</cell><cell>0.4928</cell><cell>+9.97</cell></row><row><cell>NOWA</cell><cell>0.5030</cell><cell>0.4839</cell><cell>+8.67</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="5,109.26,660.30,363.83,92.48"><head>Table 4 -Results of applying fusion methods on test set</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="5,109.26,673.11,363.83,79.67"><row><cell>Retrieval Method</cell><cell>Average Precision</cell><cell>R-Precision</cell><cell>Dif</cell></row><row><cell>TF_IDF with unstemmed single terms</cell><cell>0.3847</cell><cell>0.4122</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PL2 with 4gram terms</cell><cell>0.3669</cell><cell>0.3939</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Indri with stemmed terms</cell><cell>0.3955</cell><cell>0.4149</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>IOWA</cell><cell>0.4515</cell><cell>0.4708</cell><cell>+5.6</cell></row><row><cell>NOWA</cell><cell>0.4522</cell><cell>0.4736</cell><cell>+5.67</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>In future, we will investigate the effects of different token types and retrieval engines on Persian retrieval and will try to fine tune an engine based on fusion.</p></div>
			</div>			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Experiment</head><p>For the experiments, CLEF has obtained the standard Persian test collection which is called Hamshahri. Hamshahri collection is the largest test collection of Persian text. This collection is prepared and distributed by University of Tehran. The third version of Hamshahri collection is 600MB in size and contains more than 160,000 distinct textual news articles in Persian <ref type="bibr" coords="4,282.59,314.13,10.63,9.06" target="#b5">[9]</ref>. There were 50 training queries with their relevance judgments and 50 test queries prepared for the Persian ad-hoc track. For the CLEF, we choose nine methods of document retrieval described above and fuse the top hundred retrieved results from each of them. We use OWA operator based on normal distribution weighting for merging the lists. In this problem, we have nine decision makers, so the weighting vector is as the following: The precision-recall diagram obtained after submitting the OWA run to CLEF is illustrated in figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,475.59,440.61,3.77,9.06">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1 -The result of running NOWA published by CLEF 2008</head><p>IOWA extension was also tested. We used 50 training queries in order to calculate the weighting vector for this method. We ran the nine selected retrieval methods on the collection. The following weighting vector is obtained by using the average precision of each method as its weight: {0.4167/3.8409, 0.4009/3.8409, 0.4347/3.8409, 0.4328/3.8409, 0.4329/3.8409, 0.4461/3.8409, 0.42/3.8409, 0.4548/3.8409, 0.402/3.8409} (3.8409 is the sum of the obtained average precisions) Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,100.60,714.09,5.03,9.06">2</ref> illustrates the precision-recall diagram of IOWA run with the above weighting vector.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,108.00,137.61,406.24,9.06;7,108.00,149.13,313.71,9.06" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,317.79,137.61,196.45,9.06;7,108.00,149.13,91.89,9.06">Managing Gigabytes: Compressing and Indexing Documents and Images</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ian</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Witten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alistair</forename><surname>Moffat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Bell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<publisher>Morgan Kaufmann Publishers</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Los Altos, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,108.00,160.59,380.58,9.06" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,215.79,160.59,211.62,9.06">Experiments with Persian Text Compression for Web</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Oroumchian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Darrudi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,435.17,160.59,28.41,9.06">WWW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,108.00,206.61,394.09,9.06;7,108.00,218.07,197.61,9.06" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,153.39,206.61,344.06,9.06">On ordered weighted averaging aggregation operators in multicriteria decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Yager</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,108.00,218.07,119.52,9.06">IEEE Trans Syst Man Cybern</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="183" to="190" />
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,108.00,229.59,405.96,9.06;7,108.00,241.11,205.06,9.06" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,196.70,229.59,184.61,9.06">Induced ordered weighted averaging operators</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Yager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Filev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,387.76,229.59,126.20,9.06;7,108.00,241.11,123.42,9.06">IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics--Part B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="150" />
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,108.00,252.57,396.11,9.06;7,108.00,264.09,226.43,9.06" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,133.83,252.57,312.01,9.06">Induced uncertain linguistic OWA operators applied to group decision making</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,452.96,252.57,51.15,9.06;7,108.00,264.09,117.61,9.06">International Journal of Intelligent Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="843" to="865" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,108.00,275.61,404.43,9.06;7,108.00,287.07,125.57,9.06" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,358.27,275.61,154.16,9.06;7,108.00,287.07,99.09,9.06">Using OWA Fuzzy Operator to Merge Retrieval System Results</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Amiri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Aleahmad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Oroumchian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lucas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rahgozar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
