<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,147.78,116.95,319.81,12.62;1,249.03,134.89,117.29,12.62">Multilingual Named-Entity Recognition from Parallel Corpora</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,137.07,172.56,74.64,8.74"><forename type="first">Andreea</forename><surname>Bodnari</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">MIT</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CSAIL</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>Massachusetts</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">LIMSI-CNRS</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>rue John von Neumann</addrLine>
									<postCode>F-91400</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,228.60,172.56,63.96,8.74"><forename type="first">Aurélie</forename><surname>Névéol</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">LIMSI-CNRS</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>rue John von Neumann</addrLine>
									<postCode>F-91400</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,303.11,172.56,62.30,8.74"><forename type="first">Ozlem</forename><surname>Uzuner</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">MIT</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CSAIL</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>Massachusetts</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Information Studies</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University at Albany</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">SUNY</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Albany</settlement>
									<region>New York</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,382.30,172.56,88.75,8.74"><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Zweigenbaum</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">LIMSI-CNRS</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>rue John von Neumann</addrLine>
									<postCode>F-91400</postCode>
									<settlement>Orsay</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,282.78,184.51,64.70,8.74"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Szolovits</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">MIT</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CSAIL</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>Massachusetts</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,147.78,116.95,319.81,12.62;1,249.03,134.89,117.29,12.62">Multilingual Named-Entity Recognition from Parallel Corpora</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">4E1698941B5813369B4B9246DAA7C45B</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:33+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>Named-entity recognition, Medical NLP</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We present a named-entity recognition (NER) system for parallel multilingual text. Our system handles three languages (i.e., English, French, and Spanish) and is tailored to the biomedical domain.</p><p>For each language, we design a supervised knowledge-based CRF model with rich biomedical and general domain information. We use the sentence alignment of the parallel corpora, the word alignment generated by the GIZA++[8] tool, and Wikipedia-based word alignment in order to transfer system predictions made by individual language models to the remaining parallel languages. We re-train each individual language system using the transferred predictions and generate a final enriched NER model for each language. The enriched system performs better than the initial system based on the predictions transferred from the other language systems. Each language model benefits from the external knowledge extracted from biomedical and general domain resources.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Natural Language Processing (NLP) technologies can help extract structured information from written text, determine relationships between concepts, or perform bilingual translation. In the biomedical and clinical <ref type="bibr" coords="1,373.68,513.65,11.17,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref> domain NLP has multiple applications: computerized clinical decision support, personalized medicine, automatic extraction of protein interactions and associations of proteins to functional concepts, to name a few. Despite their value and extensive applicability, biomedical and clinical NLP systems are scarcely developed for languages other than English.</p><p>In this study, we present a system for extracting structured information from multilingual biomedical corpora. We define the structured information of interest as noun phrases (NPs) that fall under nine Unified Medical Language System (UMLS) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,165.85,621.25,15.54,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref> semantic categories. Our data consists of parallel multilingual corpora in English (en), French (fr), and Spanish (es).</p><p>We present a NP extraction system for multilingual biomedical corpora that makes use of external knowledge sources and the common structure shared by the parallel languages. We analyze the errors performed by the NER system, and we discuss the contribution of the knowledge sources and the common language structure to system performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">Problem definition</head><p>We focus on NPs that fall under nine semantic categories: anatomy (ANAT), chemicals and drugs (CHEM), devices (DEVI), disorders (DISO), geographic areas (GEOG), living beings (LIVB), objects (OBJC), phenomena (PHEN), and physiology (PHYS). These semantic categories are groupings of semantic types in the UMLS semantic network. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,274.97,241.70,13.07,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref> Our goal is two-fold: for each of the three languages, first identify noun phrases that belong to the semantic categories of interest and then map the identified noun phrases to an already existing Concept Unique Identifier (CUI) in UMLS.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Materials and Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Data</head><p>The data used for the system development is made available by the organizers of the 2013 CLEF-ER challenge <ref type="bibr" coords="2,290.28,365.47,12.52,8.74" target="#b8">[9]</ref> and comes from two sources: the European Medicines Agency (EMEA) and Medline. Each corpus contains sentencedelimited plain text. Sentence alignment information is available for the language pairs en-fr and en-es. The EMEA corpus contains the same number of sentences for each language (140522) so that each English sentence has an equivalent alignment in the other two languages. The Medline corpus contains approx. 1.5 million English sentences, 0.5 million French sentences and 0.25 million Spanish sentences (see Table <ref type="table" coords="2,225.74,449.16,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>). In the Medline corpus, half of the English sentences do not have an equivalent alignment in French or Spanish, while the other half have an equivalent alignment in either French or Spanish. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Annotations</head><p>We manually annotated all noun phrase instances of the nine semantic types within a set of 385 sentences, for each language and for each corpus source. We use different annotation processes for the EMEA and the Medline corpora. For the EMEA corpus, we randomly selected 385 sentences from the automatically generated gold standard provided by the challenge organizers. For each of the selected sentences, we transferred the English annotations to the corresponding French-and Spanish-aligned sentences based on the word alignment provided by the GIZA++ software and Wikipedia as explained below. We manually reviewed the transferred annotations and annotated additional noun phrases for each language when appropriate.</p><p>For the Medline corpus, we used the Medical Subject Heading (MeSH) indexing and the UMLS Metathesaurus to automatically generate noun phrase annotations. The MEDLINE citations corresponding to the sentences (i.e., titles) in the Medline corpus have been manually assigned a set of MeSH indexing terms by professional indexers at the National Library of Medicine. MeSH main headings can be derived from this set and mapped to UMLS CUIs. We randomly selected 385 Medline sentences for each language and made use of the MeSH indexing-UMLS CUI relationship in order to generate Medline reference annotations. Specifically, when a term associated to a CUI from the MeSH indexing can be found in the corresponding Medline sentence, we automatically create a reference annotation. We apply the same annotation process to the English, French, and Spanish versions of the Medline corpus.</p><p>The EMEA and Medline reference annotations were manually reviewed by a sole annotator, due to time constraints and lack of additional resources.</p><p>The number of unique annotations for EMEA and Medline are similar across languages (368 English annotations for EMEA and 401 for Medline, 364 French annotations for EMEA and 339 for Medline, and 368 Spanish annotations for EMEA and 303 for Medline). The EMEA corpus contains a significantly larger number of actual annotations due to numerous noun phrase duplicates (see Table <ref type="table" coords="3,134.77,430.82,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">System design</head><p>We perform word alignment using the GIZA++ software. <ref type="bibr" coords="3,393.60,476.37,12.27,8.74" target="#b7">[8]</ref> GIZA++ aligns words based on statistical models. For source sentence s J = s 1 s 2 ..s J and target sentence t I = t 1 t 2 ..t I , we define an alignment of the two sentences as A ⊆ {(i, j) : j = 1, .., J; i = 0, .., I}, where the case i = 0 represents source words that are not aligned to any target words. The probability of a source sentence given a target sentence is P (s|t) = a J P (s J , a J 1 |t I ), where a J 1 represents the sentence pair alignment. The best sentence alignment is given by âJ = argmax a J P θ (s J , a J |t I ).</p><p>In addition to the GIZA++ alignment, we use word alignment from Wikipedia metadata. We rely on the fact that some English Wikipedia articles have direct correspondents in French and Spanish. We filter the English articles that have titles consisting of a single word (e.g., "Food", "Disease", "Nausea") and find their corresponding foreign language article. The title of the English article and the title of the correspondent foreign language article represent a word alignment pair. Because Wikipedia word alignments are more precise, we overwrite the GIZA++ generated word alignments with a score lower than 0.5 with the Wikipedia generated word alignments. Noun phrase identification Our system is designed based on the supervised CRF framework. The CRF model includes lexical features (the normalized form of the token), syntactic features (part-of-speech and parse tree information of each token), and knowledge-based features (information extracted from UMLS and Wikipedia). A final set of features is generated based on the shared structure of the parallel languages. All feature sets are used in the final CRF model.</p><p>In order to obtain the parse and POS information we use different resources for each language: for English we use the Stanford parser, <ref type="bibr" coords="4,378.46,534.38,11.99,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref> while for French and Spanish we use the Malt parser. <ref type="bibr" coords="4,275.23,546.34,11.99,8.74" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="4,288.89,546.34,7.75,8.74" target="#b5">6]</ref> We extract the knowledge-based features from UMLS using MetaMap <ref type="bibr" coords="4,250.97,558.29,15.77,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref> for the English corpus and direct lexical mapping for the French and Spanish corpora. The lexicons we used contained about 0.3 million terms corresponding to 0.15 million CUIs for French and 0.5 million terms corresponding to 0.3 million CUIs for Spanish.</p><p>The Wikipedia knowledge-based features are dependent on the language and are extracted based on the respective language version of Wikipedia. We make use of the fact that Wikipedia articles are tagged with specific categories. We map these Wikipedia categories to one of the nine UMLS categories of interest. Then, we identify the n-grams (n ≤ 3) that represent titles of Wikipedia articles and signal within the attribute vector whether an n-gram belongs to one of the nine categories of interest based on its Wikipedia categorization.</p><p>Using the lexical, syntactic, and knowledge-based features described above, we create a CRF model (the Initial model) for each language and label the training data using the relevant model. We further make use of the common structure shared by the parallel corpora and transfer the NP predictions across aligned bilingual sentence pairs. We hypothesize that some language models might predict NPs that other language models would miss, and by using sentence-and word-alignment information we can inform the other language models of the missed predictions. The CRF model containing the transferred predictions is referred to as the enriched model. The entire system design is depicted in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,134.77,252.18,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">CUI Mapping</head><p>The NER system predicts the text of the NPs together with their semantic categories. In order to obtain the CUI associated with each NP we use MetaMap for English and direct lookup inside the UMLS database for the French and Spanish languages. Because the French and Spanish versions of UMLS do not contain the same number of concepts as the English UMLS, there are French and Spanish concepts identified by our system that cannot be linked to a CUI via direct UMLS lookup. For those concepts we rely on word alignment to determine the English concept to which the foreign language concepts are aligned; once an aligned English concept is found we transfer the CUI information to the foreign language concept.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Discussion</head><p>The reference annotations we generated for this challenge relied partially on automated annotation tools. These annotation tools generated an imperfect annotation output and generally failed to identify a percentage of the noun-phrase instances. For the Medline corpus, the annotation tools failed to identify NPs in the sentences that belonged to oldest citations. These citations were only assigned a couple of MeSH indexing terms, vs. about a dozen for more recent citations. Also, because the MeSH indexing terms are assigned based on the fulltext article content and not on the article title, they might be linked to CUIs not present in the title. A similar issue arises when the Medline title contains a shortened or altered version of the CUI string indexed by MeSH (e.g. the string "hypertensive patient" occurring in the title of citation 1838917 could not be reconciled with CUI C0020538 "hypertension"). For EMEA, the main problem was the transfer of English annotations based on the word alignment: the GIZA++ software does not generate a perfect word alignment, and even though the Wikipedia word alignment manages to fix some incorrect alignments, there are still cases of incorrect or missing alignments.</p><p>The problem of the noisy word alignment impacts both the generation of the reference annotations and the performance of the enriched system. Specifically, the predictions transferred between the systems are usually incomplete (e.g., for the English noun phrase active substance, the word alignment could only help transfer the labeling for the token "substance" and failed to transfer the labeling for the token "active" as it could not find a valid word French or Spanish alignment for the word "active").</p><p>Mapping the noun phrases to a CUI is a difficult problem for the French and Spanish languages since the number of annotated CUIs is relatively small. A large number of UMLS English concepts are not present in the foreign language portions of UMLS; thus, even though the English translation of a French or Spanish noun phrase is present in UMLS, the French or Spanish noun phrase is not included. Our system has to rely on machine translation or noun phrase alignment for mapping certain French and Spanish noun phrases to their CUIs.</p><p>Based on manual revision, the noun phrases identified by the enriched model present a higher precision and slightly lower recall. In general, the enriched model predicts more complete noun phrases (e.g., "insuffisance hépatique sévère" vs. "insuffisance hépatique", "diminution des bruits respiratoires", vs. "bruits respiratoires", "parésies des cordes vocales" vs. "des parésies des cordes", "tumor principal" vs. "tumor", "movimientos involuntarios" vs. "involuntarios"). We notice that the semantic categories of the noun phrases are better assigned when the enriched model is used (e.g., "linfocitos" assigned a LIVB category by the initial model and an ANAT category by the enriched model), and even correctly adjusted together with the span of the noun phrase (e.g., noun phrase "mandíbula" classified as ANAT in the initial model is changed into osteonecrosis de la mandbula classified as DISO in the enriched model).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>We present a multilingual NER extraction system targeting the biomedical domain. The NER system relies on a supervised learning framework enriched with external knowledge and cross-linguistic information transferred based on common structure between languages. We prepare reference annotations for English, French, and Spanish that together with the NER system can be used for developing additional multilingual resources. We illustrated the improvements brought by our second round of training based on cross-language transfer of initial annotations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was funded in part by award number 2U54LM008748 from the National Institutes of Health (NIH)/National Library of Medicine (NLM) and cofounded by the National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute (NHLBI), and by contract number 90TR0002 (SHARPd Secondary Use of Clinical Data) from the Office of the National Coordinator (ONC) for Health Information Technology. The main author was funded by the Chateaubriand Science Fellowship 2012-13.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="5,197.32,492.31,220.72,7.89;5,223.43,283.04,168.50,194.50"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Multilingual NP extraction: system description</figDesc><graphic coords="5,223.43,283.04,168.50,194.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,161.97,506.47,291.41,52.85"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Corpus sentence count per source type, separated by language</figDesc><table coords="2,241.90,506.47,131.55,41.94"><row><cell>Sentence count</cell></row><row><cell>English French Spanish</cell></row><row><cell>EMEA 140552 140552 140552</cell></row><row><cell>Medline 1593546 572176 247655</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,134.77,118.78,345.83,286.57"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Annotations description per corpus type: annotation count, separated by language and semantic category</figDesc><table coords="4,205.57,118.78,204.22,264.70"><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Annotation count</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">English French Spanish</cell></row><row><cell>ANAT</cell><cell cols="2">EMEA 202 Medline 62</cell><cell>31 60</cell><cell>28 38</cell></row><row><cell>CHEM</cell><cell cols="2">EMEA 1556 Medline 88</cell><cell>519 55</cell><cell>572 58</cell></row><row><cell>DEVI</cell><cell cols="2">EMEA Medline 10 43</cell><cell>6 3</cell><cell>10 1</cell></row><row><cell>DISO</cell><cell cols="2">EMEA 1658 Medline 168</cell><cell>427 180</cell><cell>465 174</cell></row><row><cell>GEOG</cell><cell cols="2">EMEA Medline 15 34</cell><cell>11 9</cell><cell>13 22</cell></row><row><cell>LIVB</cell><cell cols="2">EMEA 492 Medline 72</cell><cell>132 60</cell><cell>137 35</cell></row><row><cell>OBJC</cell><cell cols="2">EMEA 115 Medline 9</cell><cell>37 4</cell><cell>38 2</cell></row><row><cell>PHEN</cell><cell>EMEA Medline</cell><cell>77 2</cell><cell>30 2</cell><cell>30 1</cell></row><row><cell>PHYS</cell><cell cols="2">EMEA 272 Medline 29</cell><cell>53 12</cell><cell>64 6</cell></row><row><cell>Total NPs</cell><cell cols="3">EMEA 4491 1261 Medline 461 386</cell><cell>1374 340</cell></row><row><cell>Total Unique NPs</cell><cell cols="2">EMEA 368 Medline 401</cell><cell>364 339</cell><cell>368 303</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,143.58,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,154.54,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,165.50,134.18,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,333.62,143.58,146.97,7.86;8,146.91,154.54,132.02,7.86">An overview of metamap: historical perspective and recent advances</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alan</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">François-Michel</forename><surname>Lang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,291.76,154.54,188.83,7.86;8,146.91,165.50,44.63,7.86">Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="229" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,176.46,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,187.42,315.31,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,240.93,176.46,239.66,7.86;8,146.91,187.42,91.63,7.86">The unified medical language system (umls): integrating biomedical terminology</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Bodenreider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,246.76,187.42,87.40,7.86">Nucleic acids research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">suppl 1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="D270" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,198.38,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,209.34,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,220.30,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,231.26,68.09,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,361.34,198.38,119.26,7.86;8,146.91,209.34,180.78,7.86">Statistical french dependency parsing: treebank conversion and first results</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Marie</forename><surname>Candito</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Benoît</forename><surname>Crabbé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Pascal</forename><surname>Denis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,347.48,209.34,133.11,7.86;8,146.91,220.30,303.52,7.86">Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2010)</title>
		<meeting>the Seventh International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC 2010)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1840" to="1847" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,242.21,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,253.17,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,264.13,133.58,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,441.29,242.21,39.30,7.86;8,146.91,253.17,239.06,7.86">What can natural language processing do for clinical decision support</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Dina</forename><surname>Demner-Fushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Clement</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,394.49,253.17,86.11,7.86;8,146.91,264.13,44.07,7.86">Journal of biomedical informatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="760" to="772" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,275.09,342.25,7.86;8,146.91,286.05,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,297.01,303.24,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,317.75,275.09,122.91,7.86">Accurate unlexicalized parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,462.94,275.09,17.66,7.86;8,146.91,286.05,333.68,7.86">Proceedings of the 41st Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 41st Annual Meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="423" to="430" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,307.97,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,318.93,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,329.89,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,340.84,114.40,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,431.92,307.97,48.68,7.86;8,146.91,318.93,259.32,7.86">The spanish resource grammar: pre-processing strategy and lexical acquisition</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Montserrat</forename><surname>Marimon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Núria</forename><surname>Bel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sergio</forename><surname>Espeja</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Natalia</forename><surname>Seghezzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,424.35,318.93,56.24,7.86;8,146.91,329.89,177.95,7.86">Proceedings of the Workshop on Deep Linguistic Processing</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Deep Linguistic Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="111" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,351.80,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,362.76,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,373.72,142.24,7.86" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,401.40,351.80,79.19,7.86;8,146.91,362.76,208.01,7.86">Aggregating UMLS semantic types for reducing conceptual complexity</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alexa</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Mccray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Anita</forename><surname>Burgun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Bodenreider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,366.64,362.76,113.95,7.86;8,146.91,373.72,61.95,7.86">Studies in health technology and informatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="216" to="220" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,384.68,320.65,7.86" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,229.58,384.68,200.99,7.86">Giza++: Training of statistical translation models</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Och</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,395.64,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,406.60,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,417.56,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,428.52,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,439.47,169.93,7.86" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,255.01,428.52,225.58,7.86">Overview of the ShARe/CLEF eHealth Evaluation Lab</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hanna</forename><surname>Suominen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sanna</forename><surname>Salantera Sumithra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Velupillai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Guergana</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Noemie</forename><surname>Savova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sameer</forename><surname>Elhadad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Brett</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Pradhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Danielle</forename><surname>South</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Mowery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Gareth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Liadh</forename><surname>Leveling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lorraine</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Guido</forename><surname>Martinez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,183.51,439.47,105.00,7.86">Proceedings of CLEF 2013</title>
		<meeting>CLEF 2013</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013. 2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
