<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.05,75.20,26.99,16.92;1,119.93,75.20,42.10,16.92;1,182.94,75.20,14.15,16.92;1,218.22,75.20,99.13,16.92;1,338.26,75.20,39.23,16.92;1,398.40,75.20,72.93,16.92;1,492.70,75.20,30.68,16.92;1,72.05,96.08,420.76,16.92">SSN MLRG at MEDIQA-SUM 2023: Automatic Text Summarization using Support Vector Machine and RoBERTa</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,72.05,138.76,66.88,11.88"><forename type="first">Sheerin</forename><surname>Sitara</surname></persName>
							<email>sheerinsitaran@ssn.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of CSE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Sri Sivasubramaniya Nadar College of Engineering</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>-603110</postCode>
									<settlement>Kalavakkam</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,141.94,138.76,76.95,11.88"><forename type="first">Noor</forename><surname>Mohamed</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of CSE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Sri Sivasubramaniya Nadar College of Engineering</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>-603110</postCode>
									<settlement>Kalavakkam</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,256.13,138.76,89.22,11.88"><forename type="first">Kavitha</forename><surname>Srinivasan</surname></persName>
							<email>kavithas@ssn.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of CSE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Sri Sivasubramaniya Nadar College of Engineering</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>-603110</postCode>
									<settlement>Kalavakkam</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.05,75.20,26.99,16.92;1,119.93,75.20,42.10,16.92;1,182.94,75.20,14.15,16.92;1,218.22,75.20,99.13,16.92;1,338.26,75.20,39.23,16.92;1,398.40,75.20,72.93,16.92;1,492.70,75.20,30.68,16.92;1,72.05,96.08,420.76,16.92">SSN MLRG at MEDIQA-SUM 2023: Automatic Text Summarization using Support Vector Machine and RoBERTa</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">1B2429243DDABCAEB7534507C8644F2C</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T16:36+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>ImageCLEF</term>
					<term>Summarization</term>
					<term>Support Vector Machine</term>
					<term>RoBERTa</term>
					<term>Singular Value Decomposition</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The tremendous increase in the quantity of text requires an improved mechanism to extract the information quickly and effectively. It is very difficult for human beings to manually extract the summary of every large documents. Moreover, the searching for relevant documents from the number of documents available, and finding relevant information is also difficult. The automatic text summarization can solve this issue by identifying the most important meaningful information in a document or set of related documents and compressing them into a shorter version preserving its overall meanings. Considering this, ImageCLEF organizes MEDIQA-SUM task which is related to automatic text summarization. This paper concentrates on Dialogue2Topic summarization, a part of MEDIQA-SUM task. For this, two models are developed using SVM with TF-IDF and RoBERTa. From the results, it has been inferred that RoBERTa models achieved an highest accuracy of 0.765.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="842.04"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>The text summarization reduces the time and effort required to read and analyse complex and lengthy documents. Moreover, the summarization gives the clear picture about the overall inference about the document in short duration of time. The text summarization plays a major role in medical field because it saves the quality time and provides future references for doctor and clinicians. The applications of text summarization include, Diaogue2Note summarization, Dialogue2Topic summarization, patient-specific text summarization, data-to-text summarization of patient records, etc. Hence, ImageCLEF <ref type="bibr" coords="1,164.98,555.30,12.70,10.04" target="#b0">[1]</ref> contribute to the text summarization field by conducing the MEDIQA-SUM task in this year. The MEDIQA-SUM task concentrates on Diaogue2Note summarization and Dialogue2Topic summarization task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,235.22,582.68,11.53,10.04" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p><p>The Dialogue2Topic summarization task can be performed using machine learning techniques, deep learning techniques, transformer based pre-trained models. The different machine learning techniques are, Support Vector Machine <ref type="bibr" coords="2,249.75,74.15,11.81,10.04" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, Random forest <ref type="bibr" coords="2,334.30,74.15,13.07,10.04" target="#b3">[4]</ref> and decision tree <ref type="bibr" coords="2,425.32,74.15,11.81,10.04" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. The different deep learning techniques are Multi-Layer perceptron <ref type="bibr" coords="2,280.19,87.83,13.07,10.04" target="#b5">[6]</ref> and ConceptNet <ref type="bibr" coords="2,368.07,87.83,11.88,10.04" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. The different transformer based pre-trained models are BERT <ref type="bibr" coords="2,197.33,101.51,17.63,10.04" target="#b7">[8]</ref> and RoBERTa <ref type="bibr" coords="2,284.93,101.51,11.56,10.04" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. Among these techniques, SVM and RoBERTa are used in this paper for text classification because of the following reasons. They are, (i). Able to handle high dimensional data and ability to perform better with small datasets (ii). Generte representative word embedding that capture the unique characteristics of the text. Hence, in this paper, SVM and RoBERTa is used to generate classification model.</p><p>The remaining part of the paper spans across following subsections. In Sect. 2, ImageCLEF MEDIQA-SUM 2023 task and its dataset are discussed. In Sect. 3, the design of the proposed model and its implementation are explained. A brief summary about the results obtained and the performance evaluation are given in Sect. 4 with a conclusion at the end.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Task and Dataset Description</head><p>In this section, three sub tasks of MEDIQA-SUM 2023 and given datasets are discussed. The three sub tasks includes, Dialogue2Topic classification, Dialogue2Note Summarization and Full-Encounter Dialogue2Note Summarization.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">ImageCLEF MEDIQA-SUM 2023 task</head><p>ImageCLEF, a part of Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum is conducting tasks related to the medical domain since 2018. The ImageCLEF MEDIQA-SUM task focuses on the automatic summarization and classification of doctor-patient conversations through three sub tasks.</p><p>In sub task A (Dialogue2Topic Classification), the topic associated with section header is identified based on the conversation snippet between a doctor and patient. The section headers will be one of twenty normalized common section labels namely, family history, history of present illness, past medical history, chief complaint, past surgical history, allergy, review of systems, medications, assessment, exam, diagnosis, disposition, plan, emergency department course, immunizations, imaging, gynecologic history, procedures, other_history and labs.</p><p>In sub task B (Dialogue2Note Summarization), the conversation between a doctor and patient is summarized and produced a clinical note section. The sub task C (Full-Encounter Dialogue2Note Summarization) is similar to sub task B. But in sub task B, given a full encounter conversation between a doctor and patient, participants are asked to generate full clinical note summarizing the conversation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">ImageCLEF MEDIQA-SUM 2023 datasets</head><p>The MEDIQA-SUM 2023 task consists of three sub tasks namely, sub task A, sub task B and sub task C. The conversational snippet , section header and section text in each sub tasks are given in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,72.05,631.31,4.27,10.04" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. Each sub tasks consists of training set, validation set and test set. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">System Design</head><p>The system design of the proposed models for sub task A are shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,435.73,200.92,5.58,10.04" target="#fig_0">1</ref> and 2. This model is developed based on the conversation snippet (dialogue conversion between doctor and patient) in the training set and, the generated model is validated by predicting the label (ie., section label) for the test set.</p><p>In Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,132.14,263.58,4.27,10.04" target="#fig_0">1</ref>, the conversation snippet and section label in the training set is tokenized into collection of words. These words are converted into a matrix of TF-IDF features using TF-IDF vectorization. This feature matrix are regularized by factoring a feature matrix into three matrices 𝑈,  𝑎𝑛𝑑 𝑉. Then Support Vector Machine (SVM) is used to generate the classification model based on these feature vector in the training phase. Finally, the generated model is validated by predicting the section label for the conversion snippet in the test set. In Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,137.53,502.36,4.10,10.04" target="#fig_1">2</ref>, RoBERTa, classification model is used to predict the section label based on the conversion snippet. As RoBERTa is an pre-trained transformer based model, it supports tokenization, truncation and attention mask generation. The attention mask generation maintains the position of the padded indices so model understands which tokens should be attended. Based on the RoBERTa classification model, the model is generated for training set and validated for test set. The proposed architecture of RoBERTa is given in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,273.11,570.44,4.10,10.04" target="#fig_2">3</ref>. This architecture shows that RoBERTa processes the word, mask and type with respect to the ID. In RoBERTa architecture, last layer is freezes and appended with dropout, flatten and dense layer.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Experiments and Results</head><p>The hardware and software required for the implementation of concept detection and caption prediction model includes, (i). Intel i5 processor with NVIDIA graphics card, 4800M at 4.3GHZ clock speed, 16GB RAM, Graphical Processing Unit and 2TB disk space, (ii). Linux -Ubuntu 20.04 operating system, Python 3.7 package with required libraries like tensorflow, torch, sklearn, nltk, pickle, pandas, etc.</p><p>The proposed model is executed on Dialogue2Topic Classification dataset and the performance is analyzed using three different runs as given in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,305.32,583.76,4.10,10.04" target="#tab_1">2</ref>, are: (i). SVM along with TF-IDF and truncated SVD for the given dataset (ii). RoBERTa classification model for three epochs (iii). Same as (ii) for eight epochs. Among the results, run2 obtained better performance value in terms of accuracy and it is italicized in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,116.28,87.83,4.31,10.04" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. From run2, the early stopping with a patience of three epochs also achieved better performance value than eight epochs. The code status of all these runs are one, which means code runs successfully and reproduces the similar results.</p><p>In Dialogue2Topic classification task, totally 11 teams were participated and 23 submissions were recorded. Among these, we have submitted seven successful submissions and achieved fourth rank among the participated teams and seventh rank in ImageCLEF 2023 MEDIQA-SUM task. The overall ranking achieved by top teams are listed in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,291.35,174.97,4.13,10.04" target="#tab_2">3</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusion</head><p>This paper describes an approach to solve the ImageCLEF MEDIQA-SUM 2023 task. In this task, we have developed two models for Dialogue2Topic summarization tasks using SVM with TF-IDF (run1) and RoBERTa (run2 and run 3). From the runs, it has been inferred that RoBERTa gives better results of 0.765 which lacks only by 5.5% interms of accuracy. In the future work, the performance can be improved by incorporating medical related transformer based models. The overall performance can be improved by reducing the number of irrelevant dialogue in the conversation snippet, maintaining the number of epochs and minimum learning rate.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,72.05,479.65,251.42,11.16;3,72.00,351.36,453.96,117.00"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: System design of proposed SVM model (Run 1)</figDesc><graphic coords="3,72.00,351.36,453.96,117.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,72.05,754.81,270.47,11.16;3,72.00,617.04,451.44,126.36"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: System design of proposed RoBERTa model (Run 2)</figDesc><graphic coords="3,72.00,617.04,451.44,126.36" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="4,72.05,434.26,217.93,11.16;4,72.00,72.00,452.88,350.28"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Proposed RoBERTa system architecture</figDesc><graphic coords="4,72.00,72.00,452.88,350.28" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,72.05,652.52,427.80,101.93"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Dataset description for MEDIQA-SUM 2023 task</figDesc><table coords="2,77.45,688.90,422.40,65.55"><row><cell>Task</cell><cell>Input/Output</cell><cell>Training Set</cell><cell>Validation Set</cell><cell>Test Set</cell></row><row><cell>Sub task A</cell><cell>#Conversation</cell><cell>1201</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>198</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>snippet</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>#Section header/</cell><cell>20</cell><cell>20</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>labels</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,72.05,632.72,406.37,88.94"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Brief description about each runs</figDesc><table coords="4,100.15,669.44,378.27,52.22"><row><cell>Run Number</cell><cell>Accuracy</cell><cell>Run rank</cell><cell>Code Status</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell>0.140</cell><cell>23</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>0.740</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell>0.735</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>1</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,72.05,200.17,392.33,196.27"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Top ranking of MEDIQA-SUM 2023 task</figDesc><table coords="5,77.45,236.53,386.93,159.91"><row><cell>Team Name</cell><cell cols="2">Accuracy Run Rank</cell><cell cols="2">Team rank Code Status</cell></row><row><cell>Cadence</cell><cell>0.820</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>4</cell></row><row><cell>HuskyScribe</cell><cell>0.815</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>5</cell></row><row><cell>Trendence</cell><cell>0.800</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>SSNSheerinKavitha</cell><cell>0.765</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>SuryaKiran</cell><cell>0.735</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">SSNdhanyadivyakavitha 0.720</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Ds4dh</cell><cell>0.710</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Uetcorn</cell><cell>0.710</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>SKKU-DSAIL</cell><cell>0.700</cell><cell>13</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>StellEllaStars</cell><cell>0.675</cell><cell>14</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>MLRG-JBTTM</cell><cell>0.665</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>2</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="6.">Acknowledgements</head><p>Our profound gratitude to <rs type="institution">Sri Sivasubramaniya Nadar College</rs> <rs type="affiliation">of Engineering, Department of CSE</rs>, for allowing us to utilize the <rs type="institution">High Performance Computing Laboratory</rs> and GPU Server for the execution of this challenge successfully.</p></div>
			</div>			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.07,667.58,415.12,9.17;5,108.07,679.23,415.24,9.07;5,108.07,690.75,415.11,9.07;5,108.07,702.27,415.37,9.07;5,108.07,713.79,414.97,9.07;5,108.07,725.20,415.11,9.17;5,108.07,736.85,415.02,9.07;5,108.07,748.37,415.48,9.07;5,108.07,759.89,414.86,9.07;6,108.07,73.81,414.89,9.07;6,108.07,85.33,31.11,9.07;6,229.79,85.33,28.05,9.07;6,348.60,85.33,53.61,9.07;6,492.60,85.33,30.24,9.07;6,110.59,96.85,96.15,9.07" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,374.30,736.85,148.79,9.07;5,108.07,748.37,396.23,9.07">Overview of the ImageCLEF 2023: Multimedia Retrieval in Medical, Social Media and Recommender Systems Applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bogdan</forename><surname>Ionescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ana-Maria</forename><surname>Drăgulinescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wen-Wai</forename><surname>Yim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Asma</forename><surname>Ben Abacha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Neal</forename><surname>Snider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Griffin</forename><surname>Adams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Meliha</forename><surname>Yetisgen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Rückert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alba</forename><surname>García Seco De Herrera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Christoph</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Friedrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Louise</forename><surname>Bloch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Raphael</forename><surname>Brüngel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ahmad</forename><surname>Idrissi-Yaghir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Schäfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Steven</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hicks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Riegler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Vajira</forename><surname>Thambawita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Storås</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Pål</forename><surname>Halvorsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nikolaos</forename><surname>Papachrysos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Johanna</forename><surname>Schöler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Debesh</forename><surname>Jha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alexandra-Georgiana</forename><surname>Andrei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ahmedkhan</forename><surname>Radzhabov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ioan</forename><surname>Coman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Vassili</forename><surname>Kovalev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alexandru</forename><surname>Stan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Ioannidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hugo</forename><surname>Manguinhas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Liviu-Daniel</forename><surname>Ștefan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Gabriel Constantin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mihai</forename><surname>Dogariu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jérôme</forename><surname>Deshayes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Adrian</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,108.07,759.89,414.86,9.07;6,108.07,73.81,234.77,9.07">Proceedings of the 14th International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF</title>
		<title level="s" coord="6,375.00,73.81,147.96,9.07;6,108.07,85.33,31.11,9.07;6,229.79,85.33,22.44,9.07">Springer Lecture Notes in Computer Science LNCS</title>
		<meeting>the 14th International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF<address><addrLine>Thessaloniki, Greece</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023-09-18">2023. September 18-21, 2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Experimental IR Meets Multilinguality, Multimodality, and Interaction</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,108.07,109.45,415.36,9.07;6,108.07,120.61,415.58,9.07;6,108.07,132.15,414.85,9.07;6,108.07,143.67,96.15,9.07" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,472.97,109.45,50.46,9.07;6,108.07,120.61,415.58,9.07;6,108.07,132.15,55.52,9.07">Overview of the MEDIQA-Sum Task at ImageCLEF 2023: Summarization and Classification of Doctor-Patient Conversations</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wen-Wai</forename><surname>Yim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Asma</forename><surname>Ben Abacha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Neal</forename><surname>Snider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Griffin</forename><surname>Adams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Meliha</forename><surname>Yetisgen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,185.46,132.15,241.83,9.07">CLEF 2023 Working Notes, CEUR Workshop Proceedings</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Thessaloniki, Greece</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">September 18-21, 2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,108.07,155.19,414.85,9.07;6,108.07,166.71,391.18,9.07" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,307.33,155.19,215.59,9.07;6,108.07,166.71,31.51,9.07">Automatic text summarization using support vector machine</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Begum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Fattah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Ren</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,146.62,166.71,278.86,9.07">international journal of innovative computing information and control</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1987" to="1996" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,108.07,178.23,415.67,9.07;6,108.07,189.78,51.12,9.07" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,230.08,178.23,210.68,9.07">Using argument mining for legal text summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Villata</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,459.65,178.23,40.24,9.07">IOS Press</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">334</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">184</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020-12">2020, December</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,108.07,201.30,415.21,9.07;6,108.07,212.82,323.45,9.07" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,250.54,201.30,272.74,9.07;6,108.07,212.82,80.54,9.07">Deep learning-based extractive text summarization with word-level attention mechanism</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gambhir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Gupta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,195.96,212.82,141.04,9.07">Multimedia Tools and Applications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20829" to="20852" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,108.07,224.34,415.05,9.07;6,108.07,235.86,415.32,9.07;6,108.07,247.40,222.57,9.07" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,488.06,224.34,35.07,9.07;6,108.07,235.86,415.32,9.07;6,108.07,247.40,97.28,9.07">Machine learning optimized polygenic scores for blood cell traits identify sex-specific trajectories and genetic correlations with disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Vuckovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ritchie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Akbari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Grealey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Inouye</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,211.80,247.40,57.24,9.07">Cell Genomics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">100086</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,108.07,258.92,415.67,9.07;6,108.07,270.44,415.21,9.07;6,108.07,281.96,415.07,9.07;6,108.07,293.14,80.32,9.07" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,362.11,258.92,161.63,9.07;6,108.07,270.44,415.21,9.07;6,108.07,281.96,140.17,9.07">State-of-the-Art Approach to e-Learning with Cutting Edge NLP Transformers: Implementing Text Summarization, Question and Distractor Generation, Question Answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Patil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Chavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mukane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Vora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Chitre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,261.17,281.96,261.97,9.07;6,108.07,293.14,49.54,9.07">International Journal of Advanced Computer Science and Applications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,108.07,304.55,414.98,9.16;6,108.07,316.18,415.69,9.07;6,108.07,327.70,231.95,9.07" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,395.86,304.55,127.19,9.16;6,108.07,316.18,309.31,9.07">Increasing women&apos;s knowledge about HPV using BERT text summarization: An online randomized study</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Bitar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Babour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Nafa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Alzamzami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Alismail</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,426.14,316.18,97.62,9.07;6,108.07,327.70,170.92,9.07">International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">8100</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,108.07,339.22,415.15,9.07;6,108.07,350.77,323.83,9.07" xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,419.80,339.22,103.42,9.07;6,108.07,350.77,181.65,9.07">Mapping the design space of human-ai interaction in text summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Smith-Renner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Tetreault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Jaimes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2206.14863</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
