<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,90.00,75.58,449.00,16.01">TREC 2018 Precision Medicine -Medical University of Graz</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,256.50,101.65,97.91,11.01"><forename type="first">Pablo</forename><surname>López-García</surname></persName>
							<email>pablo.lopez@medunigraz.at</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Medical Informatics, Statistics and Documentation Medical</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Graz</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2 -8036</postCode>
									<settlement>Auenbruggerplatz, Graz</settlement>
									<country key="AT">Austria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,90.00,75.58,449.00,16.01">TREC 2018 Precision Medicine -Medical University of Graz</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">479F7558FC8DCEAA98A5D92F22EA8666</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:10+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper we report on our participation in the TREC 2018 Precision Medicine track (team name: imi_mug ). We submitted 5 fully automatic runs to both the biomedical articles and clinical trials subtasks. Our system was based on Elasticsearch, templates, and parameter grid search query generation, building heavily on our previous participation and the reference standard from 2017. Our results were well above the median for the biomedical articles subtask and median/below median for the clinical trials subtask.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="11" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="12" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="13" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="14" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="15" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="16" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="17" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="18" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="19" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="20" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="21" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="22" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="23" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="24" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="25" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="26" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="27" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>INTRODUCTION</head><p>The goal of the TREC 2018 Precision Medicine track was to improve search for clinicians treating cancer patients. 50 cases describing potential patients, termed topics , were provided as input and contained three features or dimensions: disease, gene, and demographic . Very similarly to last year, the challenge was divided into two subtasks that consisted of retrieving (1) relevant biomedical articles for treatment (from PubMed as well as ASCO and AACR conference proceedings) and (2) relevant clinical trials for enrollment (from ClinicalTrials.gov). The description of the challenge, the datasets, the relevance judgment guidelines are available online . </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SYSTEM OVERVIEW &amp; GENERAL APPROACH</head><p>This year we built heavily on our participation from last year. In particular, (1) we reused our indexing infrastructure, (2) we took advantage of the official reference standard released after the conference, and</p><p>(3) we applied our learnt lessons. A description of our previous participation<ref type="foot" coords="1,536.12,329.04,3.67,6.61" target="#foot_0">2</ref> and the overview paper from 2017 are 3 useful to better understand this paper.</p><p>We first reindexed all documents in Elasticsearch 5.4.0 and fixed some mistakes we had discovered, like only having indexed the Conclusion field in structured abstracts from PubMed. We used Elasticsearch's default options for indexing, except for the clinical trials , where we added shingles (word n-grams) indexing (size 2 and 3) . Due to the time and index 4 size required for this task (2GB for 241K clinical trials alone) we decided not to index the biomedical articles using n-grams. Appendix A contains a summary of our final indices and some sample documents.</p><p>Our aim was to automatically generate Elasticsearch queries that produced good results using last year's datasets for reference and training.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>QUERY TEMPLATES, EXPERIMENTS &amp; EVALUATION</head><p>To find those optimal queries, we reused our query templates from our previous participation. As a first step we analyzed our results from last year and reconsidered our strategies.</p><p>The main strategies we kept included: (1) exploring must and should clauses, (2) searching for disease and gene features in multiple fields and fine tuning multi_match type , tie_breaker and boost parameters, and (3) boosting specialized documents (extra abstracts from cancer conferences).</p><p>Strategies that we eliminated due to their poor results were: (1) positive and negative boosting of topic-oriented keywords, extra topics frequent keywords and chemotherapy suffixes, and (2) synonym expansion for diseases and genes.</p><p>New strategies introduced this year were:</p><p>(1) mapping demographics in topics into MeSH age groups , (2) splitting the list of 5 genes into separate fields gene1 , and gene2 , (3) creating a specific index and mappings to be able to search using 2 and 6 3 word n-grams (for clinical trials only, due to the performance issues mentioned in the introduction), (4) evaluating the document's language, and (5) filtering documents with empty abstracts.</p><p>For convenience, we rewrote all our code in Python as Jupyter Notebooks (except the 7 indexing part which we kept in Java), we used dataframes as data structures, and we relied on the pytrec_eval tool for restructuring of our framework was part of our future work and facilitated that we ran and evaluated experiments in an easier more replicable way (last year we used Java , Travis, and trec_eval ).</p><p>Our algorithm to find those optimal queries via experiments was an iterative version of the following :  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SUBMITTED RUNS &amp; RESULTS</head><p>We submitted 5 fully automatic runs to each subtask, where we tried to capture different strategies and evaluation measures. Our submissions, the exact steps we took, and the evaluation results for 2017 topics used for training are available online as Jupyter Notebooks for both the biomedical articles and the 10 clinical trials subtasks. 2. Same as (1) but the disease must not match the exclusion criteria (relevance: 5).</p><p>3. Same as ( <ref type="formula" coords="3,162.01,575.65,3.71,11.01">1</ref>), but all conditions are relaxed using should instead of must (relevance: 4).</p><p>4. Same as (1), but the relevance of the inclusion criteria weighs double (relevance: 2).</p><p>5. Same as (1), without grid search on word n-gram parameters for gene1 and gene2 (relevance: 1).</p><p>A comprehensive and more illustrative description of the results and how we obtained them can be found in the appendices.</p><p>Appendix B summarizes the submitted runs in a detailed table, and shows the exact Elasticsearch json queries that produced our submitted runs.</p><p>Appendix C shows our results as graphs and compares them with the average median and best results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CONCLUSION</head><p>In this notebook we reported on our participation in the TREC 2018 Precision Medicine track and described our approach, strategies, results, and lessons learnt.</p><p>From our participation last year and the re-evaluation of our approaches using the reference standard, we learned that many promising strategies (like disease and gene expansion, and keyword boosting of chemotherapy suffixes) did not produce good results and we therefore removed them. Grid search was useful to fine-tune complex Elasticsearch query parameters, such as multi_match type, tie_breaker and boost .</p><p>Similarly to last year, we got substantially better results in the biomedical articles subtask, in good agreement with our effort spent in that task.</p><p>Rebuilding our Java, Travis, and trec_eval -based framework from last year as Python modules, using pytrec_eval , dataframes, and Jupyter notebooks proved to be time well spent and provided us with a solid environment where we can easily experiment in a completely replicable way.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>APPENDIX A: Indices and Sample Documents</head><p>ALL BIOMEDICAL DATA -ELASTIC_SEARCH/_search?pretty "hits" :{ "total" : 26980432 , } PUBMED RECORDS -ELASTIC_SEARCH/abstracts/medline/_search?pretty "hits" :{ "total" : 26669401 , "max_score" : 1 , "hits" :[ { "_index" : "abstracts" , "_type" : "medline" , "_id" : "1832151" , "_score" : 1 , "_source" :{ "pubmedId" : "1832151" , "title" : "Pseudomonas aeruginosa alkaline protease: evidence for secretion genes and study of secretion mechanism." , "abstract" : "A 6.5-kb DNA fragment carrying the functions required for specific secretion of the extracellular alkaline protease produced by Pseudomonas aeruginosa was cloned. The whole 6.5-kb DNA fragment was transcribed in one direction and probably carried three genes involved in secretion. The expression in trans of these genes, together with the apr gene, in Escherichia coli allowed synthesis and secretion of the alkaline protease, which was extensively investigated by performing pulse-chase experiments under various conditions. We demonstrated the absence of a precursor form, as well as the independence of alkaline protease translocation from SecA. The absence of secretion genes impaired alkaline protease secretion; the protein then remained intracellular and was partially degraded." , "publicationType" : "Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't" , "language" : "eng" , "publicationYear" : 1991 , "meshTags" :[ "Adenosine Triphosphatases" , "Bacterial Proteins" , "Blotting, Western" , "Cloning, Molecular" , "DNA, Bacterial" , "Electrophoresis, Polyacrylamide Gel" , "Escherichia coli" , "Escherichia coli Proteins" , "Genes, Bacterial" , "Membrane Transport Proteins" , "Plasmids" , "Precipitin Tests" , "Protein Precursors" , "Pseudomonas aeruginosa" , "Restriction Mapping" , "SEC Translocation Channels" , "Serine Endopeptidases" ],</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="5,106.19,361.76,123.71,57.56">"medlineKeywords" :[ ] } },</formula><p>EXTRA ABSTRACTS -ELASTIC_SEARCH/abstracts/extra/_search?pretty "hits" :{ "total" : 70025 , "max_score" : 1 , "hits" :[ { "_index" : "abstracts" , "_type" : "extra" , "_id" : "ASCO_72552-104" , "_score" : 1 , "_source" :{ "pubmedId" : "ASCO_72552-104" , "title" : "Results of a phase II study of single-agent nab-paclitaxel in platinum-refractory second-line metastatic urothelial carcinoma (UC)." , "publicationDate" : "2011" , "publicationYear" : 2011 , "abstract" : "Background: There is currently no standard second-line chemotherapy for platinum-refractory UC. Both paclitaxel and docetaxel are commonly used but response rates are &lt; 20% and no survival advantage has been shown. In this multi-institutional phase II study, we evaluated the efficacy and tolerability of a new albumin-bound nanoparticle formulation of paclitaxel, known as Abraxane (ABI-007) as a single agent in patients with platinum-refractory metastatic UC. Methods: Patients with measurable UC, progressing on or after first-line platinum-based chemotherapy were enrolled onto this two-stage trial. ABI-007 was given at 260 mg\\/m2 IV q3weekly until progression. Clinical evaluation, CBC and blood chemistries were performed every cycle with restaging CT scans every 2 cycles. Results: Accrual is now complete with 48 patients enrolled. Baseline characteristics: Male: Female 40:8; median age 68; ECOG Performance Status 0:1:2, 15:24:8. 248 cycles were delivered: median 5.5 cycles\\/pt with 17\\/48 pts (35%) requiring dose reductions. Most frequent adverse events (AE) were alopecia (12%), fatigue (12%), pain (12%), neuropathy (9%) and nausea (4%). The most frequent grade 3+ AE were pain (45%), hypertension (14%), fatigue (8%), joint stiffness (5%), neuropathy (4%) and weakness (4%). Forty patients are evaluable for response: 1 (2.5%) complete response (CR), 11 (28%) partial responses (PR), 9 (23%) stable disease (SD) and 20 (49%) progressive disease. One patient was inevaluable for response, 7 patients are too early for evaluation. Conclusions: Single-agent ABI-007 was well tolerated with a response rate (CR+PR) of 33% (12\\/36) and a clinical benefit rate (CR+PR+SD) of 58% (21\\/36), representing one of the highest reported response rates to date in the second-line UC setting. These results suggest further study of ABI-007 in urothelial carcinoma is warranted." } }, CLINICAL TRIALS -ELASTIC_SEARCH/trials/trials/_search?pretty "hits" :{ "total" : 241006 , "max_score" : 1 , "hits" :[ { "_index" : "trials" , "_type" : "trials" , "_id" : "NCT02661217" , "_score" : 1 , "_source" :{ "id" : "NCT02661217" , "title" : "Comparison of Pre-and Post-discharge Initiation of LCZ696 Therapy in HFrEF Patients After an Acute Decompensation Event" , "summary" : "To explore two modalities of treatment initiation (Predischarge, and Postdischarge) with LCZ696 in HFrEF patients following stabilization after an ADHF episode." , "sex" :[ "female" , "male" ],</p><p>"minimum_age" : 18 , "maximum_age" : 100 , "inclusion" : " 1. Patients hospitalized due to acute decompensated HF episode (ADHF) as primary diagnosis) and consistent Signs &amp; Symptoms 2. Diagnosis of HF New York Heart Association class IItoIV and reduced ejection fraction: Left ventricular ejection fraction \\u2264 40% at Screening 3. Patients did not receive any IV vasodilators (except nitrates), and\\/or any IV inotropic therapy from the time of presentation for ADHF to Randomization 4. Stabilized (while in the hospital) for at least 24 hours leading to Randomization. 5. Meeting one of the following criteria: Patients on any dose of ACEI or ARB at screening ACEI\\/ARB na\\u00EFve patients and patients not on ACEI or ARB for at least 4 weeks before screening. " , "exclusion" : " 1. History of hypersensitivity to the sacubitril, valsartan, or any ARBs, NEP inhibitors or to any of the LCZ696 excipients. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="1,267.88,657.54,3.67,6.61;1,72.00,710.57,2.67,4.80;1,74.67,712.04,124.33,8.00"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>1 1 http://www.trec-cds.org/2018.html</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="2,386.48,183.54,3.67,6.61"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>9</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" coords="26,196.50,135.00,218.25,268.50"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="26,196.50,135.00,218.25,268.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" coords="26,90.00,419.25,206.25,254.25"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="26,90.00,419.25,206.25,254.25" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" coords="26,314.25,419.25,207.00,254.25"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="26,314.25,419.25,207.00,254.25" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="7,77.25,258.26,445.34,93.56"><head>Submitted Runs (Queries) Biomedical Articles -Summary</head><label></label><figDesc>2. Symptomatic hypotension and\\/or a SBP below 110 mm Hg or SBP above 180 mm Hg prior to randomization 3. End stage renal disease at Screening; or estimated GFR below 30 mL\\/min\\/1.73 m2 (as measured by MDRD formula at Randomization. 4. Serum potassium above 5.4 mmol\\/L at Randomization. 5. Known history of hereditary or idiopathic angioedema or angioedema related to previous ACE inhibitor or ARB therapy 6. Severe hepatic impairment, biliary cirrhosis and cholestasis"</figDesc><table coords="7,106.94,327.26,19.79,24.56"><row><cell>FEATURE age</cell><cell cols="3">QUERY tie_breaker fields match type bool fields</cell><cell cols="6">Clinical Trials -Summary RUN 2 3 -minimum_age 0.4 lte (less than or equal) should APPENDIX B: RUN 1 title maximum_age</cell><cell>4 title</cell><cell>5 -</cell></row><row><cell>FEATURE</cell><cell cols="4">QUERY match type fields</cell><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell>summary</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3 gte (greater than or equal) summary</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>bool</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>inclusion</cell><cell></cell><cell>title should</cell><cell>inclusion^2</cell></row><row><cell>FEATURE</cell><cell cols="4">fields match type QUERY</cell><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell>2</cell><cell></cell><cell>abstract meshTags multi_match best_fields 3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell></row><row><cell>disease</cell><cell cols="4">tie_breaker match type bool</cell><cell cols="2">must</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.4 best_fields multi_match should RUN</cell><cell>must</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">boost</cell><cell cols="2">bool</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>must 1.3</cell></row><row><cell>disease</cell><cell cols="4">tie_breaker</cell><cell cols="5">title.shingles (word n-grams)</cell><cell>0.4</cell><cell>title.shingles</cell><cell>title.shingles</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>fields</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">boost</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">summary.shingles</cell><cell>1.5</cell><cell>summary.shingles</cell><cell>summary.shingles</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">inclusion.shingles</cell><cell>title</cell><cell>inclusion.shingles^2</cell><cell>inclusion.shingles</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">fields match type</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>abstract multi_match</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>bool</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>meshTags should</cell></row><row><cell>gene</cell><cell cols="4">match type fields</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell>exclusion</cell><cell></cell><cell>multi_match cross_fields</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>}</cell><cell cols="4">bool match typ</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell>match</cell><cell></cell><cell>must</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>},</cell><cell cols="4">tie_breaker bool</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell>must_not</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.4</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>fields</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">boost</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>title summary 1</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>inclusion</cell><cell>title</cell></row><row><cell>gene</cell><cell cols="4">fields match type</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>MeSH tags</cell><cell></cell><cell>multi_match best_fields</cell><cell>abstract meshTags</cell><cell>MeSH tags</cell></row><row><cell>sex</cell><cell cols="4">match type bool</cell><cell cols="2">must</cell><cell>match</cell><cell></cell><cell>should</cell><cell>multi_match best_fields</cell><cell>must</cell><cell>match</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">bool tie_breaker</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>should 0.4</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">tie_breaker boost</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.8</cell><cell>0.4</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>fields</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">fields</cell><cell cols="5">meshTags (age group) title.shingles (word n-grams) summary.shingles inclusion.shingles</cell><cell>title.shingles title summary.shingles abstract meshTags inclusion.shingles^2</cell><cell>title.shingles meshTags summary.shingles (age group) inclusion.shingles</cell></row><row><cell>age gene1</cell><cell cols="4">match type match type</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>match</cell><cell cols="2">multi_match best_fields</cell><cell>multi_match best_fields</cell><cell>match multi_match</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>bool</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">bool</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>should should</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">tie_breaker tie_breaker</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.4</cell><cell>0.4</cell><cell>--</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">boost</cell><cell cols="2">fields</cell><cell>-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>1.5</cell><cell>language</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>(document) language</cell><cell cols="4">match type fields</cell><cell cols="5">-title.shingles (word n-grams) summary.shingles</cell><cell>title.shingles match (English) summary.shingles</cell><cell>title.shingles summary.shingles</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">bool</cell><cell>-</cell><cell cols="3">inclusion.shingles</cell><cell>should inclusion.shingles^2</cell><cell>inclusion.shingles</cell></row><row><cell>(document) gene2 type</cell><cell cols="4">fields match type match type bool bool</cell><cell>---</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">multi_match best_fields</cell><cell>_type match (extra/conference abstracts) should should</cell><cell>multi_match</cell></row><row><cell>Document abstract</cell><cell cols="4">tie_breaker bool boost</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0.3 1</cell><cell>Filter: must exist</cell><cell>--</cell></row><row><cell>FEATURE</cell><cell>fields</cell><cell cols="3">QUERY</cell><cell>1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>2</cell><cell>sex</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell></row><row><cell>sex</cell><cell cols="3">match type</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>RUN match</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>bool</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>should</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,326.67,682.79,205.33,8.00"><p>https://trec.nist.gov/pubs/trec26/papers/imi_mug-PM.pdf</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_1" coords="1,326.67,692.54,208.26,8.00"><p>https://trec.nist.gov/pubs/trec26/papers/Overview-PM.pdf</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_2" coords="1,326.67,702.29,209.26,8.00;1,324.00,712.04,120.37,8.00"><p>https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/5. 4/analysis-shingle-tokenfilter.html</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="8" xml:id="foot_3" coords="2,72.00,626.65,175.49,11.01;2,267.10,626.65,20.36,11.01;2,72.00,661.82,2.67,4.80;2,74.67,663.29,213.00,8.00;2,72.00,673.04,199.22,8.00;2,72.00,681.32,2.67,4.80;2,74.67,682.79,212.74,8.00;2,72.00,692.54,197.91,8.00;2,72.00,700.82,2.67,4.80;2,74.67,702.29,62.91,8.00;2,72.00,710.57,2.67,4.80;2,74.67,712.04,148.04,8.00"><p>evaluation, which we extended. This 5 Custom variation of tree number M01.061 (0-2: newborn, 3-12: child, 13-18: adolescent, 19-44: adult, &gt;44: aged). 6 https://github.com/plopezgarcia/trec-2018-precision-medic ine/blob/master/python/trials/trials_elastic_config.ipynb 7 http://jupyter.org/ 8 https://github.com/cvangysel/pytrec_eval</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="11" xml:id="foot_4" coords="2,329.33,702.29,208.44,8.00;2,324.00,712.04,193.78,8.00"><p>https://github.com/plopezgarcia/trec-2018-precision-medi cine/blob/master/python/trials/trials_submission.ipynb</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Biomedical Articles -Queries for Submitted Runs imi_mug_abs1.json { "from" : 0 , "size" : 1000 , "query" :{ "bool" :{ "must" :[ { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{disease}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1.5 } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "cross_fields" , "boost" : 1 } } ], "should" :[ { "match" :{ "meshTags" : "{{sex}}" } }, { "match" :{ "meshTags" : "{{age_group}}" } } ] } } }</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>imi_mug_abs2.json</head><p>{ "from" : 0 , "size" : 1000 , "query" :{ "bool" :{ "must" :[ { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{disease}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1.5 } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "cross_fields" , "boost" : 1 } } ], "should" :[ { "match" :{ "meshTags" : "{{sex}}" } }, { "match" :{ "meshTags" : "{{age_group}}" } }, { "match" :{ "language" : "eng" } }, { "match" :{ "_type" : "extra" } } ] } } }</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>imi_mug_abs3.json</head><p>{ "from" : 0 , "size" : 1000 , "query" :{ "bool" :{ "must" :[ { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{disease}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1.5 } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "cross_fields" , "boost" : 1 } } ], "should" :[ { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{sex}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{age_group}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" } }, { "match" :{ "language" : "eng" } }, { "match" :{ "_type" : "extra" } } ] } } }</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>imi_mug_abs4.json</head><p>{ "from" : 0 , "size" : 1000 , "query" :{ "bool" :{ "filter" :{ "exists" :{ "field" : "abstract" } }, "must" :[ { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{disease}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1.5 } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "cross_fields" , "boost" : 1 } } ], "should" :[ { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{sex}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{age_group}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" } }, { "match" :{ "language" : "eng" } }, { "match" :{</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>imi_mug_abs5.json</head><p>{ "from" : 0 , "size" : 1000 , "query" :{ "bool" :{ "filter" :{ "exists" :{ "field" : "abstract" } }, "must" :[ { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{disease}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1.5 } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "abstract" , "meshTags" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "cross_fields" , "boost" : 1 "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene1}}" , "fields" :[ "title.shingles" , "summary.shingles" , "inclusion.shingles" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1.5 } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene2}}" , "fields" :[ "title.shingles" , "summary.shingles" , "inclusion.shingles" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.3 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>imi_mug_ct2.json</head><p>{ "from" : 0 , "size" : 1000 , "query" :{ "bool" :{ "must_not" :{ "match" :{ "exclusion" : "{{disease}}" } }, "must" :[ { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{disease}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "summary" , "inclusion" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1.3 } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "summary" , "inclusion" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 0.8 "query" : "{{gene1}}" , "fields" :[ "title.shingles" , "summary.shingles" , "inclusion.shingles" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1.5 } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene2}}" , "fields" :[ "title.shingles" , "summary.shingles" , "inclusion.shingles" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.3 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>imi_mug_ct3.json</head><p>{ "from" : 0 , "size" : 1000 , "query" :{ "bool" :{ "should" :[ { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{disease}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "summary" , "inclusion" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1.3 } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "summary" , "inclusion" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 0.8</p><p>"should" :[ { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{disease}}" , "fields" :[ "title.shingles" , "summary.shingles" , "inclusion.shingles" ] } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene1}}" , "fields" :[ "title.shingles" , "summary.shingles" , "inclusion.shingles" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1.5 } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene2}}" , "fields" :[ "title.shingles" , "summary.shingles" , "inclusion.shingles" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.3 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>imi_mug_ct4.json</head><p>{ "from" : 0 , "size" : 1000 , "query" :{ "bool" :{ "must" :[ { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{disease}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "summary" , "inclusion^2" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1.3 } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "summary" , "inclusion^2" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 0. "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene1}}" , "fields" :[ "title.shingles" , "summary.shingles" , "inclusion.shingles^2" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1.5 } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene2}}" , "fields" :[ "title.shingles" , "summary.shingles" , "inclusion.shingles^2" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.3 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>imi_mug_ct5.json</head><p>{ "from" : 0 , "size" : 1000 , "query" :{ "bool" :{ "must" :[ { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{disease}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "summary" , "inclusion" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 1.3 } }, { "multi_match" :{ "query" : "{{gene}}" , "fields" :[ "title" , "summary" , "inclusion" ], "tie_breaker" : 0.4 , "type" : "best_fields" , "boost" : 0. </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
