<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,134.77,115.96,345.83,12.62;1,173.93,133.89,267.50,12.62">The University of Padua IMS Research Group at TREC 2018 Precision Medicine Track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,169.62,171.74,73.23,8.74"><forename type="first">Maristella</forename><surname>Agosti</surname></persName>
							<email>maristella.agosti@unipd.it</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Information Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Padua</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,250.57,171.74,74.98,8.74"><forename type="first">Giorgio</forename><forename type="middle">Maria</forename><surname>Di</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Information Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Padua</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,365.68,171.74,80.06,8.74"><forename type="first">Stefano</forename><surname>Marchesin</surname></persName>
							<email>stefano.marchesin@unipd.it</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Information Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Padua</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,134.77,115.96,345.83,12.62;1,173.93,133.89,267.50,12.62">The University of Padua IMS Research Group at TREC 2018 Precision Medicine Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">36FD4D99E0B8ACC78270FB3A1BB0A35B</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:10+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Precision medicine</term>
					<term>query expansion</term>
					<term>cancer-gene-protein relationships</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We report on the participation of the Information Management System (IMS) Research Group of the University of Padua in the second task of the Precision Medicine Track at TREC 2018: the Clinical Trials task. We designed a procedure to: i) expand query terms iteratively, based on knowledge bases, to increase the probability of finding relevant trials by adding neoplasm, gene, and protein term variants to the initial query; ii) filter out trials based on demographic data. We submitted three runs: a plain BM25 using the provided textual fields &lt;gene&gt; and &lt;disease&gt; as query, a BM25 with a first knowledge-based query expansion, and another BM25 with an additional knowledge-based query expansion. This initial set of experiments lays the ground for a deeper study on the effectiveness of (automatic) knowledge-based expansion techniques in the context of precision medicine.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The TREC 2018 Precision Medicine (PM) Track<ref type="foot" coords="1,345.64,479.11,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref> focuses on a relevant use case in clinical decision support: to provide useful precision medicine-related information to clinicians treating cancer patients. Each case of a patient is composed of: the disease (i.e. type of cancer), the genetic variants of the disease (i.e. which genes), and some basic demographic information of the patient (i.e. age, gender). Given the condition of a patient, the track proposes two challenges with two different corpora: 1) retrieve the relevant scientific literature about treatments for the specific condition (Literature Articles), 2) find relevant clinical trials for which the patient is eligible <ref type="bibr" coords="1,299.04,576.32,69.22,8.74">(Clinical Trials)</ref>.</p><p>In our participation to TREC 2018 PM Track, we focused on the Clinical Trials task. In this task, relevant clinical trials constitute the potential for connecting patients with experimental treatments if existing treatments have been ineffective. In this paper, we present the experiments we carried out using a fully automated system based on a procedure to: i) iteratively expand query terms, relying on medical knowledge bases <ref type="bibr" coords="2,293.72,118.99,10.52,8.74" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,305.89,118.99,7.01,8.74" target="#b2">3]</ref>, to increase the probability of finding relevant trials by adding neoplasm, gene, and protein term variants to the initial query; ii) filter out inappropriate retrieved trials relying on demographic data.</p><p>The aim of this work is twofold: we want to evaluate how a recall oriented approach based on an increasing (and more aggressive) Query Expansion (QE) method affects precision in this context, and study whether the effectiveness of the retrieval approach can be correlated to the quality of the relations contained within the knowledge base used in the query expansion process. In Section 2, we describe the approach we used to index, retrieve and filter clinical trials; in Section 3, we present the experiments and the results of each run; in Section 4, we give our concluding remarks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Methodology</head><p>In this section, we describe in detail the methodology we used to produce the ranked list of clinical trials. In particular, we present: i) what pieces of information were indexed, ii) the ranking model and the query expansion approach, iii) how documents were filtered out based on the eligibility of the patient.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Indexing Step</head><p>We first extracted from each document of the collection all the UMLS<ref type="foot" coords="2,453.37,381.28,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_1">2</ref> concepts, focusing on gene and neoplasm semantic types,<ref type="foot" coords="2,376.77,393.23,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_2">3</ref> using MetaMap <ref type="bibr" coords="2,458.26,394.81,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, a state-of-the-art biomedical concept mapper developed at the National Library of Medicine (NLM). Then, we indexed the document collection by the following fields: &lt;docid&gt;, &lt;text&gt;, &lt;max_age&gt;, &lt;min_age&gt;, &lt;gender&gt; and &lt;concepts&gt;.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Retrieval Step</head><p>We used BM25 <ref type="bibr" coords="2,207.48,481.83,10.52,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref> as the core model for our experiments. Given a query Q, containing keywords q 1 , ..., q n , the BM25 score of a document D is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,173.41,513.00,307.18,30.32">score(D, Q) = n i=1 IDF (q i ) • f (q i , D) • (k 1 + 1) f (q i , D) + k 1 • (1 -b + b • dl avgdl ) ,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where f (q i , D) is the frequency of the i-th query term in the document D, dl is the length of the document D, and avgdl is the average document length in the text collection from which documents are drawn. IDF (q i ) is the Inverse Document Frequency (IDF) weight of the query term q i , and it is computed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,239.58,611.92,236.77,23.22">IDF (q i ) = log N -n(q i ) + 0.5 n(q i ) + 0.5 , (<label>2</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,476.35,618.66,4.24,8.74">)</formula><p>where N is the total number of documents in the collection and n(q i ) is the number of documents containing q i . When performing the retrieval using plain BM25 we consider the original query terms belonging to text fields &lt;disease&gt; and &lt;gene&gt;.</p><p>In the following, we describe how we combined the core model with two different knowledge-based query expansions techniques.</p><p>BM25 + a Priori QE: With this approach, we perform a knowledge-based a priori query expansion. First, we extract from each query all the UMLS concept codes belonging to gene, neoplasm and protein semantic types using MetaMap. Second, for each extracted concept, we consider all its name variants. Lastly, the expanded query consists in the union of the original terms and the set of name variants. For example, consider a query that contains the word melanoma which is mapped to the UMLS concept code C0025202. The set of name variants for melanoma contains, among others: cutaneous melanoma; malignant melanoma; melanoma; melanoma malignant; mm -malignant melanoma; malignant melanomas; malignant melanoma (disorder); etc. The query will be expanded with the union of the terms of the initial query and all these terms. BM25 + a Priori QE + Pseudo Relevance Feedback QE: Based on the ranking obtained with the a priori query expansion, we perform an additional pseudo relevance query expansion by taking the top k returned documents and looking for the extracted UMLS concept codes that are matched. The additional expansion is performed by adding to the expanded query the name variants of the neighbour concepts which present a semantic relation <ref type="foot" coords="3,390.04,422.60,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_3">4</ref> with the extracted concepts within the UMLS Metathesuarus. We restrict this second expansion only to the concepts belonging to gene, neoplasm and protein semantic types.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Filtering Step</head><p>Within each clinical trial, one of the most -if not the most -important sections is the eligibility section. The eligibility section comprises, among the others, three important demographic aspects that a patient needs to satisfy to be considered eligible for the trial, namely: minimum age, maximum age and gender; where minimum age is the minimum age required for a patient to be considered eligible for the trial, maximum age is the maximum age required for a patient to be considered eligible for the trial; gender is the required gender for the patient to be considered for the trial.</p><p>We filter our the clinical trials for which a patient is not eligible whenever his/her demographic data (i.e. the field &lt;demographic&gt;, containing age and gender) do not satisfy the eligibility criteria. In those cases where demographic data is not complete, we keep all the clinical trials regardless the value of the missing data. For example, when minimum age is missing, we keep the clinical trial regardless the lower bound on the age.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments</head><p>We submitted three runs for the Clinical Trials task of the 2018 PM track:</p><p>1. TERM BASED refers to the core BM25 model run; 2. NO PRF refers to the a priori query expansion run; 3. PRF refers to the a priori plus pseudo relevance feedback query expansion run.</p><p>Before analyzing the results, we summarize the procedure used for each run:</p><p>• Indexing • Extract from each document in the collection all the UMLS concept codes restricted to gene and neoplasm semantic types using MetaMap; • Index documents by the following fields: &lt;docid&gt;, &lt;text&gt;, &lt;max_age&gt;, &lt;min_age&gt;, &lt;gender&gt;, &lt;concepts&gt;; • Extract from each query all the UMLS concept codes restricted to gene, neoplasm, and protein semantic types using MetaMap; • Obtain for each query all the name variants from the extracted concepts.</p><p>• Querying</p><p>• Perform a term-based search using &lt;gene&gt; and &lt;disease&gt; text fields with plain BM25 (TERM BASED); • Perform a first query expansion by using i) all gene, neoplasm, and protein concepts name variants, ii) gene and neoplasm extracted concepts (NO PRF); • Based on the previous ranking, take the first k documents (k = 10) and look for the extracted concepts that are matched in the top k clinical trials, then perform an additional query expansion by adding the name variants of the neighbour concepts -restricted to gene, neoplasm, and protein semantic types -which present a semantic relation with the matched concept within UMLS (PRF).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>• Filtering</head><p>• Filter out retrieved clinical trials for which the patient is not eligible in terms of age and gender.</p><p>We used Whoosh, a pure Python search engine library,<ref type="foot" coords="4,376.41,609.67,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_4">5</ref> for indexing, querying and filtering. We used the default values set by Whoosh for the BM25 parameters that are k 1 = 1.2 and b = 0.75. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Results</head><p>In this section, we describe the results obtained in this task by reporting the performances published in the overview paper of the 2018 Precision Medicine Track <ref type="bibr" coords="5,162.63,350.25,10.52,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref> and analyzing for each topic the values of the three performance measures chosen by the organizers: inferred NDCG (infNDCG) <ref type="bibr" coords="5,398.93,362.21,9.96,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, precision at 10 (P@10), and R-precision (RPrec).</p><p>In Table <ref type="table" coords="5,189.75,388.45,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, we report the performance of the top three runs for the Clinical Trials task for each measure ( <ref type="bibr" coords="5,264.30,400.40,10.30,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, Table <ref type="table" coords="5,308.83,400.40,3.87,8.74">6</ref>, page 12). The TERM BASED run is indicated in this table as IMS TERM. Among all the runs sent by the participants in the task, the core BM25 approach reached the top of the list of the best performing runs. This showed that a plain BM25 with a filtering step of the clinical trials based on the demographic data of the patient, performed as good as other complex approaches.</p><p>In order to compare the performance of our three runs and, in particular, to study the impact of the two query expansion approaches, we show the results of the three runs -topic by topic and compared to the median values of the Trackin Table <ref type="table" coords="5,174.67,510.33,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_2">2</ref>, 3, and 4. On average, the TERM BASED run performed about 10 points percent better compared to the median values for all the measures. The other two runs, performed worse than the median values and, in general, much worse than our baseline.</p><p>In order to better visualize the comparison between the TERM BASED run and the median values, we plotted the differences between the two values for each topic. In Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,208.41,584.39,30.03,8.74" target="#fig_1">1a, 1b,</ref> and<ref type="figure" coords="5,262.51,584.39,9.41,8.74" target="#fig_1">1c</ref> we highlight the fact that the TERM BASED run performs consistently better than the median values of the track. It is worth investigating why topic 1 is the only topic where this run performs worse for all the three measures; moreover, topic 4 shows the worst performance for P@10 (considerably large in terms of magnitude). In some cases, for example topic 25 and topic 31, when our run does not show any difference in terms of P@10 and RPrec, the value of infNDCG is slightly worse than median.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Final Remarks</head><p>In this paper, we presented the results of our participation in the TREC 2018 Precision Medicine Track. In particular, our objective was the study of a query expansion approach together with a pseudo-relevance feedback one, followed by a filtering phase in the Clinical Trials task.</p><p>The analysis of the results shows that our baseline, a plain BM25 with a filtering of the clinical trials based on the demographic data of the patient, performs well compared to all the runs of the task. In particular, the performance of the run was comparable with the top performing runs which are based on more complex retrieval models. On the other hand, the query expansion approach introduces too much noise and decreases the performances in a significant way.</p><p>Our next step is to perform a failure analysis to understand whether the use of a specific medical knowledge base instead of a metathesaurus (such as UMLS), and the choice of a more accurate set of relations between terms, can improve the performance of a query expansion approach.  </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="6,177.41,290.61,260.54,7.86;6,184.99,485.76,245.37,7.86;6,184.41,680.90,246.55,7.86"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(a) Difference between run and track median values of infNDCG (b) Difference between run and track median values of P@10 (c) Difference between run and track median values of RPrec</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="6,139.29,701.84,336.78,8.74;6,141.88,506.13,328.54,169.25"><head>Fig. 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1: Difference between TERM BASED run an median values of the track.</figDesc><graphic coords="6,141.88,506.13,328.54,169.25" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,150.86,117.78,313.62,134.88"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>A comparison of the top three runs for the Clinical Trials task.</figDesc><table coords="5,214.35,117.78,186.66,111.67"><row><cell>team</cell><cell>run</cell><cell>measure</cell><cell>score</cell></row><row><cell>hpi-dhc</cell><cell>hpictall</cell><cell cols="2">infNDCG 0.5545</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Cat Garfield MSIIP TRIAL1 infNDCG 0.5503</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ims unipd IMS TERM</cell><cell cols="2">infNDCG 0.5395</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Cat Garfield MSIIP TRIAL1 RPrec</cell><cell>0.4294</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ims unipd IMS TERM</cell><cell>RPrec</cell><cell>0.4128</cell></row><row><cell>Poznan</cell><cell cols="2">BB2 vq noprf RPrec</cell><cell>0.4101</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Cat Garfield MSIIP TRIAL1 P@10</cell><cell>0.6260</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ims unipd IMS TERM</cell><cell>P@10</cell><cell>0.5660</cell></row><row><cell>Poznan</cell><cell cols="2">BB2 vq noprf P@10</cell><cell>0.5580</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="8,186.43,699.82,242.50,8.74"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Topic by topic comparison of infNDCG values.</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,144.73,656.80,142.42,7.86"><p>http://www.trec-cds.org/2018.html</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,144.73,646.48,178.88,7.47"><p>https://www.nlm.nih.gov/research/umls/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="2,144.73,657.44,263.61,7.47"><p>https://metamap.nlm.nih.gov/SemanticTypesAndGroups.shtml</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_3" coords="3,144.73,646.48,329.51,7.47;3,144.73,657.44,122.39,7.47"><p>https://www.nlm.nih.gov/research/umls/knowledge_sources/metathesaurus/ release/abbreviations.html</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5" xml:id="foot_4" coords="4,144.73,657.44,235.37,7.47"><p>https://whoosh.readthedocs.io/en/latest/intro.html</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>topic P@10 TERM BASED NO PRF PRF 1 0.800 0.700 0.700 0.100 2 1.000 1.000 1.000 0.300 3 0.900 0.800 0.700 0.200 4 0.300 0.300 0.100 0.400 5 0.900 1.000 0.800 0.100 6 0.800 0.900 0.500 0.400 7 0.700 0.300 0.700 0.200 8 0.600 0.700 0.500 0.000 9 0.300 0.300 0.100 0.100 10 0.900   </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,353.80,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,364.75,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,375.71,177.57,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,210.65,353.80,269.94,7.86;7,146.91,364.75,88.60,7.86">Effective mapping of biomedical text to the UMLS Metathesaurus: the MetaMap program</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,256.10,364.75,148.25,7.86">Proceedings of the AMIA Symposium</title>
		<meeting>the AMIA Symposium</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>American Medical Informatics Association</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,386.67,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,397.63,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,408.59,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,419.55,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,430.51,333.68,8.12;7,146.91,442.11,175.17,7.47" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,293.98,386.67,186.61,7.86;7,146.91,397.63,289.28,7.86">QUT IElab at CLEF 2018 Consumer Health Search Task: Knowledge Base Retrieval for Consumer Health Search</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Zuccon</forename><surname>Jimmy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Koopman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2125/paper\_203.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,348.83,408.59,131.76,7.86;7,146.91,419.55,191.40,7.86;7,187.84,430.51,121.45,7.86;7,361.08,430.51,87.88,7.86">Working Notes of CLEF 2018 -Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cappellato</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Soulier</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Avignon, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">September 10-14, 2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2125</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CEUR-WS.org (2018)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,452.43,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,463.38,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,474.34,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,485.30,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,496.26,333.67,7.86;7,146.91,507.22,318.87,8.12" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,226.14,463.38,235.45,7.86">UD GU BioTM at TREC 2017: Precision Medicine Track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S M A</forename><surname>Mahmood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Mcgarvey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Madhavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Vijay-Shanker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://trec.nist.gov/pubs/trec26/papers/UD\_GU\_BioTM-PM.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,280.58,474.34,200.01,7.86;7,146.91,485.30,42.62,7.86;7,146.91,496.26,108.03,7.86">Proceedings of the Twenty-Sixth Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ellis</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the Twenty-Sixth Text REtrieval Conference<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-11-15">2017. November 15-17, 2017. 2017</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Special Publication 500-324</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,518.18,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,529.14,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,540.10,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,551.06,251.54,8.12" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,169.10,529.14,216.51,7.86">Overview of the TREC 2018 Precision Medicine Track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Demner-Fushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hersh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bedrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lazar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://trec.nist.gov/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,406.56,529.14,74.03,7.86;7,146.91,540.10,173.19,7.86">Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>the Twenty-Seventh Text REtrieval Conference<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-11-14">2018. November 14-16, 2018 (2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,562.01,342.25,7.86;7,146.91,572.95,319.57,7.89" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,264.03,562.01,216.57,7.86;7,146.91,572.97,17.61,7.86">The probabilistic relevance framework: BM25 and beyond</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zaragoza</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,172.00,572.97,207.78,7.86">Foundations and Trends R in Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="389" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,583.93,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,594.89,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,605.85,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,616.81,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,627.77,333.68,8.12;7,146.91,639.37,70.61,7.47" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,331.88,583.93,148.71,7.86;7,146.91,594.89,167.84,7.86">A Simple and Efficient Sampling Method for Estimating AP and NDCG</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Yilmaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kanoulas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Aslam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/1390334.1390437</idno>
		<ptr target="http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1390334.1390437" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,343.45,594.89,137.14,7.86;7,146.91,605.85,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,616.81,81.00,7.86;7,300.07,616.81,43.42,7.86">Proceedings of the 31st Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 31st Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="603" to="610" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SIGIR &apos;08</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
