<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,130.04,112.60,351.92,14.93">KlickLabs at TREC 2018 Precision Medicine track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,182.66,144.91,77.32,10.37"><forename type="first">Lediona</forename><surname>Nishani</surname></persName>
							<email>lnishani@klick.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Klick Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Klick Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Toronto</settlement>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,268.00,144.91,81.04,10.37"><forename type="first">Maheedhar</forename><surname>Kolla</surname></persName>
							<email>mkolla@klick.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Klick Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Klick Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Toronto</settlement>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,356.88,144.91,72.46,10.37"><forename type="first">Gaurav</forename><surname>Baruah</surname></persName>
							<email>gbaruah@klick.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Klick Labs</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Klick Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Toronto</settlement>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,130.04,112.60,351.92,14.93">KlickLabs at TREC 2018 Precision Medicine track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">E935764443402441B859F0F70ED0BDE6</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:10+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Precision medicine aims to provide the most accurate course of treatment, personalized for each patient. The 2018 Precision Medicine (PM) track aims to build systems, that sift through biomedical articles to find relevant cancer treatments for patients, as well as search for clinical trials for which a patient might be eligible. Cancer, as a disease, can occur in various forms, be of different types, and affect multiple organs as well as bodily systems. Additionally, every patient-cancer combination presents with slight variations depending on genetics, age, sex, and other factors. As of 2017, 16% of PubMed articles related to cancer [5], and over 500,000 articles are added to PubMed each year, thereby, making quality information retrieval for PM an important problem to tackle, for the benefit of doctors and patients alike. In this work, we develop query-expansion methods, with an aim to compare their performance over the 2018 PM task. Our experiments indicate that medical ontology (NCIt) based expansion performs well for retrieving scientific abstracts from PubMed. Utilizing demographic information in queries improves the performance for clinical trial retrieval.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The 2018 TREC Precision Medicine (PM) track aims to evaluate systems that identify the most relevant scientific articles and clinical trials relevant to patients suffering from cancer. Such shortlisting of pertinent documents for each patient could potentially aid the oncologist/physician to prescribe a course of treatment or medication, with high precision, for the particular patient.</p><p>The 2018 TREC PM track provides 50 synthetic cancer cases, developed by oncologists. Each patient case (topic) consists of three primary fields: Disease, Gene and Demographic. Disease field entails the specific type of sickness (form of cancer) that the patient is suffering from. Gene field comprises the genetic variants that are responsible for the disease, which can involve abnormal genes or particular variants of the gene. Demographics includes age and gender. The participants are tasked with retrieving the most relevant scientific abstracts from PubMed for each patient. Additionally, clinical trials, that are likely relevant to the patient, and for which the patient is eligible for, are also required to be retrieved from a snapshot of clinicaltrials.gov. Given that there are over 26 million scientific articles in PubMed, and there are over 240,000 clinical trials listed at clinicaltrials.gov, retrieving highly relevant documents for a patient is paramount for physicians to make informed decisions about patient care and treatment.</p><p>In order to generate high performance run for both tasks, we explored various query expansion strategies. We investigated expanding queries with a list of synonyms generated from UMLS and NCIT knowledge bases. We also tried to generate synonyms based on word embedding similarity, for query expansion. Finally, we tried a fusion based approach that fused results from differently expanded queries.</p><p>We submitted 4 runs for the first task and five runs for the second task. Based on our experiments, we find that using NCIt synonyms for query expansion improved results over our baseline queries for scientific abstract retrieval.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Topic Structure</head><p>Each topic is a synthetic medical case developed by oncologists from the University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center. Each topic consists of the following fields:</p><p>• Disease: specifies the disease category (the type of cancer the patient is suffering from)</p><p>• Gene: specifies the gene responsible, or specifies several mutated genes and variations</p><p>• Demographics: specifies the age and the gender of the patient.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Document Corpora</head><p>For scientific abstracts, the set of documents consists of 26.6 million PubMed abstracts, along with supplementary abstracts from American Association for Cancer Research (AACR) proceedings. For clinical trials, the set of documents is a collection of 240,000 clinical trials from clinicaltrials.gov. Clinical trials are semi-structured articles, which have specific fields for covering information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Evaluation Metrics</head><p>The primary metrics for the track are infNDCG <ref type="bibr" coords="2,270.36,296.15,10.58,8.64" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, P@10 and R-precision. We also utilized MAP for comparing systems before submitting our runs.</p><p>3 Additional/External data used for developing systems</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">NCIt</head><p>NCI thesaurus (NCIt-part of the National Cancer of Institute) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,323.83,384.67,11.62,8.64" target="#b5">[6]</ref> encompasses a comprehensive classifier of cancer terminology and medical ontologies. It involves various human and machine literate concept of thousands of neoplasms in a systematic logic parentchild structure. This ontology provides mappings of concepts between NCI and all other medical resources, thus facilitating data analysis and exploration across medical dictionaries and ontologies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">UMLS</head><p>UMLS-Unified Medical Language System <ref type="bibr" coords="2,248.07,467.73,11.62,8.64" target="#b0">[1]</ref> represents a repository of biomedical vocabularies designed from US National Library of Medicine. It comprises over 2 million names for more than 900,000 concepts for biomedical vocabularies, and additional 12 million associations across the underlying concepts. UMLS contains concepts (that could have many different names), and each concept has an associated Concept Unique Identifier (CUI). CUIs can be used to link those names with other medical ontologies and vocabularies (like NCIt). We identify CUIs from UMLS for query terms <ref type="bibr" coords="2,135.91,527.51,11.62,8.64" target="#b8">[9]</ref> in the provided topic. For instance, given the disease "melanoma", we find its CUIs from UMLS "C3539018 : "M elanoma , "C0025202 : "M elanoma , "C0796561 : "melanoma These CUIs help in finding synonyms from NCIt for query expansion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Systems development and Runs</head><p>We primarily explore query expansion methods for the 2018 PM track tasks. We utilize ElasticSearch<ref type="foot" coords="2,480.44,639.68,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_1">1</ref> as our underlying search engine to index and retrieve documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Indexing</head><p>For both tasks (scientific articles and clinical trials) the available documents in the corpus have been indexed by making use of ElasticSearch <ref type="bibr" coords="3,156.05,106.11,10.58,8.64" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. We created a separate index each for PubMed abstracts and clinical trials data. We indexed all fields of the clinical trials data. We extracted from each PubMed abstract the following fields for indexing:</p><p>• PMID: represents the unique identifier that serves as documents ID for submissions runs</p><p>• Abstract: specifies the full text of abstract, which summarizes the content of the paper • Title: the title of the article • Mesh-heading: the medical subject headings that are related to the articles • Publication Type: the categories of publications and MeSH terms used to classify the articles categories</p><p>• Chemicals: Mesh terms related to all registered chemical compounds that are pertinent to an article</p><p>We have configured the ElasticSearch platform to return results using the Okapi BM25 ranking algorithm <ref type="foot" coords="3,511.87,249.87,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_2">2</ref> , with parameters k1 as 1.2 and b as 0.75. The queries to ElasticSearch consisted of the disease name and the gene variant from the topic, as well as expansion terms. The same query was used to retrieve abstracts and trial runs from respective indices. We ranked documents that contained the query terms within a documents title, abstract or mesh headings, and we returned the top 1000 documents, for each query/topic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Baseline Run</head><p>In this run, we do not perform any query expansion. Our baseline query terms consist of the disease name and the gene variants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Query expansion based on similarity between word embeddings</head><p>We obtained word embeddings <ref type="bibr" coords="3,198.99,405.11,11.62,8.64" target="#b7">[8]</ref> constructed over PubMed, PMC texts and Wikipedia; the word vectors were constructed using word2vec <ref type="bibr" coords="3,171.42,417.07,10.58,8.64" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. Word embeddings are essentially representation of words depending on their collocation context with surrounding words. Thus, words that appear in similar contexts may have word vectors that are close to each other. It is therefore possible to generate a list of likely synonyms for a given words word embedding vector.</p><p>We first compute an average word embedding for our baseline query. We find the 5 most similar word vectors to the average vector. We finally add the terms corresponding to the most similar word embeddings to the query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Expansion with NCIt (synonyms) as knowledge base</head><p>To potentially increase recall, we utilize the NCIt thesaurus to find parent and child synonyms of the disease. Parent synonyms could be general terms for the specific cancer, and child synonyms could be more specific terms. For example, for the disease "liposarcoma", NCIt lists as parent synonyms, "Sarcoma" , "Malignant Lipomatous Neoplasm", and NCIt lists as child synonyms, "Myxoid Liposarcoma" , "Primary Liposarcoma" , "Adult Liposarcoma" , "Mixed Liposarcoma".</p><p>For this system, we first find UMLS CUIs for the query terms. In NCIt, each cancer related term is associated with a CUI. We use the query terms CUIs and look up the parent and child synonyms from the NCIt thesaurus. We add these synonyms to the baseline query for expansion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Fusion runs (combine all runs)</head><p>For some Information Retrieval problems, fusion approach works very well, where results of multiple ranking algorithms are combined together. We combine the ranked list of documents from each of the previous query expansion methods and constructed a single ranked list of documents using Reciprocal Rank Fusion <ref type="bibr" coords="3,432.74,666.28,10.58,8.64" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.6">Baseline with filtering (for clinical trials retrieval only)</head><p>In order to increase the likelihood of retrieving the relevant clinical trial for an eligible patient, we leveraged the demographic field of the topic . In this run we didnt employ any query expansion strategy. The formulated query involves information from the gender together with disease and gene of the patient. The baseline with filtering run appeared to outperform all the other clinical trials approaches over all metrics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Results and Discussion</head><p>We developed the systems (listed below) based on different techniques of query expansion. Each system returned results for each of the 50 topics, for both, system abstracts and clinical trials.</p><p>• KLPM18T2Bl/KLPM18T1Bl: we construct a query that combines the terms from disease and gene for each topic.</p><p>• KL18absWV/KL18TrialWV: we expand the query by obtaining synonyms based on the similarity between the PubMed word embeddings.</p><p>• KL18absHY/KL18TriHY: we exploit the hierarchy from NCIT and extract parent synonym diseases and child synonym diseases to expand the query.</p><p>• KL18AbsFuse/KL18TriFuse: a system that fuses the retrieved results from the previous 3 systems using RRF.</p><p>• KL18TrialBF: baseline with demographic filtering. This was implemented for Clinical trial retrieval task only.  <ref type="table" coords="4,121.35,497.30,3.74,8.64" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, we provide the PubMed Abstract results evaluated in P10, infNDCG, R-prec. Our first attempt, baseline run (KLPM18T2B1) performs reasonably well, with P10=0.482 and infNDCG=0.4347. Using NCIT synonym-based expansion (KL18AbsHY) increases performance over all metrics. Interestingly, the KL18absHY results in higher number of relevant articles retrieved than our other methods. Word embedding similarity based expansion (KL18absWV) seems to not improve the performance. The fusion run (KL18ABSFuse) slightly outperforms the NCIt run in terms of P10.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Scientific Abstracts results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Clinical Trials results</head><p>In Table <ref type="table" coords="4,105.97,604.28,3.74,8.64" target="#tab_1">2</ref>, we provide clinical trial results evaluated in P10, infNDCG, R-prec. The Baseline run of trials (KLPM18T1Bl) seems to perform well. The baseline with filtering(KL18TrialBF) outperformed all our runs over all metrics. Again, we notice that the word embedding similarity expansion KL18TrialWV performed poorly. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>For the TREC 2018 Precision Medicine Track, we submitted 4 runs for scientific abstracts task: finding likely relevant scientific abstracts from PubMed, and submitted 5 runs for the clinical trial task: finding clinical trials tasks relevant for the patient to be qualified for. We observe a slight improvement in performance when using synonym-based query expansion.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,86.94,391.54,400.64,114.40"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Abstract Runs results: Final runs for the 2018 topics for the scientific abstract task In Table</figDesc><table coords="4,156.08,391.54,299.83,56.86"><row><cell>runName</cell><cell>P10</cell><cell cols="3">infNDCG R-prec total</cell><cell>num rel retrieved</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">KLPM18T2Bl 0.50</cell><cell>0.4347</cell><cell>0.261</cell><cell>50000 3359</cell></row><row><cell>KL18absWV</cell><cell cols="2">0.284 0.2233</cell><cell>0.129</cell><cell>49950 2096</cell></row><row><cell>KL18absHY</cell><cell cols="2">0.534 0.4432</cell><cell>0.287</cell><cell>50000 3566</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">KL18AbsFuse 0.54</cell><cell>0.4367</cell><cell>0.274</cell><cell>50000 3422</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,139.84,74.28,332.32,90.55"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Clinical Trial results: Final runs for the 2018 topics for Clinical Trials task</figDesc><table coords="5,155.57,74.28,300.86,68.81"><row><cell>runName</cell><cell>P10</cell><cell cols="3">infNDCG R-prec total</cell><cell>num rel retrieved</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">KLPM18T1Bl 0.482 0.416</cell><cell>0.346</cell><cell cols="2">43522 1520</cell></row><row><cell>KL18TrialBF</cell><cell cols="2">0.494 0.437</cell><cell>0.358</cell><cell cols="2">42979 1538</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">KL18TrialWV 0.28</cell><cell>0.319</cell><cell>0.227</cell><cell cols="2">42662 1439</cell></row><row><cell>KL18TriHY</cell><cell cols="2">0.484 0.429</cell><cell cols="3">0.3524 43158 1518</cell></row><row><cell>KL18TriFuse</cell><cell>0.47</cell><cell>0.41</cell><cell>0.317</cell><cell cols="2">47097 1540</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,93.52,637.69,239.24,12.90;1,72.00,663.37,468.00,8.64;1,72.00,675.33,263.70,8.64"><p>Task, Datasets, and Evaluation MetricsThe 2018 PM track specifies two sets of data, one for each respective task: scientific abstracts, and clinical trials. For both tasks, a common set of 50 topics are utilized as the query set.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,86.35,673.36,109.99,5.61"><p>https://www.elastic.co/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_2" coords="3,86.35,685.67,191.28,5.61"><p>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Okapi_BM25</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We would like to thank the <rs type="institution">KlickLabs team at Klick Inc.</rs> for their feedback, and support, for this research.</p></div>
			</div>			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,88.60,366.11,436.19,8.64" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Bodenreider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="5,173.84,366.11,321.83,8.64">The unified medical language system (umls): Integrating biomedical terminology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,88.60,385.34,451.40,8.64;5,88.60,397.12,451.40,8.82;5,88.60,409.07,451.40,8.82;5,88.60,421.21,62.27,8.64" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,353.85,385.34,186.15,8.64;5,88.60,397.30,147.63,8.64">Reciprocal rank fusion outperforms condorcet and individual rank learning methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gordon</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Cormack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Charles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Büttcher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,256.23,397.12,283.77,8.59;5,88.60,409.07,272.76,8.59">Proceedings of the 32nd Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 32nd Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval<address><addrLine>Boston, MA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">July 19-23, 2009. 2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="758" to="759" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SIGIR 2009</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,88.60,440.26,451.40,8.82" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,235.66,440.26,140.58,8.59">Elasticsearch: The Definitive Guide</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Clinton</forename><surname>Gormley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Zachary</forename><surname>Tong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<publisher>O&apos;Reilly Media, Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>1st edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,88.60,459.67,451.41,8.64;5,88.60,471.45,142.77,8.82" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,329.66,459.67,210.34,8.64;5,88.60,471.63,20.51,8.64">Efficient estimation of word representations in vector space</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>CoRR, abs/1301.3781</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,88.60,490.86,451.40,8.64;5,88.60,502.64,330.68,8.82" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,239.13,490.86,300.87,8.64;5,88.60,502.82,194.78,8.64">The proportion of cancer-related entries in pubmed has increased considerably; is cancer truly the emperor of all maladies?</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Constantino</forename><surname>Carlos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Reyes-Aldasoro</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,287.56,502.64,33.97,8.59">PloS one</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">173671</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,88.60,522.05,451.41,8.64;5,88.60,533.83,451.40,8.82;5,88.60,545.78,185.68,8.82" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,122.88,534.01,378.69,8.64">NCI thesaurus: A semantic model integrating cancer-related clinical and molecular information</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Sioutos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sherri</forename><surname>De Coronado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Margaret</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Haber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Frank</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Hartel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wen-Ling</forename><surname>Shaiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,509.26,533.83,30.74,8.59;5,88.60,545.78,102.50,8.59">Journal of Biomedical Informatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="30" to="43" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,88.60,565.20,451.40,8.64;5,88.60,576.97,451.40,8.82;5,88.60,588.93,213.28,8.82" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,321.76,565.20,218.24,8.64;5,88.60,577.15,45.12,8.64">A simple and efficient sampling method for estimating ap and ndcg</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Emine</forename><surname>Yilmaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Evangelos</forename><surname>Kanoulas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Javed</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Aslam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,150.68,576.97,389.32,8.59;5,88.60,588.93,92.44,8.59">Proceedings of the 31st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 31st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="603" to="610" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,88.60,608.34,451.40,8.64;5,88.60,620.12,451.40,8.82;5,88.60,632.07,175.72,8.82" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,251.82,608.34,288.18,8.64;5,88.60,620.29,382.36,8.64">Semantic relatedness and similarity of biomedical terms: examining the effects of recency, size, and section of biomedical publications on the performance of word2vec</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Yongjun</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Erjia</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Fei</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,479.92,620.12,60.08,8.59;5,88.60,632.07,76.37,8.59">BMC Med. Inf. &amp; Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="95" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,88.60,651.48,451.41,8.64;5,88.60,663.26,451.40,8.82;5,88.60,675.21,301.20,8.82" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,241.68,651.48,298.32,8.64;5,88.60,663.44,47.41,8.64">Sigir 2018 tutorial on health search (hs2018): A full-day from consumers to clinicians</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Guido</forename><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bevan</forename><surname>Koopman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,154.86,663.26,385.14,8.59;5,88.60,675.21,81.69,8.82">The 41st International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research &amp;#38; Development in Information Retrieval, SIGIR &apos;18</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1391" to="1394" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
