<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,77.31,72.35,455.10,16.84">Learning to rank clinical trials with rule-based criteria</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,175.82,118.05,79.80,11.06"><forename type="first">Gonçalo</forename><surname>Araújo</surname></persName>
							<email>gc.araujo@campus.fct.unl.pt</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">NOVA Laboratory for Computer Science and Informatics Faculdade de Ciências e Tecnologia</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade NOVA de Lisboa</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2825-516</postCode>
									<settlement>Caparica</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,264.26,118.05,72.40,11.06"><forename type="first">André</forename><surname>Mourão</surname></persName>
							<email>a.mourao@campus.fct.unl.pt</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">NOVA Laboratory for Computer Science and Informatics Faculdade de Ciências e Tecnologia</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade NOVA de Lisboa</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2825-516</postCode>
									<settlement>Caparica</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,346.18,118.05,87.72,11.06"><forename type="first">João</forename><surname>Magalhães</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">NOVA Laboratory for Computer Science and Informatics Faculdade de Ciências e Tecnologia</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade NOVA de Lisboa</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2825-516</postCode>
									<settlement>Caparica</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,77.31,72.35,455.10,16.84">Learning to rank clinical trials with rule-based criteria</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">EDA33F7E25B470BEBF8609E49A272B3B</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:10+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Medical Text Retrieval</term>
					<term>Term expansion</term>
					<term>Clinical trial retrieval</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This report describes the NOVASearch retrieval system for the TREC 2018 Precision Medicine Track in the Clinical Trials matching task. The parsing of queries and documents in the Clinical Trials task were structured into multiple fields according to the details about inclusion and exclusion criteria. We also considered multiple text processing filters on the largest text fields.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">INTRODUCTION</head><p>The TREC Precision Medicine Track 2018, aims to provide clinicians with important information to support medical decisions. The clinical decision support is focused on a specific use case, cancer patients, so that clinicians can have access to very specific medical trials. In this paper, we report the NOVASearch team participation in the Clinical Trials retrieval task. The goal is to retrieve clinical trials were the patient could be a participant due to his disease. This is a natural step towards more comprehensive clinical decision support tasks as was explored in past TREC editions <ref type="bibr" coords="1,267.25,464.85,11.17,7.86" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,281.47,464.85,6.48,7.86" target="#b3">4]</ref>.</p><p>Section 2 details the indexing and retrieval methods implemented. Section 4 discusses the evaluation results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">METHODS AND ALGORITHMS</head><p>Both indexing and retrieval methods were implemented with Apache Lucene, a text search engine library for Java, that contains very helpful methods for creation of indexes, Queries and text search.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Documents shallow parser</head><p>The documents parser uses a pipeline of filters so that we can mitigate factors like, the number of irrelevant words and variation of words (ex.reduction to primal verbal form driving to drive), which leads to more effective retrieval results. Most of the methods are widely used in Information Retrieval, that were tuned to the tasks at hand:</p><p>• Tokenization: Used to remove all form of punctuation and split text into tokens. We also converted all words into lower case.</p><p>• Stop word removal: Remove specific words like "this", "a", "or", that will occur in most of the English texts.</p><p>• Word grams: This filter creates tokens from other tokens. We tested a range of minimum and maximum size of neighboring words to create the indexing tokens.</p><p>• Stemming: We used the Snowball filter to stem the indexed documents. Stemming is the process of reducing words to their word stem.</p><p>• Character grams: Creates n-grams of words, with a minimum and a maximum length for the words is given as a parameter. This is a technique that has been been successful in the medical domain due to the complex spelling of medical terms (many common prefixes and suffixes).</p><p>• Demographics filter Removes the demographic information from the trials, table 1 is a good example.</p><p>Creates age range and a gender exclusion criteria. This type of processing can be found in a similar way in the PICO(population, Intervention, Control, Outcome) fields extraction <ref type="bibr" coords="1,406.54,414.74,9.20,7.86" target="#b4">[5]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Document information extraction</head><p>The TREC PM 2018 collection of clinical trials, contains a large number of trials and most of them not specific for our topics. To index the information contained in the documents, it was necessary to choose the fields that could be relevant in a medical environment and index them. After some inspection, we indexed the fields gender, minimum age, maximum age, title, and condition(disease). The use of the patient specific information can be seen in other articles with proven results <ref type="bibr" coords="1,316.81,533.35,9.20,7.86" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p><p>The provided format of the documents in the collection, a field-structured document, helped us to minimize the workload on the pre-processing of the text before indexing it. For example, &lt;minimum_age&gt; 18 Years &lt;/minimum_age&gt;, after retrieving the text of the xml tag &lt;minimum_age&gt; , there's only need to split the text by white spaces and the result is an array containing ["18","years"], we know for sure that the first value on the array is a string containing a number, that represents the minimum age of the patients for this clinical trial.</p><p>The information contained in the larger text fields such as, brief title or summary are first processed using the analysis process explained in the previous section, and then indexed. Not all the fields are available in all clinical trials, however, in our implementation we stored all the fields even if they're empty, or nonexistent on the clinical trial. The indexed fields are described in table 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Extracted and created fields Description</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Full text</head><p>Field containing a concatenation of relevant text fields about the intervention, (brief title, official Title, briefSum, description, det desp).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Brief title</head><p>A brief title containing only some keywords of the title.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Official title</head><p>The official title of the clinical trial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Brief Summary</head><p>A excerpt of the summary.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Detailed description</head><p>A detailed description specifying the intervention made on the clinical trial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CriteriaInc</head><p>Specific inclusion criteria for the patients (other deceases, allergies, other drugs previously used).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CriteriaExc</head><p>Specific exclusion criteria for the patients (other deceases, allergies, other drugs previously used).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Intervention</head><p>Describes the trial intervention type.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>InterventionExp</head><p>Expansion with SNOMED and Mesh of the trial intervention type.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>StudyType</head><p>Type of clinical trial Purpose</p><p>The purpose of the clinical trial Gender</p><p>The genders acceptable for the trial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>MaxAge</head><p>The maximum age of patients acceptable for this trial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>MinAge</head><p>The minimum age of patients acceptable for this trial.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Condition</head><p>Description of the patient clinical condition requirements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ConditionExp</head><p>Expansion with SNOMED and Mesh of the condition.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="2,164.34,320.84,3.58,7.86">1</ref>: The fields created from the information extracted from the clinical trials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Filters</head><p>Several filter were implemented to remove clinical trials that do not match some of the criteria. Filters use one of the indexed fields and are applied as described in the runs section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Retrieval Models</head><p>To retrieve relevant documents for each topic (a clinical case), we first did some processing of the TREC topics text fields, corresponding to the same steps we did to the indexed fields. We examined multiple runs using different types of analyzers, so we could test which analyzers would do a better job in filtering MESH terms <ref type="bibr" coords="2,168.75,480.18,9.66,7.86" target="#b0">[1]</ref> and overall medical relevant terms. We also used several types of query parsers and various ranking functions. Our main focus was to create the maximum number of inclusion and exclusion criteria, querying the collection of documents with information relevant to the indexed fields, this way we could take advantage of having structured documents in our data set and in our topics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.1">Vector Space Model</head><p>Term Frequency-Inverse Document Frequency consists, in a statistical method to define the importance of words for a specific document and simultaneously for the collection. If a word frequency in a collection is low, and its frequency in a document is high its tf-idf value is higher than the value for words that occur more often in the collection, even if they have high frequency in a few documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.2">BM25 and variants</head><p>We use both standard BM25 and variants of BM25 to acommodate documents with different ranks and to lower bound term frequencies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.3">Language Models</head><p>Language Models are also known for being competitive in a number of scenarios. We also used LM with Dirichlet smoothing and LM with Jelineck-Mercer Smoothing. This is an important model for cases where the query expasion increase the query length, where the Jelineck-Mercer smoothing is known to work better.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Learning to Rank Models</head><p>We created the features that are described in table 3 and the retrieval models of the previous section. Some of the filters are also described in table <ref type="table" coords="2,450.74,456.42,3.58,7.86" target="#tab_1">3</ref>.</p><p>We used two tree based learning to rank methods, based on the assumption that those algorithms would capture the non-linear relations provided by the filters. In particular we used the AdaRank and the LambdaMART algorithms. Also, we used the Coordinate Ascent as a strong baseline.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">EVALUATION</head><p>The Clinical Trials retrieval system, consisted in applying BM25 with multiple combinations of search results filters based on demographic, and exclusion criteria to reduce non relevant retrievals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Runs description</head><p>The base Query is the disease, gene variant. patient demographics are used as filters to inclusion and exclusion criteria. PRF query expansion using top 3 documents retrieved and exclusion criteria based on other conditions the patient may suffer. In general, the runs for retrieving Clinical Trials are:</p><p>• Run 1: Search (BM25L similarity) in the trial title, summary and description text. Query is the disease, gene variant text and the terms "solid tumor" and "solid neoplasm". Search (BM25L similarity) in the inclusion criteria, query is the gene variant text. Searching for trials with intervention, study type and primary purpose fitted for oncology treatments. Results filtering by the patient age and gender. Final ranking list obtained after re-ranking documents according official and meSH conditions. Matching documents condition with expanded query disease and gene variation.</p><p>• Run 2: Search (BM25L similarity) in the trial title, summary and description text. Query is the disease, gene variant text and the terms "solid tumor" and "solid neoplasm". Search (BM25L similarity) in the inclusion criteria, query is the gene variant text. Searching for trials with intervention, study type and primary purpose fitted for oncology treatments. Results filtering by the patient age and gender.</p><p>• Run 3: LETOR using LambdaMart algorithm. Features based on multiple retrieval functions (BM25, TF-IDF, Language Models) and features based on to Run 1 and 2 filters.</p><p>• Run 4: LETOR using AdaRank algorithm. Features based on multiple retrieval functions (BM25, TF-IDF, Language Models) and features based on to Run 1 and 2 filters.</p><p>• Run 5: LETOR using Coordinate Ascend. Features based on multiple retrieval functions (BM25, TF-IDF, Language Models) and features based on to Run 1 and the methods described in the following section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.1">Run5: Deep IE + CoordAsc</head><p>On run 5, we added an additional set of features. We used the score values from run 1 as the main feature. In addition, we added all the features used to train LETOR models from run 3 and 4, we added a set of features that counted the number of matches according to a larger set of criteria.</p><p>We generated two versions of all fields in the query (Disease, Gene, Preconditions):</p><p>• A BROAD expansion query, with all expansion terms (for example, "breast cancer" will be expanded using SNOMed and MeSH for all terms ["Breast Cancer", "Breast", "Cancer"], resulting in a query that adds expansions to all terms: ["Breast Cancer" -&gt; ["Malignant Tumor Of Breast", "Ca -Breast Cancer"], ["Breast" -&gt; ["Breasts", "Breast Structure", "Mamma", "Breast Anatomy, "Mammary Gland, "Entire Breast"], "Cancer" -&gt; ["Neoplasm", "Benign Neoplasm", "Cancers", "Neoplasms", "Benign", "Neoplasm", "Benign", "Tumor", "Neoplasms", "Tumors", "Ca -Cancer", "Tumor", "Malignant", "Malignant Neoplasm", "Cancer Morphology", "Malignancy", "Malignant Tumor", "Malignant Tumor Morphology", "Neoplasm", "Malignant", "Malignant Neoplastic Disease", "Blastoma", "Neoplasm", "Malignant (primary)", "Unclassified Tumor", "Malignant", "Malignant Neoplastic Disease (primary)", "Malignant Neoplasm", "Primary"]</p><p>• A NARROW expanded query, which will only expand the NARROWEST terms that are present in the collection: For example: in the previous example, "Breast Cancer" contains three terms that are present in either MeSH and SNOMed: ["Breast Cancer", "Breast", "Cancer",]. The narrow expansion will recognize that "Breast" and "Cancer" are BROADER than "Breast Cancer" and thus, only expand the NARROWER term ["Breast Cancer"-&gt; ["Malignant Tumor Of Breast", "Ca -Breast Cancer"]].</p><p>The goal is to avoid the query drift that is added by adding too many expansion terms to the query. We wanted to study whether using different versions of the query on the different terms makes a different in feature selection and relevance.</p><p>To study the impact of the NARROW and BROADER terms for re-ranking, the following features were extracted for BOTH version of the query:</p><p>• the number of query terms (condition, gene, and NEGATED exclusion criteria) present in the inclusion criteria, exclusion criteria, condition,</p><p>• number of condition terms present in the title</p><p>• number of gene terms present in the title</p><p>• number of condition and gene terms is present in the inclusion criteria</p><p>• number of condition and gene terms is present in the exclusion criteria</p><p>These features were used to train a LETOR model, using coordinate accent.</p><p>• Retrieval Score da RUN 1: float feature that represents the score returned by the set of techniques used on run 1 methods.</p><p>• title matches gene: binary feature that describes whether any query term (cancer type, gene name, preconditions (for 2017 data)) or any of the expansions appear in any of the inclusion criteria sentences feature that describes whether the gene name or any of its expansions appear in the title</p><p>• exc matches gene: binary feature that describes whether any query term (cancer type, gene name, preconditions (for 2017 data)) or any of the expansions appear in any of the exclusion criteria sentences</p><p>• total pos i1: count feature that describes whether gene name or any of its expansions appear in any of the inclusion criteria sentences non-negated</p><p>• total neg i1: count feature that describes whether the negated gene name or any of its expansions appear in any of the inclusion criteria sentences</p><p>• total pos e1: count feature that describes whether gene name or any of its expansions appear in any of the exclusion criteria sentences</p><p>• total neg e1: count feature that describes whether the negated gene name or any of its expansions appear in any of the exclusion criteria sentences Run/Method P@5 P@10 P@15 P@20</p><p>(  Precision at top retrieved results, i.e., P@5, P@10, P@15 and P@20.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Discussion</head><p>The overall results for the Clinical Trials retrieval were very positive: all runs except one, attained a performance above median. In particular, the two simplest runs, without learning to rank, were the most stable ones (runs 1 and 2). Surprisingly, the learning to rank methods AdaRank and LambdaMART were not as successful as one would expect. Our initial hypothesis, that tree based methos would benefit from filtering criteria, was not confirmed by results.</p><p>Nevertheless, the Coordinate Ascent run-5, was able to achieve the best run. It is also positive that such method was the best, because it is also the mehtod that offers inter-pretable results.</p><p>What was evident in all the runs described in this paper is that the information extracted from the documents played a critical role in the success of our system. Hence, as future work, we plan to the generalise feature extraction process to make the patient / clinical trial matching process more effective. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Field</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="4,53.80,344.10,239.11,7.86"><head>Figure 1 :Figure 2 :</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Precision-recall graph illustrates the different runs.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,64.75,73.21,217.21,72.41"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results for the Clinical Trials Task.</figDesc><table coords="4,64.75,73.21,217.21,49.71"><row><cell>1) Deep IE</cell><cell>0.568 0.516</cell><cell>0.468</cell><cell>0.43</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">(2) Deep IE + Mesh 0.608 0.544 0.4973 0.466</cell></row><row><cell>(3) LambdaMART</cell><cell>0.528 0.484</cell><cell cols="2">0.44 0.408</cell></row><row><cell>(4) AdaRank</cell><cell cols="3">0.496 0.416 0.3667 0.338</cell></row><row><cell>(5) CoordAsc</cell><cell>0.612 0.552</cell><cell cols="2">0.508 0.464</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,138.40,71.64,332.77,630.84"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Learning to rank and filtering fields.</figDesc><table coords="5,138.40,71.64,332.77,608.14"><row><cell></cell><cell>Query</cell><cell>Matching or Similarity</cell></row><row><cell>gene</cell><cell>expanded gene</cell><cell>BM25</cell></row><row><cell>gene</cell><cell>expanded gene</cell><cell>LMDIR</cell></row><row><cell>purpose</cell><cell>treatment, diagnosis,prevention</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>intervention</cell><cell>drug, biological, radiation</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>studytype</cell><cell>tnterventional</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>text</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>tf</cell></row><row><cell>text</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>idf</cell></row><row><cell>text</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>tfidf</cell></row><row><cell>text</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>bm25</cell></row><row><cell>text</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>bm25l</cell></row><row><cell>text</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>bm25+</cell></row><row><cell>text</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>lmd</cell></row><row><cell>text</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>lmjm</cell></row><row><cell>text</cell><cell>text length</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>text</cell><cell>gene</cell><cell>of genes keywords</cell></row><row><cell>text</cell><cell>gene</cell><cell>% of keywords matched</cell></row><row><cell>text</cell><cell>disease</cell><cell>of diseases keywords</cell></row><row><cell>text</cell><cell>disease</cell><cell>% of keywords matched</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">detailed description gene/disease</cell><cell>tf</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">detailed description gene/disease</cell><cell>idf</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">detailed description gene/disease</cell><cell>tfidf</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">detailed description gene/disease</cell><cell>bm25</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">detailed description gene/disease</cell><cell>bm25l</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">detailed description gene/disease</cell><cell>bm25+</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">detailed description gene/disease</cell><cell>lmd</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">detailed description gene/disease</cell><cell>lmjm</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">detailed description text length</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">detailed description gene</cell><cell>of genes keywords</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">detailed description gene</cell><cell>% of keywords matched</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">detailed description disease</cell><cell>of diseases keywords</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">detailed description disease</cell><cell>% of keywords matched</cell></row><row><cell>official title</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>tf</cell></row><row><cell>official title</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>idf</cell></row><row><cell>official title</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>tfidf</cell></row><row><cell>official title</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>bm25</cell></row><row><cell>official title</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>bm25l</cell></row><row><cell>official title</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>bm25+</cell></row><row><cell>official title</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>lmd</cell></row><row><cell>official title</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>lmjm</cell></row><row><cell>official title</cell><cell>text length</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>official title</cell><cell>gene</cell><cell>of genes keywords</cell></row><row><cell>official title</cell><cell>gene</cell><cell>% of keywords matched</cell></row><row><cell>official title</cell><cell>disease</cell><cell>of diseases keywords</cell></row><row><cell>official title</cell><cell>disease</cell><cell>% of keywords matched</cell></row><row><cell>brief summary</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>tf</cell></row><row><cell>brief summary</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>idf</cell></row><row><cell>brief summary</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>tfidf</cell></row><row><cell>brief summary</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>bm25</cell></row><row><cell>brief summary</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>bm25l</cell></row><row><cell>brief summary</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>bm25+</cell></row><row><cell>brief summary</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>lmd</cell></row><row><cell>brief summary</cell><cell>gene/disease</cell><cell>lmjm</cell></row><row><cell>brief summary</cell><cell>text length</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>brief summary</cell><cell>gene</cell><cell>of genes keywords</cell></row><row><cell>brief summary</cell><cell>gene</cell><cell>% of keywords matched</cell></row><row><cell>brief summary</cell><cell>disease</cell><cell>of diseases keywords</cell></row><row><cell>brief summary</cell><cell>disease</cell><cell>% of keywords matched</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.01,156.90,224.92,9.72;4,331.01,169.22,180.86,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dutkiewicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Äź Drzejek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Werda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Put contribution to trec cds 2016</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.01,186.85,226.70,7.86;4,331.01,197.31,224.91,7.86;4,331.01,207.77,224.91,7.86;4,330.28,218.23,158.37,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,521.48,197.31,34.44,7.86;4,331.01,207.77,172.92,7.86">Machine learning and decision support in critical care</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E W</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ghassemi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nemati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Niehaus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Clifton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Clifford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,511.03,207.77,44.89,7.86;4,330.28,218.23,45.94,7.86">Proceedings of the IEEE</title>
		<meeting>the IEEE</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-02">Feb 2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="444" to="466" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.01,235.87,224.91,7.86;4,331.01,246.33,174.23,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,509.91,235.87,46.01,7.86;4,331.01,246.33,170.39,7.86">Novasearch at trec 2015 clinical decision support track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mourão</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Magalhães</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.01,263.96,225.16,7.86;4,331.01,274.42,226.19,7.86;4,331.01,284.88,226.19,7.86;4,330.78,295.35,20.96,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,501.17,263.96,55.00,7.86;4,331.01,274.42,153.05,7.86">Novasearch at trec 2014 clinical decision support track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mourao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Magalhaes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<publisher>PORTUGAL</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.01,312.98,226.45,7.86;4,331.01,323.44,224.91,7.86;4,331.01,333.90,224.91,7.86;4,331.01,344.36,91.50,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,415.27,323.44,140.64,7.86;4,331.01,333.90,224.91,7.86;4,331.01,344.36,87.49,7.86">Integrating the framing of clinical questions via pico into the retrieval of medical literature for systematic reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Scells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Koopman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Deacon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Azzopardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Geva</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
