<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,141.52,83.74,328.57,15.10">Webis at TREC 2018: Common Core Track</title>
				<funder ref="#_n7ccfWR">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_D6Rpr9x #_St36bBu">
					<orgName type="full">Deutsche Forschungsgemeinscha (DFG)</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,98.19,109.11,112.73,10.59"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Bondarenko</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Martin-Luther-Universität Halle-Wi enberg</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,263.31,109.11,74.87,10.59"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Völske</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Bauhaus-Universität Weimar</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,390.58,109.11,107.29,10.59"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Panchenko</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Universität Hamburg</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,153.11,125.62,72.97,10.59"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Biemann</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Universität Hamburg</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,266.52,125.62,58.99,10.59"><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Bauhaus-Universität Weimar</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,365.95,125.62,77.61,10.59"><forename type="first">Ma</forename><surname>Hias Hagen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Martin-Luther-Universität Halle-Wi enberg</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,141.52,83.74,328.57,15.10">Webis at TREC 2018: Common Core Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">9081FE8300C0294AE21CD7F1422F05F7</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:10+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>is paper gives a brief overview of the Webis network's participation in the TREC 2018 Common Core track. e basic idea applied in our approach is to axiomatically re-rank the top-50 results of BM25F for those topics that seem to be argumentative. To this end, we use three axioms with the goal of covering some aspects of argumentativeness in text documents. If all three argumentative axioms favor a re-ordering of two documents, they "overrule" the initial ranking and the documents change their ranks.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>Our idea of the argumentative re-ranking for argumentative queries (i.e., queries for which results containing good argumentation might be the most promising ones) basically follows our last year's Common Core track approach <ref type="bibr" coords="1,154.45,357.33,9.63,7.94" target="#b4">[5]</ref>: capture preferences for more argumentative documents using ideas of axiomatic re-ranking <ref type="bibr" coords="1,282.73,368.28,9.52,7.94" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Compared to last year, we did change the axioms and the weighting scheme a bit and only apply the re-ranking to the 25 topics / queries manually judged as argumentative .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">WEBIS COMMON CORE TRACK RUNS</head><p>We brie y describe our procedure for identifying argumentative queries / topics and give a brief explanation of the axioms and their weights that we have selected to re-rank the BM25F top-50 results for argumentative queries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Identifying Argumentative eries</head><p>We manually went through the topic titles of this year's Common Core track and labeled the ones as argumentative where our impression was that some user submi ing the title as a query might look for arguments in the resulting retrieved documents. Only for those topics that were labeled as argumentative, the axiomatic re-ranking is invoked to favor "argumentative" results. is is di erent to our last year's TREC Common Core track runs where we simply applied re-ranking with two argumentative axioms to each topic.</p><p>e 25 topics from the TREC 2018 Common Core track that we labeled as potentially argumentative are given in Table <ref type="table" coords="1,256.78,602.41,3.07,7.94" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Argumentative Axioms</head><p>One idea of axiomatic thinking for information retrieval <ref type="bibr" coords="1,257.77,637.28,9.24,7.94" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,269.24,637.28,7.30,7.94" target="#b3">4]</ref> is to identify axioms (i.e., constraints) that good retrieval models should ful ll. In a previous axiomatic re-ranking study, we have shown that weighted combinations of "all" known axioms can improve the initial ranking of several baseline retrieval systems <ref type="bibr" coords="1,514.63,206.84,9.27,7.94" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Our last year's TREC approach then focused on two rather simplistic axioms that should capture argumentativeness during the re-ranking. However, re-ranking the results for all queries with argumentative axioms did not really show any improvements. We thus suggest the following three more ne-grained axioms in our this year's approach and only selectively apply the re-ranking to the top-50 BM25F results to potentially argumentative topics / queries. Axiom ArgUC (Argumentative Units Count). e general idea of the ArgUC axiom is to favor documents that contain more argumentative units (i.e., a document is heuristically viewed as more "argumentative" when it contains more arguments).</p><p>Formalization. Let Q be an argumentative query, D 1 and D 2 be two retrieved documents, ≈ 10% indicate "equality" up to a 10% di erence, and let count Arg (D) be the number of argumentative units in a document D.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="1,317.96,381.31,240.05,20.97">If length(D 1 ) ≈ 10% length(D 2 ) and if count Arg (D 1 ) &gt; count Arg (D 2 ) then rank(D 1 , Q) &gt; rank(D 2 , Q).</formula><p>Axiom QTArg ( ery Term Occurrence in Argumentative Units). e general idea of the QTArg axiom is to favor documents where the query terms appear closer to argumentative units (i.e., a document is heuristically viewed as more argumentative on the query topic when the query terms appear in argumentative units instead of non-argumentative units).</p><p>Formalization. Let Q be an argumentative query consisting of the single term q, D 1 and D 2 be two retrieved documents, and Ar D be the set of argumentative units of a document D.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="1,317.96,502.28,240.42,32.17">If length(D 1 ) ≈ 10% length(D 2 ) and if q ∈ A D 1 for some A D 1 ∈ Ar D 1 but q A D 2 for all A D 2 ∈ Ar D 2 then rank(D 1 , Q) &gt; rank(D 2 , Q).</formula><p>Axiom QTPArg ( ery Term Position in Argumentative Units). Following the general observation that in relevant documents the query terms occur closer to the beginning <ref type="bibr" coords="1,466.24,563.00,9.23,7.94" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,477.05,563.00,10.05,7.94" target="#b9">10]</ref>, the QTPArg axiom favors documents where the rst appearance of a query term in an argumentative unit is closer to the beginning of the document.</p><p>Formalization. Let Q be an argumentative query consisting of the single term q, D 1 and D 2 be two retrieved documents, and 1 st position(q, Ar D ) be the rst position in an argumentative unit of document D where the term q appears. If length(D 1 ) ≈ 10% length(D 2 ) and if</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="1,317.96,643.05,240.25,22.00">1 st position(q, Ar D 1 ) &lt; 1 st position(q, Ar D 2 ) then rank(D 1 , Q) &gt; rank(D 2 , Q).</formula><p>Similar to our general axiomatic re-ranking pipeline <ref type="bibr" coords="1,517.21,670.95,9.27,7.94" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, in practice, we relax the axioms QTArg and QTOArg a bit more to also cover multi-term queries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Argumentative Unit Detection</head><p>To detect the argumentative units of a document, we use an own extension 1 of the system based on the BiLSTM-CNN-CRF neural network model developed by Reimers and Gurevych <ref type="bibr" coords="2,252.80,122.41,10.68,7.94" target="#b7">[8]</ref> that we retrained on the essay dataset created by Stab and Gurevych <ref type="bibr" coords="2,283.36,133.37,10.68,7.94" target="#b8">[9]</ref> employing fastText.cc vectors proposed by Bojanowski et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,273.86,144.33,10.46,7.94" target="#b2">[3]</ref> as representations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Axiom Weights</head><p>Following our general axiomatic re-ranking pipeline <ref type="bibr" coords="2,241.24,190.16,9.27,7.94" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, we employ an axiom ORIG in addition to the three argumentative axioms. e ORIG axiom simply corresponds to the preferences induced by the baseline retrieval system's ranking-BM25F in our case. e four di erent axioms' are being weighted for linearly combining the respective preference matrices <ref type="bibr" coords="2,165.21,244.95,9.27,7.94" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. As for our TREC 2018 Common Core track approach, we set the weight of ORIG to 0.43 and the argumentative axioms' weights to 0.19. e underlying idea is that the argumentative axioms have equal weights and can only "overrule" an ORIG preference i they all agree-a later ne-tuning of the weights might be a promising direction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">e Webis Runs</head><p>e result lists of our three runs submi ed to the TREC 2018 Common Core track do not fully re ect the above described argumentative idea, though. Our main goal with our three runs was to gather judgments for the whole top-50 of the BM25F baseline assuming a pooling depth of 20 would be used for the assessment. We wanted to later be able to experiment with other axiomatic re-ranking schemes for the top-50 results of BM25F without having to deal with a lot of documents without judgments.</p><p>We simply used the topic titles without any further processing or expansion as queries to an Elasticsearch BM25F index with the elds title (the document title; weight: 3) summary1 (the rst three sentences of the document body; weight: 2), summary2 (TextRankbased summarization <ref type="bibr" coords="2,133.40,466.12,9.48,7.94" target="#b1">[2]</ref>; weight: 2), and content (document body; weight: 1), while the BM25 parameters were set to the "default" k 1 = 1.2 and b = 0.75. An optimization of these parameters with respect to the Washington Post corpus, application of some query expansion, etc. are natural possible optimization steps. Our run webis-argument has as its top-20 results the top-20 of BM25F for nonargumentative topics and for argumentative topics it has the top-20 results of the argumentative re-ranking of the BM25F's top-50 results. is way, webis-argument is the representative of our general idea. In the webis-bm25f and the webis-baseline runs, though, we used the remaining top-50 documents returned by BM25F not included in the webis-argument run + some random 10 documents from the BM25F's initial ranks 51 to 100 as the respective top-20 ranks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.6">Evaluation</head><p>We analyze the performance of the re-ranking on the argumentative topics in more detail. Table <ref type="table" coords="2,154.07,654.42,3.37,7.94" target="#tab_0">1</ref>) reports the nDCG@10 of the BM25F baseline and the nDCG@10 of the argumentative axiom re-ranking for the 25 argumentative topics (manually labeled as such before 1 Available at h p://ltdemos.informatik.uni-hamburg.de/argsearch/. e nDCG@10 of the argumentatively re-ranked top-50 results (and the di erence to the baseline) are also given (the four topics with argumentative improvements ≥ 0.05 in bold). submi ing our runs to TREC, cf. Section 2.1). e argumentative re-ranking improves upon the baseline by an nDCG@10-change of at least 0.05 for four topics (bold in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,472.66,458.75,3.49,7.94" target="#tab_0">1</ref>) but reduces it for six topics; the average nDCG@10 of 0.64 does not change.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">CONCLUSION</head><p>We have used three basic axioms that aim to capture some rough ideas about documents' argumentativeness to re-rank results for queries that seem to be "argumentative" (i.e., that may bene t from argumentative results). Our rst inspections of our runs' results show some promising e ects of improved performance for some topics. We will try to ne-tune the detection of the argumentative units and axiom weights but we will also aim at developing axioms capturing further di erent angles of argumentativeness.</p><p>Natural other next steps are to improve the weighting scheme through larger-scale training, and to be er detect argumentative topics (e.g., taking into account a topic's description or narrative for the labeling and / or looking at results judged as relevant more deeply for the Core tracks or past TREC tracks that also used newspaper collections).</p><p>Also interesting could be more ne-grained pre-conditions for the axioms besides the current similar-length constraint. An example could be to only try to axiomatically re-rank documents if their original retrieval score is rather similar.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,317.66,84.49,240.78,29.85"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>e 25 manually labeled argumentative topics from the TREC 2018 Common Core track ordered by the BM25F baseline's nDCG@10.</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>is work has been partially supported by the <rs type="funder">Deutsche Forschungsgemeinscha (DFG)</rs> within the project "<rs type="projectName">Argumentation in Comparative estion Answering (AC A)</rs>" (<rs type="grantNumber">HA 5851/2-1</rs> and grant <rs type="grantNumber">BI 1544/7-1</rs>) that is part of the <rs type="programName">Priority Program</rs> "<rs type="projectName">Robust Argumentation Machines (RATIO)</rs>" (<rs type="grantNumber">SPP-1999</rs>).</p><p>We also thank <rs type="person">Oleksiy Oliinyk</rs> and <rs type="person">Philipp Heidenreich</rs> from <rs type="affiliation">Universität Hamburg</rs> for providing the pre-trained models and a RESTful API that we used for argumentative unit detection (cf. Section 2.3).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_D6Rpr9x">
					<idno type="grant-number">HA 5851/2-1</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">Argumentation in Comparative estion Answering (AC A)</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_St36bBu">
					<idno type="grant-number">BI 1544/7-1</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">Robust Argumentation Machines (RATIO)</orgName>
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">Priority Program</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_n7ccfWR">
					<idno type="grant-number">SPP-1999</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="3,70.23,221.35,223.81,6.18;3,70.23,229.32,217.09,6.18" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,192.68,221.35,101.37,6.18;3,70.23,229.32,80.84,6.18">Axiomatic Thinking for Information Retrieval: And Related Tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Amigó</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mizzaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,164.15,229.32,69.46,6.17">Proceedings of SIGIR 2017</title>
		<meeting>SIGIR 2017</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1419" to="1420" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,70.23,237.29,224.99,6.18;3,70.23,245.26,223.51,6.18" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Barrios</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>López</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Argerich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Wachenchauzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>arXiv:, 1602.03606</idno>
		<title level="m" coord="3,231.20,237.29,64.03,6.18;3,70.23,245.26,165.26,6.18">Variations of the Similarity Function of TextRank for Automated Summarization</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,334.39,88.10,223.81,6.18;3,334.39,96.07,116.26,6.18" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bojanowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Grave</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Joulin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>arXiv, 1607.04606</idno>
		<title level="m" coord="3,476.02,88.10,82.18,6.18;3,334.39,96.07,59.76,6.18">Enriching Word Vectors with Subword Information</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,334.39,104.04,224.89,6.18;3,334.39,112.01,117.79,6.18" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,415.29,104.04,141.28,6.18">A Formal Study of Information Retrieval Heuristics</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,341.98,112.01,69.46,6.17">Proceedings of SIGIR 2004</title>
		<meeting>SIGIR 2004</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="56" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,334.39,119.98,223.81,6.18;3,334.39,127.95,151.39,6.18" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,483.70,119.98,74.49,6.18;3,334.39,127.95,66.03,6.18">Webis at TREC 2017: Open Search and Core Tracks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Ajjour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kiesel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Adineh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,413.47,127.95,69.52,6.17">Proceedings of TREC 2017</title>
		<meeting>TREC 2017</meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,334.39,135.92,223.81,6.18;3,334.39,143.89,117.40,6.18" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,464.68,135.92,82.02,6.18">Axiomatic Result Re-Ranking</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Völske</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Göring</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,334.39,143.89,70.19,6.17">Proceedings of CIKM 2016</title>
		<meeting>CIKM 2016</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="721" to="730" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,334.39,151.86,223.81,6.18;3,334.39,159.83,223.81,6.18;3,334.23,167.80,31.30,6.18" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,428.59,151.86,129.61,6.18;3,334.39,159.83,114.31,6.18">Learning to Match Using Local and Distributed Representations of Text for Web Search</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Diaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Craswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,462.25,159.83,74.82,6.17">Proceedings of WWW 2017</title>
		<meeting>WWW 2017</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1291" to="1299" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,334.39,175.77,224.63,6.18;3,334.39,183.74,223.81,6.18;3,334.39,191.71,81.11,6.18" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,416.64,175.77,142.38,6.18;3,334.39,183.74,171.43,6.18">Reporting Score Distributions Makes a Di erence: Performance Study of LSTM-networks for Sequence Tagging</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Reimers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,519.04,183.74,39.16,6.17;3,334.39,191.71,33.90,6.17">Proceedings of EMNLP 2017</title>
		<meeting>EMNLP 2017</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="338" to="348" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,334.39,199.68,224.89,6.18;3,334.39,207.65,132.84,6.18" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,403.63,199.68,152.80,6.18">Parsing Argumentation Structures in Persuasive Essays</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Stab</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Gurevych</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="3,334.39,207.65,71.90,6.17">Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="619" to="659" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,334.39,215.62,223.81,6.18;3,334.18,223.59,160.08,6.18" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,412.91,215.62,145.29,6.18;3,334.18,223.59,30.06,6.18">Enhancing Relevance Scoring with Chronological Term Rank</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Troy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,377.58,223.59,69.46,6.17">Proceedings of SIGIR 2007</title>
		<meeting>SIGIR 2007</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="599" to="606" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
