<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,236.36,85.53,122.64,12.64;1,227.84,101.61,139.84,12.64">IRIT at CLEF 2004: The English GIRT task</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,167.24,128.04,62.94,8.96"><forename type="first">Mustapha</forename><surname>Baziz</surname></persName>
							<email>baziz@irit.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">IRIT/SIG</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Campus Univ. Toulouse III</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>118 Route de Narbonne</addrLine>
									<postCode>F-31062</postCode>
									<settlement>Toulouse Cedex 4</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,236.95,128.04,81.56,8.96"><forename type="first">Mohand</forename><surname>Boughanem</surname></persName>
							<email>boughane@irit.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">IRIT/SIG</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Campus Univ. Toulouse III</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>118 Route de Narbonne</addrLine>
									<postCode>F-31062</postCode>
									<settlement>Toulouse Cedex 4</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,326.14,128.04,101.72,8.96"><forename type="first">Nathalie</forename><surname>Aussenac-Gilles</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">IRIT/SIG</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Campus Univ. Toulouse III</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>118 Route de Narbonne</addrLine>
									<postCode>F-31062</postCode>
									<settlement>Toulouse Cedex 4</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,236.36,85.53,122.64,12.64;1,227.84,101.61,139.84,12.64">IRIT at CLEF 2004: The English GIRT task</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">A78C6F6196C190A6031D8BDC6149F8A8</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:06+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes our participation to the monolingual English GIRT task. The main objectives of our experiments were to evaluate the use of Mercure IRS (designed at IRIT/SIG) on domain specific corpus. Two other techniques of automatic query reformulation using WordNet are evaluated.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>The objective of IRIT/SIG participation in 2004 was to evaluate the use of Mercure IRS on domain specific data. In addition to evaluate the Mercure system, two other techniques are experimented using WordNet. The first technique consists on detecting mono and multiword concepts from queries and then to weight them according to a proposed CF.IDF formula, a kind of TF.IDF. The second concerns disambiguation-expansion method consisting of selecting the closest synset (concept) to the initial query, from WordNet, to use for expanding the query.</p><p>This paper is organized as follows. In section2, the used Mercure IRS model is described. In section3, the additional tests are formally described: the concepts detection and weighting method from queries in 3.1, and the disambiguation-expansion method in 3.2. Section4 presents the official evaluation results compared with the median average obtained by all participating systems. Finally, section5 gives some conclusions and prospects.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Mercure Model</head><p>Mercure is an information retrieval system based on a connectionist approach and modelled by three-layered network (as shown in Figure1). The network is composed of a query layer (set of query terms), a term layer representing the indexing terms and a document layer <ref type="bibr" coords="1,288.07,530.64,10.66,8.96" target="#b9">[2]</ref>. Mercure includes the implementation of a retrieval process based on spreading activation forward and backward through weighted links. Queries and documents can be either inputs of the network. The links between two layers are symmetric and their weights are based on the TF.IDF measure inspired by the OKAPI <ref type="bibr" coords="1,489.94,565.08,11.66,8.96">[5]</ref> term weighting formula.</p><p>-The term-document link weights are expressed by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="1,182.48,606.33,232.17,55.12">ij j i ij ij tf h d dl h h n N h h tf d * * )) log( * ( * 5 4 3 2 1 + ∆ + + = (1)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>-</head><p>The query-term links (at stage s) are weighted as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="1,182.48,686.74,232.17,44.65">     &gt; - = otehrwise qtf qtf nq if qtf nq qtf nq q ui ui u ui u ui u s ui ) ( * ) (<label>(2)</label></formula><p>The query weights are based on spreading activation. Each neural node computes an input and spreads an output signal: 1. The query k is the input of the network. Input k =1. Then, each neuron from the term layer computes an input value from this initial query:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,182.84,451.00,231.82,14.17">s ki k ti q Input N In * ) ( =<label>(3)</label></formula><p>The output value is computed as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,182.24,490.72,228.50,14.17">) ( ( ) ( ti ti N In g N Out = (<label>4</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="2,410.75,493.03,3.91,9.02">)</formula><p>where g is the identity function. 2. These signals are propagated forward through the network from the term layer to the document layer. Each neuron computes an input and output value:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="2,88.88,555.92,325.78,41.28">∑ = = T i ij ti dj w N Out N In 1 * ) ( ) (<label>(5) and,</label></formula><p>)) ( ( ) (</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="2,182.24,603.28,232.42,14.04">dj dj N In g N Out = (6)</formula><p>The system output is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7" coords="2,182.24,648.20,177.94,10.88">) ( ),.., ( ), ( ( 2 1 DN D D k N Out N Out N Out Output</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Notations:</head><p>T:</p><p>the total number of indexing terms, N:</p><p>The total number of documents, q ui :</p><p>The weight of the term t i in the query u, t i :</p><p>The term t i , d j :</p><p>The document d j w ij</p><p>The weight of the link between the term t i and the document d j , The frequency of the term t i in the document d j , n i</p><p>The number of documents containing term t i , nq u</p><p>The query length (number of unique terms) qtf ui Query term frequency</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Overview of the additional tests</head><p>In this section, we describe two methods used for query processing based on WordNet. The first consists of concept detection and weighting from queries. The second method, disambiguation-expansion, tend to expand a query with its closest synset from WordNet <ref type="bibr" coords="3,247.25,226.16,10.69,9.02">[4]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Concepts detection and weighting</head><p>Concept detection consists of extracting mono and multiword concepts from queries that correspond to nodes (synsets) in WordNet. Formally, let consider:</p><p>the initial query composed of n single words. The result of the concept detection process will be a query Q c . It corresponds to:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8" coords="3,177.92,464.11,325.76,10.93">Q c = {c 1 , c 2 , …, c m , w' 1 , w' 2,…, w' m' }<label>(8)</label></formula><p>Where c 1 , c 2 , , c m are concepts recognized as entries in WordNet. These concepts could be mono or multiword. It can also happen that single words w' 1 , w' 2,…, w' m' of the initial query do not belong to ontology vocabulary. They will be used for disambiguating the query. They will then be added to the final expanded query. For detecting concepts in the query, we use an ad hoc technique that relies solely on concatenation of adjacent words to identify compound (multiword) concepts of WordNet. In this technique, two alternative ways can be distinguished. The first one consists of projecting WordNet on the query by extracting all multiword concepts from WordNet and then identifying those occurring in the query. This method has the advantage of creating a reusable resource. Its drawback is the possibility to omit concepts which appear in the query and in WordNet with different forms. For example if WordNet recognizes a multiword concept "solar battery", a simple comparison do not recognizes in the query the same concept appearing in its plural form "solar batteries". The second way, which we adopt in this paper, consists in the opposite step, projecting the query on WordNet: for each multiword candidate concept derived by combining adjacent words in the query, we first question WordNet using these words just as they are, and then we use their base forms if necessary. Concerning word combination, the principle consists in selecting the longest successive terms for which a concept is detected. If we consider the example shown in Figure2, the sentence contains three (3) different concepts which are: external oblique muscle, abdominal muscle and abdominal external oblique muscle. The definition of the first concept according to WordNet is:</p><p>The noun abdominal muscle has 1 sense 1. abdominal, abdominal muscle, ab --(the muscles of the abdomen);</p><p>This concept is not retained in our approach, because its words are not adjacent. The second "external oblique muscle" and the third "abdominal external oblique muscle" are synonyms, their definition is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9" coords="3,216.44,310.63,286.40,10.93">Q= {w 1 , w 2 , …, w n } (7)</formula><p>The abdominal external oblique muscle</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure2. Example of text with different concepts</head><p>The noun external oblique muscle has 1 sense 1. external oblique muscle, musculus obliquus externus abdominis, abdominal external oblique muscle, oblique --(a diagonally arranged abdominal muscle on either side of the torso)</p><p>The selected concept is associated to the longest multiword « abdominal external oblique muscle » which corresponds to the correct sense of the sentence. Remind that in words combination, the order must be respected (left to right) otherwise we could be confronted to the syntactic variation problem (science library is different from library science).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Example of multiword concepts extracted from the official topics:</head><p>103 live_in 109 animal_husbandry 124 telephone_interview 105 on_the_job 114 federal_republic_of_germany 125 european_country 106 multiple_sclerosis 117 carbon_dioxide 125 infant_mortality The extracted concepts are then weighted according to a kind of TF.IDF, we name CF.IDF. For a concept c i composed of n words, its frequency in a query equals to the number of occurrences of a concept itself, and the one of all its sub-concepts. Formally:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10" coords="4,182.36,276.44,232.30,29.65">∑ ∈ + = ) ( ) ( ) ( ) ( ) ( ) ( i c sub sc i i i sc count c length sc length c count c cf<label>(9)</label></formula><p>Where length(c i ) represents the number of words that form c i and sub(c i ) is the set of all possible sub-concepts which can be derived from c i : concepts of n-1 words from c i , concepts of n-2, and all single words of c i .</p><p>Example: if we consider a concept "elastic potential energy" in a given topic, composed of 3 words, its frequency is computed as follows:</p><p>cf("elastic potential energy") = count("elastic potential energy") + 2/3 count("potential energy")+1/3 count("elastic") + 1/3 count("potential") + 1/3 count("energy").</p><p>Knowing that potential energy is itself also a multiword concept and here, it is a question of adding the number of occurrences of potential energy and not its frequency.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Disambiguation-expansion using WordNet synset</head><p>Once mono and multiwords concepts of initial queries are extracted and weighted, an expansion process with WordNet synsets is carried out. As each recognized concept c k (formula 8) could have several senses (a set R Syns of synsets containing C k ):</p><formula xml:id="formula_11" coords="4,212.96,517.70,142.96,24.85">{ } t k j k k k k Syns C C C C C R ,.., ,..., , )<label>( 2 1</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>=</head><p>(10) they are disambiguated using an adapted Lesk algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="4,304.28,552.32,11.84,9.02">[3]</ref> which consists of overlapping each synset with the initial query. A concept-sense (synset) having the best overlapping (the greater number of common words) with the initial query is retained. Formally: It contains 4 single-word concepts which are: C 1 = "ecological", C 2 = "farming", C 3 = "animal", C 4 = "husbandry". The first concept "ecological" has two synsets (R Syns (C 1 )={ <ref type="bibr" coords="4,307.89,699.80,12.01,9.01">[1]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" coords="4,326.68,699.80,11.86,9.01" target="#b9">[2]</ref>}) which appear in lines noticed <ref type="bibr" coords="4,470.24,699.80,11.70,9.01">[1]</ref> and <ref type="bibr" coords="4,501.85,699.80,11.70,9.01" target="#b9">[2]</ref> of Figure3, the second "farming" has three synsets (R Syns (C 2 ) ={ <ref type="bibr" coords="4,321.74,711.32,12.35,9.01">[3]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" coords="4,341.57,711.32,10.59,9.01">[4]</ref>, [5]}), the third "animal" has three ({[6],</p><formula xml:id="formula_12" coords="4,170.48,585.27,335.60,30.06">{ }Q C C C C ArgMax C R Best t k j k k k k Syns ∩ = ,.., ,..., , )) ( ( 2 1 j k,<label>(11)</label></formula><p>[7], [8]}) and the last concept "husbandry" has only one synset (at line <ref type="bibr" coords="4,366.80,722.84,10.52,9.01" target="#b7">[9]</ref>). As only one synset could be used for expanding the whole query in our "careful query expansion" approach, the best concept Best(R syns (C k )) which disambiguates the query Q is the synset of line <ref type="bibr" coords="4,288.90,745.88,11.71,9.01">[3]</ref> (or <ref type="bibr" coords="4,317.59,745.88,11.71,9.01" target="#b7">[9]</ref> which is identical to <ref type="bibr" coords="4,415.96,745.88,11.71,9.01">[3]</ref>  Roughly the obtained results are about +25% better than the median average obtained by all participating systems. These results show also that using WordNet in disambiguation-expansion and concepts frequencies do not enhance significantly the average precision even though the precision for the first retrieved documents (not reported here) are better in the case of Run5TWN. Detecting and weighting concepts method, to bring better results, should be enhanced and then applied to queries as well as to documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>We have evaluated the performances of our IRS (Mercure) in domain specific corpus, and a method for query reformulation based on concepts detection and weighting using WordNet synsets. In this method, multiword concepts are removed into single words in the final queries in order to be conforming to the used IRS indexing process. What is presented in this report is a part of a complete method achieved after our participation to 2004 CLEF campaign which is applied for queries and documents as well. This method is described in <ref type="bibr" coords="6,465.66,392.36,10.67,9.01">[1]</ref>. Next year, we intend to participate to CLEF with the new method.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="4,70.88,636.60,118.81,8.96;4,70.88,653.84,96.04,9.01;4,70.88,665.64,183.80,8.96"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Let us consider a query: Q=[ ecological farming animal husbandry].</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,430.31,745.88,94.08,9.01"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>in this example): farming Results obtained for the five official runs compared to the median average.</figDesc><table coords="5,161.60,427.88,286.52,9.01"><row><cell></cell><cell>Average Precision</cell><cell>Increment (%)</cell></row><row><cell>Run1T</cell><cell>0.3740</cell><cell>+25.08%</cell></row><row><cell>Run2TD</cell><cell>0.3855</cell><cell>+28.92%</cell></row><row><cell>Run3TDfc</cell><cell>0.3764</cell><cell>+25.88%</cell></row><row><cell>Run4TDWN</cell><cell>0.3640</cell><cell>+21.73%</cell></row><row><cell>Run5TWN</cell><cell>0.3764</cell><cell>+25.88%</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Figure3. Example of disambiguation-expansion using wordNet synsets.</cell></row></table><note coords="6,177.44,84.36,31.88,8.96"><p>Table2.</p></note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,75.38,469.60,64.01,10.80;5,70.88,494.72,453.57,9.01;5,70.88,506.12,287.49,9.01;5,218.72,541.16,157.91,9.01;5,101.84,558.08,16.65,9.01;5,305.85,558.08,46.63,9.01;5,84.08,575.72,27.72,9.01;5,147.08,575.72,124.46,9.01;5,84.08,593.84,35.07,9.01;5,147.08,593.84,194.29,9.01;5,84.08,611.96,42.73,9.01;5,147.08,611.96,261.64,9.01;5,84.08,629.96,44.55,9.01;5,147.10,629.96,311.74,9.01;5,84.08,648.08,423.12,9.01;5,70.88,687.92,453.47,9.01;5,70.88,699.44,453.34,9.01;5,70.88,710.96,166.04,9.01;5,198.92,133.80,211.97,8.96;5,208.28,150.07,193.12,7.44;5,114.68,170.83,79.80,7.44" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,396.32,494.72,128.13,9.01;5,70.88,506.12,92.31,9.01;5,336.76,133.80,74.13,8.96;5,208.28,150.07,193.12,7.44;5,114.68,170.83,76.46,7.44">WordNet Synsets Example: query &quot;ecological farming animal husbandry&quot; Synsets of &quot;ecological</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>GIRT_EN&quot;): Run1T, Run2TD, Run3TDfc, Run</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,124.39,184.56,348.50,6.44;5,114.68,192.48,24.39,6.44;5,114.68,202.56,326.35,6.44;5,114.68,219.67,71.28,7.44" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,124.39,184.56,348.50,6.44;5,114.68,192.48,24.39,6.44;5,114.68,202.56,326.35,6.44;5,114.68,219.67,67.77,7.44">ecological ecologic --characterized by the interdependence of living organisms in an environment an ecological disaster [2] ecological ecologic bionomical bionomic --of or relating to the science of ecology ecological research Synsets of &quot;farming</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,124.27,233.28,254.05,6.44" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,124.27,233.28,254.05,6.44">farming agriculture husbandry --the practice of cultivating the land or raising stock</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,124.26,243.48,360.62,6.44;5,114.68,251.40,44.33,6.44" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,247.32,243.48,237.57,6.44;5,114.68,251.40,44.33,6.44">occupation or way of life farming is a strenuous life there s no work on the land any more</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>farming land1 --working the land as an</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,124.38,261.36,353.23,6.44;5,114.68,278.59,68.56,7.44" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,124.38,261.36,353.23,6.44;5,114.68,278.59,37.39,7.44">agrarian agricultural farming --relating to rural matters an agrarian or agricultural society farming communities Synsets of</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,124.39,292.20,330.07,6.44;5,114.68,302.28,379.08,6.44;5,114.68,310.20,260.71,6.44" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,356.04,302.28,137.72,6.44;5,114.68,310.20,260.71,6.44">animal instincts carnal knowledge fleshly desire a sensual delight in eating music is the only sensual pleasure without vice</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,124.39,292.20,330.07,6.44;5,124.40,302.28,225.77,6.44">animal animate being beast brute creature fauna --a living organism characterized by voluntary movement</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>animal carnal fleshly sensual --of the appetites and passions of the body</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,124.38,320.40,345.90,6.44;5,114.68,328.32,66.83,6.44;5,114.68,345.19,82.36,7.44" xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,124.38,320.40,345.90,6.44;5,114.68,328.32,66.83,6.44;5,114.68,345.19,78.49,7.44">animal --of the nature of or characteristic of or derived from an animal or animals the animal kingdom animal instincts animal fats Synsets of &quot;husbandry</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,119.81,358.80,258.50,6.44;5,114.68,378.07,116.33,7.52;5,114.68,387.31,189.75,7.44;5,114.68,398.11,119.37,7.44;6,75.38,440.08,63.69,10.80" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,124.26,358.80,254.05,6.44;5,114.68,378.07,116.33,7.52;5,114.68,387.31,189.75,7.44;5,114.68,398.11,65.87,7.44">farming agriculture husbandry --the practice of cultivating the land or raising stock Similarities list: 1 1 2 1 1 1 1 1 2 Best Concept : --farming agriculture husbandry --Nbre of similarities</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,74.27,465.05,409.98,8.10;6,85.04,475.37,431.89,8.10;6,85.04,485.69,9.06,8.10;6,94.04,483.78,4.80,5.40;6,101.00,485.69,273.60,8.10" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,293.87,465.05,190.38,8.10;6,85.04,475.37,37.00,8.10">The Use of Ontology for Semantic Representation of documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Baziz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Boughanem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Aussenac-Gilles</forename><surname>Nathalie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,142.27,475.37,374.66,8.10;6,85.04,485.69,9.06,8.10;6,94.04,483.78,4.80,5.40;6,101.00,485.69,100.20,8.10">Proceeding of Semantic Web and Information Retrieval Workshop (SWIR) held in conjunction with the 27 th ACM SIGIR Conference&apos;04</title>
		<meeting>eeding of Semantic Web and Information Retrieval Workshop (SWIR) held in conjunction with the 27 th ACM SIGIR Conference&apos;04<address><addrLine>Sheffield, United Kingdom</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">July 25-29, 2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,74.29,502.01,405.47,8.10" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,295.34,502.01,70.07,8.10">Mercure at TREC-7</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Boughanem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Dkaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mothe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Soulé-Dupuy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,372.53,502.01,74.95,8.10">Proceeding of Trec-7</title>
		<meeting>eeding of Trec-7</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,74.29,518.45,450.10,8.10;6,85.04,528.77,159.79,8.10" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,120.22,518.45,404.17,8.10;6,85.04,528.77,15.43,8.10">Automatic sense disambiguation using machine readable dictionaries: How to tell a pine cone from a ice cream cone</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lesk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,116.22,528.77,102.44,8.10">Proceedings of SIGDOC &apos;86</title>
		<meeting>SIGDOC &apos;86</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986">1986</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,74.27,544.97,341.30,8.10" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,122.53,544.97,100.74,8.10">Wordnet: A lexical database</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,229.26,544.97,100.04,8.10">Communication of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,74.29,560.45,450.05,8.10;6,85.04,570.77,120.52,8.10" xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Okapi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="6,117.96,560.45,292.75,8.10">Proceeding of the 6th International Conference on Text Retrieval TREC</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>eeding of the 6th International Conference on Text Retrieval TREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>NIST SP</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="136" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>TREC-6</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
