<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,170.31,116.00,274.74,12.91;1,224.85,133.93,165.67,12.91;1,223.43,153.76,168.49,10.76">Lexical-Syntactic and Graph-Based Features for Authorship Verification Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2013</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,217.46,189.76,61.91,8.97"><forename type="first">Darnes</forename><surname>Vilariño</surname></persName>
							<email>darnes@cs.buap.mx</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Benemérita Universidad Autónoma de Puebla</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="MX">Mexico</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,285.76,189.76,46.24,8.97"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Pinto</surname></persName>
							<email>dpinto@cs.buap.mx</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Benemérita Universidad Autónoma de Puebla</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="MX">Mexico</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,338.42,189.76,59.47,8.97"><forename type="first">Helena</forename><surname>Gómez</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Benemérita Universidad Autónoma de Puebla</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="MX">Mexico</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,243.89,201.72,38.56,8.97"><forename type="first">Saúl</forename><surname>León</surname></persName>
							<email>saul.leon@cs.buap.mx</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Benemérita Universidad Autónoma de Puebla</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="MX">Mexico</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,306.43,201.72,65.04,8.97"><forename type="first">Esteban</forename><surname>Castillo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Benemérita Universidad Autónoma de Puebla</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="MX">Mexico</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,170.31,116.00,274.74,12.91;1,224.85,133.93,165.67,12.91;1,223.43,153.76,168.49,10.76">Lexical-Syntactic and Graph-Based Features for Authorship Verification Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2013</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">585E8142B95FA98D7383326D1156E710</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:34+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Authorship verification</term>
					<term>graph-based representation</term>
					<term>phrase-level lexicalsyntactic features</term>
					<term>support vector machines</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper we present the results obtained by an approach submitted to the author identification task of PAN 2013 which uses lexical, syntactic and graph-based features for constructing a representation model of document authors. In particular, the features extracted from the graph representation were obtained by means of the SubDue mining tool. As a classification model we have employed Support Vector Machines (SVM). The overall results have ranked our approach in the fifth place from around 17 teams.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Authorship verification is the task of determinining if a document has been written by a given author or not. This task is particularly important for forensic linguists who are often called upon to answer this kind of question. This task has been empowered by the continuous growing of information in Internet, thus, the importance of finding the correct features for characterizing the particular writing style of a given author is fundamental for solving the problem of authorship verification.</p><p>The results reported in this paper were obtained in the framework of the International Workshop on Plagiarism detection, Author Identification, and Author Profilling (PAN'13). In particular, in the task named "Author Identification" which has focused this year in the problem of authorship verification which may be described as follows:</p><p>"Given a small set (no more than 10, possibly as few as one) of "known" documents by a single person and a "questioned" document, the task is to determine whether the questioned document was written by the same person who wrote the known document set".</p><p>In order to tackle this problem, we propose to extract a set of lexical syntactic level features from each target document, and up to 100 words which are representative of each author. These representative words are selected through the tool "SubDue" (described in Section 2.2) in order to construct a representation of the whole documents written by the given author using a graph structure.</p><p>The rest of this paper is structured as follows. In Section 2 it is presented the description of the features used in the task to be tackled. Section 3 shows the SVM classification method employed in the experiments. The experimental setting and a discussion of the obtained results are given in Section 4. Finally, the conclusions of this research work is presented in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The proposed approach</head><p>In this work we combine two different types of feature extraction. The first one considers lexical-syntactic features, whereas the second uses a data mining based process for extracting the most relevant terms of the target documents. The two features extraction process are described first, and thereafter, we present the manner we construct the final text representation combining the two types of features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Lexical-syntactic features</head><p>This approach considers the following lexical-syntactic features for representing the particular writing style of a given author:</p><p>-Phrase level features</p><p>• Word sufixes. A group of letters added after a word base to alter its meaning and form a new word. • Stopwords. A group of words that bear no content or relevant semantics which are filtered out from the texts. • Punctuation marks.</p><p>• Trigrams of PoS. Sequences of three PoS tags appearing in the document. Each word text is tagged with its corresponding PoS tag according to the target language. For Spanish language we used the TreeTagger<ref type="foot" coords="2,389.48,464.76,3.49,6.28" target="#foot_0">1</ref> , for the English language we employed the Stanford PosTagger<ref type="foot" coords="2,344.43,476.71,3.49,6.28" target="#foot_1">2</ref> , whereas for the Greek language we used the Greek POS tagger <ref type="foot" coords="2,290.64,488.67,3.49,6.28" target="#foot_2">3</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>-Character level features</head><p>• Vowel combination. Consonants are removed from words and, thereafter, the remaining vowels are combined. Each vowel combination is considered to be a feature. Adjacent repetition of vowels are merged together, considering them as only one vowel. • Vowel permutation. Word consonants are removed and, thereafter, the vowel permutation is considered to be a feature.</p><p>The text representation schema using the above mentioned features is described in Section 2.3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Graph-based features</head><p>A graph based representation is considered in this approach. Formally, given a graph G = (V, E, L, f ) with V being the non-empty set of vertices, E ⊆ V × V the edges, L the tag set, and f : E → L, a function that assigns a tag to a pair of associated vertices.</p><p>This graph-based representation attempt to capture the sequence among the sentence words, so as the sequence among their PoS tags with the aim of feeding a graph mining tool which may extract relevant features that may be further used for representing the texts. Thus, the set V is constructed from the different words and PoS of the target document.</p><p>In order to demonstrate the way we construct the graph for each phrase, consider the following text phrase: "second qualifier long road leading 1998 world cup". The associated graph representation is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,338.44,258.97,3.73,8.97" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. The process for extracting relevant features from the constructed graph is given as follows.</p><p>The Subdue tool Once each paragraph is represented by means of a graph, we apply a data mining algorithm in order to find subgraphs. Subdue is a data mining tool widely used in structured domains. This tool has been used for discovering structured patterns in texts represented by means of graphs <ref type="bibr" coords="3,299.02,596.34,10.58,8.97" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Subdue uses an evaluation model named "Minimum encoding", a technique derived from the minimum description length principle <ref type="bibr" coords="3,157.75,620.25,10.58,8.97" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, in which the best graph sub-structures are chosen. The best subgraphs are those that minimize the number of bits that represent the graph. In this case, the number of bits is calculated considering the size of the graph adjancency matrix. Thus, the best substructure is the one that minimizes I(S) + I(G|S), where I(S) is the number of bits required to describe the substructure S, and I(G|S) is the number of bits required to describe graph G after it has been compacted by the substructure S.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Text representation schema</head><p>Let (x 1 , x 2 , x 3 , • • • , x n ) be the set of features selected for representing the documents, combining the lexical-syntactic and the graph-based features. Each document D is represented considering the feature frequency. Thus, the training stage uses the following feature vector:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="4,250.47,235.74,230.12,24.50">D = (x 1 , x 2 , x 3 , . . . , x n Document f eatures , C)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where C is the class manually associated to the document, in this case, the author Name or ID.</p><p>For the testing stage, we use the feature vector as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="4,256.60,313.75,223.99,24.51">D = (x 1 , x 2 , x 3 , . . . , x n Document f eatures )<label>(2)</label></formula><p>In this case, there is not a classification attribute (class name) due to the anonymous source of the document.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Description of the classifier used in the task</head><p>We have used a Support Vector Machine (SVM) classifier for the task. SVM is a learning method based on the use of a hypothesis space of lineal functions in a higher dimensional space induced by a kernel, in which the hypotheses are trained by one algorithm that uses elements of the generalization theory and taken from the optimization theory.</p><p>The linear learning machines are barely used in major real world applications due to their computational limitations. Kernel based representations are an alternative for this problem proyecting the information to a feature space of higher dimensionality which increases the computational capacity of the linear learning machines. The input space X is mapped to a new feature space as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="4,185.61,539.00,294.98,10.39">x = {x 1 , x 2 , . . . , x n } → φ(x) = {φ(x) 1 , φ(x) 2 , . . . , φ(x) n }<label>(3)</label></formula><p>By employing the kernel function, it is not necessary to explicitly calculate the mapping φ : X → F in order to learn in the feature space.</p><p>In this research work, we employed as kernel the polynomial mapping, which is a very popular method for modeling non-linear functions:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="4,258.45,613.75,222.14,11.37">K(x, x) = ( x, x + c) d (4)</formula><p>where c ∈ R.</p><p>For the experiments carried out in this paper, we used the Weka data mining platform <ref type="bibr" coords="4,152.47,656.12,13.28,8.97" target="#b2">[3]</ref> for executing the implementation of the SVM classifier.</p><p>The results obtained with the approach presented is discussed in this section. First, we describe the dataset used in the experiments and, thereafter, the obtained results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Data sets</head><p>For each author, a set of documents of his authorship is given, together with one document which needs to be verified whether or not it has been written by this author. Thus, for our system, all the "known" documents (verified authorship) written by different authors are part of the training set, whereas all the "unknown" documents form the test data. With the training set we generated a model using the SVM classifier, which was further used for classifying the test documents. If the classifier assigns the author that corresponds to each unknown document, the answer is positive, otherwise it is negative.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Results obtained in the task</head><p>The same methodology is applied to the three different languages, considering only some language particularities such as the Greek vowels and the PoS taggers. In Table <ref type="table" coords="5,475.61,358.77,4.98,8.97" target="#tab_0">1</ref> it can be seen the overall results obtained for each one of the teams that have participated in this edition of the author identification task of PAN 2013. The system proposed by our team (ayala13) obtained the fifth place from 17 teams. Given that this approach uses graph mining techniques through the SubDue tool, it can be observed that the runtime is greater than most of the runs submitted to the competition. In Table <ref type="table" coords="6,186.86,119.00,4.98,8.97" target="#tab_1">2</ref> we present the results obtained by our approach with each one of the three datasets considered in the competition. Three different languages were tackle out. The best performance was obtained with the English language (F 1 = 0.733), followed by an F 1 = 0.667 in the corpus of Greek documents. However, we obtained a low performance in the Spanish corpus (F 1 = 0.560), a result we consider obtained because of the PoS tagger used in the experiments. Further analysis will investigate this issue. It is worth to notice that we always performed better than the competition baselines. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>We have presented an approach that uses two types of features: lexical-syntactic and graph-based. Even if the runtime is greater than the most approaches of this competition, the performance is good. It was surprising that being a Spanish native language team, we performed better in English and Greek languages, but it is a good oportunity for analyzing the text into more deep for determining the reason of this issue. As we mentioned before, we have executed the same methodology across the different languages, varying basically only the PoS taggers. As future work, we would like to observe the performance of the proposed methodology using the FreeLing PoS tagger instead of TreeTagger. When the graph-based features were selected, we empirically determined to extract at most 100 relevant terms using the SubDue graph mining tool. However, more experiments should be performed to analyze whether or not this number introduces significant changes in the obtained results.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,156.83,484.39,301.70,8.07;3,152.06,290.78,311.20,178.82"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Graph based text representation with words and their corresponding PoS tags</figDesc><graphic coords="3,152.06,290.78,311.20,178.82" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,182.75,451.89,249.86,207.67"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Overall results for the PAN 2013 authorship verification task</figDesc><table coords="5,211.26,473.82,192.84,185.74"><row><cell>Submission</cell><cell cols="4">F1 Precision Recall Runtime</cell></row><row><cell>seidman13</cell><cell>0.753</cell><cell>0.753</cell><cell cols="2">0.753 65476823</cell></row><row><cell>halvani13</cell><cell>0.718</cell><cell>0.718</cell><cell>0.718</cell><cell>8362</cell></row><row><cell>layton13</cell><cell>0.671</cell><cell>0.671</cell><cell>0.671</cell><cell>9483</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">jankowska13 0.659</cell><cell>0.659</cell><cell>0.659</cell><cell>240335</cell></row><row><cell>ayala13</cell><cell>0.659</cell><cell>0.659</cell><cell>0.659</cell><cell>5577420</cell></row><row><cell>bobicev13</cell><cell>0.655</cell><cell>0.663</cell><cell>0.647</cell><cell>1713966</cell></row><row><cell>vladimir13</cell><cell>0.612</cell><cell>0.612</cell><cell>0.612</cell><cell>32608</cell></row><row><cell>ghaeini13</cell><cell>0.606</cell><cell>0.671</cell><cell>0.553</cell><cell>125655</cell></row><row><cell>vandam13</cell><cell>0.600</cell><cell>0.600</cell><cell>0.600</cell><cell>9461</cell></row><row><cell>moreau13</cell><cell>0.600</cell><cell>0.600</cell><cell>0.600</cell><cell>7798010</cell></row><row><cell>jayapal13</cell><cell>0.576</cell><cell>0.576</cell><cell>0.576</cell><cell>7008</cell></row><row><cell>grozea13</cell><cell>0.553</cell><cell>0.553</cell><cell>0.553</cell><cell>406755</cell></row><row><cell>gillam13</cell><cell>0.541</cell><cell>0.541</cell><cell>0.541</cell><cell>419495</cell></row><row><cell>kern13</cell><cell>0.529</cell><cell>0.529</cell><cell>0.529</cell><cell>624366</cell></row><row><cell>baseline</cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">petmanson13 0.448</cell><cell>0.700</cell><cell cols="2">0.329 20671346</cell></row><row><cell>zhenshi13</cell><cell>0.417</cell><cell>0.800</cell><cell>0.282</cell><cell>962598</cell></row><row><cell>sorin13</cell><cell>0.331</cell><cell>0.633</cell><cell>0.224</cell><cell>3643942</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="6,221.66,222.41,172.02,62.95"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results obtained in different languages</figDesc><table coords="6,227.37,244.35,160.62,41.02"><row><cell cols="2">Language F1</cell><cell cols="3">Precision Recall Rank</cell></row><row><cell>English</cell><cell>0.733</cell><cell>0.733</cell><cell>0.733</cell><cell>3rd</cell></row><row><cell>Greek</cell><cell>0.667</cell><cell>0.667</cell><cell>0.667</cell><cell>3rd</cell></row><row><cell>Spanish</cell><cell>0.560</cell><cell>0.560</cell><cell>0.560</cell><cell>8th</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,144.73,634.50,215.63,8.07"><p>http://www.cis.uni-muenchen.de/~schmid/tools/TreeTagger/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,144.73,645.65,159.54,8.07"><p>http://nlp.stanford.edu/software/tagger.shtml</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="2,144.73,656.80,292.62,8.07"><p>http://nlp.cs.aueb.gr/software_and_datasets/AUEB_POS_tagger_2_1_alpha.tar.gz</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,557.17,335.82,8.07;6,201.74,568.13,162.12,8.07" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,285.68,557.17,188.27,8.07;6,201.74,568.13,6.64,8.07">Subgraph isomorphism detection using a code based In</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Olmos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gonzalez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Osorio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,213.95,568.13,72.73,8.07">FLAIRS Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="474" to="479" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,579.09,302.79,8.07;6,146.47,590.05,179.20,8.07" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,193.80,579.09,182.63,8.07">Stochastic Complexity in Statistical Inquiry Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rissanen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989">1989</date>
			<publisher>World Scientific Publishing Co., Inc</publisher>
			<pubPlace>River Edge, NJ, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,601.01,325.38,8.07;6,146.47,611.97,326.29,8.07;6,146.47,622.92,20.91,8.07" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,231.28,601.01,228.32,8.07">Data Mining: Practical Machine Learning Tools and Techniques</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Witten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,146.47,611.97,183.51,8.07">Morgan Kaufmann Series in Data Management Sys</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005-06">June 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>second edn.</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
