<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,182.33,115.90,250.70,12.90;1,223.43,135.75,168.50,10.75">Distance learning for Author Verification Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2013</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,140.23,172.15,60.44,8.64"><forename type="first">Paola</forename><surname>Ledesma</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Escuela Nacional de Antropología e Historia (ENAH)</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,210.12,172.15,61.15,8.64"><forename type="first">Gibran</forename><surname>Fuentes</surname></persName>
							<email>gibranfp@turing.iimas.unam.mx</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Instituto de Investigaciones en Matemáticas aplicadas y en Sistemas (IIMAS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM) http</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>www</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,280.72,172.15,57.82,8.64"><forename type="first">Gabriela</forename><surname>Jasso</surname></persName>
							<email>gabrielajassolopez@gmail.mx</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Instituto de Investigaciones en Matemáticas aplicadas y en Sistemas (IIMAS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM) http</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>www</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,347.99,172.15,54.27,8.64"><forename type="first">Angel</forename><surname>Toledo</surname></persName>
							<email>angeltc@ciencias.unam.mx</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Instituto de Investigaciones en Matemáticas aplicadas y en Sistemas (IIMAS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM) http</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>www</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,428.59,172.15,42.07,8.64"><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Meza</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Instituto de Investigaciones en Matemáticas aplicadas y en Sistemas (IIMAS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM) http</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>www</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,182.33,115.90,250.70,12.90;1,223.43,135.75,168.50,10.75">Distance learning for Author Verification Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2013</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">9222B82AEC74347A34EE36AA8448E46A</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:34+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper presents a distance metric learning method for the 'PAN 2013 Author Identification' challenge. Our approach extracts multiple distance metrics of different document representations from which our system learns to tune each one of these distances and representations to form an combined distance metric. We reach this learning distances by means of linear programming, Support Vector Regression and Neuronal Networks models. As specified by the description of the task our system can be applied to English, Greek and Spanish, and can be configured to be language independent. We achieved moderately successful results on this PAN competition, with better results on the development test set. We present results with the official test set and our own corpus based on web documents.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Authorship attribution <ref type="bibr" coords="1,228.59,475.49,11.38,8.64" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,239.97,475.49,7.59,8.64" target="#b4">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,247.56,475.49,7.59,8.64" target="#b7">8]</ref> is an important task for several areas including information retrieval and computational linguistics and has an impact in fields such as law and journalism. A common scenario for this task is the author verification problem. In this setting we have access to a set of documents by a single author and a questioned document, the problem is to determine if the questioned document was written by that particular author or not.</p><p>This year in the PAN 2013 Author Identification task was defined as follow <ref type="foot" coords="1,447.67,545.55,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_0">1</ref> :</p><p>Given a small set (no more than 10, possibly as few as one) of "known" documents by a single person and a "questioned" document, the task is to determine whether the questioned document was written by the same person who wrote the known document set.</p><p>There are multiple features which could characterise an author writing: lexical, syntactic and stylistic. In our approach, we focus into capture these features in different vector space representations of the known documents, for instance bag of words, ngrams. A reasonable hypothesis is that two documents by the same author should be "closer" while documents by different authors should be "distant". We aim to capture this intuition by calculating a metric distance between the vector space representations of the documents. Documents by the same author would share similar characteristics and therefore they would have a distance close to zero while documents by different authors would have a distance close to one.</p><p>We frame the author verification problem as a problem of learning a distance <ref type="bibr" coords="2,468.52,203.00,12.07,8.64" target="#b8">[9]</ref> from multiple distances over multiple vector space representations. In order to achieve this we tried a linear programming <ref type="bibr" coords="2,280.34,226.91,11.62,8.64" target="#b5">[6]</ref> (LP), a Support Vector Regression <ref type="bibr" coords="2,439.80,226.91,11.62,8.64" target="#b1">[2]</ref> (SVR) and Neural Network <ref type="bibr" coords="2,217.25,238.86,11.62,8.64" target="#b2">[3]</ref> (NN) machine learning frameworks. The intuition is to identify the contribution of each one of the distances to form a new distance by means of a linear combination of distances, support vectors or weights. This setting allows us to verify the author in two documents. In order to infer the author for a set of documents, as stated in the task, we calculate the distance between the questioned document and each of the known documents. We used a voting scheme in which we count how many times the system decided a yes or no for the questioned document.</p><p>The outline of this works is the following. Section 2 reviews the vector space representation of documents and lists the representations used in our approach 2. Section 3 presents the metrics used to calculate the distance between documents. Section 4 introduces the different machine learning methods we experimented with. Section 6.2 lists some specification of our final system. Section 5 shows the characteristics of the corpora used during development. Section 6 shows our development and final results using this approach and our system. Finally, 7 discuss about future work and presents some conclusions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Vector Space Representation</head><p>A vector space model <ref type="bibr" coords="2,219.13,455.91,13.70,8.64" target="#b6">[7]</ref> represents a document as a vector space:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,264.83,472.46,85.71,9.65">d = (w 1 , w 2 , ..., w m )</formula><p>In which w i is a frequency or weight of a word of the vocabulary of size m for the word i. A common representation of a vector space model is the bag of words model, in which the words represent actual words of the document and the frequencies counts of occurrence of such words in the represented document.</p><p>In our approach we use the following documents representations:</p><p>Bag of words Frequencies of words in the document.</p><p>Bigram Frequencies of two consecutive words. A distance function calculates the dis-similarity between two elements. We can calculate distances between the vector space representations of our documents presented in the previous section. Formally, a distance function D and vector space d form metric spaces when the following holds:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,209.33,203.78,196.39,54.48">D(d i , d j ) ≥ 0 D(d i , d i ) = 0 D(d i , d j ) = d(d i , d j ), i = j D(d i , d k ) ≤ D(d i , d j ) + D(d j , d k ), i = j, j = k</formula><p>In particular we focus on bounded distances, these are distances that also hold:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="3,255.81,309.16,97.59,9.65">D(d i , d j ) ≤&lt; 1.0, i = j</formula><p>This means that the distances are bounded by one: they range from zero, when they are the same element, to one, when they are completely dis-similar elements.</p><p>There are multiple distance functions to used with the vector space representation. We divided the metrics into three categories: binary, weighted and euclidian based distances. Next we describe each one of these categories.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Binary distances</head><p>This type of distances are based on point wise logical operations on the vector spaces. Example of these distances are Jaccard, Massi and Sorensen. However in our approach we only used: Jaccard This metric measures the common type vocabulary between two sets:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="3,267.03,503.97,213.57,23.22">D(d 1 , d 2 ) = d 1 ∧ d 2 d 1 ∨ d 2<label>(1)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Weighted distances</head><p>This type of distances are based on binary distances but they are modified to take into account the frequencies or weights of the vector space representation. In our approach we use the following weighted distances:</p><p>Weighted Jaccard This metric measures the common token vocabulary between two sets:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="3,256.62,640.05,223.97,23.23">D(d 1 , d 2 ) = min(d 1 , d 2 ) max(d 1 , d 2 )<label>(2)</label></formula><p>Weighted Sorensen This metric measures the twice the common token vocabulary between two sets:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="4,266.47,140.90,214.12,23.22">D(d 1 , d 2 ) = d 1 ⊕ d 2 d 1 + d 2<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where ⊕ is the sum of the vectors components with values grater than zero. Weighted Massi This metric measures the common token vocabulary compared with the vector with more mass frequency:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="4,250.53,217.96,230.06,23.23">D(d 1 , d 2 ) = min(d 1 , d 2 ) max( d 1 , d 2 )<label>(4)</label></formula><p>Weighted h 0 <ref type="bibr" coords="4,190.26,253.21,11.62,8.96" target="#b0">[1]</ref> This metric measures the minimum token vocabulary in common versus the maximum vocabulary in common:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7" coords="4,244.83,286.75,141.44,23.23">D(d 1 , d 2 ) = min(d 1 , d 2 ) max( max(d 1 , d 2 )</formula><p>(5)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Euclidean distances</head><p>This type of distances are based on the Euclidean representation of the vector space. In order to bound them to 1 we normalize them.</p><p>Euclidean This metrics measures the Euclidean distance between two vectors :</p><formula xml:id="formula_8" coords="4,252.20,411.54,228.39,53.24">D(d 1 , d 2 ) = m i=0 (d 2i -d 1i ) 2 m i=0 (d 2i -d 1i ) 2<label>(6)</label></formula><p>Cosine This metric measures cosine angle between to vectors:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9" coords="4,264.29,497.52,216.30,27.21">D(d 1 , d 2 ) = d 1 ḋ2 d 1 ḋ1 * d 2 ḋ2<label>(7)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Ledesma Coefficient</head><p>Additionally to the standard distances presented in the previous sections, we found the following coefficient quite helpful during the learning stage:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10" coords="4,243.19,600.57,237.40,23.22">c(d 1 , d 2 ) = d 1 + d 2 ( d 1 ) 2 * ( d 2 ) 2<label>(8)</label></formula><p>We found this coefficient to be sensitive to documents that are very different among themselves, which helps to signal when two documents did not belong to the same author.</p><p>Let (V, D) be a metric space bounded by 1 in which V is a vector space and D a distance function, then for all </p><formula xml:id="formula_11" coords="5,134.77,154.84,345.83,21.61">d 1 , d 2 , d 3 ∈ V , D(d n , d n ) = 0, D(d 1 , d 2 ) = d(d 2 , d 1 ), D(d 1 , d 3 ) ≤ D(d 1 , d 2 ) + D(d 2 , d</formula><formula xml:id="formula_12" coords="5,186.62,248.40,242.12,83.68">minimize λ 1 + λ 2 + ... + λ m subject to λ 1 * d 1 λ 2 * d 2 ... + λ m * d m ≥ 0.0, if author λ 1 * d 1 λ 2 * d 2 ... + λ m * d m ≤ 0.5, if author λ 1 * d 1 λ 2 * d 2 ... + λ m * d m &gt; 0.5, if not author λ 1 * d 1 λ 2 * d 2 ... + λ m * d m ≤ 1.0, if not author and λ &gt; 0</formula><p>This linear program aims to find the weights λ such that it can split the distances which makes two document be assigned to the same author or otherwise. During the training stage the inequality constrains are expanded with actual examples of values for distances and subject to the inequality depending if thats an example of documents from the same author or not. Then the linear program is run and the solution represents the weights λ.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Corpora</head><p>Additionally to the official training corpus provided by PAN organization we collected an extra corpus based on documents from the web. Table <ref type="table" coords="5,365.41,472.90,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_3">3</ref>  For our development stage we performed a leave-one-out cross-validation using the official training corpus, but we tested the model created by our approach using the Web corpus we collected explained in the previous section. Table ?? presents our development and final results for the official training and testing set and the web documents corpus we extracted. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Linear regression setting</head><p>Additionally, to the linear programming approach we tried a linear regression setting with Support Vector Regression and Neural Network. Table ?? shows the reached results, we do not have results for the official test corpus since these configurations were not part of the final system. The distance learning setting was not compatible with the linear regression since it was difficult to constraint the sum of the weights between zero and one. This situation make it hard to reach good results with these settings. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Final System</head><p>Additionally to the distance learning setting we incorporating several pre-processing strategies to our finale system<ref type="foot" coords="7,252.02,148.97,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_1">2</ref> . The following explains these strategies and list the used parameters for the final version of the system.</p><p>Weighting frequencies For the vector space representation of the documents we tried the following weighting:</p><p>-Term frequency tf -Log term frequency tf log -Inverse document frequency term frequency idtf * tf From experimentation we settle with log term frequency which only a change to a logarithm scale for the frequencies of the terms in the vector space.</p><p>Stop words Some of the representations were preprocessed by eliminating stop words. For this, we used a standard list of words for each of the languages<ref type="foot" coords="7,408.61,317.70,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_2">3</ref> . The representations which were preprocessed with stop words were: Comma, dots and Capitals.</p><p>Cut-off frequencies The vector space representation were also preprocessed by eliminating term with few counts, these are uncommon terms. For each of the representation a cut-off value was defined, the following list the values for each of the representations which were different than zero: Bag of words 5 Numbers 1</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusions and Future work</head><p>In this paper we have presented a learning distance metric method for the 'PAN 2013 Author Identification' challenge. Our approach extracts multiple distance metrics of multiple document representation from which our system learns to tune each one of these distances and representations to form an combined distance metric. Our main approach uses linear programming to find a linear combination of distances, however we also present prelimilary results with a support vector regression and neural networks setting. Our final system achieved moderately successful results on this PAN competition, with better results on the development test set. In particular, English language was harder to verify the author, our system did worst than the baseline system, while for Greek and Spanish we were 4th place in performance. However, the current results point to more work on the side of representations, we are investigating syntactic and semantic feature representations.</p><p>We are investigating improvements to our system, in particular the current version verifies an author by a voting scheme from a set of distances from the known document to the unknown document. But our intuition is that even for an author there will be documents which are closer to the unknown and other than no so close, if a cluster are highly closer it should be considered a good evidence of authorship. We are studying mechanism to add this intuition into our inference processing.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="5,271.18,166.80,209.41,9.65;5,134.77,178.75,345.83,8.96;5,134.77,190.71,345.83,9.65;5,134.77,202.66,345.83,8.96;5,134.77,214.94,36.52,8.64"><head>3 )</head><label>3</label><figDesc>and D(d 1 , d 2 ) ≤ 1 holds. With these properties in mind we propose to have a linear combination λ of distance functions D such that for D 1 , D 2 , ..., D n ∈ D, d l = λ 1 D 1 + λ 2 D 2 + ... + λ n D n is a bound distance function bounded by 1. In order to find such linear combination we propose the following linear program:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,134.77,472.90,345.82,157.38"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>summarises the main characteristics of both corpora. Corpora characteristics for known documents</figDesc><table coords="5,170.88,518.40,273.60,101.02"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">No. Know. Docs No. Problems Vocabulary Type Vocabulary Token</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Official training corpus</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>English</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>2, 612</cell><cell>33, 794</cell></row><row><cell>Greek</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>20</cell><cell>23, 773</cell><cell>149, 373</cell></row><row><cell>Spanish</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>2, 913</cell><cell>7, 920</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Web corpus</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>English</cell><cell>75</cell><cell>13</cell><cell>10, 748</cell><cell>9, 1751</cell></row><row><cell>Greek</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>2, 172</cell><cell>6, 163</cell></row><row><cell>Spanish</cell><cell>37</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>5, 805</cell><cell>27, 713</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="6,207.03,239.75,201.30,63.27"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Development results using linear programming</figDesc><table coords="6,239.80,239.75,135.75,52.41"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Training Web Corpus Test</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">English 70.0%</cell><cell>46.2% 46.7%</cell></row><row><cell>Greek</cell><cell>95.0%</cell><cell>100.0% 66.7%</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Spanish 60.0%</cell><cell>90.9% 72.0%</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell>82.9%</cell><cell>70.4% 61.2%</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="6,218.86,498.30,177.64,129.82"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Development results using SVR and NN</figDesc><table coords="6,253.23,498.30,108.90,118.96"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Training Web Corpus</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Support Vector Regression</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">English 70.0%</cell><cell>53.8%</cell></row><row><cell>Greek</cell><cell>85.0%</cell><cell>66.7%</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Spanish 60.0%</cell><cell>72.7%</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell>77.1%</cell><cell>63.0%</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Neural Network</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">English 60.0%</cell><cell>46.2%</cell></row><row><cell>Greek</cell><cell>40.0%</cell><cell>0.0%</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Spanish 60.0%</cell><cell>63.6%</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell>48.6%</cell><cell>48.1%</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,144.73,657.08,303.86,7.77"><p>As described in the official website of the competition http://pan.webis.de/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="7,144.73,635.82,215.19,6.31"><p>https://github.com/ivanvladimir/authorid</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="7,144.73,646.13,335.86,7.77"><p>This can be found here: https://raw.github.com/ivanvladimir/authorid/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_3" coords="7,144.73,657.93,317.41,6.31"><p>4e3bd5b968135380ce839340541892c30d13cf5d/data/stopwords.txt</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,234.53,329.60,7.77;8,146.47,245.49,160.88,7.77" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,281.97,234.53,185.77,7.77;8,146.47,245.49,34.30,7.77">Near duplicate image detection: min-hash and tf-idf weighting</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Chum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Philbin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zisserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,199.02,245.49,82.19,7.77">Proceedings of BMVC</title>
		<meeting>BMVC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,256.45,320.86,7.77;8,146.47,267.41,154.12,7.77" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Drucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Burges</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kaufman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kaufman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Smola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vapnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="8,146.47,267.41,127.98,7.77">Support vector regression machines</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,278.37,322.05,7.77;8,146.47,289.33,144.22,7.77" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,189.31,278.37,172.08,7.77">Neural Networks: A Comprehensive Foundation</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Haykin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
			<publisher>Prentice Hall PTR</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Upper Saddle River, NJ, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd edn.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,300.28,309.06,7.77" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,180.84,300.28,78.73,7.77">Authorship attribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Juola</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,265.10,300.28,86.22,7.77">Found. Trends Inf. Retr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="233" to="334" />
			<date type="published" when="2006-12">Dec 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,311.24,317.87,7.77;8,146.47,322.20,333.80,7.77" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,279.08,311.24,173.63,7.77">Computational methods in authorship attribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Argamon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,146.47,322.20,263.58,7.77">Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,333.16,313.85,7.77;8,146.47,344.12,74.96,7.77" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,295.51,333.16,156.46,7.77;8,146.47,344.12,48.81,7.77">Interior point methods for large-scale linear programming</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Farwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ramsden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,355.08,332.71,7.77;8,146.47,366.04,125.77,7.77" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,269.14,355.08,160.11,7.77">A vector space model for automatic indexing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,435.21,355.08,35.62,7.77;8,146.47,366.04,20.07,7.77">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="613" to="620" />
			<date type="published" when="1975-11">Nov 1975</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,377.00,339.86,7.77;8,146.47,387.96,258.11,7.77" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,202.76,377.00,182.01,7.77">A survey of modern authorship attribution methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,391.09,377.00,86.90,7.77;8,146.47,387.96,174.43,7.77">Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="538" to="556" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,398.91,251.35,7.77" xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,181.94,398.91,181.39,7.77">Distance metric learning: A comprehensive survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
