<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,226.38,115.96,162.60,12.62;1,175.57,133.89,264.22,12.62;1,243.76,151.82,127.84,12.62">Adapting a Pre-Neural Named Entity Recognizer and Linker to Historical Data</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,153.04,190.78,69.88,8.74"><forename type="first">Damien</forename><surname>Nouvel</surname></persName>
							<email>damien.nouvel@inalco.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">INALCO ERTIM</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,337.30,190.78,59.29,8.74"><forename type="first">Zagabe</forename><surname>Seruti</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">INALCO ERTIM</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,226.38,115.96,162.60,12.62;1,175.57,133.89,264.22,12.62;1,243.76,151.82,127.84,12.62">Adapting a Pre-Neural Named Entity Recognizer and Linker to Historical Data</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">90AED05A7FF84316FBD76C746CB6BFB7</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T16:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Named Entity Recognition</term>
					<term>French</term>
					<term>Pattern Mining</term>
					<term>Historical Texts</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This article describes the participation of ERTIM (INALCO) to the French NER task of CLEF HIPE 2020 lab with the mXS system, a combination of pattern mining and machine learning, implemented in 2010-2013. Due to multiple reasons, almost no upgrades or improvements were achieved since then, only a minimal linking module and some lexical entries were added. No training and almost no adaptation were implemented for this lab. Results on historical data show severe degradations, in particular concerning the recognition of organisations.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Named Entity Recognition for French language was implemented by several resource building, evaluation campaigns or shared tasks. Many resources have already been described <ref type="bibr" coords="1,233.81,477.83,12.82,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref> and it undoubtly remains an important task in the field of NLP.</p><p>Our system, mXS 3 , was developed during the QUAERO <ref type="bibr" coords="1,393.56,503.03,16.22,8.74" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,409.78,503.03,10.81,8.74" target="#b4">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,420.59,503.03,10.81,8.74" target="#b7">8]</ref> evaluation campaign. This shared task, held in 2011, aimed at transcription and named entity recognition (only classification, no linking) of radio broadcast news in French. At this occasion, our system performed 3 rd with competitive results.</p><p>Since its implementation, mXS was minimally updated. Recently, the TA-LAD 4 research project (NLP and Discourse Analysis) provided the opportunity to use mXS on political data (radio interviews). It is in the context of this project that we decided to participate in the CLEF HIPE 2020 lab <ref type="bibr" coords="1,396.18,588.01,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The mXS System</head><p>Our system has already been exhaustively described <ref type="bibr" coords="2,369.28,143.24,9.96,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, it combines data preprocessing, pattern mining and pre-neural machine learning. We only report the main characteristics of the system here.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Data preprocessing</head><p>The same preprocessing are used during training and inference (prediction) steps. For French, the tokenisation and POS tagging are done using TreeTagger <ref type="bibr" coords="2,467.31,229.58,9.96,8.74" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, some postprocessing are implemented (e.g. proper nouns, numbers, verbs) to provide relevant features for named entity classification. The second step consists in looking up each token in a gazetteer which uses several large lexicons (in total more than 1M entries) containing names for French (mainly common and proper nouns, including multiword expressions).</p><p>Both preprocessing are considered as an enrichment process: raw textual data is transformed into sequences of disjunctive itemsets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Pattern Mining</head><p>One of the main differences of mXS compared to other existing software is that named entity recognition is considered as a segmentation task rather than a classification task. In other words, the system tries to find positions where entities begin and end, while most systems consider this task as assigning a class (named entity category) to each element in the sequence.</p><p>Based on this assumption, during the training step the software runs a pattern mining algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="2,235.01,435.61,10.52,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref> to discover rules that segment sequences and reach a minimum level of frequency and confidence in this regard. Those rules are stored in a separate file, and a single rule may introduce multiple segmentations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Machine Learning</head><p>Once patterns are extracted, they are considered as features for a machine learning model implemented using the SciKit <ref type="bibr" coords="2,310.00,521.95,10.52,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref> software. The goal is to predict what is the probablity that a given named entity class would begin or end solely based on extracted patterns. Once this model is learned, it is therefore able to provide probabilities of named entity segmentation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Named Entity Recognition</head><p>The recognition is a decoding step where individual segmentation probabilities are constrained (started entities must end within the considered sentence, nesting can be allowed and follow guidelines, etc.). The resulting annotation corresponds to the segmentation which respects the constraints and maximises the joint probabilities over the sequence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Named Entity Linking</head><p>We did implement a simple entity linker, executed after recognition, and based on Wikipedia. As a first version, the system only links PERS entities. The main steps are:</p><p>1. The name is checked against a local database (very limited for now, it does only contain names and Wikipedia links of a small set of entities), 2. If no match, the wikiapi<ref type="foot" coords="3,252.71,209.19,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">5</ref> python module, connected to the French Wikipedia, is searched for entries based on the entity label (as far as we understood, this API executes the search both in Wikipedia titles and pages), 3. Retrieved results are filtered with an approximate string matching based on the title of the Wikipedia page, 4. A similarity (cosine) between the BoW of processed document and the Wikipedia page content is computed, 5. The page which has highest similarity is selected.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Adaptation to the CLEF HIPE 2020 Lab</head><p>As previously mentioned, due to multiple reasons including the COVID19, we did not have much time to prepare the system for the CLEF HIPE 2020 lab. Actually we did not use the development and training data at all. Fortunately, this shared task was conducted using annotation guidelines mainly inspired by the QUAERO campaign, which facilitated our work.</p><p>Input data is simply converted into raw text (with some minor French tokenisation adaptations) and passed to mXS. Output of our system as tagged texts are converted to the expected column format. A simple script checks and filters out unwanted named entities. For linking, another process runs our linker as previously described, and we used the wikimapper<ref type="foot" coords="3,364.91,458.94,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_1">6</ref> python module to obtain the corresponding WikiData key.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Classification Results and Discussion</head><p>We report our system official results <ref type="bibr" coords="3,297.53,530.18,10.52,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref> (off-the-shelf without any upgrade) for NER in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,200.48,542.13,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. In this paper, we do not report the linker results, since they are very low because this part is very simple and only links PERS entities. Performance is clearly very distant from other systems (best system F1 was 0.84 on COARSE-LIT-micro-strict). We still think it is interesting to have those results as an evaluation of how much an pre-neural system is degraded on unseen historical data when it has been minimally maintained and was neither updated nor trained on the domain and available data. As a side-product of our participation, we provide a valuable estimate of the expected performance before adaptation. Clearly, our main problem is recall, as expected. Table <ref type="table" coords="4,401.49,219.59,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref> reports detailed results per type. We note that PERS, TIME and LOC types have a limited degradation, while ORG suffer from a very severe loss. Given the fact that the lab focused on historical data, this reveals that locations and persons are quite robust over time periods, as depicted below in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,368.41,267.41,3.87,8.74">1</ref>, what is not the case for organisations. We conducted some additional experiments reported in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,430.67,440.28,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_2">3</ref>, with the coarse strict metric (in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,262.42,452.24,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, COARSE-LIT-micro-strict) computed using the provided scorer <ref type="foot" coords="4,200.75,462.62,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_2">7</ref> . First, we corrected some scripts which led to minimal improvements (up). In a second step, we added to mXS's lexicon dev and train data entries with their types (up,lex), but this did almost not change scores. Finally, we re-trained the machine learning component of the system (up,lex,train) with only CLEF HIPE 2020 lab data or merged with the data the system was initially trained on (QUAERO). Those last experiments more significantly improved the system performance, especially for precision, but recall still remains an issue.</p><p>From those results, we first notice to what extent a system's performance is degraded when changing the dataset, both for the domain (historical) and annotation scheme (there are notable differences between QUAERO and HIPE). Despite our efforts, the system does not reach the organizers baseline (CRF). Secondly, even with a modular system where lexicon is an external resource, it is not sufficient to update only this component, the machine learning model parameters have to be recomputed. Finally, from the fact that scores are better  when training with CLEF HIPE 2020 lab data only we make the assumption that QUAERO and HIPE datasets are somehow heterogeneous. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="6,182.01,142.90,4.98,8.74">1</ref> depicts F1, precision and recall of entity types over time periods (20 years, each point is plotted at the beginning of the period). For person and location types, results are quite stable. This is not the case for other types, especially for the organisation type which fluctuates a lot. The global score (ALL) is quite stable and increases smoothly, at the exception of the 1940-1960 period where there is an important loss.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>This paper describes the results obtained by our old-fashioned mXS system for the CLEF HIPE 2020 lab (named entity classification and linking). Diverse reasons prevented us from updating and training the system for this shared task. Performance is severely degraded compared to what was obtained during the QUAERO evaluation campaign (2012). Our analysis showed that organisation entities have higher performance losses performance decrease compared to person and location entities. Our participation provides and estimation of how much a system trained on recent radio transcripts decreases its quality when faced with historical data.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,190.16,115.91,235.04,73.50"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>NER tasks results.</figDesc><table coords="4,190.16,134.94,235.04,54.47"><row><cell>Task</cell><cell cols="3">Rank F1 Precision Recall</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">COARSE-LIT-micro-strict 25 th 0.316 0.435</cell><cell>0.248</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">COARSE-LIT-micro-fuzzy 23 rd 0.439 0.604</cell><cell>0.344</cell></row><row><cell>FINE-LIT-micro-strict</cell><cell>7 th</cell><cell>0.303 0.418</cell><cell>0.238</cell></row><row><cell>FINE-LIT-micro-fuzzy</cell><cell>7 th</cell><cell>0.412 0.568</cell><cell>0.324</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,134.77,313.25,345.83,96.81"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Litteral micro precision, recall and F1 scores for French coarse NER per type.</figDesc><table coords="4,243.96,334.02,127.44,76.03"><row><cell cols="2">Type F1 Precision Recall</cell></row><row><cell>ALL 0.435 0.583</cell><cell>0.346</cell></row><row><cell>PERS 0.55 0.628</cell><cell>0.49</cell></row><row><cell>TIME 0.462 0.336</cell><cell>0.736</cell></row><row><cell>LOC 0.421 0.718</cell><cell>0.297</cell></row><row><cell>ORG 0.117 0.158</cell><cell>0.092</cell></row><row><cell>PROD 0.082 0.25</cell><cell>0.049</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,184.86,128.97,245.64,128.05"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Litteral coarse strict results after system upgrades.</figDesc><table coords="5,195.97,149.74,223.42,107.28"><row><cell>Type</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell cols="2">Precision Recall</cell></row><row><cell>up</cell><cell cols="2">0.288 0.36</cell><cell>0.24</cell></row><row><cell>up,lex</cell><cell cols="2">0.293 0.367</cell><cell>0.244</cell></row><row><cell>up,lex,train(HIPE)</cell><cell cols="2">0.548 0.733</cell><cell>0.438</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">up,lex,train(QUAERO,HIPE) 0.449 0.533</cell><cell>0.388</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Fig. 1. Performance by Type over Time Periods.</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5" xml:id="foot_0" coords="3,144.73,645.84,136.54,7.86"><p>https://pypi.org/project/wikiapi/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6" xml:id="foot_1" coords="3,144.73,656.80,154.73,7.86"><p>https://pypi.org/project/wikimapper/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7" xml:id="foot_2" coords="4,144.73,656.80,220.28,7.86"><p>https://github.com/impresso/CLEF-HIPE-2020-scorer</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,406.01,342.24,7.86;6,146.91,416.97,275.13,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,246.29,406.01,106.97,7.86">Mining Sequential Patterns</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Srikant</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,372.71,406.01,107.88,7.86;6,146.91,416.97,177.31,7.86">Proceedings of the eleventh international conference on data engineering</title>
		<meeting>the eleventh international conference on data engineering</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,427.71,342.25,7.86;6,146.91,438.67,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,449.63,200.43,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,300.43,427.71,180.16,7.86;6,146.91,438.67,15.57,7.86">Named Entity Resources-Overview and Outlook</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ehrmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Nouvel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rosset</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,182.75,438.67,297.84,7.86;6,146.91,449.63,106.65,7.86">Proceedings of the Tenth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC&apos;16)</title>
		<meeting>the Tenth International Conference on Language Resources and Evaluation (LREC&apos;16)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3349" to="3356" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,460.38,342.24,7.86;6,146.91,471.34,305.20,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ehrmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Romanello</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Flückiger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Clematide</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5281/zenodo.3604227</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3604227" />
		<title level="m" coord="6,385.78,460.38,94.81,7.86;6,146.91,471.34,90.99,7.86">Impresso Named Entity Annotation Guidelines</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-01">Jan 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,482.09,342.24,7.86;6,146.91,493.05,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,504.00,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,514.96,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,525.92,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,536.88,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,547.84,145.82,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,381.73,482.09,98.86,7.86;6,146.91,493.05,286.22,7.86">Overview of CLEF HIPE 2020: Named Entity Recognition and Linking on Historical Newspapers</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ehrmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Romanello</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Flückiger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Clematide</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,345.02,514.96,135.58,7.86;6,146.91,525.92,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,536.88,184.84,7.86">Proceedings of the 11th International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF 2020)</title>
		<title level="s" coord="6,338.70,536.88,141.90,7.86;6,146.91,547.84,24.41,7.86">Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNCS</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Arampatzis</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kanoulas</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tsikrika</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Vrochidis</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Joho</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lioma</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Eickhoff</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Névéol</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cappellato</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the 11th International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF 2020)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12260</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Experimental IR Meets Multilinguality, Multimodality, and Interaction</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,558.59,342.24,7.86;6,146.91,569.55,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,580.51,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,591.47,76.80,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,437.54,558.59,43.05,7.86;6,146.91,569.55,314.89,7.86">Structured and Extended Named Entity Evaluation in Automatic Speech Transcriptions</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Galibert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rosset</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Grouin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Zweigenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Quintard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,146.91,580.51,329.58,7.86">Proceedings of 5th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>5th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="518" to="526" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,602.21,342.25,7.86;6,146.91,613.17,317.37,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,313.90,602.21,166.69,7.86;6,146.91,613.17,22.38,7.86">Pattern Mining for Named Entity Recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Nouvel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Antoine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Friburger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,190.17,613.17,150.52,7.86">Language and Technology Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="226" to="237" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,623.92,342.24,7.86;6,146.91,634.88,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,645.84,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,656.77,325.87,7.89" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,393.75,645.84,86.84,7.86;6,146.91,656.80,73.64,7.86">Scikit-learn: Machine learning in Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Pedregosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Varoquaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gramfort</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Thirion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Grisel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Blondel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Prettenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Weiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Dubourg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vanderplas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Passos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Cournapeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brucher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Perrot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Duchesnay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,228.21,656.80,155.11,7.86">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2825" to="2830" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,119.67,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,130.63,279.43,7.86" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,359.81,119.67,120.78,7.86;7,146.91,130.63,106.07,7.86">Entités nommées structurées : guide d&apos;annotation Quaero</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sophie</forename><surname>Rosset</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Grouin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Cyril</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Zweigenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>2011-04</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>LIMSI-CNRS</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Tech. Rep.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,141.59,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,152.55,186.54,7.86" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,199.35,141.59,240.17,7.86">Probabilistic Part-Of-Speech Tagging using Decision Trees</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Schmid</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,462.93,141.59,17.67,7.86;7,146.91,152.55,126.24,7.86">New methods in language processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">154</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
