<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,144.20,115.96,326.96,12.62;1,239.27,133.89,136.82,12.62">IITH at CLEF 2017: Finding Relevant Tweets for Cultural Events</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,189.45,171.56,89.47,8.74"><forename type="first">Sreekanth</forename><surname>Madisetty</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of CSE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">IIT Hyderabad</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Hyderabad</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,301.62,171.56,124.28,8.74"><forename type="first">Maunendra</forename><surname>Sankar Desarkar</surname></persName>
							<email>maunendra@iith.ac.in</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of CSE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">IIT Hyderabad</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Hyderabad</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,144.20,115.96,326.96,12.62;1,239.27,133.89,136.82,12.62">IITH at CLEF 2017: Finding Relevant Tweets for Cultural Events</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">784B0350FE1CB383AFBD87BE36369808</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:48+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Retrieving relevant tweets corresponding to cultural events can be used in various applications like event reporting, event recommendation, etc. This type of retrieval is challenging due to short length of the tweet, noise, out of vocabulary words, abbreviations in the tweet. In this paper, we focus on the problem of retrieving relevant tweets related to given cultural event of a festival. We consider several factors like BM25, DFR, presence of artist name, relevant hashtag, festival name for finding the relevance of tweets to the event. We apply BM25 + DFR model to retrieve candidate set of tweets related to each event of a festival. We find the top hashtags for each event by exploring meta-attributes of an event. We re-rank the initial rank list from BM25 + DFR based on two strategies, namely, presence of the event meta-attributes (artist name, festival name, title, etc.) and the identified top hashtags in the tweet, and based on the timestamp of the event. We experimented on a subset of CLEF 2017 cultural microblog contextualization dataset. The experimental results show that the proposed method is able to put relevant tweets at the top of the retrieval list.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>There are three tasks in CLEF 2017 microblog cultural contextualization track, namely, content analysis, microblog search, and timeline illustration <ref type="bibr" coords="1,427.77,488.75,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Festivals dataset is provided for all the tasks. There are 70,000,000 microblogs available in the dataset which is collected between May 2015 and October 2016. We focus on task 3, timeline illustration that aims to retrieve all relevant tweets related to each event of a festival provided in the topic queries <ref type="bibr" coords="1,375.18,536.57,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Each topic is related to one cultural event. Here, one event means one occurrence of a show (theater, music, etc.). Same show can be performed on different days of the festival. Each such show is treated as a separate event. Each topic is described by metaattributes such as id, festival name, title, artist (or band), start date, end date, and venue. We apply BM25, BM25 + DFR and several re-ranking methods for retrieving the tweets of cultural events. Re-ranking by event timestamp gives better performance as most of the tweets are posted at few days before, during or after the events scheduled time.</p><p>Rest of the paper is organized as follows: Section 2 describes the problem definition. Next in Section 3, details of the proposed method are presented. Submitted runs for evaluation are described in Section 4. We conclude the work by providing directions for future research in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Problem Definition</head><p>Here we briefly define the problem addressed in this paper: Given an event E of a festival with its meta attributes title, artist name, festival name, start date, end date, and venue, retrieve all relevant tweets related to the event. Such information is useful for attendees of festivals, for people that are interested in knowing what happens in a festival, and for organizers to get feedback <ref type="bibr" coords="2,442.79,234.30,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. Each event is represented as a topic. The following is the example of a topic in the festival. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>&lt;topics&gt;</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>&lt;/topics&gt;</head><p>In the topics dataset provided, the id attribute ranges between 1 to 664, i.e., there are 664 topics in total for this task. The topic given in the above example specifies the live music show given by Anna Calvi in Vielles Charreus 2015 festival without any specific title, the title field is empty. The artist can be a single artist, a list of artist names, orchestra name, as they appear in the official programs of the festivals. The festival labels in the dataset are: charrues for Vielles Charrues 2015, transmusicales for Transmusicales 2015, avignon for Avignon 2016, edinburgh for Edinburgh 2016. Startdate is start date and time of the festival whereas enddate is end date and time of the festival. The venue is a string that corresponds to the name of the event location, given in the official program description.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Methodology</head><p>In this section, we describe our methodology to retrieve relevant tweets for given cultural events. There are three phases involved in our method, preprocessing the tweets, identifying relevant tweets, and re-ranking the tweets. Each of these phases is explained in detail in the following subsections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Pre-processing the tweets</head><p>This is the first phase in our method. The dataset contains 70 million tweets <ref type="bibr" coords="3,467.31,139.81,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. We have observed that discussions about events often happen few days before or after the events scheduled time. So, we filter the dataset based on timestamps of the festival before the indexing step. For an event, while retrieving the relevant tweets, we consider only those tweets that were posted within ±15 days of the event. For example, if a certain event is happening on 15th June then we consider the tweets posted in the month of June. We assume that most of the tweets about this event are posted in this duration only. Although, there are tweets related to this event which are posted beyond this period, they are usually very less. This filtered dataset is used for faster indexing and retrieval of the tweets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Identifying relevant tweets</head><p>This is the second phase in our method. We use two independent strategies to retrieve relevant tweets for a festival.</p><p>BM25: First, we apply BM25 (BM stands for Best Matching) also called as Okapi BM25 <ref type="bibr" coords="3,191.39,353.68,10.52,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref> scoring mechanism to retrieve the tweets related to an event. It is a probabilistic retrieval model. The ranking function used in BM25 is not a single function but a family of scoring functions, with a small change in parameters and components. Content matching to the given query is done by the BM25 algorithm. The ranking function of BM25 is as follows.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,198.92,422.64,277.43,26.35">Score = t∈q log( N df t ). (k 1 + 1)tf td k 1 ((1 -b) + b.( dl avg dl ) + tf td (<label>1</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,476.35,429.38,4.24,8.74">)</formula><p>where N is total number of documents, df t is document frequency of the term, tf td is term frequency in document d, dl is document length, avg dl is the average document length in the whole collection, k 1 is tuning parameter for controlling the scaling of term frequency, and b is tuning parameter for controlling the scaling of document length. We have used k 1 =1.2 and b=0.75 in our experiments.</p><p>BM25+DFR: DFR (DFR stands for Divergence From Randomness) <ref type="bibr" coords="3,450.51,536.39,10.52,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref> is a method in Information Retrieval to retrieve documents related to a given query. There are three building blocks in this model: basic randomness model selection, first normalization, and term frequency normalization.</p><p>The first step in this model is to select basic randomness model to find the weight of a term in the document. Several possible randomness models are Poisson approximation of the binomial, Divergence approximation of the binomial, Bose-Einstein distribution, Geometric approximation of the Bose-Einstein, Inverse term frequency model, Inverse document frequency model, Inverse expected document frequency model <ref type="bibr" coords="3,256.26,644.16,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Next step is to apply the first normalization. If a rare term does not occur in the document, then the probability of that term in the document is zero and is less informative. On the other hand, if a rare term occurred many times in the document then the probability of that term is high and is more informative. The risk component for the term is used in this step similar to <ref type="bibr" coords="4,201.44,154.86,9.96,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. This risk component is multiplied to the weight of the term described in the first step. Some of the first normalization techniques are ratio of two Bernoulli processes <ref type="bibr" coords="4,250.25,178.77,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, Laplace's law of succession <ref type="bibr" coords="4,385.71,178.77,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. The last step is to normalize the term frequencies. Document length is considered for this normalization. The following equation describes the term frequency normalization.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="4,218.63,219.40,261.96,22.31">tf normalized = tf * log(1 + c * avg dl dl )<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where tf normalized is the normalized term frequency, tf is the term frequency, c is a parameter, avg dl is the normalized document length, and dl is the document length. Equation 2 is referred as Normalization 2. BM25 can be calculated using DFR model. So, we use DFR version of BM25 in this method. We call it as BM25 + DFR. The components used in DFR model in our method are Inverse document frequency model for randomness, Laplace succession for the first normalization, and Normalisation 2 for term frequency normalization. The tweet set which is obtained from BM25 + DFR algorithm is denoted by initial rank list. The score obtained after applying BM25 + DFR model is denoted by Score BD . Next, we will apply different re-ranking methods to re-rank the tweets from initial rank list.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Re-ranking</head><p>After pre-processing and identifying relevant tweets, the next phase is to re-rank the identified tweets as described in Section 3.2. The following are the different re-ranking mechanisms that we applied to re-rank the results of initial rank list.</p><p>-Meta-Attributes: The meta-attributes of an event are artist name, festival name, etc. We also come up with a list of top hashtags for each event. Top hashtags are obtained by finding the similarity between meta-attributes and hashtags. This re-ranking strategy checks for the presence of artist name in the tweet, festival name, and one of the top hashtags in the tweet. Frequency is also used along with similarity features. Tweets that are not having any of these features are ignored. For each tweet we compute a meta score as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="4,161.66,558.42,318.92,38.63">Score m (tweet) = δ(tweet contains artist name) + δ(tweet contains festival name) + δ(tweet contains any top hashtag) (3)</formula><p>Here δ is a boolean function that returns 1 if and only if the predicate is true. We re-rank the tweets based on the combined score as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="4,196.59,637.29,284.00,9.65">Score BDM (tweet) = Score BD (tweet) + Score m (tweet)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where Score BD (tweet) is the score obtained by BM25 + DFR model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fig. 1: Modeling Time</head><p>-Time: This method re-ranks the tweets based on the performance time of the event in the festival. We observe that some events are repeated on different days of the festival. In order to differentiate the tweets for repeated events scheduled on different days, the timestamp of the event will be helpful.</p><p>Preference will be given to the tweets whose creation time is close to starting time of the show. Each tweet is assigned a time-based score to an event. If t is the absolute time difference between the event start time and the tweet creation time, then the Score time is computed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="5,257.69,472.56,222.90,23.89">Score time (tweet) = γ t + λ 1 + λ<label>(5)</label></formula><p>In our setting, we put γ = 0.9 and λ = 0.1. The value of Score time (tweet) is ranges between 0 and 1. The graph with different time values is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,197.04,536.57,3.87,8.74">1</ref>. If the absolute time difference between event start time and tweet post time is less, then the time-based score of the tweet will be close to 1. Here, we have taken the time difference in hours. We used this function to suppress the tweets for which the tweet creation time is far away from event time and to give importance to the tweets for which the tweet creation time is close to the event time. We wanted this function to be non-linear in nature. If the time difference is small, then the importance dampens quickly, and after some time it will stabilize to some small but non-zero value. In this way, tweets that are posted far from the event time are still considered if the tweet content appears to be relevant to the event and get a chance to show up in the final ranking. We re-rank the tweets based on the combined score of BM25 + DFR, meta-attributes, and timestamp as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="6,188.68,136.77,291.90,9.65">Score f inal (tweet) = Score BDM (tweet) + Score time (tweet)<label>(6)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>The dataset consists of 70 million microblogs <ref type="bibr" coords="6,331.66,185.94,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Each microblog has the following attributes.</p><p>id: unique id of the microblog from user: author of the tweet (screen name) from userid: unique id of the author iso language code: encoding of the tweet (en, es, fr, pt) source: interface used for posting the tweet (frequent tags: Twitter Web Client iPhone and Twitterfeed clients) profile image url: url of the profile image wday: week day created at: tweet creation date time s: quantitative variable (integer) time ord: quantitative variable (integer) content: tweet content</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Runs Submitted</head><p>We have used Terrier IR platform <ref type="bibr" coords="6,289.70,456.50,10.52,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref> for indexing and retrieval of the tweets. We have submitted the following runs for task 3, timeline illustration, in CLEF 2017 microblog cultural contextualization track.</p><p>-Baseline1: Only BM25 is used in this method.</p><p>-Baseline2: BM25 + DFR combined run to retrieve the top ranked documents from each event of the festival. -Meta Attributes: This run is performed using meta-attributes of the event like artist name, festival name. Top hashtags are also used as described in Section 3.3. -MetaAttributes+Time: This run is performed based on Baseline2 + Meta-Attributes + timestamp of an event as described in Section 3.3.</p><p>The precision results of BM25, BM25 + DFR, Meta Attributes, and MetaA-trributes+Time are shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="6,299.49,608.30,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_0">2</ref>. The number of queries used for evaluation is 35. We observe that Meta Attributes precision values are higher than BM25 and BM25 + DFR models. Precision values of MetaAttributes+Time are greater than all other methods. This shows the importance of selected features, meta-attributes, and timestamp. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>We assume that event to be a pre-planned event that is having context features like title, artist name, festival name, event start date, event end date, and venue. We have employed a method to retrieve relevant tweets for different events as part of time line illustration task, CLEF 2017 microblog cultural contextualization. We have used four different methods in this task. The first method use content matching for retrieving the tweets. The second method is DFR version of BM25. Remaining methods are based on re-ranking the initial rank list. We observe that re-ranking method which combines meta-attributes, and timestamp is performing better. For future work, we would like to see other methods which will further improve the recall.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="7,181.75,359.44,251.86,8.74"><head>Fig. 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2: Precision comparison of different retrieval methods</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,590.58,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,601.54,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,612.50,155.74,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,279.58,590.58,201.00,7.86;7,146.91,601.54,185.89,7.86">Probabilistic models of information retrieval based on measuring the divergence from randomness</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Rijsbergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,340.60,601.54,139.99,7.86;7,146.91,612.50,65.12,7.86">ACM Transactions on Information Systems (TOIS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="357" to="389" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,623.92,342.25,7.86;7,146.91,634.88,333.67,7.86;7,146.91,645.84,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,656.80,62.50,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,464.46,623.92,16.13,7.86;7,146.91,634.88,224.10,7.86">Clef 2017 microblog cultural contextualization lab overview</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ermakova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mothe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mulhem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sanjuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,394.31,634.88,86.28,7.86;7,146.91,645.84,329.46,7.86">International Conference of the Cross-Language Evaluation Forum for European Languages Proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,119.67,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,130.63,84.02,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,192.58,119.67,233.50,7.86">An introduction to probability theory and its applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Feller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,141.59,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,152.55,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,163.51,263.23,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,320.06,141.59,160.52,7.86;8,146.91,152.55,41.07,7.86">Meme-tracking and the dynamics of the news cycle</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leskovec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Backstrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,208.71,152.55,271.88,7.86;8,146.91,163.51,151.66,7.86">Proceedings of the 15th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the 15th ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="497" to="506" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,174.47,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,185.43,306.13,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,377.03,174.47,103.56,7.86;8,146.91,185.43,131.47,7.86">From puppy to maturity: Experiences in developing terrier</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mccreadie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,284.92,185.43,97.48,7.86">Proc. of OSIR at SIGIR</title>
		<meeting>of OSIR at SIGIR</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="63" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,196.39,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,207.34,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,218.30,275.00,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,254.37,196.39,222.65,7.86">A language modeling approach to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ponte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,160.17,207.34,320.42,7.86;8,146.91,218.30,164.19,7.86">Proceedings of the 21st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 21st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="281" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,229.26,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,240.22,242.62,7.86" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,146.91,240.22,60.10,7.86">Okapi at trec-3</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hancock-Beaulieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gatford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,213.75,240.22,110.76,7.86">Nist Special Publication Sp</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">109</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
