<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,142.70,151.67,321.36,12.54;1,222.29,169.07,150.82,12.54">SINAI at ImageCLEF Wikipedia Retrieval task 2011: testing combined systems</title>
				<funder ref="#_YMZzQTU">
					<orgName type="full">Regional Government of Andalucía (Spain)</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_3Z3bvTF #_nRsvpJJ">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_xWT4Vjq">
					<orgName type="full">Spanish Government</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,149.66,207.32,132.11,9.05"><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><surname>Ángel García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">SINAI Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Campus las Lagunillas</addrLine>
									<postCode>A3, 23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,290.09,207.32,115.39,9.05"><forename type="first">Manuel</forename><surname>Carlos Díaz-Galiano</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">SINAI Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Campus las Lagunillas</addrLine>
									<postCode>A3, 23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,413.83,207.32,43.21,9.05;1,223.49,218.84,52.62,9.05"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Alfonso Ureña-López</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">SINAI Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Campus las Lagunillas</addrLine>
									<postCode>A3, 23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,284.21,218.84,84.60,9.05"><forename type="first">Javier</forename><surname>Arias-Buendía</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">SINAI Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Campus las Lagunillas</addrLine>
									<postCode>A3, 23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,142.70,151.67,321.36,12.54;1,222.29,169.07,150.82,12.54">SINAI at ImageCLEF Wikipedia Retrieval task 2011: testing combined systems</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">5032A9877A894FF9453A4D2EE8AEA583</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:26+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Text Retrieval</term>
					<term>Machine Translation</term>
					<term>Indexing</term>
					<term>Retrieved Lists Combination</term>
					<term>IRs Fusion</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Several researches demonstrate that the use and integration of various knowledge sources improves the quality and efficiency of information systems. This paper presents the system developed by the SINAI research group at the ImageCLEF Wikipedia Retrieval task. Using only the English text associated with each image or its translation from French or German, our system applies several combinations of the textual tags and the combination of information retrieval (IR) systems. The influence of machine translation, the use of the different annotation tags and the retrieval results from different IRs systems are the main aims of this work. The obtained results show that the election of the annotation tags and the IR system have influence in the results, and some fusions of the retrieved lists can improve the performance.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The Wikipedia Retrieval task is an ad-hoc image retrieval task. The aim of ImageCLEF Wikipedia Retrieval task is to investigate retrieval approaches with a large and heterogeneous collection of images and their annotations, extracted from Wikipedia<ref type="foot" coords="1,166.46,542.39,3.00,5.45" target="#foot_0">1</ref>  <ref type="bibr" coords="1,171.98,542.65,10.66,9.05" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p><p>In 2011 the collection is the same used in the 2010 ImageCLEF Wikipedia task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,456.58,554.05,10.66,9.05" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, and it is composed by 237,434 Wikipedia images with unstructured and noisy annotations in English, French and German.</p><p>Given an English query as an image, sample images and annotations, our textbased system uses the annotations to find relevant images from the Wikipedia image collection. Several combinations of the results obtained with the annotation labels were tested and the fusion of the results obtained with two IRs systems.</p><p>The remainder of the paper is organized as follows: in the second section the system is described. In Section 3, the experiments and results are presented. Finally, conclusions and further work are shown in Section 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Description of the system</head><p>An image from the Wikipedia collection contains some data, such as the name or the file of this image and annotations data. These annotations contain three optional tags (description, comment and caption) in different languages (English, French and German) also optional. Fig. <ref type="figure" coords="2,239.21,260.87,4.98,9.05" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows an example of an image with metadata from the collection. The queries module (on the right of the figure) works with the queries. The first module preprocesses the query (stopwords removal and stemming), and then the information is run against the indexes, obtaining different lists of retrieved documents. In some cases a fusion module is applied to join the lists from the IR systems. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Annotation document</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Tags combination</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IRs Indexes</head><p>Query processing (stopper, stemmer) Tags Indexes Fig. <ref type="figure" coords="3,153.26,585.01,3.41,8.04">2</ref>. Architecture of the SINAI system.</p><p>Our text-based system uses English as main language and according with the language distribution of the collection, the 237,434 Wikipedia images cannot be used. Some of the do not have annotations or the language is not determined. The following images were used in our experiments:</p><p>-English only: The first module makes the automatic translation for the non-English metadata. For this purpose we used the online machine translator Reverso<ref type="foot" coords="4,400.75,252.81,3.00,5.45" target="#foot_1">2</ref> . Captions and descriptions were translated, and comments were discarded because in previous experiments we concluded that they were not useful. The second module makes a typical text preprocessing (text from caption and description tags). English stopwords removal and the Porter's stemmer <ref type="bibr" coords="4,261.09,299.03,11.90,9.05" target="#b2">[3]</ref> were applied.</p><p>Then, the third module uses two Information Retrieval (IR) systems, Lemur<ref type="foot" coords="4,449.86,310.29,3.00,5.45" target="#foot_2">3</ref> and Lucene <ref type="foot" coords="4,154.22,321.81,3.00,5.45" target="#foot_3">4</ref> . Lucene is a high performance, full-featured text search engine that has shown to be robust in several text retrieval tasks. The Lemur Toolkit is an opensource toolkit designed to facilitate research in language modelling and information retrieval. It supports different automatic indexing strategies and a variety of retrieval models. In both cases the default parameters were used, the Okapi weighting schema for Lemur and automatic feedback was applied.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Combining the lists</head><p>We have implemented two simple methods to combine the lists of relevant documents retrieved by the IR or IRs systems.</p><p>The first method is the combination of the lists for each annotation tag. The baseline experiments were run using only the description and caption tags. The results of these experiments were two lists of relevant documents for each IR system used. In a second step we used a simple technique to merge these lists <ref type="bibr" coords="4,384.19,504.49,10.90,9.05" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="4,395.09,504.49,7.27,9.05" target="#b5">6]</ref>. The method is simple; first, we have normalized the relevant values of each list; then, we applied different weighting percentages to each partial list and finally we have merged them into one final list re-ranking the new relevance obtained. The different combinations are showed in the following list:</p><p>-The use of the description tag only -10% of caption and 90% of description -20% of caption and 80% of description -….. -80% of caption and 20% of description -90% of caption and 10% of description -The use of the caption tag only All these combinations were indexed with Lucene and Lemur separately and then the queries were run against each index. We made previous experiments with the ImageCLEF Wikipedia Retrieval 2010 framework (non-official results) and the best results were obtained with the combination 80% of caption and 20% of description. The next section shows these experiments and results.</p><p>The second method fusion the lists of relevant documents obtained the IRs systems used. Lucene and Lemur results were combined for each query, with different weights for each list, as it was explained in the previous paragraph. Based on the experiments made with the 2010 framework, the results show that Lemur works better than Lucene. The best combined result was obtained with the fusion 90% of Lemur and a 10% of Lucene, although the improvement over the Lemur global result was not significant. The next section shows also these experiments and results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiment description and results</head><p>This section describes some previous experiments made in the ImageCLEF Wikipedia framework that were the base of the system developed. The previous results are not shown completely due to the amount of them.</p><p>As it was described previously, the dataset used contains 140,653 English annotations and 88,398 non-English annotations translated (229,051 in total). The complete collection contains 237,434 Wikipedia images, so we used a 96% of the total collection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Previous experiments</head><p>Some previous experiments were run with the 2010 framework (the same collection and 70 different queries). These experiments were evaluated using the relevance judgments delivered. The main aims were to test the best combination of tags (caption, description and comments) and the improvement of results with a simple fusion of lists of relevant documents delivered by the IR systems Lemur and Lucene.</p><p>The following experiments were made (with Reverso as automatic translator):</p><p>- The best textual run in 2010 was submitted by XRCE with a MAP of 0.2361 <ref type="bibr" coords="6,445.13,545.65,10.73,9.05" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p><p>After the analysis of these results we extracted the following conclusions: -Lemur with feedback works better than Lucene.</p><p>-Caption tag works well. Description tag decreases the results. The joined use of caption and description tags improves the baseline results and also a percentage combination of both tags. -The combination of both IR systems with caption and description tags improves a bit the textual result. We analyzed some features of the queries such as the number of words of the query and the relevant documents obtained with each IR system, and some features of the retrieved list of relevant documents such as the RSV (Retrieval Status Value).</p><p>After this analysis we concluded that these features cannot determine the use of one or another IR system or the use of each tag or its combination.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Results with the 2011 framework.</head><p>Based on the previous results shown we run six experiments with the 2011 framework to test some features of our system. These six official runs are the following:</p><p>- The best result was obtained with the combination of IR systems, using caption and description tags but the improvement over the use of Lemur with caption and description tags is not significant. Some conclusions of these official results are the following:</p><p>-Lemur improves Lucene in all the experiments.</p><p>-Caption tag introduces almost the complete relevant documents, and description tag does not introduce some relevant documents. -The combination of tags improves the results.</p><p>-The fusion of lists of relevant documents retrieved by the IR systems improves only a bit the MAP result.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions and further work</head><p>In this paper we present the experiments and results obtained with our system developed for the ImageCLEF Wikipedia retrieval environment. We tested some techniques with the 2010 framework, applying them to the official runs in 2011.</p><p>In this participation we have tested some textual features such as different IR systems, the importance of the annotation labels and some simple fusion methods to combine these labels and the lists of relevant documents retrieved.</p><p>Our results show that the IR systems do not obtain the same results, some labels are more important than others and the combination of them improves the final results.</p><p>As further work we want to analyze in depth the results obtained, queries grouped by topics, by length, etc. We will also test the influence of the translation with different automatic translators. An important future aim will be to train a machine learning system with relevant features that decide what to apply to improve the results (combination of IR systems, external knowledge or the annotations from the different tags).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,124.82,517.27,265.46,8.18;2,136.20,293.15,345.85,211.70"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Example of image from the Wikipedia collection and its metadata.</figDesc><graphic coords="2,136.20,293.15,345.85,211.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,160.82,546.85,309.84,135.56"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Lemur with Okapi and feedback. Caption label. -Exp6: Lemur with Okapi and feedback. Description label. -Exp7: Lemur with Okapi and feedback. Caption and description labels. -Exp8: Lemur with Okapi and feedback. 80% Caption and 20% description labels. -Exp9-Best combination: 90% Lemur with Okapi and feedback and 10%Lucene without feedback. Caption and description labels. All the results are evaluated using the Mean Average Precision (MAP) function. Last column shows the improvement or decrement in percentage of each MAP result over the baseline case with Lucene and Lemur. Some results obtained with the 2010 framework.</figDesc><table coords="5,160.82,546.85,309.84,135.56"><row><cell>Lucene IR system and different combinations of caption and description</cell></row><row><cell>tags:</cell></row><row><cell>o caption tag</cell></row><row><cell>o description tag</cell></row><row><cell>o caption + description tags</cell></row><row><cell>o 10% of caption + 90% of description</cell></row><row><cell>o ….</cell></row><row><cell>o 90% of caption + 10% of description</cell></row><row><cell>-Lemur IR system with caption and different weighting functions (Okapi</cell></row><row><cell>with feedback, kl divergence and kl divergence with feedback).</cell></row><row><cell>-Lemur IR system with Okapi and feedback and the same combinations</cell></row><row><cell>of caption and description tags explained before.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="7,124.82,239.96,345.64,210.50"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Lemur with Okapi and feedback. Caption and description labels. -Exp6: 90% Lemur with Okapi and feedback and 10% Lucene without feedback. Caption and description labels. Table2shows the official runs and results for Image Wikipedia retrieval 2011. Official runs and results for Image Wikipedia retrieval 2011.</figDesc><table coords="7,160.82,239.96,309.64,210.50"><row><cell>Exp1: Lucene without feedback. Caption label.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">-Exp2: Lemur with Okapi and feedback. Caption label.</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">-Exp3: Lucene without feedback. Caption and description labels.</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">-Exp4: Lucene without feedback. 80% Caption and 20% description</cell></row><row><cell>labels.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>-Exp5: Experiment</cell><cell>MAP</cell></row><row><cell>Exp1</cell><cell>0.1496</cell></row><row><cell>Exp2</cell><cell>0.1732</cell></row><row><cell>Exp3</cell><cell>0.1200</cell></row><row><cell>Exp4</cell><cell>0.1618</cell></row><row><cell>Exp5</cell><cell>0.2052</cell></row><row><cell>Exp6</cell><cell>0.2068</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,130.10,686.14,141.41,8.18"><p>Available at http://www.wikipedia.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="4,130.10,665.14,131.46,8.18"><p>Available at http://www.reverso.net/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="4,130.10,675.70,151.90,8.18"><p>Available at http://www.lemurproject.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_3" coords="4,130.10,686.14,134.91,8.18"><p>Available at http://lucene.apache.org/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>Acknowledgments. This work has been supported by the <rs type="funder">Regional Government of Andalucía (Spain)</rs> under excellence project <rs type="projectName">GeOasis</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">P08-41999</rs>), the <rs type="funder">Spanish Government</rs> under project <rs type="grantNumber">TEXT-COOL 2.0</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">TIN2009-13391-C04-02</rs>) and the local project <rs type="grantNumber">RFC/UJA2009/12/14</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_YMZzQTU">
					<idno type="grant-number">P08-41999</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">GeOasis</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_xWT4Vjq">
					<idno type="grant-number">TEXT-COOL 2.0</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_3Z3bvTF">
					<idno type="grant-number">TIN2009-13391-C04-02</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_nRsvpJJ">
					<idno type="grant-number">RFC/UJA2009/12/14</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="8,128.23,398.69,342.32,8.18;8,136.22,409.01,329.95,8.18" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,318.07,398.69,152.48,8.18;8,136.22,409.01,88.44,8.18">Overview of the wikipedia image retrieval task at ImageCLEF 2011</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Theodora</forename><surname>Tsikrika</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Adrian</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jana</forename><surname>Kludas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,231.02,409.01,94.29,8.18">CLEF 2011 working notes</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam, The Netherlands</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,128.23,419.35,342.35,8.18;8,136.22,429.67,264.86,8.18" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,262.83,419.35,207.75,8.18;8,136.22,429.67,62.93,8.18">Kludas Overview of the Wikipedia Retrieval Task at ImageCLEF 2010</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tsikrika</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,215.21,429.67,155.10,8.18">CLEF (Notebook Papers/LABs/Workshops</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,128.23,440.11,342.08,8.18;8,136.22,450.43,113.87,8.18" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,186.90,440.11,119.65,8.18">An algorithm for suffix stripping</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,323.29,440.11,120.37,8.18">Readings in information retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="316" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,128.22,460.75,342.40,8.18;8,136.22,471.07,334.30,8.18;8,136.22,481.51,334.58,8.18;8,136.22,491.83,185.90,8.18" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,298.61,471.07,171.91,8.18;8,136.22,481.51,301.83,8.18">XRCE&apos;s Participation in Wikipedia Retrieval, Medical Image Modality Classification and Ad-hoc Retrieval Tasks of ImageCLEF</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Stéphane</forename><surname>Clinchant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gabriela</forename><surname>Csurka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Julien</forename><surname>Ah-Pine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Guillaume</forename><surname>Jacquet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Florent</forename><surname>Perronnin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jorge</forename><surname>Sánchez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Keyvan</forename><surname>Minoukadeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,136.22,491.83,155.21,8.18">CLEF (Notebook Papers/LABs/Workshops</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010. 2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,128.22,502.15,342.64,8.18;8,136.22,512.47,334.29,8.18;8,136.22,522.91,334.65,8.18;8,136.22,533.23,302.40,8.18" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,274.85,512.47,195.66,8.18;8,136.22,522.91,126.14,8.18">Knowledge integration using textual information for improving ImageCLEF collections</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Manuel</forename><surname>Carlos Díaz-Galiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><surname>Angel García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">María</forename><surname>Teresa Martín-Valdivia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Arturo</forename><surname>Montejo-Ráez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-642-15181-1_16</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,279.62,522.91,63.66,8.18">ImageCLEF book</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="295" to="313" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,128.22,543.55,342.49,8.18;8,136.22,553.87,334.32,8.18;8,136.22,564.31,334.62,8.18;8,136.22,574.63,139.08,8.18" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,136.22,553.87,334.32,8.18;8,136.22,564.31,41.55,8.18">Improving Performance of Medical Images Retrieval by Combining Textual and Visual Information</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Díaz-Galiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Martín-Valdivia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Montejo-Ráez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ureña-Lopez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/MICAI.2007.12</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,193.97,564.31,140.44,8.18">Artificial Intelligence -Special Session</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007. 2007. 2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="185" to="192" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
