<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,146.82,115.96,321.72,12.62;1,238.87,133.89,137.62,12.62">Automatic classification of coral images using colour and textures</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,173.34,171.68,101.01,8.74"><forename type="first">Cristina</forename><forename type="middle">M R</forename><surname>Caridade</surname></persName>
							<email>caridade@isec.pt</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Coimbra Polytechnic -ISEC</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Coimbra</settlement>
									<country key="PT">Portugal</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,393.42,171.68,44.00,8.74;1,245.35,183.63,28.25,8.74"><forename type="first">André</forename><forename type="middle">R S</forename><surname>Marcal</surname></persName>
							<email>andre.marcal@fc.up.pt</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Faculdade de Ciências</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade do Porto</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="PT">Portugal</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,146.82,115.96,321.72,12.62;1,238.87,133.89,137.62,12.62">Automatic classification of coral images using colour and textures</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">30B4336F126A2BBD0153640C1DD10728</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:57+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Image classification</term>
					<term>classification methods</term>
					<term>image processing</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The purpose of this work is to address the imageCLEF 2019 coral challenge -to develop a system for the detection and identification of substrates in coral images. Initially a revision of the 13 classes was carried out by identifying a number of sub-classes for some substrates. Four features were considered -3 related to greyscale intensity (1) and texture (2), and 1 related to the colour content. The Breiman's Random forest algorithm was used to classify the corals in one of 13 classes defined. A classification accuracy of about 49% was obtained.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="11" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Coral reefs are large underwater structures composed of the skeletons of colonial marine invertebrates called coral. The coral species that build reefs are known as hermatypic, or "hard," corals because they extract calcium carbonate from seawater to create a hard, durable exoskeleton that protects their soft, sac-like bodies. Other species of corals that are not involved in reef building are known as "soft" corals. These types of corals are flexible organisms often resembling plants and trees and include species such as sea fans and sea whips, according to the Coral Reef Alliance (CORAL), a non-profit environmental organization <ref type="bibr" coords="1,466.82,531.35,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p><p>Coral reefs support immense biodiversity and provide important ecosystem services to many millions of people, yet they are degrading rapidly in response to numerous anthropogenic drivers <ref type="bibr" coords="1,288.51,567.33,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. In fact, coral reefs are in danger of being lost within the next 30 years, and with them the ecosystems they support <ref type="bibr" coords="1,467.31,579.29,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. This catastrophe will not only see the extinction of many marine species, but also create a humanitarian crisis on a global scale for those who rely on reef services. By monitoring the changes and composition of coral reefs conservation efforts can be better implemented and prioritised <ref type="bibr" coords="2,363.42,118.99,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. The imageCLEF 2019 initiative addresses this issue, by proposing a challenge based on the detection and identification of substrates in coral images. The aim is to define a set of bounding boxes around the substrates found, and to make the identification of the classes to which they belong <ref type="bibr" coords="2,278.56,166.81,10.52,8.74" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,290.74,166.81,7.01,8.74" target="#b4">5]</ref>.</p><p>In this paper, we propose to solve this challenge using a fully automatic process to identify coral substrates in digital images. The method developed uses colour and texture to identify regions of interest and, using the Breiman's Random forest algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="2,248.22,214.74,10.52,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref> to classify a coral in one of 13 classes. The digital images used in this study are 3024 × 4032 pixels, in RGB (Red, Green and Blue) format.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Data</head><p>The data for the ImageCLEF2019 Coral task originates from a growing, largescale collection of images taken from coral reefs around the world as part of a coral reef monitoring project with the Marine Technology Research Unit at the University of Essex <ref type="bibr" coords="2,220.47,331.35,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Substrates of the same type can have very different morphologies, color variation and patterns. Some of the images contain a white line (scientific measurement tape) that may occlude part of the entity. The quality of the images is variable, some are blurry, and some have poor color balance. This is representative of the Marine Technology Research Unit dataset and all images are useful for data analysis. The images contain annotations of the following 13 types of substrates: Hard Coral -Branching, Hard Coral -Submassive, Hard Coral -Boulder, Hard Coral -Encrusting, Hard Coral -Table, Hard Coral -Foliose, Hard Coral -Mushroom, Soft Coral, Soft Coral -Gorgonian, Sponge, Sponge -Barrel, Fire Coral -Millepora and Algae -Macro or Leaves <ref type="bibr" coords="2,446.67,438.94,10.52,8.74" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,458.85,438.94,7.00,8.74" target="#b3">4]</ref>. A more detailed description of the dataset is presented in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,378.05,450.90,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p><p>The training set contains 240 images with 6430 substrates annotated. Two files are provided with ground truth annotations:</p><p>one based on bounding boxes "imageCLEFcoral2019 annotations training task 1" and a more detailed annotation based on bounding polygon "imageCLEFcoral2019 annotations training task 2".</p><p>The test set contains 200 images <ref type="bibr" coords="2,280.27,551.46,10.52,8.74" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,292.45,551.46,7.01,8.74" target="#b3">4]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Methodology</head><p>The methodology proposed to detected and identify substrates in coral images is presented schematically in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,295.09,620.25,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. In a first phase, the training images are processed, and the regions that define each coral substrates are identified (Coral substrates). Then, the features of each of these substrates (Coral features) are used to train the classifier (Classification). In a second phase, the classifier is applied to the test images, thus obtaining images of classified corals. These images are post-processed and their corals (Connected components) are identified, a text file with the relevant information is produced. The 13 types of substrates were identified in the 240 training images. A total of 6430 substrates annotations are availably, as listed in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,408.65,394.63,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref> and illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,180.22,406.59,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. A colour is assigned for each substrate, presented in the second column of Table <ref type="table" coords="3,208.22,418.54,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. The number of occurrences of each substrate in the training images is presented in the third column of Table <ref type="table" coords="3,349.46,430.50,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,181.43,443.22,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_1">2</ref> shows two training images and the number and type of substrates identified in these images. On the image on the left (2018 0714 11244 018), the following substrates were identified: "hard coral branching" (4 times), "hard coral boulder" (2 times), "hard coral encrusting" (3 times), "soft coral" (8 times), "sponge" (7 times), "sponge barrel" (1 time) and "algae macro or leaves" (3 times). For image 2018 0729 112525 048 (right): "hard coral branching" (4 times), "hard coral boulder" (4 times), "hard coral encrusting" (2 times), "soft coral" (11 times) and "sponge barrel" (1 time).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Coral substrates</head><p>By visual observation of several training images, it was verified that within the same substrate there are different types of corals, both in shape, colour and texture. Therefore, within each substrate different types (sub-classes) were identified. Another difficulty in the analysis of these images is the overlapping of the substrates identified in the training image. For example, in the left image of Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,179.24,644.16,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_1">2</ref>, the substrate "sponge" (number 11 in green) is inside the region defined by the substrate "hard coral boulder" (number 0 in pink).  Table <ref type="table" coords="4,176.62,534.01,4.98,8.74">2</ref> shows different types of corals identified in each substrate. The types of corals defined in this table are due to the different textures and shapes that each one presents. For example, in the hard coral branching (first line) two different types were identified and in the soft coral (line 7) six types because the latter substrate has a huge variety of types. This procedure was performed visually by the observation of different images with different types of substrates.</p><p>For each type of coral in each substrate, several replicates were identified in different training images by manual process. These replicates were identified, where possible, so that the substrate would fill the entire region defined. In the type of corals that appear more frequently more replicates were identified than in others.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="5,223.40,115.91,4.13,7.89">2</ref>. The type of corals defined for each substrates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Coral features</head><p>When we look at the coral images we find that they have different colours from green, blue, red, orange, brown and white. However, these colours are not unique identifiers of a substrate. The textures are also present on the substrates. Some corals are harder, rugged, sharper, and others smoother and softer. Hue is also a relevant characteristic of substrates.</p><p>With the replicates identified, the 4 most relevant features (by empirical way) were calculated, in a 5x5 neighbourhood of each pixel: mean (M), standard deviation (STD), entropy (E) of grayscale image and hue ratio (HR). The mean and the standard deviation of the neighbourhood identify the spatial arrangement of intensities in a selected region of an image and are represented in Equation <ref type="formula" coords="5,475.61,656.12,4.98,8.74" target="#formula_0">1</ref>and Equation 2 respectively. This is</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="6,285.87,152.40,194.72,22.31">M = p N<label>(1)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="6,262.19,188.85,214.16,23.15">ST D = (p -M ) 2 N -1 , (<label>2</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="6,476.35,196.42,4.24,8.74">)</formula><p>where p is the intensity of the pixels and N is the neighbourhood size. The Entropy is a statistical measure of randomness that can be used to characterize the image texture. Entropy (Equation <ref type="formula" coords="6,303.63,243.00,4.43,8.74" target="#formula_3">3</ref>) is defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="6,260.70,267.94,215.65,10.59">E = - p * log 2 (p), (<label>3</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="6,476.35,267.94,4.24,8.74">)</formula><p>where p is the intensity of the pixels.</p><p>The RGB image is converted to the HSV (Hue, Saturation, Value) colour model. Only values of Hue (H) below 0.34 or above 0.73 are considered for this feature. This threshold values were obtained by visual inspection of the training images. After that, the Hue ratio (HR) in equation 4 is calculated by dividing the number of pixels belonging to the range (H &lt; 0.34 or H &gt; 0.73) over the total number of pixels in the neighbourhood region.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>HR =</head><p>#pixels(H &lt; 0.34 or H &gt; 0.73) #pixels .</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="6,177.70,412.20,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_1">3</ref> shows the type of corals defined for each substrate, the number of replicates identified in each type and their features (mean, standard deviation, entropy and hue ratio). In hard coral branching substrate the first and second types was defined by 24 replicates while in algae macro or leaves substrate only 8 replicates are defined for the types.</p><p>The features are elements of each type that identify it individually in relation to the other types. With these elements it is intended to characterize each type in a unique way. In Figure <ref type="figure" coords="6,251.31,496.14,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_2">3</ref> it is possible to observe the features of a test image (2018 0712 073252 024). In the first line we can observe the original image (a) on the left, the average image (b) in the center and the standard deviation (c) on the right. In the second line the entropy (d) on the center and hue ratio of the image (e) on the right.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Classification method</head><p>Using Classification learner app available in MATLAB <ref type="bibr" coords="6,385.82,596.34,10.52,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref> environment, it is possible to classify the training coral image using various algorithms and compare the results in the same environment. After training multiple models, they were compared, based on validation errors. The classification models available in this app are: decision trees, discriminant analysis, Support Vector Machines (SVM), logistic regression, nearest neighbors, and ensemble classification. With the data  described previously and the 4 features used, the best model was Random Forest which obtained a classification accuracy score of about 49%.</p><p>Random Forest consists of a collection of classifiers based on decision trees in which each tree gives rise to a vote for the output forecast. Random Forest produces a model consisting of n decision trees (ensemble), where each tree is based on a number of randomly selected instances of the training set. Each node of each tree is constructed from a random subset of the attributes. Upon receiving a test instance each tree will decide (vote) on which class it belongs to. The most voted class will be the class provided by the model. The most widely reported Random Forest algorithm is the Breiman algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="8,403.34,202.68,9.96,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref>.</p><p>The application of Random Forest pixel to pixel classifier in a test image with 3024 x 4032 pixels has a large computational weight since 4 matrices of 3024 x 4032 are constructed for the 4 features of each image pixel and another matrix with same size with confidence values. On the other hand, as it was necessary to classify 200 test images, the initial images were reduced by a factor of 4, so that the processing became faster.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Connected components</head><p>After classification it is necessary to find connected components of pixels belonging to the same substrate (area). As the areas of the substrates already identified in the training image are greater than 43,865 pixels, then in the classification of the test images, only areas with more than 500 (20 percent of one sixteenth of the average size of the substrates -20%(43, 865/16) ≈ 500) pixels will be validated as substrate areas if the confidence valuer is greater than or equal to 0.5. With the regions identified in the images it is necessary to collect information about the image and class to which they belong, the degree of confidence of this classification and the position in the image of the bounding box that surrounds it (x minimum, y minimum, width and height). Finally, this information is placed in a text file as follows:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>The 200 test images were processed according to the methodology described in section 3. Figures <ref type="figure" coords="8,212.47,572.43,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_3">4</ref> and<ref type="figure" coords="8,238.82,572.43,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_4">5</ref> show the results obtained for two different test images.</p><p>In Figure <ref type="figure" coords="8,195.56,584.39,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_3">4</ref> the results for the image 2018 0712 073252 024 and in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="8,134.77,596.34,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_4">5</ref> for the image 2018 0712 073534 067. The original image (a) and the classified image (b) and (c) where the pixels are identified within a substrate. The black pixels are not classified one of the following situations: substrate areas or confidence valuer (see section 3.4). The coral identified (d) with only the coral substrates presents in the test image. The colour shown in the images correspond to the colours identified for each substrate in the table 1. In the case of  Figure <ref type="figure" coords="10,166.12,118.99,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_3">4</ref>, the substrates identified are: "soft coral" (light blue), "sponge barrel" (red), "sponge" (light green), "hard coral encrusting" (dark blue), "hard coral boulder" (pink) and hard coral mushroom" (white). With this classification obtained, the relevant information is exported to a text file. An example (for image 2018 0712 073252 024) is presented in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="10,335.12,166.81,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_5">6</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>The methodology developed allows to identify substrates of different classes in digital images of corals. The preliminary results are not very favourable, but there are many potential improvements that can be implemented. The most promising lines of work forward would be to focus on a better identification of sub-classes, and the use of additional features related to both colour and texture.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,213.75,347.36,187.85,7.89;3,137.60,175.86,340.16,156.73"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Diagram of the proposed methodology.</figDesc><graphic coords="3,137.60,175.86,340.16,156.73" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,134.77,485.96,345.82,7.89;4,134.77,496.94,22.04,7.86;4,134.77,338.26,172.91,132.92"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. Training images with bounding box of the substrates annotated in the respective color.</figDesc><graphic coords="4,134.77,338.26,172.91,132.92" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="7,134.77,600.86,345.82,7.89;7,134.77,611.85,86.30,7.86;7,256.65,495.11,102.04,79.97"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3. : Original image (a) and its features: mean (b), standard deviation (c), entropy (d) and hue ratio (e).</figDesc><graphic coords="7,256.65,495.11,102.04,79.97" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="9,134.77,366.19,345.82,7.89;9,134.77,377.17,110.36,7.86;9,311.20,397.56,128.96,100.56"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4. : Original image (a), classified image in gray (b) and color (c) representation and the coral identified (c).</figDesc><graphic coords="9,311.20,397.56,128.96,100.56" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="9,134.77,641.55,345.82,7.89;9,134.77,652.53,110.36,7.86;9,309.50,512.64,132.38,103.12"><head>Fig. 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Fig. 5. : Original image (a), classified image in gray (b) and color (c) representation and the coral identified (c).</figDesc><graphic coords="9,309.50,512.64,132.38,103.12" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5" coords="10,231.96,321.35,151.43,7.89;10,194.29,198.92,226.77,107.66"><head>Fig. 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Fig. 6. : Line information in text file.</figDesc><graphic coords="10,194.29,198.92,226.77,107.66" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,205.55,115.91,204.26,7.89"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Substrates annotated in training images.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="7,216.93,115.91,181.50,7.89"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Features valuers for the substrates.</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="10,138.35,503.11,342.24,7.86;10,146.91,514.07,333.67,7.86;10,146.91,525.02,333.68,7.86;10,146.91,535.98,166.74,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Chamberlain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Antonio</forename><surname>Campello</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jessica</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Louis</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Clift</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Adrian</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alba</forename><surname>García</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Seco</forename><surname>De Herrera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2380/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,313.64,514.07,166.95,7.86;10,146.91,525.02,104.69,7.86">Overview of ImageCLEFcoral 2019 Task, CLEF 2019 working notes</title>
		<title level="s" coord="10,258.90,525.02,170.76,7.86">CEUR Workshop Proceedings (CEUR-WS</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,138.35,547.01,342.24,7.86;10,146.91,557.97,333.68,7.86;10,146.91,568.93,333.68,7.86;10,146.91,579.89,194.19,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,282.89,568.93,129.79,7.86">Coral reefs in the Anthropocene</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Hughes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Barnes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bellwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Cinner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Cumming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B C</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kleypas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Van De Leemput</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Morrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Palumbi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Van Nes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Scheffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nature22901</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="10,420.88,568.93,36.20,7.86">NATURE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">546</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7656</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="82" to="90" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,138.35,590.91,342.24,7.86;10,146.91,601.87,41.72,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Lifescience</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.livescience.com/40276-coral-reefs.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-05-22">22 May 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,138.35,612.90,342.24,7.86;10,146.91,623.85,41.72,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="https://www.imageclef.org/2019/coral" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="10,146.91,612.90,68.50,7.86">ImageCLEFcoral</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-05-23">2019. 23 May 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,138.35,634.88,342.24,7.86;10,146.91,645.84,333.68,7.86;10,146.91,656.80,333.68,7.86;11,146.91,119.67,333.67,7.86;11,146.91,130.63,333.68,7.86;11,146.91,141.59,333.68,7.86;11,146.91,152.55,333.68,7.86;11,146.91,163.51,333.68,7.86;11,146.91,174.47,333.68,7.86;11,146.91,185.43,333.68,7.86;11,146.91,196.39,333.68,7.86;11,146.91,207.34,135.23,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="11,192.03,163.51,49.02,7.86;11,270.86,163.51,209.73,7.86;11,146.91,174.47,333.68,7.86;11,146.91,185.43,42.73,7.86">Multimedia Retrieval in Medicine, Lifelogging, Security and Nature In: Experimental IR Meets Multilinguality, Multimodality, and Interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bogdan</forename><surname>Ionescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Renaud</forename><surname>Péteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Yashin</forename><surname>Dicente Cid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Vitali</forename><surname>Liauchuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Vassili</forename><surname>Kovalev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Dzmitri</forename><surname>Klimuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Aleh</forename><surname>Tarasau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Asma</forename><surname>Ben Abacha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sadid</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Vivek</forename><surname>Datla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Joey</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Dina</forename><surname>Demner-Fushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Duc-Tien</forename><surname>Dang-Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Luca</forename><surname>Piras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Riegler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Minh-Triet</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mathias</forename><surname>Lux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Cathal</forename><surname>Gurrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Obioma</forename><surname>Pelka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Christoph</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Friedrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alba</forename><surname>García Seco De Herrera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Narciso</forename><surname>Garcia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ergina</forename><surname>Kavallieratou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Carlos</forename><surname>Roberto Del Blanco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Carlos</forename><surname>Cuevas Rodríguez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nikos</forename><surname>Vasillopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Konstantinos</forename><surname>Karampidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Chamberlain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Adrian</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Antonio</forename><surname>Campello</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="11,196.12,185.43,284.47,7.86;11,146.91,196.39,69.70,7.86">Proceedings of the 10th International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF 2019)</title>
		<title level="s" coord="11,310.38,196.39,166.24,7.86">LNCS Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<meeting>the 10th International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF 2019)<address><addrLine>Lugano, Switzerland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019-09-09">2019. September 09-12 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>ImageCLEF</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="11,138.35,218.30,283.67,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="11,200.70,218.30,61.96,7.86">Random forests</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Breiman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="11,269.30,218.30,70.67,7.86">Machine Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="11,138.35,229.26,332.58,7.86" xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Matlab R</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<publisher>The MathWorks, Inc</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Natick, Massachusetts, United States</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
