<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,160.64,115.96,294.08,12.62;1,225.76,133.89,163.83,12.62">ECNU at 2016 eHealth Task 1: Handover Information Extraction</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,147.20,171.58,46.49,8.74"><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
							<email>ysong@ica.stc.sh.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Shanghai Key Laboratory of Multidimensional Information Processing</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science &amp; Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">East China Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>200241</postCode>
									<settlement>Shanghai</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,210.59,171.58,32.93,8.74"><forename type="first">Yun</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Shanghai Key Laboratory of Multidimensional Information Processing</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science &amp; Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">East China Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>200241</postCode>
									<settlement>Shanghai</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,260.41,171.58,51.62,8.74"><forename type="first">Hongyu</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Shanghai Key Laboratory of Multidimensional Information Processing</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science &amp; Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">East China Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>200241</postCode>
									<settlement>Shanghai</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,328.92,171.58,59.78,8.74"><forename type="first">Yueyao</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>yywang@ica.stc.sh.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Shanghai Key Laboratory of Multidimensional Information Processing</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science &amp; Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">East China Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>200241</postCode>
									<settlement>Shanghai</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,405.59,171.58,48.99,8.74"><forename type="first">Qinmin</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
							<email>qmhu@cs.ecnu.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Shanghai Key Laboratory of Multidimensional Information Processing</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science &amp; Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">East China Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>200241</postCode>
									<settlement>Shanghai</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,238.31,183.54,39.71,8.74"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,314.29,183.54,51.95,8.74"><forename type="first">Guihua</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Shanghai Key Laboratory of Multidimensional Information Processing</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science &amp; Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">East China Normal University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>200241</postCode>
									<settlement>Shanghai</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Science and Technology Commission</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Shanghai Municipality</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Shanghai Digital Trade Co. Ltd</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>200241</postCode>
									<settlement>Shanghai</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,160.64,115.96,294.08,12.62;1,225.76,133.89,163.83,12.62">ECNU at 2016 eHealth Task 1: Handover Information Extraction</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">565D0466B79174388448EC772E562D64</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:45+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Conditional Random Field</term>
					<term>Association Rule</term>
					<term>MetaMap</term>
					<term>Information Extraction</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The CLEF eHealth 2016 Task 1 is set to automatically assign pre-defined medical tag to each word in the patient case records. The difficulty of the task is that many classes have little training data. This paper presents our work on the 2016 CLEF eHealth Task 1. In particular, we propose an optimized Conditional Random Field algorithm to better fulfill the task. We also utilize the information extracted through association rules and MetaMap to boost the performance of our results. The evaluation results show our runs outperform the four official baselines in this difficulty task.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>CLEF eHealth 2016 Task 1 addresses clinical information extraction, related to Australian nursing shift change <ref type="bibr" coords="1,263.93,524.56,24.65,8.74">[1][2]</ref>. This extends the 2015 task 1a of converting verbal nursing handover to written free-text records. In 2016, our participants are challenged to maximize the correctness in structuring these written freetext records by pre-filling a handover form by automatically identifying relevant text-snippets for each slot of the form.</p><p>The data set utilized in this task is called NICTA Synthetic Nursing Handover Data In this task, the organizers provide us with 36 tags which are related to the categories of Patient Introduction, My Shift, Appointments, Medication and Future Case in the handover form. We are asked to assign one of the 36 tags to each word in the patient case records. The 36 tags are summarized in table <ref type="table" coords="2,466.38,130.95,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. Our system architecture is proposed in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,347.57,560.48,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_1">1</ref>. We mainly utilize the Conditional Random Field (CRF) model to achieve the results <ref type="bibr" coords="2,382.44,572.43,10.20,8.74" target="#b3">[6]</ref> <ref type="bibr" coords="2,392.64,572.43,10.20,8.74" target="#b4">[7]</ref>. To better satisfy the assignment, we design strategy to automatically select features to train different tags. Furthermore, we use association rules <ref type="bibr" coords="2,350.14,596.34,10.52,8.74" target="#b5">[8]</ref>[9] to extract information of patient name, age, gender, room number, bed number and doctor name to enhance our outputs. At last, we apply MetaMap to recognize the Unified Medical Language System (UMLS) concepts in the patient case records. The MetaMap tags are utilized as the supplement to decide which word should have the tag of Medication Medicine. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">CRF Model Training</head><p>The organizers provide us with 17 features for each word in the health care records, which are listed in table 2 <ref type="bibr" coords="3,284.71,433.95,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[5]</ref>. All of these features are relevant to the 36 health care information tags. We intent to utilize CRF model to implement the labeling task. However, different feature set have different precision and recall rate. We are motivated to solve this problem by select the proper feature set for each tag to train the CRF model.</p><p>Suppose A = {f i }, i = 1, 2, ..., 17 is the feature set which contains the whole 17 features, and B is the feature set which contains features should be removed from A. For a tag, such as PatientIntroduction CarePlan, we utilize the following method to discover its suitable feature set for the CRF model training. Denote C as the suitable feature set for the PatientIntroduction CarePlan tag.</p><p>-Utilizing feature set A to train CRF model in data set 1, and using data set 2 to test the model. denote the precision of PatientIntroduction CarePlan as p.  -The suitable set C = A -B. This means that the features in the set B will decrease the precision and ought to be removed from the features collection.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,140.99,596.69,196.54,9.68">-∀f i ∈ A, i = 1, 2, ..., 17, remove f i from A.</formula><p>Thus, we obtain a suitable feature set for each tag. The suitable feature sets are noted as C i , i = 1, 2, ..., 36, corresponding to the 36 medical tags. Next step, we utilize C i , i = 1, 2, ..., 36, to train CRF model respectively, and we obtain 36 results by using those learned CRF model to perform labelling task in a patient case record. Then, we combine these results through the method of voting. Note the 36 medical tags as t i , i = 1, 2, ..., 36. For a word w in the patient case record, suppose the tag t i appears n i times. We select the tag which have the highest voting count as the final tag of the word w. Suppose t A is the label of w obtained by the CRF model which is trained by utilizing the feature set A. If two or more tags which share the same highest appear time we select t A as the final tag of w.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Utilizing Association Rules to Extract Information</head><p>We analyze the test and training set and discover that information about patient name, room, bed, gender, age and doctor name have the same expressing format. Thus, we utilize association rules to extract relevant information and assign them with the relevant tags automatically. The association rules are listed in table 3</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">MetaMap Application</head><p>We use MetaMap<ref type="foot" coords="6,213.92,436.07,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">6</ref> to obtain the Unified Medical Language System (UMLS) concepts in the patient case records. Meanwhile, we identify the words with MetaMap tag "phsu" and assign them with the tag "Medication Medicine".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Combination</head><p>We combine our results achieved from the CRF model, association rules and MetaMap in order to get a better performance. Runs obtained by CRF models are utilized as our basic runs. We use the results achieved by using rules and MetaMap to modify the tags in CRF runs.</p><p>Suppose S C , S R , S M are the results achieved by CRF, association rules and MetaMap respectively. For a word in a patient case record, if its tag in CRF run is different from its tag in rule and MetaMap runs, we utilize the tag in association rules and MetaMap runs to replace the tag in CRF run. Note that, there is no conflict between the tags resulted from the association rules and the MetaMap, since the two methods extract information for different tags. We utilize the features in the file "CRF Matrix noLabel.data" provided by organizers to train our CRF model. We implement the training and tagging process of CRF by a open-source toolkit named "CRF++-0.58". Data set 1 and data set 2 are all used for training a CRF model to tag each word in the data set 3. Specifically, we submit six runs based on two methods, where the description for each method is as follows.</p><p>-Method A: We use rules mainly based on regular expressions to extract information of bed number, room number age and doctor's name. Then, we use all features provided to run CRF model and obtain label for each word. Finally, we combine the result achieved by CRF model with result obtained by the association rules. -Method B: We use the method, which is detailed in section 2.1, to select the best suitable feature set for different label among the features provided by the organizers. Then, we train the CRF model based on those feature sets.</p><p>At last, we use the method of voting to determine the label for each word.</p><p>We also use association rules to extract information of bed number, room number, age and doctor's name. The final submission is the combination of results obtained by the association rules and the voting methods.</p><p>The primary evaluation measure of this year is the macro-precision(MaAPrec), macro-recall(MaARec), macro-F1(MaAF1), micro-precision(MiAPrec), microrecall(MiARec), micro-F1(MiAF1), precision of NA tag(NA-Prec), recall of NA tag(NA-Recall), F1 value of NA tag(NA-F1). Data set 1 is used for training. Data set 2 is used for validation and data set 3 is designed for test. Evaluation of our methods over the data set 1, 2 and 3 is summarized in Table <ref type="table" coords="8,433.13,442.55,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_2">3</ref>, where A and B imply our method A and method B respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>In 2016 CLEF eHealth task 1, we propose an optimized CRF model and utilize the association rules and MetaMap tag to achieve the better performance for the handover form automatically filling. All of our submissions outperform the four baseline methods. In the future, we will continue on the research of handover form automatically filling methods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Acknowledgement</head><p>This research is funded by National Key Technology Support Program (No. 2015BAH12F01-04) and Science and Technology Commission of Shanghai Municipality (No.14DZ1101700). We also thank anonymous reviewers for their review comments on this paper. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="1,158.94,596.32,321.65,8.74;1,134.77,608.27,345.82,8.74;1,134.77,620.23,345.82,8.74;1,134.77,632.18,345.83,8.74"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>[3][4]. It has been developed for clinical speech recognition and information extraction related to nursing shift-change handover at NICTA from 2012. This data set contains 200 synthetic patient cases which can be used for training and validation. The patient cases record the patient's profile and health information.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,251.06,348.92,113.23,7.89;3,152.06,115.83,311.25,218.31"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. System Architecture</figDesc><graphic coords="3,152.06,115.83,311.25,218.31" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="3,341.26,596.72,139.33,8.74;3,151.70,608.67,328.89,9.65;3,151.70,620.63,328.89,8.74;3,151.70,632.58,109.34,9.65;3,140.99,644.13,339.60,9.68;3,151.70,656.12,243.04,9.65"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Train the CRF model by utilizing the data set 1 based on the feature set A without f i . Test the learned CRF model on data set 2. Denote the precision on the PatientIntroduction CarePlan tag as p fi . -Calculate the mean value of p fi , i = 1, 2, ..., 17 and denote it as p m . If p fi &gt; p and p fi -p m &gt; 10%, then put the feature f i into set B.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,141.86,162.85,331.64,359.42"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Summarization of the Tags</figDesc><table coords="2,141.86,196.60,331.64,325.67"><row><cell>Patient Introduction</cell><cell>Medication</cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction AdmissionReason/Diagnosis</cell><cell>Medication Dosage</cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction Ageinyears</cell><cell>Medication Medicine</cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction Allergy</cell><cell>Medication Status</cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction CarePlan</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction ChronicCondition</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction CurrentBed</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction CurrentRoom</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction Disease/ProblemHistory</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction Gender</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction GivenNames/Initials</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction Lastname</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction UnderDr GivenNames/Initials</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction UnderDr Lastname</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Appointment/procedure</cell><cell>My Shift</cell></row><row><cell>Appointment/Procedure City</cell><cell>MyShift RiskManagement</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Appointment/Procedure ClinicianGivenNames/Initials MyShift Contraption</cell></row><row><cell>Appointment/Procedure ClinicianLastname</cell><cell>MyShift Input/Diet</cell></row><row><cell>Appointment/Procedure Day</cell><cell>MyShift OtherObservation</cell></row><row><cell>Appointment/Procedure Description</cell><cell>MyShift Status</cell></row><row><cell>Appointment/Procedure Status</cell><cell>MyShift Wounds/Skin</cell></row><row><cell>Appointment/Procedure Time</cell><cell>MyShift Output/Diuresis /BowelMovement</cell></row><row><cell>Appointment/Procedure Ward</cell><cell>MyShift Activities OfDailyLiving</cell></row><row><cell>Future Care</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>Future Alert/Warning/AbnormalResult</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>Future Discharge/TransferPlan</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Future Goal/TaskToBeCompleted/ExpectedOutcome</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,138.51,115.91,338.34,557.08"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Experimented Syntactic Features</figDesc><table coords="4,138.51,149.66,338.34,523.33"><row><cell>ID Name</cell><cell>Definition</cell><cell>Example</cell><cell>Software</cell></row><row><cell>Word</cell><cell>Word itself</cell><cell>"Patients" or "had"</cell><cell>None</cell></row><row><cell>Lemma</cell><cell>Lemma of the word</cell><cell>"patients" or "have"</cell><cell>CoreNLP</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>NER tag of the word for</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>NER (named entity recognition)</cell><cell>named entities(ie, person, numerical entities (ie. location, organization, other proper name) and</cell><cell>"number" for "5"</cell><cell>CoreNLP</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>date, time, money, number)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>"IN"(ie, perposition)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>for "in", "NN"(ir, c-</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>POS (part of speech)</cell><cell>POS tag of the word</cell><cell>ommon noun as opp-"PN") for "bed", osed to Proper Name,</cell><cell>CoreNLP</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>"CN"(ie, cardinal</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>number) for "5"</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Parse tree</cell><cell>Parse tree of the sentence from the root to the current word</cell><cell>"ROOT-NP-NN" (ie, in "In bed 5 we have..." root-noun phrase-common noun). For "5"</cell><cell>CoreNLP</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>"Cardinal number 5"</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Basic dependents</cell><cell>Basic dependents of the word</cell><cell>that refers to the bed ID for "bed" in "In</cell><cell>CoreNLP</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>the bed 5 we have..."</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Basic governors</cell><cell>Basic governors of the word</cell><cell>Preposition "in" and in "In bed 5 we have..." subject "we" for "have"</cell><cell>CoreNLP</cell></row><row><cell>Phrase</cell><cell>Phrase that contains this word</cell><cell>"In bed 5" for "bed" in "In bed 5 we have"</cell><cell>MetaMap</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>"BP" may refer to, for</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>example, "Bachelor of</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Top 5 candidates</cell><cell>Top 5 candidates retrie-ved from UMLS</cell><cell>Pharmacy", "bed-pan", "before present",</cell><cell>MetaMap</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>"birth-place", or</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>"blood pressure"</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Top mapping</cell><cell>Top UMLS mapping for the concept that is the text snippet best match with a given</cell><cell>"pneumonia" is a type infection" "respiratory tract</cell><cell>MetaMap</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="7,140.04,242.76,335.28,281.41"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Association Rules</figDesc><table coords="7,140.04,274.76,335.28,249.41"><row><cell>Tag</cell><cell>Rule</cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction CurrentBed</cell><cell>"bed" + No.</cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction CurrentRoom</cell><cell>"room" + NO.</cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction GivenNames/Initials</cell><cell>without the word "under" + words capitalized the first letter</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>without the word "under" + words</cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction Lastname</cell><cell>capitalized</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>the first letter</cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction UnderDr GivenNames/Initials</cell><cell>"under" + ("Dr") + name</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">PatientIntroduction UnderDr Lastname "under" + ("Dr") + name</cell></row><row><cell>PatientIntroduction Ageinyears</cell><cell>NO. + "years old" / "yrs old" / "yr old"</cell></row></table><note coords="7,140.04,346.44,112.35,7.86;7,309.02,329.95,147.02,7.86;7,309.02,340.91,159.09,7.86;7,309.02,351.87,141.29,7.86;7,309.02,362.83,130.47,7.86"><p>PatientIntroduction Gender word in {male,him,his,he,gentleman, gentlemen, man,men,boy,boys,himself } or {female,her,she, hers,lady,ladies, woman,women,girl,girls,herself }</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="9,211.35,140.69,192.67,495.51"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Evaluation of our submissions</figDesc><table coords="9,211.35,159.75,192.67,476.45"><row><cell>Classifier</cell><cell></cell><cell>Set</cell><cell cols="3">MaAPrec MaARec MaAF1</cell></row><row><cell>NA</cell><cell></cell><cell>Training</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>NA</cell><cell cols="2">Validation</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>NA</cell><cell></cell><cell>Test</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Majority Training</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.029</cell><cell>0.003</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Majority Validation 0.001</cell><cell>0.029</cell><cell>0.003</cell></row><row><cell>Majority</cell><cell></cell><cell>Test</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.029</cell><cell>0.001</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Random Training</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.017</cell><cell>0.027</cell><cell>0.017</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Random Validation 0.018</cell><cell>0.025</cell><cell>0.018</cell></row><row><cell>Random</cell><cell></cell><cell>Test</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.018</cell><cell>0.028</cell><cell>0.019</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">NICTA Training</cell><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell>0.976</cell><cell>0.98</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">NICTA Validation 0.485</cell><cell>0.297</cell><cell>0.324</cell></row><row><cell>NICTA</cell><cell></cell><cell>Test</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.435</cell><cell>0.233</cell><cell>0.246</cell></row><row><cell>A</cell><cell></cell><cell>Training</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.995</cell><cell>0.992</cell><cell>0.994</cell></row><row><cell>A</cell><cell cols="4">Validation 0.467</cell><cell>0.329</cell><cell>0.345</cell></row><row><cell>A</cell><cell></cell><cell>Test</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.493</cell><cell>0.406</cell><cell>0.374</cell></row><row><cell>B</cell><cell></cell><cell>Training</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.454</cell><cell>0.328</cell><cell>0.344</cell></row><row><cell>B</cell><cell cols="4">Validation 0.483</cell><cell>0.313</cell><cell>0.331</cell></row><row><cell>B</cell><cell></cell><cell>Test</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.428</cell><cell>0.292</cell><cell>0.297</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Classifier</cell><cell>Set</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">MiAPrec MiARec MiAF1</cell></row><row><cell>NA</cell><cell></cell><cell>Training</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>NA</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Validation</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>NA</cell><cell></cell><cell>Test</cell><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Majority Training</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.058</cell><cell>0.105 0.075</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Majority Validation 0.05</cell><cell>0.085 0.063</cell></row><row><cell>Majority</cell><cell></cell><cell>Test</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.016</cell><cell>0.027</cell><cell>0.02</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Random Training</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.017</cell><cell>0.03</cell><cell>0.022</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Random Validation 0.018</cell><cell>0.03</cell><cell>0.022</cell></row><row><cell>Random</cell><cell></cell><cell>Test</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.018</cell><cell>0.03</cell><cell>0.022</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">NICTA Training</cell><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell>0.914 0.955</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">NICTA Validation 0.649</cell><cell>0.398 0.493</cell></row><row><cell>NICTA</cell><cell></cell><cell>Test</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.433</cell><cell>0.368 0.398</cell></row><row><cell>A</cell><cell></cell><cell>Training</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.995</cell><cell>0.991 0.993</cell></row><row><cell>A</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Validation 0.655</cell><cell>0.478 0.553</cell></row><row><cell>A</cell><cell></cell><cell>Test</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.51</cell><cell>0.522 0.516</cell></row><row><cell>B</cell><cell></cell><cell>Training</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.461</cell><cell>0.528 0.492</cell></row><row><cell>B</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Validation 0.603</cell><cell>0.454 0.518</cell></row><row><cell>B</cell><cell></cell><cell>Test</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.581</cell><cell>0.459 0.513</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6" xml:id="foot_0" coords="6,144.73,656.80,110.38,7.86"><p>https://mmtx.nlm.nih.gov/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="10,138.35,376.67,342.25,7.86;10,142.31,387.63,338.28,7.86;10,142.31,398.59,338.28,7.86;10,142.31,409.55,69.14,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,442.93,376.67,37.66,7.86;10,142.31,387.63,151.98,7.86">Overview of the CLEF eHealth Evaluation Lab</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Suominen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nvol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Palotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,322.16,387.63,158.43,7.86;10,142.31,398.59,101.05,7.86">CLEF 2016 -7th Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<title level="s" coord="10,252.64,398.59,177.31,7.86">Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNCS</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016-09">2016. September, 2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,138.35,420.51,342.24,7.86;10,142.31,431.47,338.29,7.86;10,142.31,442.43,278.17,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,360.41,420.51,120.18,7.86;10,142.31,431.47,215.56,7.86">Task 1 of the CLEF eHealth evaluation lab 2016: Handover information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Suominen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,365.10,431.47,115.50,7.86;10,142.31,442.43,151.81,7.86">CLEF 2016 Evaluation Labs and Workshop: Online Working Notes</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CEUR-WS</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016-09">September, 2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,138.35,475.30,342.24,7.86;10,142.31,486.26,338.28,7.86;10,142.31,497.22,152.63,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,357.67,475.30,122.92,7.86;10,142.31,486.26,329.95,7.86">Benchmarking Clinical Speech Recognition and Information Extraction: New Data, Methods, and Evaluations</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Suominen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hanlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ferraro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="10,142.31,497.22,106.56,7.86">JMIR Medical Informatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,138.35,508.18,342.24,7.86;10,142.31,519.14,272.12,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="10,334.27,508.18,146.32,7.86;10,142.31,519.14,236.80,7.86">Conditional Random Fields: Probabilistic Models for Segmenting and Labeling Sequence data</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Andrew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Fernando</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,138.35,530.10,342.24,7.86;10,142.31,541.06,338.29,7.86;10,142.31,552.01,298.58,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,235.08,530.10,204.48,7.86">Shallow Parsing with Conditional Random Fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Sha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,463.04,530.10,17.56,7.86;10,142.31,541.06,338.29,7.86;10,142.31,552.01,239.52,7.86">Proceedings of the 2003 Conference of the North American Chapter of Association for Computational Linguistics on Human Language Technology</title>
		<meeting>the 2003 Conference of the North American Chapter of Association for Computational Linguistics on Human Language Technology</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,138.35,562.97,342.24,7.86;10,142.31,573.93,338.29,7.86;10,142.31,584.89,100.34,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,292.86,562.97,187.73,7.86;10,142.31,573.93,25.89,7.86">Integrating classification and association rule mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wynne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Yiming</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,176.24,573.93,304.35,7.86;10,142.31,584.89,64.80,7.86">Proceedings of the fourth international conference on knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the fourth international conference on knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,138.35,595.85,342.24,7.86;10,142.31,606.81,338.29,7.86;10,142.31,617.77,214.59,7.86" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,235.04,595.85,245.55,7.86;10,142.31,606.81,50.79,7.86">Privacy preserving association rule mining in vertically partitioned data</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vaidya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Chris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,200.38,606.81,280.22,7.86;10,142.31,617.77,151.66,7.86">Proceedings of the eighth ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</title>
		<meeting>the eighth ACM SIGKDD international conference on Knowledge discovery and data mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
