<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,170.88,115.90,273.59,12.90;1,257.35,133.83,100.65,12.90;1,223.43,153.70,168.49,10.75">Exploring Information Retrieval features for Author Profiling Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2014</title>
				<funder ref="#_yZUKq9G">
					<orgName type="full">CNPq-Brazil</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,174.92,190.12,74.74,8.64"><forename type="first">Edson</forename><forename type="middle">R D</forename><surname>Weren</surname></persName>
							<email>erdweren@inf.ufrgs.br</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UFRGS -Porto Alegre</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,256.85,190.12,72.86,8.64"><forename type="first">Viviane</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Moreira</surname></persName>
							<email>viviane@inf.ufrgs.br</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UFRGS -Porto Alegre</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,353.40,190.12,87.05,8.64"><forename type="first">José</forename><forename type="middle">P M</forename><surname>De Oliveira</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">UFRGS -Porto Alegre</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,170.88,115.90,273.59,12.90;1,257.35,133.83,100.65,12.90;1,223.43,153.70,168.49,10.75">Exploring Information Retrieval features for Author Profiling Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2014</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">3572920850F2ACCE28376A4475E27ABA</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:38+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the methods we have employed to solve the author profiling task at PAN-2014. Our goal was to rely mainly on features from Information Retrieval to identify the age group and the gender of the author of a given text. We describe the features, the classification algorithms employed, and how the experiments were run. Also, we provide an analysis of our results compared to other groups.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Author profiling deals with the problem of finding as much information as possible about an author, just by analysing a text produced by that author. This is a challenging task which has applications in forensics, marketing, and security <ref type="bibr" coords="1,393.94,391.07,10.58,8.64" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p><p>This paper reports on the participation of the INF-UFRGS team at the second edition of the author profiling task, organised in the scope of the PAN Workshop series, which is collocated with CLEF2014. More details about the task and the workshop can be found in <ref type="bibr" coords="1,171.08,438.92,11.45,8.64" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,182.53,438.92,7.64,8.64" target="#b4">5]</ref> The task requires that participating teams come up with approaches that take a text as input and predict the gender (male/female) and the age group (18-24, 25-34, 35-49, 50-64, or 64+) of its author.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Features</head><p>The texts from each author, or documents, were represented by a set of 64 features (or attributes), which were divided into five groups. Next, we explain each of these groups.</p><p>Length These are simple features that calculate the absolute length of the text. Information Retrieval This is the group of features that encode our assumption that authors from the same gender or age group tend to use similar terms and that the distribution of these terms would be different across genders and age groups. The process here was the same as in <ref type="bibr" coords="1,236.85,656.44,10.58,8.64" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. The complete set of texts is indexed by an Information Retrieval (IR) System. Then, the text that we wish to classify is used as a query and the k most similar texts are retrieved. The ranking is given by the cosine or Okapi metrics as explained below. We employ a total of 30 IR-based features.</p><p>-Cosine These features are computed as an aggregation function over the top-k results for each age/gender group obtained in response to a query composed by the keywords in the text that we wish to classify. We tested three types of aggregation functions, namely: count, sum, and average. For this featureset, queries and documents were compared using the cosine similarity (Eq. 1). For example, if we retrieve 100 documents in response to a query composed by the keywords in q, and 50 of the retrieved documents were in the 18-24's age group, then the value for 18-24_cosine_avg is the the average of the 50 cosine scores for this class. Similarly, 18-24_cosine_sum is the summation of such scores, and 18-24_cosine_count simply counts how many retrieved documents fall into the 18-24_cosine_count category.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,268.23,391.30,212.36,26.62">cosine(c, q) = - → c • - → q | - → c || - → q | (1)</formula><p>where -→ c and -→ q are the vectors for the document and the query, respectively. The vectors are composed of tf i,c × idf i weights where tf i,c is the frequency of term i in document c, and</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,230.15,450.10,66.63,13.47">IDF i = log N n(i)</formula><p>where N is the total number of documents in the collection, and n(i) is the number of documents containing i.</p><p>-Okapi BM25 female_okapi_sum, male_okapi_sum, female_okapi_count, male_okapi_count, female_okapi_avg, male_okapi_avg, 18-24_okapi_sum, 25-34_okapi_sum, 35-49_okapi_sum, 50-64_okapi_sum, 65-xx_okapi_sum, 18-24_okapi_count, 25-34_okapi_count, 35-49_okapi_count, 50-64_okapi_count, 65-xx_okapi_count, 18-24_okapi_avg, 25-34_okapi_avg, 35-49_okapi_avg, 50-64_okapi_avg, 65-xx_okapi_avg . Similar to the previous featureset, these features compute an aggregation function (average, sum, and count) over the the retrieved results from each gender/age group that appeared in the top-k ranks for the query composed by the keywords in the document. For this featureset, queries and documents were compared using the Okapi BM25 score (Eq. 2).</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,217.74,614.39,262.85,27.36">BM 25(c, q) = n i=1 IDFi tfi,c • (k1 + 1) tfi,c + k1(1 -b + b |D| avgdl )<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where tfi,c and IDFi are as in Eq. 1 |d| is the length (in words) of document c, avgdl is the average document length in the collection, k1 and b are parameters that tune the importance of the presence of each term in the query and the length of the text. In our experiments, we used k1 = 1.2 and b = 0.75.</p><p>Readability Readability tests indicate the comprehension difficulty of a text.</p><p>-Flesch-Kincaid readability tests We employ two tests that indicate the comprehension difficulty of a text: Flesch Reading Ease (FRE) and Flesch-Kincaid Grade Level (FKGL) <ref type="bibr" coords="3,406.56,205.01,10.58,8.64" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. They are given by Eqs. </p><p>Correctness This group of features aims at capturing the correctness of the text.</p><p>-Words in the dictionary: ratio between the words from the text found in the OpenOffice US dictionary<ref type="foot" coords="3,270.70,429.16,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_0">1</ref> and the total number of words in the text. -Cleanliness: ratio between the number of characters in the preprocessed text and the number of characters in the raw text. The idea is to assess how "clean" the original text is. -Repeated Vowels: in some cases, authors use words with repeated vowels for emphasis. e.g. "I am soo tired". This group of features counts the numbers of repeated vowels (a, e, i, o, and u) in sequence within a word. -Repeated Punctuation: this features compute the number of repeated punctuation marks (i.e., commas, semi-colons, full stops, question marks, and exclamation marks) in sequence in the text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Style</head><p>-HTML tags: this feature consists in counting the number of HTML tags that indicate line breaks &lt;br&gt;, images &lt;img&gt;, and links &lt;href&gt;. -Diversity: this feature is calculated as the ratio between the distinct words in the text and the total number of words in the text. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Usefulness of the Features</head><p>In order to evaluate how discriminant each of the 64 features described in Section 2 is, we calculated their information gain with respect to the class. The five highest ranking features for each corpus and each class are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,373.45,548.40,3.74,8.64" target="#tab_2">1</ref>. The vast majority of the most discriminative features is from the IR group. Style, length, and correctness also appear, but at a much lower frequency. For Age-Blogs-EN, none of our features had a good score for information gain. Interestingly, we got the best scores for this corpus on the test data, compared to other groups. Information gain evaluates each feature independently from each other. However, when selecting the best group of features, we wish to avoid redundant features by keeping features that have at the same time a high correlation with the class and a low intercorrelation. With this aim, we used Weka's <ref type="bibr" coords="4,323.59,644.48,11.62,8.64" target="#b2">[3]</ref> subset evaluators to select good subsets of features. These subsets are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,337.14,656.44,3.74,8.64" target="#tab_3">2</ref>. The number of attributes in these We also analysed our results compared against the mean of all participants. These are shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,220.49,331.80,3.74,8.64">1</ref>. For 9 out of 14 cases, our results were above the mean. The case with the biggest gain was Age-Blogs-EN, in which the advantage was of 31%. In 5 runs, our results were at or below the mean. Our worst scores were for Age-Blogs-ES, in which our loss was of nearly 66%. Adding up all gains and losses, we get a positive result of 10% in relation to the average.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>This paper describes our participation in the Author Profiling task run in PAN 2014. We used the training data to build classifiers using several machine learning algorithms. Our focus was on exploring Information Retrieval-based features. The official results show that our scores were above the mean for all participants in most cases (9 times out of 14).</p><p>Author profiling is a challenging task. Consequently, there are many possibilities for future work. As a first step, once the test data is released, we will further investigate the cases in which our system fails or succeeds in the classification. The goal is to try and establish patterns. We are also interested in testing methods for instance selection to improve our classification models. In addition, we have treated gender and age classification separately as independent problems. However, since some attributes meant to discriminate gender were found useful for age (and vice-versa), we wish to explore the influence of both types of classification into each other.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="1,141.74,566.23,132.28,8.96;1,141.74,578.21,119.27,9.03;1,141.74,590.19,126.03,8.96"><head>-</head><label></label><figDesc>Number of Characters; -Number of Words; and -Number of Sentences.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,151.70,216.97,328.91,160.95"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>3 and 4.  Higher FRE scores indicate a material that is easier to read. For example, a text with a FRE scores between 90 and 100 could be easily read by a 11 year old, while texts with scores below 30 would be best understood by undergraduates. FKGL scores indicate a grade level. A FKGL of 7, indicates that the text is understandable by a 7th grade student. Thus, the higher the FKGL score, the higher the number of years in education required to understand the text. The idea of using these scores is to help distinguish the age of the author. Younger authors are expected to use shorter words and thus have a smaller FKGL and a high FRE.</figDesc><table coords="3,181.40,321.44,299.19,56.48"><row><cell cols="2">F RE = 206.835 -1.015</cell><cell cols="2">#words #sentences</cell><cell>-84.6</cell><cell>#syllables #words</cell><cell>(3)</cell></row><row><cell>F KGL = 0.39</cell><cell cols="2">#words #sentences</cell><cell>+ 11.8</cell><cell cols="2">#syllables #words</cell><cell>-15.59</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="4,139.50,115.83,337.20,350.02"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Top 5 features in terms of Information Gain</figDesc><table coords="4,139.50,138.82,337.20,327.03"><row><cell>Corpus</cell><cell>Lang</cell><cell>Top 5 features</cell><cell>Age</cell><cell>IG</cell><cell>Type</cell><cell cols="2">Top 5 features Gender</cell><cell>IG</cell><cell>Type</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>18-24_okapi_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.083</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>male_okapi_avg</cell><cell cols="2">0.160</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>50-64_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.083</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>25-34_okapi_avg</cell><cell cols="2">0.154</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell>Twitter</cell><cell>EN</cell><cell>25-34_okapi_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.081</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>male_okapi_sum</cell><cell cols="2">0.153</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>25-34_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.077</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>35-49_okapi_avg</cell><cell cols="2">0.152</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>18-24_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.075</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>female_okapi_avg</cell><cell cols="2">0.140</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>&lt;href&gt;</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.140</cell><cell>Style</cell><cell>number of words</cell><cell cols="2">0.183</cell><cell>Length</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>25-34_okapi_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.136</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell cols="4">words in the dictionary 0.157 Correctness</cell></row><row><cell>Twitter</cell><cell>ES</cell><cell>25-34_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.129</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>male_okapi_sum</cell><cell cols="2">0.155</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>25-34_cosine_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.123</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>diversity</cell><cell cols="2">0.149</cell><cell>Style</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>50-64_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.114</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>male_cosine_sum</cell><cell cols="2">0.148</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>diversity</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.000</cell><cell>Style</cell><cell>female_cosine_sum</cell><cell cols="2">0.156</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>male_okapi_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.000</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>male_okapi_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.146</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell>Blog</cell><cell>EN</cell><cell>male_okapi_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.000</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>female_okapi_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.137</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>female_okapi_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.000</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>female_cosine_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.118</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>female_okapi_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.000</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>cleanliness</cell><cell cols="3">0.114 Correctness</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>25-34_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.260</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>number of words</cell><cell cols="2">0.251</cell><cell>Length</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="8">words in the dictionary 0.231 Correctness words in the dictionary 0.226 Correctness</cell></row><row><cell>Blog</cell><cell>ES</cell><cell>50-64_okapi_avg</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.224</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>repeated_e</cell><cell cols="3">0.206 Correctness</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>50-64_okapi_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.224</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>50-64_okapi_avg</cell><cell cols="2">0.200</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>25-34_cosine_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.223</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>male_okapi_sum</cell><cell cols="2">0.194</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>50-64_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.122</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>female_cosine_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.008</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>50-64_cosine_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.122</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>female_cosine_sum</cell><cell cols="2">0.007</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell>SocialMedia</cell><cell>EN</cell><cell>35-49_cosine_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.117</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>female_okapi_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.007</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>18-24_cosine_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.116</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>male_okapi_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.007</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>35-49_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.114</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>male_cosine_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.006</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>18-24_okapi_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.200</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>female_cosine_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.081</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>50-64_okapi_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.200</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>female_cosine_sum</cell><cell cols="2">0.079</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell>SocialMedia</cell><cell>ES</cell><cell>18-24_cosine_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.193</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>male_cosine_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.071</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>35-49_cosine_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.191</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>25-34_cosine_avg</cell><cell cols="2">0.053</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>18-24_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.189</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>female_okapi_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.052</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>65-XX_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.098</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>female_okapi_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.106</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>25-34_okapi_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.098</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>male_okapi_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.106</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell>Reviews</cell><cell>EN</cell><cell>25-34_cosine_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.087</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>female_cosine_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.079</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>65-XX_cosine_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.083</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>male_cosine_count</cell><cell cols="2">0.079</cell><cell>IR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>65-XX_okapi_count</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.082</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell>female_cosine_sum</cell><cell cols="2">0.072</cell><cell>IR</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,199.02,115.83,213.78,514.79"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Best subset of features for each corpus</figDesc><table coords="5,199.02,140.73,213.78,489.89"><row><cell>Corpus</cell><cell>Lang</cell><cell>Age</cell><cell>Gender</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>18-24_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>18-24_cosine_count</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Twitter</cell><cell>EN</cell><cell>35-49_okapi_count male_okapi_count</cell><cell>male_okapi_sum</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>repeated_e</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>repeated_exclamation</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>50-64_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>65-XX_cosine_count</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Twitter</cell><cell>ES</cell><cell>25-34_okapi_sum 25-34_okapi_count &lt;href&gt; words_in_dictionary number_of_characters</cell><cell>male_cosine_sum male_cosine_count words_in_dictionary repeated_exclamation</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>repeated_e</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>repeated_semicolon</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>male_cosine_avg</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>50-64_okapi_count</cell><cell>female_cosine_sum</cell></row><row><cell>Blog</cell><cell>EN</cell><cell>&lt;img&gt;</cell><cell>male_cosine_count</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>repeated_exclamation</cell><cell>female_okapi_count</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>repeated_interrogation</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Blog</cell><cell>ES</cell><cell>65-XX_cosine_count 65-XX_cosine_avg 25-34_okapi_sum</cell><cell>repeated_e repeated_exclamation</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">SocialMedia EN</cell><cell>female_cosine_avg male_cosine_avg 25-34_cosine_avg 35-49_cosine_avg 18-24_okapi_count 65-XX_okapi_avg FKGL repeated_i repeated_fullstop</cell><cell>male_cosine_count 18-24_cosine_sum 35-49_cosine_count female_okapi_count FRE &lt;img&gt; repeated_exclamation repeated_interrogation</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>50-64_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>18-24_cosine_count</cell><cell>female_cosine_sum</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>female_okapi_sum</cell><cell>male_cosine_avg</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>male_okapi_count</cell><cell>male_okapi_count</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>18-24_okapi_sum</cell><cell>18-24_okapi_count</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">SocialMedia ES</cell><cell>18-24_okapi_count</cell><cell>FKGL</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>18-24_okapi_avg</cell><cell>repeated_a</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>&lt;img&gt;</cell><cell>repeated_i</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>number_of_characters</cell><cell>repeated_u</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>repeated_a</cell><cell>repeated_exclamation</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>repeated_ponto</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>female_cosine_avg</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>18-24_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>65-XX_cosine_sum</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>65-XX_cosine_count</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>65-XX_okapi_sum</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Reviews</cell><cell>EN</cell><cell>25-34_okapi_count 65-XX_okapi_count FKGL number_of_characters repeated_i repeated_o</cell><cell>female_cosine_sum 50-64_okapi_count 65-XX_okapi_count diversity repeated_semicolon</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>repeated_comma</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>repeated_semicolon</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>repeated_exclamation</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>cleanliness</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>diversity</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="7,167.30,187.84,301.12,101.64"><head>age gender age gender age gender age gender age gender age gender age gender</head><label></label><figDesc>Comparison against the mean results of all participants</figDesc><table coords="7,173.65,201.23,282.11,88.19"><row><cell>Twitter</cell><cell>SocialMedia</cell><cell>Blogs</cell><cell>Reviews</cell><cell>Twitter</cell><cell>SocialMedia</cell><cell>Blogs</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>English</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Spanish</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Figure 1.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="3,144.73,646.97,236.70,6.31;3,144.73,657.93,205.92,6.31"><p>http://extensions.openoffice.org/en/project/ english-dictionaries-apache-openoffice</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>Acknowledgements: This work has been partially supported by <rs type="funder">CNPq-Brazil</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">478979/2012-6</rs>). We thank <rs type="person">Anderson Kauer</rs> for his help in revising this paper. We thank <rs type="person">Martin Potthast</rs>, <rs type="person">Francisco Rangel</rs>, and other members of the PAN organising team for their help in getting our software to run.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_yZUKq9G">
					<idno type="grant-number">478979/2012-6</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>subsets varied a lot, from one (Gender-Twitter-EN) to 16 (Age-Reviews-EN). Again, we observed that most features in the subsets are IR-based. Surprisingly, readability features (namely FKGL) appear in only two subsets for Age. Style and correctness attributes also appear in the chosen subsets. Also, we noticed that some features that were intended for age, have been selected as useful for gender and vice-versa.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Official Experiments</head><p>We treated gender and age classification separately. Thus, the features described in the previous section were used to train one classifier for each corpus for gender and age resulting in 14 classifiers. We used Weka <ref type="bibr" coords="6,303.39,228.83,11.62,8.64" target="#b2">[3]</ref> to build the machine learning models. A number of algorithms was tested, namely: BayesNet, Logistic, MultilayerPerceptron, SimpleLogistic, LogitBoost, RotationForest, and MetaMultiClass. We chose the algorithm which got the best result for the training data using 10-fold cross-validation. To make such choice, we analysed the results of the classifiers in two scenarios: using all 64 attributes and using just the attributes in the best subset.</p><p>The preprocessing consisted basically in tokenisation, removal of tags, and escape characters. No stemming or stopword removal was performed. All training instances were used to generate the model. No attempt to remove noise was taken.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="6,173.82,336.43,4.98,8.64">3</ref> shows our official results for both training and test corpora in terms of accuracy. It also shows which classification algorithm was used and whether all attributes or just a subset were used. Most classifiers (11 out of 14) used just the subset of attributes, as their results on the training data outperformed (or got very close to) the results using all attributes.</p><p>As expected, results on the training corpora were superior to the results on the test corpora. The biggest drop was for Age-Blog-ES as in this corpus, in which accuracy dropped by half. Interestingly, the results for three corpora were better on the test data (Age-Twitter-ES, Age-Blogs-EN, and Gender-Twitter-ES). We still need to investigate these differences further. </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,142.88,339.39,7.77;8,146.47,153.83,229.24,7.77" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,345.03,142.88,132.49,7.77;8,146.47,153.83,66.60,7.77">Automatically profiling the author of an anonymous text</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Argamon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,218.42,153.83,57.93,7.77">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="2009-02">Feb 2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,164.79,342.45,7.77;8,146.47,175.75,319.42,7.77;8,146.47,186.71,333.25,7.77;8,146.47,197.67,325.08,7.77" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,159.43,175.75,306.47,7.77;8,146.47,186.71,121.96,7.77">Recent trends in digital text forensics and its evaluation -plagiarism detection, author identification, and author profiling</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gollub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Beyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Busse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">M R</forename><surname>Pardo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="s" coord="8,168.88,197.67,152.15,7.77">CLEF. Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Forner</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Paredes</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8138</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="282" to="302" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,208.63,327.03,7.77;8,146.47,219.59,301.11,7.77" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,422.09,208.63,43.07,7.77;8,146.47,219.59,113.46,7.77">The WEKA data mining software: an update</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Holmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Pfahringer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Reutemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Witten</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,265.91,219.59,89.43,7.77">SIGKDD Explor. Newsl</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="2009-11">Nov 2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,230.55,333.26,7.77;8,146.47,241.51,327.69,7.77;8,146.47,252.46,321.54,7.77;8,146.47,263.42,71.02,7.77" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Kincaid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Fishburne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Chissom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="8,361.25,230.55,110.14,7.77;8,146.47,241.51,327.69,7.77;8,146.47,252.46,86.96,7.77">Derivation of New Readability Formulas (Automated Readability Index, Fog Count and Flesch Reading Ease Formula) for Navy Enlisted Personnel</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Springfield, Virginia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1975-02">Feb 1975</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>National Technical Information Service</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Tech. rep.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,274.38,312.02,7.77;8,146.47,285.34,307.21,7.77;8,146.47,296.30,211.93,7.77" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,367.09,274.38,83.05,7.77;8,146.47,285.34,89.86,7.77">Overview of the author profiling task at pan 2013</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Inches</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,254.81,285.34,198.87,7.77;8,146.47,296.30,40.57,7.77">Notebook Papers of CLEF 2013 LABs and Workshops, CLEF-2013</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Valencia, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-09">September. 2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.13,307.26,320.53,7.77;8,146.47,318.22,293.10,7.77;8,146.47,329.18,189.73,7.77" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,146.47,318.22,172.01,7.77">Examining multiple features for author profiling</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R D</forename><surname>Weren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Kauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Mizusaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Moreira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P M D</forename><surname>Oliveira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wives</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,324.03,318.22,115.54,7.77;8,146.47,329.18,75.94,7.77">Journal of Information and Data Management (JIDM)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014-10">October 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>to appear</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
