<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,140.30,148.76,326.32,15.96;1,155.78,166.16,283.92,15.96;1,211.37,186.64,172.60,12.00">Evaluating robustness for &apos;IPCRESS&apos;: Surrey&apos;s text alignment for plagiarism detection Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2014</title>
				<funder ref="#_fshf4aH">
					<orgName type="full">JISC</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_h8MRuuF">
					<orgName type="full">UK&apos;s Technology Strategy Board</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">EPSRC</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,253.13,224.72,43.29,9.05"><forename type="first">Lee</forename><surname>Gillam</surname></persName>
							<email>l.gillam@surrey.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Surrey</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,303.27,224.72,50.31,9.05"><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Notley</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Surrey</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,140.30,148.76,326.32,15.96;1,155.78,166.16,283.92,15.96;1,211.37,186.64,172.60,12.00">Evaluating robustness for &apos;IPCRESS&apos;: Surrey&apos;s text alignment for plagiarism detection Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2014</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">E0CAA3222DEDD212A5055AC225927568</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:38+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper briefly describes the approach taken to the subtask of Text Alignment in the Plagiarism Detection track at PAN 14. We have now reimplemented our PAN12 approach in a consistent programmatic manner, courtesy of secured research funding. PAN 14 offers us the first opportunity to evaluate the performance/consistency of this re-implementation. We present results from this re-implementation with respect to various PAN collections, although it is important to note that our target is to be able to undertake plagiarism detection in such a way as would be impervious to a range of attempts to discover the content being matched against -a kind of privacypreserving plagiarism detection.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>As reported in our PAN 13 notebook paper, having secured funding from the UK government-backed Technology Strategy Board for 18 months, the University of Surrey have been working on the Intellectual Property Protecting Cloud Services in Supply Chains (IPCRESS) project, a collaboration with Jaguar Land Rover and GeoLang Ltd. The IPCRESS project is focused on the difficulty of entrusting valuable Intellectual Property (IP) to third parties, through the Cloud, as is necessary to allow for the construction of components in the supply chain. The key innovation is the ability to track high-value IP without having to reveal that IP -so approaches need to avoid being reversible to text in clear. Such tracking is then suited to the tasks of (i) preventing IP leakage; (ii) detecting IP leakage or theft; and (iii) identifying retention beyond allowed review periods. The project builds from the proposed formulation of such a system in Cooke and Gillam 2011. This can be formulated as a kind of plagiarism detection, and hence the relevance of/to PAN, with a more challenging aim: to be able to generate reliable detections without access to the textual contentand so allowing for matches to be undertaken in public without exposing the content high-value documents that ought to be locked in secure electronic vaults. As such, only those with suitable access to the document in the vault should be able to verify the match.</p><p>In this paper, we briefly discuss the simplification of the code-base from our original submissions to the present and much more self-contained setup, and demonstrate the consistency of results obtained. We also hint at improvements in our treatment of obfuscation that are likely to become a focal point for future work also.</p><p>Section 2 provides a brief summary of results found with re-used software applied to PAN 2011, PAN 2012 and PAN 2013 datasets. Section 3 carries discussion of the IPCRESS re-implementation. Section 4 presents results of applying IPCRESS to the datsets for PAN 2012 and PAN 2013, and preliminary results found using initial obfuscation handling approaches. Section 5 comments on the PAN 2014 results and future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Previous PAN results</head><p>We have discussed in previous PAN efforts (e.g. Cooke, 2011) how our intention is to be able to find matching text without revealing the textual content. In PAN 11, the approach brought us 4th place, with PlagDet=0.2467329, Recall=0.1500480, Precision=0.7106536, Granularity=1.0058894. In 2012, we showed good granularity, with high recall and precision for non-obfuscated text, but not such great recall in the face of obfuscation (see </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">The IPCRESS implementation</head><p>For the IPCRESS project, the previous codebase needed to be homogenized and developed in such a manner as to be scalable to very large datasets. The previous version/s were memory-based and thus not suitable for use at real scale (hundreds of gigabytes or more). The IPCRESS code has been fully re-designed as a disk-based approach, as an object oriented implemention in C++. A new stitching algorithm has also been developed.</p><p>The IPCRESS approach generates what we refer to as secure stamps from whole documents. From each stamp, we derive a set of shorter individual hash-like codes , I , from sets of words. These codes are considered irreversible. Individual codes are generated by using a sliding window of length, Wlen , across the document stamp to extract that portion of the stamp in a manner similar to creating shingles. From this set of hash-like codes an index is populated with information related to the current window position within the document stamp and a document ID. This process is illustrated in figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,203.81,254.72,3.76,9.05" target="#fig_1">1</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>S s </head><p>, that gives {suspicious start position, suspicious length, source start position source length}; the start positions are given by the first element of R and the lengths are determined from the last element of R. Any segments found that are shorter than a defined minimum segment length (MSL) are discarded.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Obfuscation Handling</head><p>We consider two initial obfuscation handling approaches based on transformations of a single query into closely related queries. The hash-like codes mentioned above are formulated such that code similarity can be indicative of data similarity, and as such the 'closeness' of any two queries can be based on binary distance approaches such as Hamming and Levenshtein.</p><p>The first approach, based on Hamming distances, generates transformed queries with a given maximum Hamming distance with relation to the original enquiry. For an original query Q q i  , of length Wlen, this approach will generate an extra Wlen transformations. For a Hamming distance of 1, say, this method involves an extra Wlen look-ups for each initial query.</p><p>The second approach, based on the Levenschtein distance, similarly generates transformed queries from each original query, qi. For a query length of Wlen, this approach generates 2 sets of transformations Ti 0 and Ti 1 where i refers to a word position within query, qi, and lies in the range 2*Wlen extra look-ups for each query. For each insertion the transformed query, Ti n , is masked to length Wlen for index compatibility.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">IPCRESS vs previous PAN collections</head><p>Prior results offer up a standard to be achieved in re-implementation. The new codebase has been tested against data from PAN12 and PAN13, with modifications to the algorithm largely demonstrating slightly improved performance, as shown in the tables below: Through PAN 2014, we have demonstrated that the IPCRESS code produces results comparable to, and even slightly better than, the previous implementation, and effort has been put into ensuring the implementation is suited to scaling to very large datasets. These results are certainly not going to be anywhere near the best that is possible when evaluating similarity between texts where the content is fully exposed. However, that is not our challenge. and it is important to note again that our specific challenge is to be able to undertake plagiarism detection in such a way as would be impervious to a range of attempts to discover the content being matched against -a kind of privacy-preserving plagiarism detection that can be used against documents whose content should be kept from plain sight.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IPCRESS raw -PAN12 data</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,194.54,404.87,217.65,9.05;3,136.22,427.91,334.65,9.05;3,124.82,439.44,345.80,9.06;3,124.82,452.77,94.58,9.05;3,223.47,459.64,8.60,1.00;3,234.05,452.76,2.49,9.06;3,136.22,469.93,153.27,9.05;3,313.06,477.06,4.16,1.00;3,293.97,477.06,5.17,4.06;3,302.26,468.57,138.48,11.12;3,445.99,477.18,4.12,1.00;3,453.79,469.93,16.84,9.05"><head>Figure 1 .Figure 2 .</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Figure 1. The indexing process using IPCRESS codes A query for a suspicious document is similarly generated using the sliding window of length, Wlen, over the stamp of the suspicious document to generate a set of IPCRESS code queries, Q . Document ID and code position pairs, I i i  , are retrieved from the index, I , for</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,359.34,678.72,8.60,1.00;4,350.70,675.96,9.62,1.00;4,337.37,675.96,3.21,1.00;4,343.09,668.34,6.34,9.99;4,329.08,668.34,6.34,9.99;4,321.32,668.45,5.77,9.89;4,369.43,668.32,101.14,9.05;4,197.02,198.20,2.59,1.00;4,193.12,196.39,3.62,1.00;4,184.06,202.13,6.90,1.00;4,196.35,225.23,2.54,1.00;4,192.90,223.44,3.56,1.00;4,183.82,229.10,6.78,1.00;4,197.12,292.05,2.59,1.00;4,193.12,290.24,3.62,1.00;4,184.06,295.98,6.90,1.00;4,154.70,176.12,25.18,9.05;4,328.01,168.81,89.59,7.31;4,328.01,193.65,89.68,7.31;4,328.01,276.00,107.44,7.31;4,328.01,300.84,94.12,7.31;4,313.37,153.68,15.50,9.05;4,341.56,158.19,1.90,1.00;4,338.98,156.84,2.66,1.00;4,332.19,161.11,5.07,1.00;4,345.19,153.68,39.14,9.05"><head>1 dT</head><label>1</label><figDesc>.: 0, Src. Pos.: 0} {Susp. Pos.: 1, Src. Pos.: 1} {Susp. Pos.: m-1, Src. Pos.: m-1} {Susp. Pos.: m, Src. Pos.: m} Set: (srcID: 1)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,124.82,352.79,345.93,221.59"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Table below).In 2013, precision and granularity figures remained high, though recall had dropped. For different kinds of obfuscation from 2012, recall remains low -though perhaps surprisingly is better for random obfuscation than for translation or summary.</figDesc><table coords="2,124.82,376.71,345.93,197.67"><row><cell>Test</cell><cell>Plagdet</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>Precision</cell><cell>Granularity</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Score</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>02_no_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.92530</cell><cell>0.90449</cell><cell>0.94709</cell><cell>1.0</cell></row><row><cell>03_artificial_low</cell><cell>0.09837</cell><cell>0.05374</cell><cell>0.93852</cell><cell>1.04688</cell></row><row><cell>04_artificial_high</cell><cell>0.01508</cell><cell>0.00867</cell><cell>0.96822</cell><cell>1.20313</cell></row><row><cell>06_simulated_paraphrase</cell><cell>0.11229</cell><cell>0.05956</cell><cell>0.97960</cell><cell>1.0</cell></row><row><cell>Test</cell><cell>Plagdet</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>Precision</cell><cell>Granularity</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Score</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>02_no_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.85884</cell><cell>0.83788</cell><cell>0.88088</cell><cell>1.0</cell></row><row><cell>03_random_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.04191</cell><cell>0.02142</cell><cell>0.95968</cell><cell>1.0</cell></row><row><cell>04_translation_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.01224</cell><cell>0.00616</cell><cell>0.97273</cell><cell>1.0</cell></row><row><cell>05_summary_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.00218</cell><cell>0.00109</cell><cell>0.99591</cell><cell>1.0</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,124.82,296.79,348.91,380.82"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>PAN 2014 test results showed expected granularity and precision, but a surprising difference between values for recall. Investigations led to the discovery of a bug in detecting UTF-8 codes; when applied to PAN 2012 and 2013 collections, a similar lowering of values was also observed. Further, our initial attempts at handling obfuscation show some promise, but much more rigorous evaluation will be required to determine the fullest extent of impact achievable by these approaches on the hashlike codes.</figDesc><table coords="5,124.82,296.79,348.91,380.82"><row><cell cols="5">5 IPCRESS vs PAN 2014 collections and Future Work</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Test data</cell><cell>Plagdet</cell><cell>Precision</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell cols="2">Granularity Runtime</cell></row><row><cell>Corpus 2</cell><cell>0.28302</cell><cell>0.88630</cell><cell>0.16840</cell><cell>1.00000</cell><cell>00:00:55</cell></row><row><cell>Test Corpus 3</cell><cell>0.44076</cell><cell cols="2">Plagdet Score Recall 0.85744 0.29661</cell><cell cols="2">Precision Granularity 1.00000 00:00:56</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">02_no_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.9437</cell><cell>0.9045</cell><cell>0.9877</cell><cell>1.0008</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">03_artificial_low</cell><cell>0.0956</cell><cell>0.0525</cell><cell>0.9942</cell><cell>1.0608</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">04_artificial_high</cell><cell>0.0200</cell><cell>0.0118</cell><cell>0.9852</cell><cell>1.2459</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">06_simulated_paraphrase</cell><cell>0.0992</cell><cell>0.0522</cell><cell>0.9922</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Obfuscation handler #1 (Hamming)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">02_no_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.9358</cell><cell>0.9048</cell><cell>0.9703</cell><cell>1.0008</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">03_artificial_low</cell><cell>0.1970</cell><cell>0.1110</cell><cell>0.9853</cell><cell>1.0178</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">04_artificial_high</cell><cell>0.0373</cell><cell>0.0201</cell><cell>0.9577</cell><cell>1.0759</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">06_simulated_paraphrase</cell><cell>0.1512</cell><cell>0.0825</cell><cell>0.9038</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Obfuscation handler #2 (Levenshtein)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">02_no_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.9236</cell><cell>0.9057</cell><cell>0.9423</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">03_artificial_low</cell><cell>0.1888</cell><cell>0.1066</cell><cell>0.9820</cell><cell>1.0266</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">04_artificial_high</cell><cell>0.0682</cell><cell>0.0368</cell><cell>0.9489</cell><cell>1.0535</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">06_simulated_paraphrase</cell><cell>0.1345</cell><cell>0.0723</cell><cell>0.9572</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">IPCRESS raw -PAN13 data</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Test</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Plagdet Score Recall</cell><cell cols="2">Precision Granularity</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">02_no_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.9253</cell><cell>0.9273</cell><cell>0.9233</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">03_random_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.1356</cell><cell>0.0729</cell><cell>0.9675</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">04_translation_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.0243</cell><cell>0.0123</cell><cell>0.9865</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">05_summary_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.0022</cell><cell>0.0011</cell><cell>0.9959</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Obfuscation handler #1 (Hamming)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">02_no_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.9029</cell><cell>0.9289</cell><cell>0.8783</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">03_random_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.1297</cell><cell>0.1297</cell><cell>0.9120</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">04_translation_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.0244</cell><cell>0.0244</cell><cell>0.8953</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">05_summary_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.0035</cell><cell>0.0017</cell><cell>0.9807</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Obfuscation handler #2 (Levenshtein)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">02_no_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.9058</cell><cell>0.9274</cell><cell>0.8853</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">03_random_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.2151</cell><cell>0.1224</cell><cell>0.8936</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">04_translation_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.0743</cell><cell>0.0386</cell><cell>0.9533</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">05_summary_obfuscation</cell><cell>0.0035</cell><cell>0.0017</cell><cell>0.9920</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>The authors gratefully recognize prior contributions of <rs type="person">Neil Newbold</rs>, <rs type="person">Neil Cooke</rs>, <rs type="person">Peter Wrobel</rs> and <rs type="person">Henry Cooke</rs> to the formulation of the codebase used for prior versions of this task, and by <rs type="person">Cooke</rs> and <rs type="person">Wrobel</rs> to the patents generated from these efforts. This work has been supported in part by the <rs type="funder">EPSRC</rs> and <rs type="funder">JISC</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">EP/I034408/1</rs>) and more substantially since PAN13 by the <rs type="funder">UK's Technology Strategy Board</rs> (TSB, <rs type="grantNumber">169201</rs>). The authors are also grateful for the efforts of the PAN organizers in system provision and managing the submissions.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_fshf4aH">
					<idno type="grant-number">EP/I034408/1</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_h8MRuuF">
					<idno type="grant-number">169201</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,139.98,620.92,330.67,9.05;6,154.22,632.32,316.38,9.05;6,154.22,643.84,316.21,9.05;6,154.22,655.36,155.76,9.05" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,267.65,620.92,203.00,9.05;6,154.22,632.32,297.89,9.05">Clowns, Crowds and Clouds: A Cross-Enterprise Approach to Detecting Information Leakage without Leaking Information</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Cooke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gillam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,277.16,643.84,189.26,9.05">Cloud Computing for Enterprise Architectures</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Mahmood</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hill</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>London</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="301" to="322" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,139.98,149.48,330.76,9.05;7,154.22,161.00,316.63,9.05;7,154.22,172.52,246.56,9.05" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,439.63,149.48,31.11,9.05;7,154.22,161.00,167.58,9.05">A high performance plagiarism detection system</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Cooke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gillam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Wrobel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Cooke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Al-Obaidli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,343.03,161.00,127.82,9.05;7,154.22,172.52,56.09,9.05">Proceedings CLEF 2011, Labs and Workshop</title>
		<title level="s" coord="7,217.73,172.52,66.91,9.05">Notebook Papers</title>
		<meeting>CLEF 2011, Labs and Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">3</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>PAN workshop</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
