<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,136.84,116.00,341.68,12.91;1,248.38,133.93,118.58,12.91;1,223.43,153.76,168.51,10.76">Ensembles of Proximity-Based One-Class Classifiers for Author Verification Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2014</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,188.29,189.76,88.05,8.97"><forename type="first">Magdalena</forename><surname>Jankowska</surname></persName>
							<email>jankowsk@cs.dal.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalhousie University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,283.44,189.76,50.59,8.97"><forename type="first">Vlado</forename><surname>Kešelj</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalhousie University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,357.37,189.76,69.78,8.97"><forename type="first">Evangelos</forename><surname>Milios</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalhousie University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,136.84,116.00,341.68,12.91;1,248.38,133.93,118.58,12.91;1,223.43,153.76,168.51,10.76">Ensembles of Proximity-Based One-Class Classifiers for Author Verification Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2014</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">9F250035C45688CF26276438B1AA0439</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:38+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We use ensembles of proximity based one-class classifiers for authorship verification task. The one-class classifiers compare, for each document of the known authorship, the dissimilarity between this document and the most dissimilar other document of this authorship to the dissimilarity between this document and the questioned document. As the dissimilarity measure between documents we use Common N-Gram dissimilarity based on character or word n-grams.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>We describe our submission to the task of Author Identification of the PAN 2014 competition <ref type="bibr" coords="1,158.42,377.10,10.58,8.97" target="#b5">[5]</ref>. This task presents participants with author verification problems, formulated as follows: "Given a small set (no more than 5, possibly as few as one) of 'known' documents by a single person and a 'questioned' document, the task is to determine whether the questioned document was written by the same person who wrote the known document set."</p><p>The required output in the competition task is a real number in the range from 0 to 1, encoding the probability of the positive answer to this question. A probability score that is less than 0.5 is interpreted as a negative answer; a probability score that is greater than 0.5 is interpreted as a positive answer; the score of 0.5 is interpreted as the "I don't know" answer.</p><p>The submissions are evaluated using the measure of area under the ROC curve (AUC) based on the probability scores, and the c@1 measure <ref type="bibr" coords="1,390.14,508.61,10.54,8.97" target="#b6">[6]</ref>. c@1 is equivalent to accuracy when the "I don't know" answer is not used. For a given number of correct answers, the higher number of incorrect answers is replaced by "I don't know", the higher is c@1. The final evaluation score in the competition is the product of AUC and c@1.</p><p>The Author Identification at PAN 2014 is similar to the Author Identification task at PAN 2013, described in <ref type="bibr" coords="1,241.80,580.34,10.58,8.97" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Methodology</head><p>We use an ensemble of our proximity-based one-class classifiers. The method is described in detail in <ref type="bibr" coords="1,212.21,644.17,10.58,8.97" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. For the purpose of self-containment we describe our algorithm below.</p><p>Let A = {d 1 , ..., d k }, k ≥ 2, be a set of "known" documents written by a given author. Let u be the questioned document which authorship we are to verify.</p><p>Our algorithm is a proximity-based one-class classification algorithm, based on an idea resembling the idea of the k-centers algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="2,367.87,154.86,10.79,8.97" target="#b8">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,378.66,154.86,7.19,8.97" target="#b7">7]</ref>. The algorithm calculates for each known document d i the maximum dissimilarity between this document and all other known documents D max (d i , A) as well as the dissimilarity between this document and the questioned document D(d i , u), and finally the dissimilarity ratio</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,134.77,201.40,109.11,14.85">r(d i , u, A) = D(di,u) D max (di,A) .</formula><p>We apply a threshold θ on the value of M (u, A) that is the average of the r(d i , u, A) over all known documents d i , i = 1, ..., k. We classify u as written by the same author as known documents iff M (u, A) &lt;= θ. Specifically, we linearly scale the average dissimilarity ratio M (u, A) using the threshold θ, so that the value of M equal to θ corresponds to the score 0.5, values greater than θ correspond to the scores between 0 and 0.5, and values less than θ correspond to the scores between 0.5 and 1 (a cutoff is applied, i.e. all values of M (u, A) &lt; θcutoff are mapped to the score 1, and all values of M (u, A) &gt; θ + cutoff are mapped to the score 0).</p><p>For the dissimilarity measure between documents we use the Common N-Gram (CNG) dissimilarity, proposed by Kešelj et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,318.26,313.56,10.58,8.97" target="#b4">[4]</ref>. For each document a sequence of the most common n-grams (of characters or words) coupled with their frequencies (normalized by the length of the document) is extracted; such a sequence is called a profile of the document. The dissimilarity between two documents of the profiles P 1 and P 2 is defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,214.10,377.88,266.49,34.50">D(P 1 , P 2 ) = x∈(P1∪P2) f P1 (x) -f P2 (x) fP 1 (x)+fP 2 (x) 2 2<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where x is an n-gram from the union of two profiles, and f Pi (x) is the normalized frequency of the n-gram x in the the profile P i , i = 1, 2 (f Pi (x) = 0 whenever x does not appear in the profile P i ).</p><p>If there is only one known document, we cut it in half to obtain two known documents. We also truncate all documents in a given problem to the length of the shortest one. We also make sure that each profile for a given problem has exactly the same length in cases when the number of distinct n-grams in any of the documents within given problem is less than the requested length of the profiles.</p><p>Ensembles comprise of such classifiers that differ between themselves in at least one of the following parameters: type of the tokens in n-grams (characters or words), the length of n-grams, the length of profiles. We used ensembles with weighted voting <ref type="bibr" coords="2,150.49,554.48,11.62,8.97" target="#b0">[1]</ref> in the competition submission. The output probability score of an ensemble is an arithmetic average of the scores of the single classifiers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Selection of classifiers using training data</head><p>We select classifiers for the ensembles separately for each corpus, based on their performance on the training datasets. We investigate performance of classifiers, varying their parameters. The tokens were utf8-encoded characters or turned to uppercase words. For classifiers based on characters the length of n-grams varied from 3 to 10. For classifiers based on word n-grams the length of n-grams varied from 1 to 6. The of profiles was in {200, 500, 1000, 1500, 2000, 2500, 3000} for both kinds of tokens. This space of parameters results in 98 single classifiers: 56 character-based ones and 42 word-based ones. Package Text::Ngrams <ref type="bibr" coords="3,250.12,154.86,11.62,8.97" target="#b3">[3]</ref> has been used in the software. For scaling of M values to the probability scores the cutoff was set to 0.2.</p><p>We select for each training corpora separately a fixed odd number of 31 classifiers that yield the best AUC. Subsequently for each of those classifiers the optimal threshold is found (i.e., the threshold for which the maximum accuracy is achieved). In an ensemble for a given corpus, the threshold for all classifiers is set to one value: the average of the optimal thresholds on the training data for the selected single classifiers.</p><p>The ranges of AUC and of maximum accuracy (accuracy at the optimum threshold) for the sets of 31 classifiers are presented in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,335.97,250.50,3.74,8.97" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. We observe that our method performs best for the training corpus for Dutch essays and Spanish articles. It performs worse on the Greek articles set. For the sets of English novels and Dutch reviews the performance is low. Most likely the reason behind that lies in the fact that in these two sets all but one problem have exactly one known document. We observed that such problems are especially challenging for our method. This is most likely because the two halves of a single known document, that we compare the questioned document with, are much more similar to each other than two different documents written by the same person. The reasons behind the low results on the English essays set are not clear to us and require further investigation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Competition results</head><p>The results of our submission on the PAN 2014 evaluation set for the Author Identification tasks are presented in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,278.75,656.12,3.74,8.97" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. Similarly as in our experiments on the training data, the sets of English novels, English essays and Dutch reviews were most challenging for our method, as discussed in section 3. On the English novel set the ensemble achieved a noticeable lower AUC value then the separate classifiers on the training data. Our method performed better on the sets of Dutch essays, Spanish articles, and Greek articles. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,134.77,281.04,345.83,178.72"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Results of experiments on the training corpora in the PAN 2014 competition task Author Identification.</figDesc><table coords="3,143.89,314.95,322.28,144.81"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">range of results of 31 classifiers</cell><cell cols="3">parameters of the classifier</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">with the highest AUC</cell><cell cols="3">with the highest AUC</cell></row><row><cell>training corpus</cell><cell>AUC</cell><cell cols="2">maximum accuracy token</cell><cell>n-gram length</cell><cell>profile length</cell></row><row><cell>Dutch essays</cell><cell>0.82 -0.86</cell><cell>0.77 -0.83</cell><cell>character</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>500</cell></row><row><cell>Dutch reviews</cell><cell>0.54 -0.56</cell><cell>0.55 -0.59</cell><cell>character</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>200</cell></row><row><cell>English essays</cell><cell>0.52 -0.55</cell><cell>0.52 -0.58</cell><cell>word</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>3000</cell></row><row><cell>English novels</cell><cell>0.64 -0.74</cell><cell>0.62 -0.71</cell><cell>word</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>500</cell></row><row><cell>Greek articles</cell><cell>0.68 -0.79</cell><cell>0.66 -0.77</cell><cell>word</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>500</cell></row><row><cell>Spanish articles</cell><cell>0.82 -0.85</cell><cell>0.76 -0.80</cell><cell>word</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>500</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,134.77,195.56,345.82,144.85"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>The results of our submission in the PAN 2014 competition task Author Identification (as announced on June 11, 2014). The final score is the product of the values of AUC and c@1.</figDesc><table coords="4,184.03,231.32,235.34,109.09"><row><cell></cell><cell>AUC</cell><cell>c@1</cell><cell>final score</cell></row><row><cell>Dutch essays</cell><cell>0.86892</cell><cell>0.84201</cell><cell>0.73165</cell></row><row><cell>Dutch reviews</cell><cell>0.6376</cell><cell>0.56</cell><cell>0.35706</cell></row><row><cell>English essays</cell><cell>0.5179</cell><cell>0.54837</cell><cell>0.284</cell></row><row><cell>English novels</cell><cell>0.49125</cell><cell>0.45727</cell><cell>0.22464</cell></row><row><cell>Greek articles</cell><cell>0.7308</cell><cell>0.68</cell><cell>0.49694</cell></row><row><cell>Spanish articles</cell><cell>0.8026</cell><cell>0.73</cell><cell>0.5859</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.13,420.11,336.65,8.07;4,146.48,431.07,328.46,8.07;4,146.48,442.02,146.67,8.07" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,284.25,420.11,190.53,8.07;4,146.48,431.07,66.40,8.07">Author Verification Using Common N-Gram Profiles of Text Documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jankowska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Milios</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kešelj</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,231.63,431.07,243.30,8.07;4,146.48,442.02,92.39,8.07">Proceedings of the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics. COLING &apos;14</title>
		<meeting>the 25th International Conference on Computational Linguistics. COLING &apos;14</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-08">August 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.13,452.53,316.01,8.07" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,236.90,452.53,182.62,8.07">Overview of the Author Identification Task at PAN</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Juola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,146.48,463.50,326.83,8.07;4,146.48,474.46,84.16,8.07" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,284.88,463.50,188.42,8.07;4,146.48,474.46,17.43,8.07">Working Notes Papers of the CLEF 2013 Evaluation Labs</title>
		<editor>Forner, P., Navigli, R., Tufis, D.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-09">September 2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.13,484.97,331.95,8.07" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,185.94,484.97,97.73,8.07">Perl Package Text::Ngrams</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kešelj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.cs.dal.ca/vlado/srcperl/Ngrams" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.13,495.48,338.70,8.07;4,146.48,506.44,306.00,8.07;4,146.48,517.40,334.14,8.07;4,146.48,528.36,52.05,8.07" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,313.01,495.48,163.82,8.07;4,146.48,506.44,38.42,8.07">N-gram-based Author Profiles for Authorship Attribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kešelj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Peng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Cercone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,202.84,506.44,249.64,8.07;4,146.48,517.40,91.48,8.07">Proceedings of the Conference Pacific Association for Computational Linguistics, PACLING&apos;03</title>
		<meeting>the Conference Pacific Association for Computational Linguistics, PACLING&apos;03<address><addrLine>Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-08">August 2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="264" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Dalhousie University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.13,538.87,259.92,8.07;4,146.48,549.83,310.69,8.07" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.uni-weimar.de/medien/webis/research/events/pan-14/pan14-web/author-identification.html" />
		<title level="m" coord="4,168.32,538.87,60.68,8.07">PAN competition</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Author Identification</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.13,560.35,332.84,8.07;4,146.48,571.30,323.25,8.07;4,146.48,582.26,298.23,8.07;4,146.48,593.22,170.18,8.07" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,232.41,560.35,153.38,8.07">A Simple Measure to Assess Non-response</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Peñas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rodrigo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,404.23,560.35,66.74,8.07;4,146.48,571.30,323.25,8.07;4,146.48,582.26,52.92,8.07;4,298.87,582.26,29.49,8.07">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies<address><addrLine>Stroudsburg, PA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011-06">June 2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1415" to="1424" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>HLT &apos;11</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.13,603.73,324.56,8.07;4,146.48,614.70,204.73,8.07" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,177.64,603.73,281.19,8.07">One Class Classification. Concept-learning in the absence of counter-examples</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Tax</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-06">June 2001</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Delft University of Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Ph.D. thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.13,625.21,301.48,8.07;4,146.48,636.16,323.27,8.07;4,146.48,647.12,126.30,8.07" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,266.31,625.21,157.02,8.07">Support Objects for Domain Approximation</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ypma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ypma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Duin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,146.48,636.16,252.77,8.07">Proceedings of International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks</title>
		<meeting>International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks<address><addrLine>Skovde, Sweden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998-09">September 1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="4" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
