<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,89.29,84.74,402.86,15.42;1,89.29,106.66,359.06,15.42">Semi-supervised Multi-Label Classification with 3D CBAM Resnet for Tuberculosis Cavern Report</title>
				<funder ref="#_CcyymKs">
					<orgName type="full">in Military Medicine Program</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_vtyKywf">
					<orgName type="full">Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,88.90,134.97,39.24,11.96"><forename type="first">Xing</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,140.78,134.97,35.88,11.96"><forename type="first">An</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
							<email>ayan@eng.ucsd.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,189.30,134.97,64.39,11.96"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
							<email>e8chang@health.ucsd.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">San Diego VA Health Care System</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,271.62,134.97,74.05,11.96"><forename type="first">Chun-Nan</forename><surname>Hsu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">San Diego VA Health Care System</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,363.60,134.97,75.50,11.96"><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Mcauley</surname></persName>
							<email>jmcauley@eng.ucsd.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,451.74,134.97,42.73,11.96"><forename type="first">Jiang</forename><surname>Du</surname></persName>
							<email>jiangdu@health.ucsd.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,113.26,148.92,80.84,11.96"><forename type="first">Amilcare</forename><surname>Gentili</surname></persName>
							<email>agentili@ucsd.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">San Diego VA Health Care System</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,89.29,84.74,402.86,15.42;1,89.29,106.66,359.06,15.42">Semi-supervised Multi-Label Classification with 3D CBAM Resnet for Tuberculosis Cavern Report</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">1613-0073</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">F344CDC56E1D46C6B942F4EB00CBCC9D</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T16:23+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Tuberculosis Cavern</term>
					<term>3D Convolutional Neural Network</term>
					<term>Semi-supervised Learning</term>
					<term>Attention Mechanism</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Detection and characterization of tuberculosis and the evaluation of lesion characteristics are challenging. To provide a solution for a multi-label classification task of tuberculosis cavern report task, we performed a deep learning study with backbones of 3D Resnet. Semi-supervised learning strategy was implied in this study to leverage the unlabeled dataset from cavern detection task. A convolutional block attention model (CBAM) was used to add an attention mechanism in each block of the Resnet to further improve the performance of the convolutional neural network (CNN). Our solution is ranked the 1st place with submissions obtained Mean_AUC of 0.687 and 0.681 for this task.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Tuberculosis (TB) is a bacterial infection caused by the germ Mycobacterium tuberculosis, and is a leading cause of death from infectious disease worldwide. An epidemic in many developing regions, such as Africa and Southeast Asia, it was responsible for 1.6 million deaths in 2017 alone. There are different manifestations of TB which require different treatments, making the detection and characterization of TB disease and the evaluation of lesion characteristics critically important tasks in the monitoring, control, and treatment of this disease. An accurate and automated method for classification of TB from CT images may be especially useful in regions of the world with few radiologists.</p><p>The ImageCLEF 2022 Tuberculosis task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,284.94,512.86,11.49,10.91" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,299.98,512.86,9.03,10.91" target="#b1">2]</ref> includes two sub-tasks. The first sub-task is lung cavern regions detection,participants must detect lung cavern regions in lung CT images associated with lung tuberculosis; The second sub-task is caverns classification problem. Participants must predict 3 binary features of caverns suggested by experienced radiologists.</p><p>We tried both tasks, but the detection task is too tight in a limited time and we didn't get very reasonable results, so we focused on report our efforts for the second task, which we used our preciously developed 3D CBAM Resnet model and a semi-supervised training strategy to leverage the uncategorized cavern regions that provided in the detection task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Semi-supervised training strategy</head><p>For this task, the most challenge comes from the small dataset provided by the organizer for training, which only included 60 in total. But luckily, they also provided a relative larger dataset for the detection task, so we wondered if we could leverage this detection dataset for the report task. As shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,207.43,247.86,3.81,10.91" target="#fig_0">1</ref>, we adopted a semi-supervised training strategy for this task to use both datasets of detection and the report task. Firstly, we randomly split the dataset of report task into train/validation cohort with a ratio of 4:1. Then we use the train cohort to train the model and obtain a best performance model m using the validation cohort. This model m was then used to infer on the unlabeled lesion that obtained from the detection task dataset to generate a pseudo-label for each lesion. Finally, the model m will be trained on the combined dataset to generate a final model M. Then the model M will be used to do the inference on the Test dataset that provided by the organizer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Model and Training</head><p>The dataset provided for the report task training set contained a total of 60 patients, with labeling provided for 3 categories: thick walls, calcification, foci, on a patient level. Also the bounding box(bbox) of the carven lesion is provided along with two type of lung masks are provided. To prepare the data to feed into our classification model, the original NIFTI-formatted dataset was transformed into image data using the NiBabel package as the first step. Then, the reformatted images were adjusted to three different window levels, namely baseline, lung, and soft tissue, and then normalized. For baseline window level, the foreground was obtained via the Otsu thresholding algorithm provided in openCV package; for lung and soft tissue, the image levels were set as [-600,1500] and [50,350], respectively. Then, images were normalized to [0,1] with their mean and std value. Finally, the bbox provided were used to crop the lesion area and all three windows and levels of data were saved, and annotation file were rearranged for use in further training.</p><p>In this study, a 3D convolutional block attention module (CBAM)-Resnet was employed to train the model for 3-class multi-label classification based on the PyTorch framework. For the Resnet, same as last year <ref type="bibr" coords="2,200.09,582.12,11.23,10.91" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,213.57,582.12,7.49,10.91" target="#b3">4]</ref>, a standard 3D-resnet34 <ref type="bibr" coords="2,331.69,582.12,12.68,10.91" target="#b4">[5]</ref> was used as the convolutional neural network backbone, with three fc layers to be the classifier. CBAM <ref type="bibr" coords="2,387.46,595.66,12.84,10.91" target="#b5">[6]</ref> was used to implement channel and spatial attention mechanisms for each block of the Resnet. Sigmoid was used as the activation function for binary classification. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Network and Training</head><p>In this study, a 3D convolutional block attention module (CBAM)-Resnet and a 3D EfficientNet were employed to train the model for 5-class classification based on the PyTorch framework. Similar to our last year's work <ref type="bibr" coords="3,228.25,518.43,11.51,10.91" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, a standard 3D-resnet34 <ref type="bibr" coords="3,355.64,518.43,12.92,10.91" target="#b4">[5]</ref> was used as the convolutional neural network (CNN) backbone, with three fc layers as the classifier. CBAM <ref type="bibr" coords="3,440.29,531.98,15.24,10.91" target="#b5">[6]</ref>was used to implement channel and spatial attention mechanisms for each block of the Resnet, and sigmoid was used as the activation function for binary classification.</p><p>To train the neural networks, we used a workstation with 4 Nvidia GTX 1080 Ti video cards, 128 GB RAM, and a 1 TB solid state drive. During the training process, to avoid overfitting, image augmentation and a balanced sampler were implemented in each batch. For the image augmentation, traditional data augmentation methods, including brightness, shear, scale, and flip, were applied. The balanced sampler strategy, which equalized the data sampled from all five classes for each batch, was adopted during the training process. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4.">Experiments and Model Selection</head><p>As the semi-supervised training process was implemented, three model selection experiments were conducted for final submissions. The first is to choose the best mean AUC that evaluated on the validation dataset. The second experiment is choose models saved at every improvement of the AUC for each category during training. The third experiment is choosing models as ensemble of previous models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Results and Submissions</head><p>The provided TST dataset including 15 patient level data with lesion bbox provided. With our pre-processing pipeline, the TST data were cropped according to the provided bbox to generate calibrated image files. After evaluation of the trained model, the results were rearranged according to the requirement and saved as the .txt file to be submitted. As mentioned in methods, for three different model choosing strategies, we have 9 saved model for evaluating the TST datasets, the performance could be seen in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,345.80,546.19,3.74,10.91" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p><p>From the results, the best Mean_AUC was achieved of 0.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Discussion and Conclusion</head><p>To provide a deep learning solution for a multi-label classification task of tuberculosis carven report with a small training dataset, we did experiments with semi-supervised 3D CBAM Resnet. There are several challenges for this task, such as the extremely small dataset that provided and 3D dimensions of CT images, so we tried several techniques to improve the model performance. First, semi-supervised training strategy was implied to get fully usage of the detection dataset that without the category labeling provided. Second, CBAM was used to add an attention mechanism in each block of the Resnet to further improve the performance of the CNN. Third, different windowing of the CT images were concatenated to make the CNN more focus on the illness features according to radiologist's experience. Using all the aforementioned techniques, we achieved a Mean_AUC of 0.687 and 0.681 in the evaluation of the test dataset, and placed 1st place in this competition task.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,89.29,433.16,287.53,8.93;3,130.96,84.19,333.37,336.41"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Semi-supervised training strategy for the cavern report task</figDesc><graphic coords="3,130.96,84.19,333.37,336.41" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,89.29,307.45,305.73,8.93;4,89.29,84.19,458.36,210.69"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Data prepare and 3D CBAM Resnet for multi-label classification</figDesc><graphic coords="4,89.29,84.19,458.36,210.69" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="4,352.51,559.74,153.47,10.91;4,89.29,573.29,416.69,10.91;4,89.29,586.83,416.69,10.91;4,89.29,600.38,167.00,10.91"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>687 by slightly correction based on the epoch 10 model, while the epoch 10 model obtained a second Mean_AUC of 0.681. The best Min_AUC was obtained by the epoch 35 model of 0.571 and epoch 51 model obtained the second high Min_AUC score of 0.524.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,88.99,90.49,367.79,144.55"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Submission model types and results</figDesc><table coords="5,138.49,118.13,318.29,116.91"><row><cell>Submission name</cell><cell>Model Description</cell><cell>Mean AUC</cell><cell>Min AUC</cell></row><row><cell>182843</cell><cell>Best on Validation</cell><cell>0.576</cell><cell>0.444</cell></row><row><cell>182852</cell><cell>Epoch 60</cell><cell>0.612</cell><cell>0.413</cell></row><row><cell>182853</cell><cell>Epoch 35</cell><cell>0.593</cell><cell>0.571</cell></row><row><cell>182854</cell><cell>Epoch 20</cell><cell>0.651</cell><cell>0.476</cell></row><row><cell>182893</cell><cell>Epoch 51</cell><cell>0.595</cell><cell>0.524</cell></row><row><cell>182894</cell><cell>Epoch 10</cell><cell>0.681</cell><cell>0.492</cell></row><row><cell>182896</cell><cell>Visual Adjustment</cell><cell>0.687</cell><cell>0.513</cell></row><row><cell>182897</cell><cell>Ensemble Nodules</cell><cell>0.660</cell><cell>0.513</cell></row><row><cell>182900</cell><cell>Ensemble Calcification</cell><cell>0.581</cell><cell>0.513</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="5.">Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was supported in part by the <rs type="funder">Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs</rs> through the <rs type="programName">Accelerating Innovation</rs> <rs type="funder">in Military Medicine Program</rs> under Award No. (<rs type="grantNumber">W81XWH-20-1-0693</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_vtyKywf">
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">Accelerating Innovation</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_CcyymKs">
					<idno type="grant-number">W81XWH-20-1-0693</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,107.59,563.55,399.59,10.91;5,107.59,577.10,400.08,10.91;5,107.59,590.65,399.60,10.91;5,107.41,604.20,398.57,10.91;5,107.59,617.75,400.24,10.91;5,107.59,631.30,398.40,10.91;5,107.59,644.85,399.60,10.91;5,107.59,658.39,89.12,10.91" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,292.03,604.20,213.95,10.91;5,107.59,617.75,247.74,10.91">Overview of the ImageCLEF 2022: Multimedia retrieval in medical, social media and nature applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Ionescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Peteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rückert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ben Abacha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G S</forename><surname>De Herrera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Friedrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bloch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Brüngel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Idrissi-Yaghir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Schäfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kozlovski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kovalev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L.-D</forename><surname>Ştefan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Constantin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dogariu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Popescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Deshayes-Chossart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Schindler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chamberlain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Campello</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,377.90,617.75,129.92,10.91;5,107.59,631.30,398.40,10.91;5,107.59,644.85,161.81,10.91">Experimental IR Meets Multilinguality, Multimodality, and Interaction, Proceedings of the 13th International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF 2022)</title>
		<title level="s" coord="5,276.45,644.85,183.53,10.91">LNCS Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Bologna, Italy</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,107.59,86.97,398.40,10.91;6,105.74,100.52,400.24,10.91;6,107.59,114.06,317.10,10.91" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,325.30,86.97,180.69,10.91;6,105.74,100.52,179.46,10.91">Overview of ImageCLEFtuberculosis 2022 -CT-based caverns detection and report</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kozlovski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Dicente Cid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kovalev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target=".org&lt;http://ceur-ws.org&gt;" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,308.26,100.52,113.82,10.91">CLEF2022 Working Notes</title>
		<title level="s" coord="6,429.57,100.52,76.42,10.91;6,107.59,114.06,99.32,10.91">CEUR Workshop Proceedings, CEUR-WS</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Bologna, Italy</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,107.59,127.61,398.40,10.91;6,107.59,141.16,398.40,10.91;6,107.59,154.71,399.60,10.91;6,107.06,168.26,400.12,10.91;6,107.59,181.81,399.60,10.91;6,107.59,195.36,238.81,10.91" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,343.94,127.61,162.05,10.91;6,107.59,141.16,398.40,10.91;6,107.59,154.71,144.04,10.91">Imageclef2020: Laterality-reduction three-dimensional cbam-resnet with balanced sampler for multi-binary classification of tuberculosis and CT auto reports</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Du</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gentili</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2696/paper_70.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,107.06,168.26,334.28,10.91">Working Notes of CLEF 2020 -Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<title level="s" coord="6,315.32,181.81,148.95,10.91">CEUR Workshop Proceedings, CEUR</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cappellato</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Eickhoff</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Névéol</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Thessaloniki, Greece</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">September 22-25, 2020. 2696. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,107.59,208.91,398.40,10.91;6,107.18,222.46,398.80,10.91;6,107.26,236.01,398.72,10.91;6,107.59,249.56,398.40,10.91;6,107.59,263.11,399.10,10.91;6,107.23,276.66,107.71,10.91" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,306.50,208.91,199.49,10.91;6,107.18,222.46,161.58,10.91">Multi-classification study of the tuberculosis with 3d cbam-resnet and efficientnet</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Du</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gentili</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2936/paper-107.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,139.16,236.01,366.82,10.91;6,107.59,249.56,78.49,10.91">Proceedings of the Working Notes of CLEF 2021 -Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<title level="s" coord="6,107.59,263.11,150.60,10.91">CEUR Workshop Proceedings, CEUR</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Faggioli</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Joly</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Maistro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Piroi</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the Working Notes of CLEF 2021 -Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum<address><addrLine>Bucharest, Romania</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">September 21st -to -24th, 2021. 2936. 2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1305" to="1309" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,107.59,290.20,400.08,10.91;6,107.59,306.20,97.35,7.90" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1512.03385</idno>
		<title level="m" coord="6,264.91,290.20,210.20,10.91">Deep residual learning for image recognition</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,107.59,317.30,400.08,10.91;6,107.59,333.29,97.35,7.90" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Woo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J.-Y</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kweon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1807.06521</idno>
		<title level="m" coord="6,275.30,317.30,201.45,10.91">Cbam: Convolutional block attention module</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
