<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,220.63,115.96,174.10,12.62">IPL at ImageCLEF 2010</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,143.07,153.65,100.87,8.74"><forename type="first">Alexandros</forename><surname>Stougiannis</surname></persName>
							<email>stougiannis@gail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Information Processing Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Athens University of Economics and Business</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>76 Patission street</addrLine>
									<postCode>10434</postCode>
									<settlement>Athens</settlement>
									<country key="GR">Greece</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,251.68,153.65,91.83,8.74"><forename type="first">Anestis</forename><surname>Gkanogiannis</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Information Processing Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Athens University of Economics and Business</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>76 Patission street</addrLine>
									<postCode>10434</postCode>
									<settlement>Athens</settlement>
									<country key="GR">Greece</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,370.92,153.65,101.37,8.74"><forename type="first">Theodore</forename><surname>Kalamboukis</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Informatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Information Processing Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Athens University of Economics and Business</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>76 Patission street</addrLine>
									<postCode>10434</postCode>
									<settlement>Athens</settlement>
									<country key="GR">Greece</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,220.63,115.96,174.10,12.62">IPL at ImageCLEF 2010</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">32757A1871A0EDF34D908FACD33D8496</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:24+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the participation of the IPL team in the ImageCLEF-2010 campaign. Our research group has participated in the ad hoc task the case-based and the modality tasks of image retrieval based only on textual data. To reach our aim we performed a quantitative evaluation of Lucene search engine using several state of the art similarity functions. Our runs performed moderately well using the MAP and the early precision (P10) metric.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This paper presents the participation of the IPL at the CLEF 2010 Image retrieval task. The main goal of the medical ImageCLEF task is to improve the retrieval of medical images from heterogeneous and multilingual document collections containing images and text. Queries are formulated with sample images and some textual description explaining the search goal.</p><p>Image retrieval systems do not currently perform as well as their text counterparts <ref type="bibr" coords="1,159.63,476.73,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Although the last decades CBIR systems have been extensively studied with significant advances they still demonstrate poor performance when applied to large databases with a wide spectrum of imaging modalities. However the retrieval performance has shown improvement by fusing the results of textual and visual techniques. This year's image collection contains approximately 77,000 images. Some records had only one image while others had many images. This situation makes a purely text-based retrieval of images problematic however, since although only one image from a record containing many images might be relevant to a query based on the content, all the images of the record will be equally retrieved, reducing in this way the precision of the search.</p><p>Most of our effort this year was concentrated in a quantitative evaluation of a search engine under several state of the art similarity functions.</p><p>Our retrieval system is based on Lucene [2]. Lucene is a very popular opensource IR toolkit, which has been used in many search-related applications. Our evaluation was relied on the CLEF-2009 image collection. This test collection contains a set of about 74000 images, a set of 25 topics and the relevance judgements.</p><p>To achieve this goal we incorporated within the lucene search engine three similarity functions, as will see in more details in the next section, namely the BM25, the axiomatic similarity function and the document pivoted normalization function.</p><p>Each figure in the database represented in XML format as the following simple example.</p><p>simple record &lt; record &gt; &lt; pmid &gt; 12345 &lt; /pmid &gt; &lt; articleurl &gt; http : //www.someurl.com/somearticle.html</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,134.77,275.04,206.94,176.11">&lt; /articleurl &gt; &lt; caption &gt; somecaption &lt; /caption &gt; &lt; f igureid &gt; f ig.xyz &lt; /f igureid &gt; &lt; f igureids &gt; &lt; f igureidss &gt; f ig.xyz.a &lt; /f igureidss &gt; &lt; f igureidss &gt; f ig.xyz.b &lt; /f igureidss &gt; &lt; f igureidss &gt; f ig.xyz.c &lt; /f igureidss &gt; &lt; /f igureids &gt; &lt; meshterms &gt; &lt; meshterm &gt; meshterm1 &lt; /meshterm &gt; &lt; meshterm &gt; meshterm2 &lt; /meshterm &gt; &lt; meshterm &gt; meshterm3 &lt; /meshterm &gt; &lt; meshterm &gt; meshterm4 &lt; /meshterm &gt; &lt; /meshterms &gt; &lt; /record &gt;</formula><p>We note that several figures referred to the same image with the same title and same captions, so we decided to unify those records into one, with one header "figureid" and the rest figures as relevant ones. Thus we have two different fields for the figures of the case (figureid, figureids), and the first one plays the role of the header figure and the rest the role of relevant figures. Moreover the title and caption of the unified figure were merged into a single field named "caption" that contains all the textual information that accompanies each figure.</p><p>For the indexing with the Lucene, we used our own Analyzer which performs tokenization, removes stop words, short words (less than 2 characters), long words (more than 50 characters), transforms each word to lower case, and performs stemming using the Porter stemmer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">AdHoc Retrieval</head><p>The ad hoc task involves retrieving relevant images using the text associated to each image query. For this task we investigated four similarity functions with the lucene search engine: the default similarity function <ref type="bibr" coords="2,373.31,656.12,12.25,8.74" target="#b1">[3]</ref>, the BM25 <ref type="bibr" coords="2,439.28,656.12,10.52,8.74" target="#b2">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,453.02,656.12,7.01,8.74">5]</ref>, the axiomatic <ref type="bibr" coords="3,180.82,118.99,10.52,8.74" target="#b3">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,195.04,118.99,7.75,8.74" target="#b4">7]</ref> and the default with document pivoted normalization <ref type="bibr" coords="3,446.44,118.99,9.96,8.74" target="#b5">[8]</ref>. The aim was to examine the behavior of each of these similarity functions on small documents as the ones of the CLEF database. The evaluation was based on the CLEF-2009 database. In the following we give briefly the definition of each function. More details can be found in <ref type="bibr" coords="3,305.32,166.81,14.61,8.74">[11]</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,138.97,189.09,341.62,45.38">1. BM25 score(D, Q) = t∈Q∧D IDF (t) tf (t, D) • (k 1 + 1) tf (t, D) + k 1 • (1 -b + b • dl avgdl )<label>(1)</label></formula><p>The inverse document frequency is computed according to the classical BM25 model:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="3,253.59,279.43,227.00,22.31">IDF (t) = log N -n(t) + 0.5 n(t) + 0.5 (2)</formula><p>where N is the number of documents in the collection and n(t) is the number of documents where the term t appears.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Axiomatic</head><p>It has been shown in an axiomatic approach to develop retrieval functions proposed in <ref type="bibr" coords="3,206.63,358.19,10.52,8.74" target="#b3">[6]</ref> that the following scoring function ( <ref type="formula" coords="3,381.06,358.19,4.24,8.74">2</ref>) is more robust than other state-of-the-art with comparable optimal performance. The following function (F2-EXP) according to <ref type="bibr" coords="3,291.17,382.11,10.52,8.74" target="#b3">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,304.12,382.11,7.75,8.74" target="#b4">7]</ref> is one of the best performing functions.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="3,165.76,411.77,314.84,30.50">score(D, Q) = t∈Q∧D tf (t, Q) • N df (t) 0.35 tf (t, D) tf (t, D) + 0.5 + 0.5•|D| avgdl (3)</formula><p>where tf (t, Q) is the number of occurrences of term t in query Q, df (t) is the number of documents that contain term t, |D| is length of document D, and avgdl is the average document length in the collection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Document Pivoting Normalization</head><p>This approach uses the default scoring function of lucene but tf (t, D) which is given by the square root of the term frequency is now estimated by the relation ( <ref type="formula" coords="3,192.50,526.50,4.24,8.74" target="#formula_4">4</ref>)</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="3,245.46,547.21,235.13,22.31">tf (t, D) = 1 + log(f req(t, D)) 1 + log(avgF req(D))<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where avgF req(D) = 1</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="3,151.70,578.95,328.89,29.04">|U D | t∈d f req(t, D), U D =the discrete terms in D, lengthN orm = 1 √ (1-slope)•pivot+slope•|U D | and pivot = 1 |D| d∈D |U D |</formula><p>The results out of these four functions from the CLEF-2009 image-collection are presented in table <ref type="bibr" coords="3,232.56,632.14,7.75,8.74">1.</ref> In table 2 are presented the Ad Hoc runs we submitted and a short description for each one. In the AdHoc version of the Medical Retrieval, the unit of retrieval is a figure. A figure is identified by the figureid. The goal of the retrieval is to correctly retrieve the most relevant figures for each one of the 16 queries-figures. To complete this task we create indexes with the Lucene search engine using only the textual information of the figures (title + caption).</p><p>Moreover as we can see in the runs with suffix TCM the documents are expanded with the MeSH terms. In this case we have the two searchable fields. In that case we weight the two fields by ratio 0.9/0.1 in favor of "caption" over the "mesh". The scoring function is given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="4,179.56,624.25,301.04,9.65">score(Q, D) = 0.9 * score(Q, D C ) + 0.1 * score(Q, D M eSH ) (5)</formula><p>where the field D C contains the title and caption and the D M eSH the MeSH terms. In table <ref type="table" coords="5,187.65,470.12,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_2">3</ref> and 4 we present the top 10 performing participations in the Ad Hoc track based on the MAP metric and the early precision (P@10).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Case based Retrieval</head><p>In the Case-based version of the Medical Retrieval, the unit of the retrieval is not an image but a case. Cases are identified by a PubMed id ("pmid" tag in the xml format). Unfortunately not all cases are marked with a "pmid", so the identifier is the "ArticleURL" tag of the xml format. In other words, a case is pointed by a link in the web of an article that describes it.</p><p>A simple fusion method has been implemented to obtain a simple list of relevant figures. The total score of each relevant document is calculated by the sum of the scores for all the retrieved figures in the document:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7" coords="5,239.66,647.67,240.92,20.06">score(Q, D) = F ∈D score(Q, F )<label>(6)</label></formula><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="6,223.71,115.91,4.13,7.89">5</ref>. Case based runs on the 2010 image collection.</p><p>Ad Hoc -submitted runs Description ipl aueb casebased CT Unified caption and title "contents" searchable field ipl aueb casebased CTM 0.1 "contents" and "mesh" terms searchable fields, 0.1 ratio of "mesh" ipl aueb casebased CTM 0.2 "contents" and "mesh" terms searchable fields, 0.2 ratio of "mesh" ipl aueb casebased CTM 0.3 "contents" and "mesh" terms searchable fields, 0.3 ratio of "mesh" ipl aueb casebased CTM 0.4 "contents" and "mesh" terms searchable fields, 0.4 ratio of "mesh" ipl aueb casebased CTM 0.5 "contents" and "mesh" terms searchable fields, 0.5 ratio of "mesh" Finally, the documents are sorted by their final fusion score. Table <ref type="table" coords="6,177.68,496.91,4.98,8.74">5</ref> summarizes the runs we submitted and a short description for the Case-based task.</p><p>Similarly in this case we use two types of indexes. For the first type, only the field "contents" (title+caption) is searchable. At the retrieval phase we get the top 1000 results and iterate over them to add the score of the results with the same "articleurl". This procedure produces the run named "ipl aueb casebased CT".</p><p>In the second type of indexes, there is an additional searchable field "mesh", we performed 5 runs. The number in the run's name denotes the weight given in the "mesh" field. A value 0.1 means a weight 0.1 for the score of the "mesh" field and 0.9 for the score of the "contents" field.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="6,176.57,632.21,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_4">6</ref> contains the top 10 performing participations in the case-based track based on the MAP metric. IPL was at the 28 th position at the sequence with MAP equal to 0.1228. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Modality Runs</head><p>For the task of modality classification, a list of 2,390 records was given for training. The goal was to correctly classify the 2,620 records of the test set into one of the eight modalities: "CT" , "GX" , "MR" , "NM" , "PET" , "PX" , "US", "XR". We used two classifiers on this task: a modified Perceptron-type algorithm we have described in previous work <ref type="bibr" coords="7,293.36,315.60,10.52,8.74" target="#b6">[9]</ref> and the well known SVM classifier <ref type="bibr" coords="7,462.33,315.60,14.60,8.74" target="#b7">[10]</ref>. Again we used two types of indexes, with and without MeSH terms. Table <ref type="table" coords="7,475.61,327.56,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_5">7</ref> contains our results of the modality classification 5 Conclusions Our baseline textual system performed quite well, with a MAP of 32%. We will continue to improve our image retrieval system by adding more image tags using automatic visual feature extraction and heuristics. There was only a minimal improvement in performance with the use of the image modality. As future research we plan to improve the pseudo-relevance feedback strategy.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,147.58,115.91,320.20,152.64"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Performance of scoring functions on the CLEF-2009 image collection.</figDesc><table coords="4,202.93,147.48,209.49,121.06"><row><cell cols="5">CLEF-2009 Deafult BM25 Axiomatic Pivoted</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Lucene</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Norm</cell></row><row><cell>numrel</cell><cell>2362</cell><cell>2362</cell><cell>2362</cell><cell>2362</cell></row><row><cell>numrelret</cell><cell>1844</cell><cell>1812</cell><cell>1847</cell><cell>1847</cell></row><row><cell>map</cell><cell cols="2">0.4070 0.3513</cell><cell>0.3835</cell><cell>0.4132</cell></row><row><cell>R-prec</cell><cell cols="2">0.4462 0.3827</cell><cell>0.4169</cell><cell>0.4546</cell></row><row><cell>bpref</cell><cell cols="2">0.4297 0.3614</cell><cell>0.3979</cell><cell>0.4390</cell></row><row><cell>P5</cell><cell cols="2">0.6800 0.6160</cell><cell>0.6480</cell><cell>0.6880</cell></row><row><cell>P10</cell><cell cols="2">0.6040 0.5760</cell><cell>0.6040</cell><cell>0.6520</cell></row><row><cell>P20</cell><cell cols="2">0.6060 0.5340</cell><cell>0.5720</cell><cell>0.6080</cell></row><row><cell>P30</cell><cell cols="2">0.5720 0.5107</cell><cell>0.5293</cell><cell>0.5627</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,141.67,284.49,332.01,195.28"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Ad Hoc runs on the 2010 image collection.</figDesc><table coords="4,141.67,316.06,332.01,163.71"><row><cell cols="2">Ad Hoc -submitted runs Description</cell></row><row><cell>ipl aueb AdHoc default TC</cell><cell>Default Lucene Indexing,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>one searchable field ("caption")</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ipl aueb adhoq Pivoting TC Pivoting normalization Lucene indexing,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>one searchable field ("caption")</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ipl aueb adhoq default TCg Default Lucene Indexing,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>one searchable field ("caption"),</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>alternative method for duplicate figures recognition</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ipl aueb adhoq Pivoting TCg Pivoting normalization Lucene indexing,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>one searchable field ("caption"),</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>alternative method for duplicate figures recognition</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ipl aueb adhoq default TCM Default Lucene Indexing,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>two searchable fields ("caption", "mesh")</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ipl aueb adhoq Pivoting TCM Pivoting normalization Lucene indexing,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>two searchable fields ("caption", "mesh")</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,172.48,115.91,270.39,153.04"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Ad Hoc top 10 performing participations based on MAP.</figDesc><table coords="5,209.58,147.48,196.20,121.46"><row><cell>Run name</cell><cell>MAP</cell></row><row><cell>XRCE AX rerank comb,trec</cell><cell>0.3572</cell></row><row><cell>WIKI AX MOD late,trec</cell><cell>0.3380</cell></row><row><cell>ipl aueb AdHoc default TC</cell><cell>0.3235</cell></row><row><cell>ipl aueb adhoq default TCg</cell><cell>0.3225</cell></row><row><cell>ipl aueb adhoq default TCM</cell><cell>0.3209</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">XRCE CHI2 LOGIT IMG MOD late,trec 0.3167</cell></row><row><cell>ipl aueb AdHoc pivoting TC</cell><cell>0.3155</cell></row><row><cell>ipl aueb adhoq Pivoting TCg</cell><cell>0.3145</cell></row><row><cell>XRCE AF LGD IMG late,trec</cell><cell>0.3119</cell></row><row><cell>ipl aueb adhoq Pivoting TCM</cell><cell>0.3102</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,172.48,286.11,270.39,153.04"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Ad Hoc top 10 performing participations based on MAP.</figDesc><table coords="5,231.53,317.68,152.30,121.46"><row><cell>Run name</cell><cell>P@10</cell></row><row><cell>WIKI AX MOD late,trec</cell><cell>0.5062</cell></row><row><cell>ipl aueb AdHoc default TC</cell><cell>0.4687</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ipl aueb adhoq default TCM 0.4687</cell></row><row><cell>ipl aueb adhoq default TCg</cell><cell>0.4562</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ipl aueb AdHoc pivoting TC 0.4500</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ipl aueb adhoq Pivoting TCg 0.4500</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ipl aueb adhoq Pivoting TCM 0.4375</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">XRCE AX rerank comb,trec 0.4375</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">XRCE AF LGD IMG late,trec 0.4375</cell></row><row><cell>OHSU pm major all mod</cell><cell>0.4375</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="6,165.64,297.58,284.07,153.04"><head>Table 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Case-based top-10 performing participations based on MAP.</figDesc><table coords="6,207.56,329.15,200.24,121.46"><row><cell>Run name</cell><cell>MAP</cell></row><row><cell>PhybaselinefbWMR 10 0.2sub</cell><cell>0.3165</cell></row><row><cell>baselinefbWMR 10 0.2sub</cell><cell>0.2926</cell></row><row><cell>PhybaselinefbWsub</cell><cell>0.2699</cell></row><row><cell>PhybaselinefbWMD 25 0.2sub</cell><cell>0.2699</cell></row><row><cell>baselinefbWsub</cell><cell>0.2553</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">IRIT SemAnnotator-1.5.2 BM25 N34 1.res 0.2521</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">IRIT SemAnnotator-2.0 BM25 N34 1.res 0.2521</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">IRIT SemAnnotator-1.5.2 BM25 N34.res 0.2444</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">IRIT SemAnnotator-2.0 BM25 N28 1.res 0.2444</cell></row><row><cell>PhybaselineRelfbWMR 10 0.2sub</cell><cell>0.2435</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="7,203.22,115.91,208.91,84.89"><head>Table 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>IPL's Modality results based on accuracy.</figDesc><table coords="7,234.95,147.48,145.31,53.32"><row><cell>Run name</cell><cell>Accuracy</cell></row><row><cell>ipl aueb rhcpp full CT</cell><cell>0.74</cell></row><row><cell>ipl aueb rhcpp full CTM</cell><cell>0.71</cell></row><row><cell>ipl aueb svm full CT</cell><cell>0.53</cell></row><row><cell>ipl aueb svm full CTM</cell><cell>0.49</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,142.85,500.34,337.74,8.74;7,151.70,512.30,328.89,8.74;7,151.70,524.25,57.00,8.74" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,274.53,500.34,206.06,8.74;7,151.70,512.30,165.98,8.74">Advancing biomedical image retrieval: development and analysis of a test collection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hersh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,325.83,512.30,125.07,8.74">J. Am. Med. Inform. Assoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="488" to="496" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,142.85,548.31,165.77,8.74;7,151.70,560.26,256.32,8.74;7,151.70,572.22,128.79,8.74" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://lucene.apache.org/java/301/api/core/org/apache/lucene/search/Similarity.html" />
		<title level="m" coord="7,151.70,548.31,152.64,8.74">Lucene&apos;s default similarity function</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,142.85,584.24,337.75,8.74;7,151.70,596.20,328.89,8.74;7,151.70,608.15,238.00,8.74" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,364.07,584.24,116.52,8.74;7,151.70,596.20,269.47,8.74">A probabilistic model of information retrieval: development and comparative experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">Sparck</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,429.09,596.20,51.50,8.74;7,151.70,608.15,102.59,8.74">Information Processing Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="809" to="840" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,142.85,632.21,337.74,8.74;7,151.70,644.16,328.89,8.74;7,151.70,656.12,213.70,8.74" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,244.99,632.21,235.60,8.74;7,151.70,644.16,34.83,8.74">An exploration of axiomatic approaches to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,207.29,644.16,273.30,8.74;7,151.70,656.12,183.49,8.74">Proceedings of the 2005 ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 2005 ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.85,118.99,337.75,8.74;8,151.70,130.95,105.02,8.74" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,151.70,118.99,238.02,8.74">Evaluation of the Default Similarity Function in Lucene</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Chengxiang</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-07-15">July 15, 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.85,142.90,337.74,8.74;8,151.70,154.86,328.89,8.74;8,151.70,166.81,282.58,8.74" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,151.70,142.90,174.66,8.74">Pivoted Document Length Normalization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Singhal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,151.70,154.86,328.89,8.74;8,151.70,166.81,219.51,8.74">Proceedings of the 19th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 19th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="29" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.85,178.77,337.74,8.74;8,151.70,190.72,328.89,8.74;8,151.70,202.68,328.89,8.74;8,151.70,214.64,328.89,8.74;8,151.70,226.59,134.24,8.74" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,319.62,178.77,160.97,8.74;8,151.70,190.72,328.89,8.74;8,151.70,202.68,18.30,8.74">A modified and fast Perceptron learning rule and its use for Tag Recommendations in Social Bookmarking Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gkanogiannis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kalamboukis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,346.99,202.68,133.60,8.74;8,151.70,214.64,302.56,8.74">ECML PKDD Discovery Challenge 2009 (DC09), International Workshop at the ECML/PKDD in</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><surname>Folke Eisterlehner</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Bled, Slovenia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-09-07">September 7th, 2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.48,238.55,338.11,8.74;8,151.70,250.50,328.89,8.74;8,151.70,262.46,114.29,8.74" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,214.76,238.55,265.82,8.74;8,151.70,250.50,51.32,8.74">Making large-scale support vector machine learning practical in Scholkopf</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Joachims</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,248.76,250.50,227.64,8.74">Advances in kernel methods: support vector learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="184" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
