<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,130.41,146.21,342.18,18.08;1,232.40,168.13,138.18,18.08">GEOUJA System. University of Jaén at GEOCLEF 2007</title>
				<funder ref="#_CGU5GYQ">
					<orgName type="full">Spanish Government (MCYT)</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,95.98,203.19,92.61,10.46"><forename type="first">José</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Perea-Ortega</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">SINAI Group. Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,196.54,203.19,124.06,10.46"><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">SINAI Group. Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,328.76,203.19,86.76,10.46"><forename type="first">Manuel</forename><surname>García-Vega</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">SINAI Group. Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,423.50,203.19,93.19,10.46"><forename type="first">Arturo</forename><surname>Montejo-Ráez</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">SINAI Group. Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,130.41,146.21,342.18,18.08;1,232.40,168.13,138.18,18.08">GEOUJA System. University of Jaén at GEOCLEF 2007</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">00D3BA98D14ADAE41453739FB1D35A37</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:14+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.3 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: H.3.1 Content Analysis and Indexing</term>
					<term>H.3.3 Information Search and Retrieval</term>
					<term>H.3.4 Systems and Software</term>
					<term>H.3.7 Digital Libraries Algorithms, Languages, Performance, Experimentation Information Retrieval, Geographic Information Retrieval, Named Entity Recognition, GeoCLEF</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the second participation of the SINAI group of the University of Jaén in GeoCLEF 2007. We have developed a system different from the one presented in GeoCLEF 2006. Our architecture is made up of five main modules. The first one is the Information Retrieval Subsystem, that works with collections and queries in English and returns relevant documents for a query. The queries that are not in English are translated by the Translation Subsystem. All the queries are filtered by the Geo-Relation Finder Subsystem, that finds any spatial relation in the topic, and NER (Named Entities Recognition) Subsystem, that looks for any location in the topic. The most important module is the Geo-Relation Validator Subsystem, it applies some heuristics to filter documents recovered by the IR Subsystem. We have made several runs, combining these modules to resolve the monolingual and the bilingual tasks. The results obtained show that the heuristics applied are quite restrictive and therefore it must be generated new heuristics and to improve the definition of new rules to filter recovered documents.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The objective of GeoCLEF is to evaluate Geographical Information Retrieval (GIR) systems in tasks that involve both spatial and multilingual aspects. Given a multilingual statement describing a spatial user need (topic), the challenge is to find relevant documents from target collections in English, but with topics in English, Spanish, German or Portuguese <ref type="bibr" coords="1,406.66,694.80,9.96,10.46" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. This is our second participation in GeoCLEF, after the previous year <ref type="bibr" coords="1,307.05,706.75,11.84,10.46" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p><p>In the last edition we studied the behavior of query expansion. The results obtained showed us that filtering improves precision and recall. For this reason, our system consists of five subsystems: Translation, Geographical Relations Finder, NER, Validator and Information Retrieval.</p><p>The most important one is the Validator module. The list of relevant documents is filtered using it: if a document doesn't pass the validation test it is removed from the list. Next section describes the whole system. Then, in the section 3, each module of the system is explained. Later on, results are described and finally, the conclusions about our participation in GeoCLEF 2007 are expounded.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System overview</head><p>We propose a Geographical Information Retrieval System that is made up of five related subsystems. These modules are explained in detail in the next section.</p><p>In our architecture we only worked with the English collection<ref type="foot" coords="2,376.17,235.82,3.97,7.32" target="#foot_0">1</ref> and we have applied a off-line preprocess to it. This preprocess consists in using the English stop-words list, a named entity recognizer (NER) and the Porter stemmer <ref type="bibr" coords="2,279.83,260.81,9.96,10.46" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. The preprocessed data set will be indexed later using the IR Subsystem.</p><p>The translated query or topic proposed is indexed using the IR Subsystem too. If the language of topic is different from English, then it is translated by means of the Translation Subsystem. For each translated query to evaluate we labeled it with NER and geo-relation information. The Geo-Relation Finder Subsystem (GR Finder Subsystem) extracts spatial relations from the geographic query and the NER Subsystem recognizes named entities.</p><p>From the original English query the documents are recovered by the IR Subsystem that previously indexed the data collection. The NER information and the geo-relation components in relevant documents, and the NER locations from the geographic query are the input for Geo-Relation Validator Subsystem (GR Validator Subsystem), the most important module in our architecture.</p><p>In the GR Validator Subsystem we eliminate those relevant documents previously retrieved that do not agree with several rules. These rules are related to all the information that handles this module (locations and spatial relations from documents and geographic queries) and are explained in section 3.4. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,230.81,440.13,4.98,10.46" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows the proposed system architecture.</p><p>3 Subsystems description</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Translation Subsystem</head><p>As translation module, we have used SINTRAM (SINai TRAnslation Module) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,423.58,515.14,13.59,10.46" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. This subsystem translates the queries from several languages into English. SINTRAM uses some on-line Machine Translators for each language pair and implements some heuristics to combine the different translations. After a complete research the best translators were found to be </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">NER Subsystem</head><p>The main goal of NER Subsystem is to detect and recognize the entities appearing in the queries. We are only interested in geographical information, so we have just used locations detected by this NER Module. We have used the NER module of the GATE<ref type="foot" coords="2,349.31,658.84,3.97,7.32" target="#foot_1">2</ref> toolkit. The location terms includes everything that is town, city, capital, country and even continent. The NER module adds entity labels to the topics with the found locations. An entity label example recognized in the title of the topic follows: &lt; en title position = "15" type = "LOC" &gt; USA &lt; /en title &gt; The basic operation of NER Subsystem is the following:</p><p>• The first step is the preprocessing phase. Each query is preprocessed using a tokenizer, a sentence splitter and a POS tagger. The NER Subsystem we have used needs this information in order to improves the named entity detection and recognition.</p><p>• The second is the detection of the geographical places. For this proposal we have use a Gazetteer, included also in GATE.</p><p>The NER Subsystem generates some topic labels, based on the original ones, adding the locations. These topic labels will be used later by the GR Validator Subsystem.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">GR Finder Subsystem</head><p>The Geo-Relation Finder Subsystem is used to find the spatial relations in the geographic queries. This module makes use of four text files to store the geo-relations identified. Four geo-relations files exist because our system detects spatial relations of four words at the most. Some geo-relations examples are: in, near, north of, next to, in or around, in the west of... The GR Finder module adds geo-relation labels to the topics with the found spatial relations. A geo-relation label example recognized in the title of the topic would be the following one: &lt; gr title position = "43" &gt; near &lt; /gr title &gt; where position is the position of the spatial relation in the phrase.</p><p>In this module we controlled a special geo-relation named between. For this case, the GR Finder Subsystem adds the two entities that this preposition relates. An example of the label that this module adds for description label "To be relevant documents describing oil or gas production between the UK and the European continent will be relevant" is: &lt; gr desc position = "9" &gt; between the; U K; European &lt; /gr desc &gt; where we can see how both entities (UK and European) are added after the preposition, separated by a semicolon.</p><p>The basic operation of GR Finder Subsystem is the following:</p><p>• For each topic label (title, desc or narr ) the subsystem looks for some spatial relation. It makes use of the text files that store the geo-relations that can detect.</p><p>• For each found spatial relation we verified that the word that comes next is an entity. For that reason it is necessary that the NER Subsystem is executed before.</p><p>Like NER Subsystem, the GR Finder Subsystem also generates topic labels, based on the original topic, adding the spatial relations. These topic labels (entities and geo-relations) will be used later by the GR Validator Subsystem. In the Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,351.64,294.79,4.98,10.46" target="#fig_1">2</ref> we can see an example of the text that generates this subsystem. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">GR Validator Subsystem</head><p>This it is the most important module of our system. Its main goal is to discriminate what documents among the recovered ones by the IR Subsystem are valid.</p><p>In order to apply different heuristics, this module makes use of geographical data. This geoinformation has been obtained from Geonames Gazetteer<ref type="foot" coords="4,343.00,718.30,3.97,7.32" target="#foot_2">3</ref> . This module solves evaluations like:</p><p>• Find the country name of a city.</p><p>• Find the latitude and longitude for a given location.</p><p>• Check if a city belongs to a certain country.</p><p>• Check if a location is to the north of another one.</p><p>• Calculate the distance from a location to another one.</p><p>Many heuristics can be applied with the former check points to make the validation of a document recovered by the IR Subsystem. The GR Validator Subsystem receives external information from IR Subsystem (entities from each document recovered) and from GR Finder and NER Subsystems (entities and spatial relations from each topic). This year we have used the following heuristics in our experiments:</p><p>1. For every entity appearing in query without an associated geo-relation, the system checks if this entity is present in documents recovered by IR Subsystem. The module discards a document whenever the number of entities found in topic with no associated geo-relation and not appearing in that document exceeds the fifty percent of the total of topic entities.</p><p>2. If the entity appearing in the topic has associated some spatial relation, the module checks if location is a continent, a country or a city. Depending on this location type for the query, the heuristics which we have followed in our experiments are the following ones:</p><p>(a) If the location from a query is a continent or a country and its associated geo-relation is in, on, at, from, of or along, then the module checks if most of the entities of the document belong to that continent or country (at least fifty percent).</p><p>(b) If the location from a query is a city and its associated spatial relation is near, north of, south of, east of or west of, the subsystem obtains the latitude and longitude information from Geonames Gazetteer about all locations from the document to be validated. The module will check if the geographic situation of each location is valid or not depending on the topic space relation.</p><p>For each heuristic to check, the system is adding or reducing points of a final score, depending on the result of that validation. A recovered document will be considered valid when the sum of all the scores when applying the heuristics to each entity of the document is greater than zero.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">IR Subsystem</head><p>The information retrieval system that we have employed is Lemur<ref type="foot" coords="5,379.59,560.22,3.97,7.32" target="#foot_3">4</ref> . It is a toolkit that supports indexing of large-scale text databases, the construction of simple language models for documents, queries, or sub-collections, and the implementation of retrieval systems based on language models as well as a variety of other retrieval models.</p><p>Previous to the index step, the English collection provided for GeoCLEF have been preprocessed, using the English stop-words list for meaningless terms removal, and the Porter stemmer <ref type="bibr" coords="5,90.00,633.03,10.52,10.46" target="#b3">[4]</ref> for suffix stripping. A NER has also been used to recognize possible entities in each document. Next, the English collection data set has been indexed using Lemur. After indexing the collection, each topic already translated is sent to Lemur. The relevant documents retrieved and their NER information will be used by the GR Validator Subsystem.</p><p>One parameter for each experiment is the weighting function, such as Okapi <ref type="bibr" coords="5,448.38,680.85,10.52,10.46" target="#b4">[5]</ref> or TF.IDF. Another is the use or not of Pseudo-Relevant Feedback (PRF) <ref type="bibr" coords="5,365.30,692.81,9.96,10.46" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. In all experiments we have considered all tags from topics (title, description and narrative) as source for the information retrieval process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Experiment Mean Average Precision R-Precision</head><p>Our baseline experiment consists in the Lemur retrieval on preprocessed collections (stopper and stemmer ) without applying heuristics on relevant documents retrieved. This experiment has been applied in the monolingual and bilingual tasks.</p><p>The second experiment that we have made, consists in applying the heuristics that has been explained in section 3.4, on relevant documents retrieved by the IR Subsystem. This experiment also has been used in the monolingual and bilingual tasks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Monolingual task</head><p>In the monolingual task we have participated with a total of 8 experiments: four about baseline experiment (Exp1 ) and other four about second experiment applying the heuristics introduced previously in this paper(Exp2 ). Some results are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,375.38,410.85,3.87,10.46" target="#tab_1">1</ref>.</p><p>Experiments named against an ending "fb okapi " we have used Okapi with feedback as weighting function in the information retrieval process. Those ending with "fb tfidf " indicate that we have applied TF.IDF with feedback. Also we have run experiments with Okapi but without feedback ("simple okapi ") and with TF.IDF but without feedback ("simple tfidf ").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Bilingual task</head><p>In the bilingual task we have participated with a total of 18 experiments: twelve about the baseline case (Exp1 ) and six applying our heuristics (Exp2 ). Some results are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,464.54,516.91,3.87,10.46" target="#tab_2">2</ref>.</p><p>For naming the experiments we have followed the same convention described in the previous section (see section 4.1). For German-English task we submitted six experiments in total. The string "GEEN " identifies them. For Portuguese-English task we submit six experiments too, identified by the string "PTEN ". For Spanish-English task we submit six experiments in total (string "SPEN ").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions and Future work</head><p>In this paper we have presented the experiments carried out in our second participation in the GeoCLEF campaign. The philosophy followed in this second experimental study has changed with respect to the approach presented last year. This year we have introduced a very restrictive system: we have tried to eliminate those documents recovered by the IR Subsystem that do not satisfy certain validation rules. However, the previous year we were centered in increasing the queries, expanding them with entities and thesauri information in order to improve retrieval effectiveness.</p><p>The results obtained the previous year showed that query expansion does not improve in general the quality of the information retrieval process. The results of this year shown that the documents For the future, we will try to add more heuristics to the GR Validator Subsystem making use of Geonames Gazetteer. Also we will define more precise rules so that the system is less restrictive for the selection of recovered documents. Finally, we will also explore a larger number of retrieved documents by the IR Subsystem, in the aim of providing a larger variety of documents to be checked by the GR Validator Subsystem.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,213.60,377.61,175.81,10.46;3,131.42,109.09,340.10,255.08"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: GEOUJA System architecture</figDesc><graphic coords="3,131.42,109.09,340.10,255.08" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,170.54,625.71,261.92,10.46;4,131.42,328.86,340.10,283.40"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Text example generated by GR Finder Subsystem</figDesc><graphic coords="4,131.42,328.86,340.10,283.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,104.94,570.26,396.83,30.06"><head>•</head><label></label><figDesc>Systran for French, Italian and Portuguese. It is available at http://www.systransoft.com • Prompt for Spanish. It is available at http://translation2.paralink.com</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="6,90.00,121.70,423.02,145.74"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Summary of results for the monolingual task 4 Experiments and Results SINAI 5 has participated in monolingual and bilingual tasks for GeoCLEF 2007 with a total of 26 experiments.</figDesc><table coords="6,142.91,121.70,305.93,58.27"><row><cell>Sinai ENEN Exp1 fb okapi</cell><cell>0.2605</cell><cell>0.2636</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai ENEN Exp1 fb tfidf</cell><cell>0.1803</cell><cell>0.1858</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai ENEN Exp1 simple okapi</cell><cell>0.2486</cell><cell>0.2624</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai ENEN Exp1 simple tfidf</cell><cell>0.1777</cell><cell>0.1745</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai ENEN Exp2 fb tfidf</cell><cell>0.1343</cell><cell>0.1656</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="7,90.00,109.34,423.01,231.91"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Summary of results for the bilingual task that have been recovered are valid but the GR Validator Subsystem has filtered some ones that must not have eliminated.</figDesc><table coords="7,142.74,109.34,317.53,166.27"><row><cell>Experiment</cell><cell cols="2">Mean Average Precision R-Precision</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai GEEN Exp1 fb okapi</cell><cell>0.0686</cell><cell>0.0704</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai PTEN Exp1 fb okapi</cell><cell>0.1568</cell><cell>0.1519</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai SPEN Exp1 fb okapi</cell><cell>0.2362</cell><cell>0.2238</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai GEEN Exp1 fb tfidf</cell><cell>0.0572</cell><cell>0.0606</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai PTEN Exp1 fb tfidf</cell><cell>0.1080</cell><cell>0.1133</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai SPEN Exp1 fb tfidf</cell><cell>0.1511</cell><cell>0.1533</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai GEEN Exp1 simple okapi</cell><cell>0.0484</cell><cell>0.0569</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai PTEN Exp1 simple okapi</cell><cell>0.1544</cell><cell>0.1525</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai SPEN Exp1 simple okapi</cell><cell>0.2310</cell><cell>0.2476</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai GEEN Exp1 simple tfidf</cell><cell>0.0435</cell><cell>0.0420</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai PTEN Exp1 simple tfidf</cell><cell>0.1053</cell><cell>0.1117</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai SPEN Exp1 simple tfidf</cell><cell>0.1447</cell><cell>0.1513</cell></row><row><cell>Sinai PTEN Exp2 fb tfidf</cell><cell>0.0695</cell><cell>0.1074</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,105.24,736.35,290.94,8.37"><p>English Los Angeles Times 94 (LA94) and English Glasgow Herald 95 (GH95)</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,105.24,745.85,68.24,8.37"><p>http://gate.ac.uk/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="4,105.24,736.39,407.87,8.37;4,90.00,745.85,413.71,8.37"><p>http://www.geonames.org/. Geonames geographical database contains over eight million geographical names and consists of 6.3 million unique features whereof 2.2 million populated places and 1.8 million alternate names</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_3" coords="5,105.24,712.61,407.87,8.37;5,90.00,722.09,423.11,8.37;5,90.01,731.55,113.22,8.37"><p>http://www.lemurproject.org/. The toolkit is being developed as part of the Lemur Project, a collaboration between the Computer Science Department at the University of Massachusetts and the School of Computer Science at Carnegie Mellon University.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5" xml:id="foot_4" coords="6,105.24,734.40,75.39,8.37"><p>http://sinai.ujaen.es</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="6">Acknowledgments</head><p>This work has been supported by <rs type="funder">Spanish Government (MCYT)</rs> with grant <rs type="grantNumber">TIN2006-15265-C06-03</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_CGU5GYQ">
					<idno type="grant-number">TIN2006-15265-C06-03</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,512.07,407.51,10.46;7,105.50,524.02,407.51,10.46;7,105.50,535.97,362.48,10.46" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,212.18,524.02,300.83,10.46;7,105.50,535.97,18.15,10.46">Bruja system. the university of jaén at the spanish task of qa@clef 2006</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Miguel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><forename type="middle">Martínez</forename><surname>Alfonso Ureña-López</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">José</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Santiago</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Perea-Ortega</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,145.06,535.97,292.37,10.46">Proceedings of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</title>
		<meeting>the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,555.90,407.51,10.46;7,105.50,567.85,407.51,10.46;7,105.50,579.81,322.91,10.46" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,145.13,567.85,347.25,10.46">Geouja system. the first participation of the university of jaén at geoclef 2006</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Manuel</forename><surname>García-Vega</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ureña-López</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">José</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Perea-Ortega</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,105.50,579.81,292.37,10.46">Proceedings of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</title>
		<meeting>the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,599.73,407.52,10.46;7,105.50,611.70,407.50,10.46;7,105.50,623.65,407.51,10.46;7,105.50,635.60,87.50,10.46" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,283.12,611.70,229.88,10.46;7,105.50,623.65,154.45,10.46">Geoclef 2006: the clef 2006 cross-language geographic information retrieval track overview</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Fredric</forename><surname>Gey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ray</forename><surname>Larson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Sanderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Kerstin</forename><surname>Bischoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Mandl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Christa</forename><surname>Womser-Hacker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Diana</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Paulo</forename><surname>Rocha</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,281.25,623.65,231.76,10.46;7,105.50,635.60,56.95,10.46">Proceedings of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</title>
		<meeting>the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,655.53,368.27,10.46" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,164.76,655.53,140.78,10.46">An algorithm for suffix stripping</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,326.56,655.53,36.55,10.46">Program</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="130" to="137" />
			<date type="published" when="1980">1980</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,675.45,407.51,10.46;7,105.50,687.41,381.14,10.46" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,245.80,675.45,119.95,10.46">Okapi-Keenbow at TREC-8</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,392.07,675.45,120.94,10.46;7,105.50,687.41,128.11,10.46">Proceedings of the 8th Text Retrieval Conference TREC-8</title>
		<meeting>the 8th Text Retrieval Conference TREC-8</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="162" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,707.33,407.50,10.46;7,105.50,719.29,269.77,10.46" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,223.78,707.33,235.86,10.46">Improving retrieval performance by relevance feedback</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,468.30,707.33,44.70,10.46;7,105.50,719.29,185.75,10.46">Journal of American Society for Information Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="288" to="297" />
			<date type="published" when="1990">1990</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
