<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,128.23,148.86,346.55,15.15;1,127.90,170.78,347.21,15.15">TALP at GeoQuery 2007: Linguistic and Geographical Analysis for Query Parsing</title>
				<funder ref="#_8GbjTwQ">
					<orgName type="full">Spanish Research Dept</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_hhaxtfb">
					<orgName type="full">Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya</orgName>
					<orgName type="abbreviated">UPC</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_gxKSCua">
					<orgName type="full">DURSI</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Research Department of the Catalan Government</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_eVKrVSY">
					<orgName type="full">UPC-Recerca</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,220.82,204.67,57.67,8.74"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Ferrés</surname></persName>
							<email>dferres@lsi.upc.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Research Center Software Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,301.18,204.67,81.00,8.74;1,250.87,218.62,26.85,8.74"><forename type="first">Horacio</forename><forename type="middle">Rodríguez</forename><surname>Talp</surname></persName>
							<email>horacio@lsi.upc.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Research Center Software Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,128.23,148.86,346.55,15.15;1,127.90,170.78,347.21,15.15">TALP at GeoQuery 2007: Linguistic and Geographical Analysis for Query Parsing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">C8ED9782624741728275D354488BD6A6</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:14+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.3 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: H.3.1 Content Analysis and Indexing</term>
					<term>H.3.3 Information Search and Retrieval</term>
					<term>H.3.4 Systems and Software Design, Performance, Experimentation report. Information Retrieval, Passage Retrieval, Geographical Thesaurus, Gazetteers, Feature Type Thesaurus, Named Entity Recognition and Classification</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes our experiments on the Geographical Query Parsing pilot-task for English at GeoCLEF 2007. Our system uses some modules of a Geographical Information Retrieval system presented at GeoCLEF 2006 [3] and modified for GeoCLEF 2007. The system uses deep linguistic analysis and Geographical Knowledge to perform the task.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This paper describes our experiments on the Geographical Query Parsing pilot-task for English at GeoCLEF 2007. The Query Parsing task (GeoQuery) is a pilot task proposed in GEOCLEF 2007. It consists on five subtasks:</p><p>• Detect whether the query is geographic or no.</p><p>• Extract the WHERE component of the query.</p><p>• Extract the GEO-RELATION (from a set of predefined types) if present.</p><p>• Extract the WHAT component of the query and classify it as MAP, YELLOW PAGE or INFORMATION types.</p><p>• extract the coordinates (LAT-LONG) of the WHERE component. This process involves sometimes a disambiguation task.</p><p>As an example, see in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,224.28,112.02,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref> the information that has to be extracted from the query "Discount Airline Tickets to Brazil". In this paper we present the overall architecture of our Geographical Query Parsing system and we describe briefly its main components. We also present the experiments, results and conclusions in the context of the GeoCLEF's 2007 GeoQuery pilot task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System Description</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Overview</head><p>The system architecture has two main phases that are performed sequentially: Topic Analysis and Question Classification.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Topic Analysis</head><p>The Topic Analysis phase has two main components: a Linguistic Analysis and a Geographical Analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.1">Linguistic Analysis</head><p>This process extracts lexico-semantic and syntactic information using the following set of Natural Language Processing tools: i) TnT an statistical POS tagger <ref type="bibr" coords="2,357.04,463.76,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, ii) WordNet lemmatizer (version 2.0), iii) A Maximum Entropy based NERC trained with the CONLL-2003 shared task English data set, iv) Spear<ref type="foot" coords="2,211.90,486.09,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref> , a modified version of the Collins parser, which performs full parsing and robust detection of verbal predicate arguments <ref type="bibr" coords="2,332.90,499.62,10.51,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref> (limited to three predicate arguments: agent, direct object (or theme), and indirect object (benefactive or instrument).</p><p>We pre-processed the data-set of 800.000 queries in English from a web search-engine with linguistic tools to obtain the following data structures:</p><p>• Sent, which provides lexical information for each word: form, lemma, POS tag (Penn-Tree-Bank (PTB) tag-set for English), semantic class of NE, list of EWN synsets and, finally, whenever possible the verbs associated with the actor and the relations between some locations (specially countries) and their gentiles (e.g. nationality).</p><p>• Sint, composed of two lists, one recording the syntactic constituent structure of the question (basically nominal, prepositional and verbal phrases) and the other collecting the information of dependencies and other relations between these components.</p><p>• Environment. The environment represents the semantic relations that hold between the different components identified in the question text. These relations are organized into an ontology of about 100 semantic classes and 25 relations (mostly binary) between them. Both classes and relations are related by taxonomic links. The ontology tries to reflect what is needed for an appropriate representation of the semantic environment of the question (and the expected answer). The environment of the question is obtained from Sint and Sent. A set of about 150 rules was built to perform this task. Refer to <ref type="bibr" coords="2,388.58,727.75,10.51,8.74" target="#b4">[4]</ref> for details.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2">Geographical Analysis</head><p>The Geographical Analysis is applied to the Named Entities from the queries that have been classified as LOCATION or ORGANIZATION by the NERC module. A Geographical Thesaurus is used to extract geographical information about these Name Entities. This component has been built joining four gazetteers that contain entries with places and their geographical class, coordinates, and other information:</p><p>1. GEOnet Names Server (GNS)<ref type="foot" coords="3,245.35,195.39,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_1">2</ref> : a gazetteer covering worldwide excluding the United States and Antarctica, with 5.3 million entries.</p><p>2. Geographic Names Information System (GNIS)<ref type="foot" coords="3,327.39,226.00,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_2">3</ref> , contains 2.0 million entries about geographic features of the United States and its territories. We used a subset of 39,906 entries of the most important geographical names.</p><p>3. GeoWorldMap<ref type="foot" coords="3,177.78,268.56,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_3">4</ref> World Gazetteer: a gazetteer with approximately 40,594 entries of the most important countries, regions, and cities of the world.</p><p>4. World Gazetteer<ref type="foot" coords="3,186.50,299.17,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_4">5</ref> : a gazetteer with approximately 171,021 entries of towns, administrative divisions and agglomerations with their features and current population. From this gazetteer we added only the 29,924 cities with more than 5,000 unhabitants.</p><p>A subset of the most important features from this thesaurus has been manually set using 46.132 places (including all kind of geographical features: countries, cities, rivers, states,. . . ). This subset of important features has been used to decide if the query is geographical or not geographical.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Question Classification</head><p>The query classification task is performed through the following steps:</p><p>• The query is linguistically preprocessed (as described in the previous subsection) for getting its lexical, syntactic and semantic content. See in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,392.94,443.72,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_1">1</ref> the results of the process for the former example. What is relevant in the example is the fine grained classification of 'Brazil' as country, the existence of taxonomic information, both of location type (administrative areas@@political areas@@countries) and location content (America@@South America@@ Brazil), and coordinates (-10.0 -55.0, useful for disambiguating the location and for restricting the search area) and the existence of a shallow syntactic tree consisting on simple tokens and chunks, in this case built by the composition of two chunks, a nominal chunk ('Discount Airline Tickets') and a prepositional one ('to Brazil').</p><p>Query: "Discount Airline Tickets to Brazil" Semantic: [entity(3),mod(3,1),quality(1),mod(3,2),entity(2),i en proper country(5)] Linguistic: Brazil Brazil NNP LOCATION Geographical: America@@South America@@Brazil@@-10.0 -55.0 Feature type: administrative areas@@political areas@@countries Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,221.66,609.51,3.88,8.74" target="#fig_1">1</ref>. Semantic and Geographical Content of GQ-38.</p><p>• Over the sint structure, a DCG like grammar consisting of about 30 rules developed manually from the sample of GeoQuery and the set of queries of GeoCLEF 2006, is applied for obtaining the list of topics (each topic represented by its initial and final positions) represented by a triple &lt;geo-relation, initial position, final position&gt;). A set of features (consultive operations over chunks or tokens and predicates on the corresponding sent structures) is used by the grammar. The following features were available:</p><p>-chunk features: category, inferior, superior, descendents.</p><p>-token features: num, POS, word form, lemma, NE 1 (general), NE 2 specific.</p><p>-token semantics: synsets, concrete and generic Named Entity type predicates (Named Entity types include: location, person, organization, date, entity, property, magnitude, unit, cardinal point, and geographical relation.</p><p>-head of the chunk features: num, POS, word, lemma, first NE, second NE.</p><p>-head of the chunk semantic features.</p><p>-left corner of the chunk: num, POS, word form, lemma, NE 1 (general), NE</p><p>-left corner of the chunk semantics: WordNet synsets.</p><p>See Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,166.97,262.54,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_2">2</ref> for a sample rule. The rule can be paraphrased as follows: a sentence is composed by two chunks followed by a gap. The first chunk is of type 'npb' or 'np', i.e. it is a nominal phrase, basic or complex, its head cannot be a Named Entity and the limits of the chunk provide the limits of the topic. The second chunk is a 'pp' and it provides the list of locations.  • Finally from the result of step 2 several rule-sets are in charge of extracting: i) LOCAL, ii) WHAT and WHAT-TYPE, iii) WHERE and GEO-RELATION, and iv) LAT-LONG data. So, there are four rule sets with a total of 25 rules. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,365.49,459.27,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_3">3</ref> presents an example of a WHAT rule. The rule selects from the list of topics one containing a generic location (e.g. the noun 'city'). In this case the selected topic is assigned to WHAT and the WHAT TYPE set to 'Map'.</p><p>classify_question_topic(X,WHAT,'Map'):-sentence_2(X,(_,CT,_,_)), CT\==[], sentence_1(X,S), member((LC1,LC2),CT), range(LC1,LC2,R), member(LC,R), nth(LC,S,Tk1), is_ generic_location(Tk1,_), concatenate_words_pos(X,R,WHAT),!. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments and Results</head><p>We performed only one experiment for the GeoQuery2007 data set. The experiment consisted in to extracting the requested data for the GeoQuery from a set of 800.000 queries.</p><p>The results of the TALP system presented at the GeoCLEF's 2007 GeoQuery Geographical parsing task for English are summarized in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,307.73,733.69,3.88,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. This table has the following IR measures for each run: Precision, Recall, and F1.</p><p>In the evaluation data set, a set of 500 queries had been labeled which are chosen to represent the whole query set (800.000). The submitted results have been manually evaluated using a strict criterion where a correct results should have all &lt;local&gt;, &lt;what&gt;, &lt;what-type&gt; and &lt;where&gt; fields correct (the &lt;lat-long&gt; field was ignored in the evaluation).</p><p>Our run achieved the following results: 0.2222 of Precision, 0.249 of Recall, and 0.235 of F1. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions</head><p>This is our first approach to deal with a geographical query parsing task. Our system for the GeoCLEF's 2007 GeoQuery pilot task is based on a deep linguistic and geographical knowledge analysis. Although we need to do further evaluations to compare the system with other ones it seems that our approach could be feasible for the task.</p><p>As a future work we propose the following improvements to the system: i) further evaluations of each problem subtask, ii) apply more sophisticated geographical desambiguation algorithms.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,114.91,335.82,172.60,8.30;4,125.37,347.77,339.98,8.30;4,125.37,359.73,78.46,8.30;4,125.37,371.68,198.75,8.30;4,125.37,383.64,146.45,8.30;4,125.37,395.59,83.69,8.30"><head>parse_sentence( 1 ,</head><label>1</label><figDesc>DS,CT,CNES) --&gt; cc(DS,[(cc,[npb,np]),(hne1,[nil]),(ci,[LI]),(cs,[LS])],[],(1,1)), {CT=[(LI,LS)]}, cc(DS,[(cc,[pp]),(cd,[CD])],[],(1,1)), {parse_pp(_,DS,CNES,CD,[])}, parse_gap(_,DS).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="4,243.12,410.62,141.68,8.74"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. Example of DCG rule.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="4,209.54,643.22,208.83,8.74"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3. Example of WHAT classification rule.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,195.56,190.61,211.87,34.78"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>TALPGeoIR results at GeoQuery 2007.</figDesc><table coords="5,210.16,202.31,179.36,23.08"><row><cell cols="3">Team Name Precision Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell></row><row><cell>TALP</cell><cell>0.222</cell><cell cols="2">0.249 0.235</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,105.24,747.58,182.07,6.64"><p>http://www.lsi.upc.edu/~surdeanu/spear.html</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="3,105.24,709.00,216.60,7.01"><p>GNS. http://gnswww.nima.mil/geonames/GNS/index.jsp</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="3,105.24,718.51,198.43,7.01"><p>GNIS. http://geonames.usgs.gov/geonames/stategaz</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_3" coords="3,105.24,728.01,407.75,7.01;3,90.00,737.50,151.12,6.99"><p>Geobytes Inc.: Geoworldmap database containing cities, regions and countries of the world with geographical coordinates. http://www.geobytes.com/.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5" xml:id="foot_4" coords="3,105.24,746.98,198.86,7.01"><p>World Gazetteer: http://www.world-gazetteer.com</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work has been supported by the <rs type="funder">Spanish Research Dept</rs>. (<rs type="grantNumber">TEXT-MESS</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">TIN2006-15265-C06-05</rs>). <rs type="person">Daniel Ferrés</rs> is supported by a <rs type="funder">UPC-Recerca</rs> grant from <rs type="funder">Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC)</rs>. <rs type="projectName">TALP Research Center</rs> is recognized as a <rs type="projectName">Quality Research Group</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">2001 SGR 00254</rs>) by <rs type="funder">DURSI</rs>, the <rs type="funder">Research Department of the Catalan Government</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_8GbjTwQ">
					<idno type="grant-number">TEXT-MESS</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_eVKrVSY">
					<idno type="grant-number">TIN2006-15265-C06-05</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_hhaxtfb">
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">TALP Research Center</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_gxKSCua">
					<idno type="grant-number">2001 SGR 00254</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">Quality Research Group</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,500.57,407.50,8.74;5,105.50,512.52,264.54,8.74" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,156.43,500.57,177.39,8.74">TnT -a statistical part-of-speech tagger</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Brants</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,356.43,500.57,156.57,8.74;5,105.50,512.52,109.00,8.74">Proceedings of the 6th Applied NLP Conference (ANLP-2000)</title>
		<meeting>the 6th Applied NLP Conference (ANLP-2000)<address><addrLine>Seattle, WA, United States</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,532.45,407.50,8.74;5,105.50,544.40,129.24,8.74" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,159.87,532.45,268.61,8.74">Head-Driven Statistical Models for Natural Language Parsing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Pennsylvania</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">PhD thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,564.33,407.50,8.74;5,105.50,576.28,407.51,8.74" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,289.89,564.33,223.11,8.74;5,105.50,576.28,402.73,8.74">The GeoTALP-IR System at GeoCLEF-2005: Experiments Using a QA-based IR System, Linguistic Analysis, and a Geographical Thesaurus</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ferrés</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ageno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Rodríguez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,588.24,407.51,8.74;5,105.50,600.19,407.50,8.74;5,105.50,612.15,22.70,8.74" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Gey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gonzalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J F</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,204.78,600.19,23.53,8.74">CLEF</title>
		<title level="s" coord="5,309.86,600.19,155.26,8.74">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kluck</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Magnini</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Mller</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>De Rijke</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4022</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,632.08,407.50,8.74;5,105.50,644.03,407.51,8.74;5,105.50,655.99,407.51,8.74;5,105.50,667.94,407.51,8.74;5,105.50,679.90,86.40,8.74" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,105.50,644.03,407.51,8.74;5,105.50,655.99,92.34,8.74">The TALP-QA System for Spanish at CLEF 2004: Structural and Hierarchical Relaxing of Semantic Constraints</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ferrés</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kanaan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ageno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>González</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Rodríguez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Surdeanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Turmo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,198.17,667.94,23.53,8.74">CLEF</title>
		<title level="s" coord="5,302.35,667.94,154.44,8.74">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gonzalo</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J F</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kluck</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Magnini</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3491</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="557" to="568" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
