<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,254.15,115.90,176.49,12.90;1,137.84,133.83,339.69,12.90;1,223.43,153.91,168.50,10.75">Profiling Approach Based on Language-dependent Content and Stylometric Features Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2015</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,190.51,190.53,59.32,8.64"><forename type="first">Alberto</forename><surname>Bartoli</surname></persName>
							<email>bartoli.alberto@univ.trieste.it</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">DIA -University of Trieste</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,256.10,190.53,77.14,8.64"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>De Lorenzo</surname></persName>
							<email>andrea.delorenzo@units.it</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">DIA -University of Trieste</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,340.19,190.53,80.44,8.64"><forename type="first">Alessandra</forename><surname>Laderchi</surname></persName>
							<email>alessandra.laderchi@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">DIA -University of Trieste</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,242.24,202.49,47.18,8.64"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Medvet</surname></persName>
							<email>emedvet@units.it</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">DIA -University of Trieste</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,313.47,202.49,59.65,8.64"><forename type="first">Fabiano</forename><surname>Tarlao</surname></persName>
							<email>fabiano.tarlao@phd.units.it</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">DIA -University of Trieste</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,254.15,115.90,176.49,12.90;1,137.84,133.83,339.69,12.90;1,223.43,153.91,168.50,10.75">Profiling Approach Based on Language-dependent Content and Stylometric Features Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2015</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">2ECA8AA13F87C7F80FED2B4D059BF2CF</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:42+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We describe the approach that we submitted to the 2015 PAN competition [5]  for the author profiling task 1 . The task consists in predicting some attributes of an author analyzing a set of his/her Twitter tweets. We consider several sets of stylometric and content features, and different decision algorithms: we use a different combination of features and decision algorithm for each language-attribute pair, hence treating it as an individual problem.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Problem statement</head><p>A problem instance consists of a tuple xD, Ly, where D is a set of tweets written by the same author and L is a value of enumerated type that describes the language of the tweets-English, Spanish, Italian, or Dutch.</p><p>The author profiling consists in generating, given a problem instance, the value for several attributes with respect to the author of the tweets: gender, age group (only for English and Spanish), and 5 personality traits. Age group is an enumerated value among the following: 18-24, 25-34, 35-49 or ě 50. The 5 personality traits are widely accepted characteristics used to describe human personality (also known as Big Five <ref type="bibr" coords="1,462.88,486.65,10.62,8.64" target="#b6">[7]</ref>): extroversion, neuroticism, agreeableness, conscientiousness, and openness to experience. For each trait, the attribute value consists of a score in r´0.5, `0.5s.</p><p>A set of solved problem instances (the training set) is available in which, for each problem instance xD, Ly, the tuple of the attributes values is provided.</p><p>The effectiveness of a method for author profiling is assessed using a testing set of solved problem instances. In particular, the effectiveness is assessed separately for each attribute as follows: the attribute values generated by the method for the problem instances in the testing set are compared against the actual values and the comparison outcome is expressed in terms of accuracy for gender and age, and in terms of Rootmean-square error (RMSE) for the personality traits.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Our approach</head><p>We chose to handle the prediction of each attribute for each language as an individual problem: in particular, we consider gender and age group prediction as 2 classification tasks and personal traits prediction as 5 regression tasks. Since we had tweets written in four languages and we had to predict age groups for those written in English and Spanish only, we hence considered 26 different problems.</p><p>We propose a machine learning approach based on a number of different stylometric and content features which are processed by one among three different decision algorithms-we used SVM and random forests as classifiers and regressors. We carried out an extensive experimental campaign for systematically assessing a large number of the possible combinations, through leave-one-out cross validation on the available training data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Training set analysis and repetitions</head><p>During preliminary analysis, we noticed that the training set included some subsets of problem instances for which L and the solution were the same, i.e., the attributes values for all the problem instances in a subset were the very same, despite being D different. We call repetitions those problem instances. We argued that the tweets of the problem instances in each of those subsets were authored by the same person. For this reason, we decided to build a new training set by replacing each of those subsets with a single problem instance in which D is the union of all the tweet sets of the subset-i.e., we merged the repetitions. Table <ref type="table" coords="2,224.02,437.98,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows the sizes of the training set portions corresponding to each language before and after merging repetitions. We later experimentally verified that this transformation did affect the learned classifiers and regressors. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Features</head><p>The feature extraction procedure requires a language-dependent dictionary in which words are grouped according to their prevalent topic (e.g., "money", "sports", or "religion") or their function (e.g., "prepositions", "articles", or "negations"). To this end, we used an English dictionary similar to the one used by LIWC <ref type="bibr" coords="3,401.51,119.31,10.58,8.64" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. For the other 3 languages, we proceeded as follows. For Spanish and Dutch, we built the dictionary by automatically translating the English dictionary with Google Translate. For Italian, we manually built the dictionary, by using the English one as guideline. Moreover, for each language, we augmented the dictionary with a new category of words ("chat acronyms") containing the top fifty most popular chat acronyms exposed on NetLingo <ref type="foot" coords="3,428.89,177.42,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_1">2</ref> .</p><p>The feature extraction procedure is also based on the notion of automatic tweet, that we define as follows. We determined a set of ordered sequences of n " 1, . . . , 4 words, that we call templates, based on an analysis of the full training set:</p><p>1. we automatically extracted from the full training set all tweets starting with the same ordered sequence of n words; 2. we automatically constructed a set including all word sequences that were the starting sequence of at least 3 different tweets; 3. we manually analyzed each sequence and retained only those which appeared to be the beginning of an automatically-generated tweet.</p><p>We say that a tweet is an automatic tweet if its first words correspond to a template. Table <ref type="table" coords="3,159.91,330.30,4.98,8.64">2</ref> provides some examples of templates, along with the presence or absence of corresponding automatic tweets of different languages in the training sets.  <ref type="table" coords="3,158.48,475.54,3.36,8.06">2</ref>. Some examples of templates and the languages for which at least one automatic tweet with that template were found. The first row corresponds to a template found only in Spanish problem instances, while the other rows are templates found in problem instances of multiple languages. The last row contains, for each language, the count of templates for which at least one automatic tweet with that template was found.</p><p>The feature extraction procedure is as follows. Given a problem instance xD, Ly, we denote by D M the set of tweets obtained by D by removing all the automatic tweets. We extract several numerical features from each problem instance: the value of all (except of 3) features is obtained by averaging the corresponding computation outcomes on the tweets in D or D M -the remaining three feature values are computed on the whole D and/or D M . For ease of presentation, we group conceptually similar features together; the full list is given in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,248.42,635.94,3.74,8.64" target="#tab_1">3</ref>.</p><p>Stylometric These features tend to capture the structural properties of a tweet in a way largely independent of both the language and the specific semantic content; therefore, they are not based on the dictionaries. Stylometric features are computed on tweets in D M : the reason is because we assume that automatic tweets are not really representative of the tweet writing style of the author. Content These features are based on the dictionaries categories related to word topic and are computed on tweets in D: the reason is because we assume that the content of automatic tweets is indeed informative of the author profile. Hybrid These features are based on the dictionaries categories related to word function and are computed on tweets in D M .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Feature selection</head><p>Past studies on author profiling report several correlations between gender, age, personality traits and writing style. In particular, <ref type="bibr" coords="4,320.31,294.82,11.62,8.64" target="#b5">[6]</ref> showed that stylometric features are more predicitve than content features for determining the gender, and viceversa for the age group, but the combination of both stylometric and content features can offer better results. In <ref type="bibr" coords="4,190.99,330.68,10.58,8.64" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, the authors provided a list of correlations between some LIWC and non-LIWC features and the five personality traits. We constructed 40 different feature groups based on this knowledge and we assessed each of the resulting feature groups as described in the next section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Classifier and regressor</head><p>We decided to build a different model for each language-problem pair, for a total of 26, as described in Section 1. We explored the usage of SVM <ref type="bibr" coords="4,372.29,427.27,11.62,8.64" target="#b1">[2]</ref> and Random Forest <ref type="bibr" coords="4,468.97,427.27,11.62,8.64" target="#b0">[1]</ref> with different configurations, as these methods can be used both as classifiers and as regressors. In particular, we considered:</p><p>svm: SVM with default gaussian kernel and C " 1; -rf500: Random Forest with 500 trees; -rf2000: Random Forest with 2000 trees.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Analysis</head><p>As described in the previous sections, we considered 40 sets of features and 3 classifiers/regressors. We systematically assessed the effectiveness of all the 120 resulting combinations by means of a leave-one-out procedure applied on the training set, separately for each language-attribute pair. That is, for each language-attribute pair, set of features, and classifier/regressor, (i) we built the subset T of the problem instances of the training set with that language, (ii) we removed one element t 0 from T , (iii) we computed the values for the features set on the problem instances in T and trained the classifier/regressor, (iv) we applied the trained classifier/regressor to the problem instance t 0 and compared the generated answer against the known one. We repeated all but first steps |T | times, i.e., by removing each time a different element, and computed the performance of the method in terms of the indexes defined in Section 1. Finally, we chose, for each language-attribute pair, the best performing combination, in terms of accuracy or RMSE, as appropriate for that attribute. The resulting configurations are summarized in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,220.57,155.18,3.74,8.64" target="#tab_2">4</ref>.</p><p>In order to provide a synthetic baseline, we built 3 baseline methods using each of the 3 classifiers/regressors with all the features. The results, obtained by means of the same leave-one-out procedure, are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,336.99,191.04,3.74,8.64">5</ref>.</p><p>It can be seen from Table <ref type="table" coords="6,250.83,203.00,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_2">4</ref> that our procedure lead us to chose a different configuration of classifier/regressor and features set for each language-attribute pair. There could be several reason to explain that. First, every language has its own writing rules and culture, so it is possible that a middle aged English man could not have the same interests and the same writing style of a middle aged Italian man. Second, the Spanish, Dutch, and Italian dictionaries we used were not as good as the LIWC English one. Finally, the number of problem instances in the training set was not the same for every language, and so was the number of tweets in the instances within each language subset. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,229.12,376.56,33.24,7.77;3,334.53,376.56,51.70,7.77;3,229.12,388.76,102.22,6.31;3,229.12,399.72,32.28,6.31;3,229.12,410.68,32.28,6.31;3,229.12,421.64,48.42,6.31;3,229.12,432.60,69.94,6.31;3,229.12,443.56,59.18,6.31;3,229.12,454.52,16.14,6.31;3,229.12,465.03,153.37,7.77;3,134.77,475.54,21.10,8.06"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Template EN ES IT NL # Move más reciente Photo: I'm at I liked a I favorited a Ik vind een #in Total number of templates 29 8 12 1 Table</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,134.77,493.68,345.83,73.83"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Number of problem instances in the original training set and in the new training built by merging repetitions.</figDesc><table coords="2,258.21,493.68,98.94,52.01"><row><cell cols="3">Language Original Merged</cell></row><row><cell>English</cell><cell>152</cell><cell>83</cell></row><row><cell>Spanish</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>50</cell></row><row><cell>Italian</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>19</cell></row><row><cell>Dutch</cell><cell>34</cell><cell>18</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,141.54,117.69,332.52,537.09"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Features list.</figDesc><table coords="5,141.54,117.69,332.52,526.23"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Feature name Description</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>allpunc</cell><cell>Number of .,:;</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>commas</cell><cell>Number of ,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>exclmar</cell><cell>Number of !</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>questma</cell><cell>Number of ?</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>parenth</cell><cell>Number of parenthesis</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>numbers</cell><cell>Number of numbers</cell></row><row><cell>stylometric</cell><cell>wocount longwor upcawor carrret atmenti</cell><cell>Number of words Number of words longer than 6 letters Number of uppercase words Number of carriage returns (\n, \r, \r\n) Number of @ mentions</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>extlink</cell><cell>Number of links</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>hashtag</cell><cell>Number of #</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>posemot</cell><cell>Number of positive emoticons</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>negemot</cell><cell>Number of negative emoticons</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>emotico</cell><cell>Number of emoticons</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>emotiyn</cell><cell>Presence of emoticons in D (binary feature)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>moneywo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "money" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>jobword</cell><cell>Number of words in the "job or work" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>sportwo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "sports" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>televwo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "tv or movie" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>sleepwo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "sleeping" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>eatinwo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "eating" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>sexuawo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "sexuality" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>familwo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "family" category</cell></row><row><cell>content</cell><cell>frienwo posemwo negemwo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "friends" category Number of words in the "positive emotion" category Number of words in the "negative emotion" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>emotiwo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "positive emotion" or "negative emotion" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>swearwo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "swear words" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>affecwo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "affective process" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>feeliwo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "feeling" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>religwo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "religion" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>schoowo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "school" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>occupwo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "occupation" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>autotwe</cell><cell>Automatic tweets ratio, i.e., |DzD M | |D|</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>autweyn</cell><cell>Presence of automatic tweets in D (binary feature)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>fsipron</cell><cell>Number of words in the "I" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>fplpron</cell><cell>Number of words in the "we" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>ssipron</cell><cell>Number of words in the "you" category</cell></row><row><cell>hybrid</cell><cell>selfref negpart asspart</cell><cell>Number of words in the "self" category Number of words in the "negations" category Number of words in the "assents" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>article</cell><cell>Number of words in the "articles" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>preposi</cell><cell>Number of words in the "prepositions" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>pronoun</cell><cell>Number of words in the "pronoun" category</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>slangwo</cell><cell>Number of words in the "chat acronyms" category</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="7,136.56,144.97,342.24,480.79"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Chosen classifier/regressor and features set for each language-attribute pair.</figDesc><table coords="7,136.56,144.97,342.24,469.93"><row><cell cols="4">L Attribute Class./Regr. Chosen features set</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Gen</cell><cell cols="2">rf2000 commas negemot exclmar</cell></row><row><cell>EN</cell><cell>Age</cell><cell cols="2">rf2000 allpunc commas exclmar questma parenth numbers wocount longwor upcawor carrret atmenti extlink hashtag posemot negemot emotico</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>autotwe</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Ext</cell><cell>svm</cell><cell>wocount questma parenth familwo</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Neu</cell><cell>svm</cell><cell>selfref fsipron chatacr affecwo emotiwo hashtag posemot pronoun</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>wocount</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Con</cell><cell>rf500</cell><cell>extlink longwor numbers hashtag fsipron selfref</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Agr</cell><cell>svm</cell><cell>questma atmenti allpunc ssipron article longwor jobword chatacr</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Ope</cell><cell cols="2">rf2000 commas extlink hashtag exclmar questmar parenth wocount</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ssipron negpart article feeliwo moneywo jobword eatinwo familwo</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>negemwo religwo</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Gen</cell><cell>svm</cell><cell>allpunc commas exclmar questma parenth numbers wocount long-</cell></row><row><cell>ES</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>wor upcawor carrret atmenti extlink hashtag posemot negemot fsipron fplpron ssipron selfref negpart asspart article preposi pronoun</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>slangwo moneywo jobword sportwo televwo sleepwo eatinwo sexu-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>awo familwo frienwo posemwo negemwo affecwo feeliwo</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Age</cell><cell>svm</cell><cell>extlink hashtag numbers sleepwo sexuawo</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Ext</cell><cell cols="2">rf2000 longwor carrret questma preposi autweyn emotico</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Neu</cell><cell cols="2">rf2000 posemot ssipron exclmar selfref extlink</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Con</cell><cell>rf500</cell><cell>extlink longwor numbers hashtag fsipron selfref affecwo emotiwo</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Agr</cell><cell>svm</cell><cell>allpunc commas exclmar questma parenth numbers wocount long-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>wor upcawor carrret atmenti extlink hashtag posemot negemot +</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>fsipron fplpron ssipron selfref negpart asspart article preposi pronoun</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>slangwo moneywo jobword sportwo televwo sleepwo eatinwo sexu-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>awo familwo frienwo posemwo negemwo swearwo religwo</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Ope</cell><cell cols="2">rf2000 autotwe hashtag preposi wocount religwo</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Gen</cell><cell>rf500</cell><cell>asspart fsipron selfref exclmar extlink hashtag emotiyn</cell></row><row><cell>IT</cell><cell>Ext Neu</cell><cell cols="2">svm rf2000 commas longwor fplpron chatacr autweyn allpunc wocount hashtag questma</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Con</cell><cell>svm</cell><cell>commas extlink hashtag exclmar questmar parenth wocount</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ssipron negpart article feeliwo moneywo jobword eatinwo familwo</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>negemwo religwo</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Agr</cell><cell>svm</cell><cell>posemot exclmar moneywo hashtag pronoun autweyn</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Ope</cell><cell>svm</cell><cell>negpart hashtag atmenti exclmar longwor</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Gen</cell><cell cols="2">rf2000 negemot upcawor preposi</cell></row><row><cell>NL</cell><cell>Ext</cell><cell>svm</cell><cell>questma atmenti allpunc ssipron article longwor jobword chatacr extlink autweyn</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Neu</cell><cell cols="2">rf2000 atmenti preposi longwor emotiyn</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Con</cell><cell>svm</cell><cell>hashtag questma exclmar atmenti posemot wocount extlink longwor</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Agr</cell><cell>svm</cell><cell>atmenti commas exclmar hashtag autweyn emotiyn</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Ope</cell><cell>svm</cell><cell>negpart hashtag atmenti exclmar longwor</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,144.73,591.33,335.86,7.77;1,144.73,602.29,335.86,7.77;1,144.73,613.25,335.86,7.77;1,144.73,624.21,335.86,7.77;1,144.73,635.17,335.86,7.77;1,144.73,646.13,335.86,7.77;1,144.73,657.08,40.78,7.77"><p>During the competition we discovered several opportunities for fraudulently boosting the accuracy of our method during the evaluation phase. We will describe these opportunities in a future report. We notified the organizers which promptly acknowledged the high relevance of our concerns and took measures to mitigate the corresponding vulnerabilities. The organizers acknowledged our contribution publicly. We submitted for evaluation an honestly developed method-the one described in this document-that did not exploit such unethical procedures in any way.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="3,144.73,657.08,197.11,7.77"><p>http://www.netlingo.com/top50/popular-text-terms.php</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,342.13,250.39,7.77" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,194.28,342.13,55.51,7.77">Random forests</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Breiman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,255.30,342.13,63.00,7.77">Machine learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,353.09,341.01,7.77;6,146.47,364.05,214.79,7.77" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,230.91,353.09,162.95,7.77">Libsvm: a library for support vector machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,400.12,353.09,79.02,7.77;6,146.47,364.05,155.77,7.77">ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology (TIST)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">27</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,375.00,337.32,7.77;6,146.47,385.96,325.09,7.77;6,146.47,396.92,309.06,7.77;6,146.47,407.88,81.43,7.77" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,337.23,375.00,122.88,7.77">Predicting personality from twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Golbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Robles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Edmondson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,146.47,385.96,325.09,7.77;6,146.47,396.92,122.53,7.77;6,295.42,396.92,133.21,7.77">Privacy, Security, Risk and Trust (PASSAT) and 2011 IEEE Third Inernational Conference on Social Computing (SocialCom)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011. 2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="156" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IEEE Third International Conference</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,418.84,329.99,7.77;6,146.47,429.80,214.92,7.77" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,310.81,418.84,157.31,7.77;6,146.47,429.80,126.28,7.77">Linguistic inquiry and word count (liwc): A computerized text analysis program</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Francis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Booth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>Mahwah (NJ)</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,440.76,326.22,7.77;6,146.47,451.72,334.12,7.77;6,146.47,462.68,315.59,7.77;6,146.47,473.63,298.91,7.77" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,367.10,440.76,97.25,7.77;6,146.47,451.72,93.77,7.77">Overview of the 3rd author profiling task at PAN 2015</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Daelemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.clef-initiative.eu/publication/working-notes" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,458.67,451.72,21.92,7.77;6,146.47,462.68,93.16,7.77">CLEF 2015 Labs and Workshops</title>
		<title level="s" coord="6,246.11,462.68,215.95,7.77;6,146.47,473.63,19.77,7.77">Notebook papers. CEUR Workshop Proceedings, CLEF and CEUR</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cappellato</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gareth</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>San Juan</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-09">Sep 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,484.59,309.51,7.77;6,146.47,495.55,324.30,7.77;6,146.47,506.51,57.53,7.77" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,345.04,484.59,102.60,7.77;6,146.47,495.55,30.33,7.77">Effects of age and gender on blogging</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Argamon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Pennebaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,182.84,495.55,278.97,7.77">AAAI Spring Symposium: Computational Approaches to Analyzing Weblogs</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="205" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,517.47,312.80,7.77;6,146.47,528.43,275.61,7.77" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,236.63,517.47,214.30,7.77;6,146.47,528.43,63.16,7.77">The big five personality traits and the life course: A 45-year longitudinal study</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Soldz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Vaillant</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,215.39,528.43,123.02,7.77">Journal of Research in Personality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="208" to="232" />
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
