<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,147.91,115.90,319.53,12.90;1,286.70,133.83,41.96,12.90;1,223.43,153.76,168.50,10.75">Automatic Profiling of Twitter Users Based on Their Tweets Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2015</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,221.01,190.23,82.52,8.64"><forename type="first">Octavia-Maria S</forename><surname>Ulea</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Bitdefender</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="RO">Romania</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Computational Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Bucharest</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,333.71,190.23,56.17,8.64"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Dichiu</surname></persName>
							<email>ddichiu@bitdefender.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Bitdefender</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="RO">Romania</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,147.91,115.90,319.53,12.90;1,286.70,133.83,41.96,12.90;1,223.43,153.76,168.50,10.75">Automatic Profiling of Twitter Users Based on Their Tweets Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2015</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">031FCF4D0E18E6610C66C5BC1C9B3896</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:42+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper we go through our approach at solving the PAN Author Profiling task. We introduce a novel way of computing the type/token ratio of an author and show that, although strong correlations have been observed between high extroversion and low type/token ratios in the past, this ratio is not necessarily a strong indicator of extroversion. Since the text of a person is influenced by all 7 features (gender, age, and big five personality traits) that are required to be automatically identified in this task, we used this ratio, along with Term frequency-Inverse document frequency (tf-idf ) matrices, in all 7 subtasks and all 4 corpora and obtained good results.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>While the importance of age and gender is a more familiar notion in user or author profiling, automatic personality detection is a relatively new task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,394.24,432.51,15.27,8.64" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. Since many correlations between personality traits and consumer preferences have been reported ( <ref type="bibr" coords="1,466.65,444.46,10.45,8.64" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" coords="1,134.77,456.42,10.45,8.64" target="#b8">[9]</ref>), a natural interest arose in the automatic detection of personality on social media networks in the last few years, especially on the micro-blogging site, Twitter, where the privacy setting for its users' posts and activity is by default public ( <ref type="bibr" coords="1,406.42,480.33,10.45,8.64" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" coords="1,423.19,480.33,10.45,8.64" target="#b2">[3]</ref>). Since the main activity of Twitter users involves language (tweets), and since many correlations have been identified between lingusitic features of a text and personality traits of its author <ref type="bibr" coords="1,162.68,516.19,10.58,8.64" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, the idea of automatically detecting the personality of Twitter users based on their tweets is only natural. In what follows, we will describe our approach to PAN's third Author Profiling task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,242.77,540.10,10.58,8.64" target="#b7">[8]</ref>, discuss our cross-validation results and briefly compare them with the results obtained after the final testing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Our Approach</head><p>For all datasets and subtasks, the estimators, the parameter search function, the crossvalidation strategy, and some of the feature extractors we used were from the scikit-learn module for python <ref type="bibr" coords="1,212.96,632.53,10.58,8.64" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. For the processing of the other features, we also used the nltk module <ref type="bibr" coords="1,166.80,644.48,10.58,8.64" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. This implementation choice of python modules was motivated by the swiftness with which prototyping can occur. The two classification tasks (for gender and age) were carried out using LinearSVC() <ref type="bibr" coords="2,282.22,119.31,11.62,8.64" target="#b1">[2]</ref> while the 5 regression tasks (for the personality traits), using Ridge(). In order to have balanced classes during cross-validation, we used StratifiedKFold() with the number of folds set to 5. The best parameters for the estimators were found using RandomizedSearch().</p><p>For features, we tried several approaches, but eventually settled on using two: first, the tf-idf matrix at character level, with various n-gram ranges and parameter tuning, depending on the language and subtask, and second, the type/token ratio of a user or verbosity rate. These two features were combined using scikit-learn's FeatureUnion().</p><p>The tf-idf scores were extracted using scikit-learn's TfidfVectorizer(). This vectorizer was applied either on all tweets of one user put together, or on each tweet pertaning to one user. More precisely, in the sparse matrix created by the TfidfVectorizer(), the columns represented, in both cases, all the character n-grams extracted from all the tweets in one of the four datasets, while each line represented either all tweets of one user concatenated, or one tweet of a user. Our cross-validation results, which will be presented further, showed that the former method was consistently more appropriate for the classfication tasks and the latter, for regression. An intuitive answer would be that gender and age specific features change less often, while personality traits may influence each tweet.</p><p>The verbosity ratio of a user was only inspired by the type/token ratio and is not one per se, since distinguishing between a linguistic manifestation of a conceptual type (bicycle in sentence 1.a), and its token (bicycle in sentence 1.b), implies deep semantic analysis which is far from trivial with today's tools in Natural Language Processing. What we did to echo the idea of a type/token ratio was to compute, for each user, the ratio between the total number of unique stems and the total number of words used after applying stemming. From this ratio we excluded stop words. Stemming was done using the nltk implementation of the Snowball algorithm since it offered a version for each of the four languages present in this year's task. For stopwords lists, we used nltk.corpus.stopwords. The motivation for using this feature was the often observed correlation between extroversion and type/token ratio <ref type="bibr" coords="2,350.03,523.42,10.58,8.64" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. However, our preliminary analysis, by computing both Pearson and Spearman correlation coefficients on verbosity ratios versus personality scores, showed no clear-cut linear relationships. The fact that Spearman correlation coefficient was better than the Pearson correlation coefficient only goes to show that the relationship is rather a monotonic one than linear. Below are the top three statistically significant correlation scores on all corpora and all personality scores, computed with python's scipy.stats package. The plots were drawn using seaborn python module.</p><p>For the Dutch corpus (figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,266.77,620.57,4.98,8.64" target="#fig_0">1</ref> on page 3), we found that there was a -0.46 Pearson correlation with a p-value &lt; 0.001 and -0.49 Spearman rank correlation with a p-value &lt; 0.001 between verbosity ratios and openness scores. Also, given a verbosity ratio, males tended to have higher openness scores than females. Also for the Dutch corpus (figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,291.56,364.57,4.98,8.64" target="#fig_2">2</ref> on page 4), we found that there was a -0.34 Pearson correlation with a p-value &lt; 0.001 and -0.45 Spearman rank correlation with a p-value &lt; 0.001 between verbosity ratios and neuroticism (stable) scores. Regarding gender separation, males tended to be more stable at a given verbosity ratio.</p><p>For the Italian corpus (figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,267.51,417.73,4.98,8.64" target="#fig_3">3</ref> on page 4), we found that there was a -0.33 Pearson correlation with a p-value &lt; 0.001 and -0.40 Spearman rank correlation with a p-value &lt; 0.001 between verbosity ratios and agreeableness scores. Apparently, on average, Italian females were more agreeable than Italian males at a given verbosity ratio.</p><p>We also present the results of verbosity ratios for the classification tasks.</p><p>In the English training corpus (table 1 on page 3), across all age groups, males had a slightly higher verbosity ratio than females. We also observed that verbosity ratios increased slightly with age, across both genders.   The difference betweem male and female verbosity ratios was minimal on the Spanish training corpus (table 2 on page 5). However, we observed a larger difference when it came to age groups, with the highest verbosity ratio being for age group 25-34 (with a median of 0.70) and the lowest for age group 35-49 (with a median of 0.67). A similar difference we also observed on the Italian corpus (table 3 on page 5). Female users tended to have a lower verbosity ratio (with a median of 0.69), while males had a median verbosity ratio of 0.72. As for the Dutch training corpus (table 4 on page 5), the difference between male and female verbosity ratios was again minimal, with a difference between medians of under 2 percentage points. Given these inconclusive findings, we decided to use a combination of tf-idf on character n-grams with verbosity scores, which improved cross-validation results over models based on the same features taken 3 Cross-Validation Results Comparing the cross-validation results to the final test results, we can see signs of overfitting only in some of the cases in which we used relatively more features. Overall, our models generalized well when the number of features was smaller. LinearSVC() and Ridge() allowed us to use sparse matrices, which meant we did not have to transform to dense matrices (which would have occupied too much memory) or reduce dimensions (which is a computationally expensive operation).</p><p>As we stated before, we concatenated each user's tweets for the classification tasks, while for the regression tasks we used each individual tweet. This led, on average, to a smaller vocabulary for the classification tasks.</p><p>On the English corpus (table 5 on page 6), our system over-fitted slightly on the gender, stable and open tasks. On the Spanish corpus (table 6 on page 6), our system over-fitted slightly on extroverted and conscientious tasks. On the Dutch corpus (table 7 on page 7), our system over-fitted slightly on extroverted and conscientious tasks.</p><p>The biggest difference between cross-validation and test results was on the Italian corpus (table 8 on page 7), where our system over-fitted on all tasks, but extroverted. The biggest overfit was for the gender task, with a difference of 15 percentage points between cross-validation results and test corpus results. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions</head><p>Based on our results, we conclude that a combination of simple features like tf-idf and verbosity ratios obtain reasonable results that generalize well. Comparing our approach across all corpora, we found that this solution worked best as a regressor for the Dutch corpus and as a classifier for the Spanish corpus. We found that the best tf-idf features are those at character-level ngrams, with ngram ranges of up to 2, 6. Above this threshold, the system seemed to overfit. We also found that there is at best a monotone relationship between verbosity ratios and personality scores. Nevertheless, combining them with other, many-dimensional features, like tf-idf matrices, improves results and generalizes well.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,144.73,396.58,110.62,8.64;2,168.74,411.99,146.10,8.81;2,461.96,411.99,18.63,8.58;2,168.58,427.57,125.52,8.81;2,457.26,427.57,23.33,8.58"><head>( 1 )</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Type/token distinction a. The bicycle is more popular now. Type b. The bicycle is in the garage. Token</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,193.56,307.28,228.24,8.12;3,193.56,318.59,184.39,7.77;3,147.69,115.83,319.99,180.00"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: A somewhat negative correlation between a Dutch person's openness score and his/her verbosity ratio.</figDesc><graphic coords="3,147.69,115.83,319.99,180.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="4,193.56,336.12,228.24,8.12;4,193.56,347.43,193.86,7.77;4,147.68,144.67,319.99,180.00"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: A somewhat negative correlation between a Dutch person's neuroticism score and his/her verbosity ratio.</figDesc><graphic coords="4,147.68,144.67,319.99,180.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="4,193.56,613.65,228.25,8.12;4,193.56,624.96,201.82,7.77;4,147.69,422.20,319.98,180.00"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: A somewhat negative correlation between an Italian person's aggreableness score and her/his verbosity ratio.</figDesc><graphic coords="4,147.69,422.20,319.98,180.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,226.42,555.62,160.27,105.56"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Verbosity ratios on English</figDesc><table coords="3,226.42,581.27,160.27,79.90"><row><cell>Gender</cell><cell>Median Mean Std</cell></row><row><cell>female (all ages)</cell><cell>0.6731 0.6584 0.0887</cell></row><row><cell>male (all ages)</cell><cell>0.683 0.68 0.083</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">18-24 (both genders) 0.6763 0.6650 0.0782</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">25-34 (both genders) 0.6864 0.6704 0.0921</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">35-49 (both genders) 0.6756 0.6737 0.0903</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">50-xx (both genders) 0.6927 0.6769 0.0989</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,226.42,191.13,160.27,105.56"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Verbosity ratios on Spanish</figDesc><table coords="5,226.42,216.79,160.27,79.90"><row><cell>Gender</cell><cell>Median Mean Std</cell></row><row><cell>female (all ages)</cell><cell>0.6937 0.6817 0.0483</cell></row><row><cell>male (all ages)</cell><cell>0.6901 0.6855 0.0623</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">18-24 (both genders) 0.6844 0.6858 0.0645</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">25-34 (both genders) 0.7016 0.6873 0.0514</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">35-49 (both genders) 0.6693 0.6787 0.0528</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">50-xx (both genders) 0.6859 0.6715 0.0614</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,244.71,387.44,125.94,61.72"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Verbosity ratios on Italian</figDesc><table coords="5,250.83,413.10,111.46,36.07"><row><cell>Gender Median Mean Std</cell></row><row><cell>female 0.6870 0.6891 0.0328</cell></row><row><cell>male 0.7223 0.7117 0.0874</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,245.21,539.92,124.95,61.72"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Verbosity ratios on Dutch</figDesc><table coords="5,250.83,565.57,111.46,36.07"><row><cell>Gender Median Mean Std</cell></row><row><cell>female 0.6995 0.6967 0.0502</cell></row><row><cell>male 0.6822 0.6934 0.0694</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="6,168.67,158.00,275.77,116.52"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>TfidfVectorizer parameters and results on English</figDesc><table coords="6,168.67,183.65,275.77,90.86"><row><cell>Subtask</cell><cell cols="4">Range Max-df Min-df Sublinear tf Vocab. CV result Result</cell></row><row><cell>gender</cell><cell>1, 3 0.75</cell><cell>0.17 TRUE</cell><cell cols="2">3211 78.94% 76.76%</cell></row><row><cell>age</cell><cell>3, 5 0.98</cell><cell>0.14 FALSE</cell><cell cols="2">13677 75.65% 78.87%</cell></row><row><cell>stable</cell><cell>2, 6 N/A</cell><cell>N/A TRUE</cell><cell cols="2">773075 0.1825 0.1951</cell></row><row><cell>agreeable</cell><cell>2, 6 N/A</cell><cell>N/A FALSE</cell><cell cols="2">773075 0.1411 0.1396</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">extroverted 2, 6 N/A</cell><cell>N/A TRUE</cell><cell cols="2">773075 0.1359 0.1318</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">conscientious 2, 6 N/A</cell><cell>N/A TRUE</cell><cell>773075 0.131</cell><cell>0.1297</cell></row><row><cell>open</cell><cell>2, 6 N/A</cell><cell>N/A TRUE</cell><cell cols="2">773075 0.1193 0.1246</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="6,170.16,320.34,272.78,116.52"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>TfidfVectorizer parameters and results on Spanish</figDesc><table coords="6,170.16,346.00,272.78,90.86"><row><cell>Subtask</cell><cell cols="5">Range Max-df Min-df Sublinear tf Vocab. CV result Result</cell></row><row><cell>gender</cell><cell>2, 6 0.85</cell><cell>0.15 FALSE</cell><cell cols="2">20649 88%</cell><cell>87.5%</cell></row><row><cell>age</cell><cell>1, 3 0.82</cell><cell>0.07 FALSE</cell><cell cols="2">6540 73%</cell><cell>75%</cell></row><row><cell>stable</cell><cell>2, 6 N/A</cell><cell>N/A TRUE</cell><cell cols="3">563605 0.1812 0.1816</cell></row><row><cell>agreeable</cell><cell>2, 6 N/A</cell><cell>N/A FALSE</cell><cell cols="3">563605 0.1478 0.1501</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">extroverted 2, 6 N/A</cell><cell>N/A TRUE</cell><cell cols="3">563605 0.1517 0.1703</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">conscientious 1, 3 0.94</cell><cell>0.07 TRUE</cell><cell>431</cell><cell cols="2">0.1137 0.1559</cell></row><row><cell>open</cell><cell>2, 6 N/A</cell><cell>N/A FALSE</cell><cell cols="3">563605 0.1421 0.1417</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" coords="7,168.67,117.32,275.77,105.56"><head>Table 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>TfidfVectorizer parameters and results on Dutch</figDesc><table coords="7,168.67,142.97,275.77,79.90"><row><cell>Subtask</cell><cell cols="4">Range Max-df Min-df Sublinear tf Vocab. CV result Result</cell></row><row><cell>gender</cell><cell>1, 3 0.95</cell><cell>0.17 FALSE</cell><cell cols="2">3663 76.47% 84.38%</cell></row><row><cell>stable</cell><cell>1, 3 N/A</cell><cell>N/A TRUE</cell><cell cols="2">17015 0.1592 0.1405</cell></row><row><cell>agreeable</cell><cell>2, 6 N/A</cell><cell>N/A FALSE</cell><cell>237795 0.123</cell><cell>0.1114</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">extroverted 2, 6 N/A</cell><cell>N/A TRUE</cell><cell cols="2">237795 0.1075 0.131</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">conscientious 2, 6 N/A</cell><cell>N/A FALSE</cell><cell cols="2">237795 0.0964 0.1147</cell></row><row><cell>open</cell><cell>3, 5 N/A</cell><cell>N/A TRUE</cell><cell cols="2">127649 0.0915 0.0846</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" coords="7,168.67,237.20,275.77,105.56"><head>Table 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>TfidfVectorizer parameters and results on Italian</figDesc><table coords="7,168.67,262.85,275.77,79.90"><row><cell>Subtask</cell><cell cols="5">Range Max-df Min-df Sublinear tf Vocab. CV result Result</cell></row><row><cell>gender</cell><cell>5, 7 0.72</cell><cell>0.1</cell><cell>TRUE</cell><cell cols="2">31745 78.94% 63.89%</cell></row><row><cell>stable</cell><cell>3, 5 N/A</cell><cell cols="2">N/A TRUE</cell><cell cols="2">165628 0.1502 0.1913</cell></row><row><cell>agreeable</cell><cell>3, 5 N/A</cell><cell cols="2">N/A FALSE</cell><cell cols="2">165628 0.1227 0.122</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">extroverted 2, 4 N/A</cell><cell cols="2">N/A FALSE</cell><cell cols="2">74719 0.1191 0.1141</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">conscientious 3, 5 N/A</cell><cell cols="2">N/A FALSE</cell><cell>165628 0.101</cell><cell>0.114</cell></row><row><cell>open</cell><cell>2, 6 N/A</cell><cell cols="2">N/A FALSE</cell><cell cols="2">307144 0.1298 0.1438</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,142.61,538.27,327.51,7.77;7,150.95,549.23,39.84,7.77" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,257.69,538.27,149.71,7.77">Natural Language Processing with Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Loper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<publisher>O&apos;Reilly Media Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,142.61,559.76,326.52,7.77;7,150.95,570.72,309.78,7.77" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,366.21,559.76,102.93,7.77;7,150.95,570.72,68.45,7.77">Liblinear: A library for large linear classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hsieh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,224.92,570.72,139.44,7.77">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1871" to="1874" />
			<date type="published" when="2008-06">June 2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,142.61,581.24,337.32,7.77;7,150.95,592.20,328.22,7.77;7,150.95,604.00,247.47,6.31" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,341.71,581.24,122.88,7.77">Predicting personality from twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Golbeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Robles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Edmondson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://dblp.uni-trier.de/db/conf/socialcom/socialcom2011.html#GolbeckRET11" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,150.95,592.20,71.05,7.77">SocialCom/PASSAT</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="156" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,142.61,613.68,306.80,7.77;7,150.95,624.64,292.99,7.77;7,150.95,635.60,174.27,7.77" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,348.30,613.68,101.11,7.77;7,150.95,624.64,216.91,7.77">Using linguistic cues for the automatic recognition of personality in conversation and text</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Mairesse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mehl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,373.21,624.64,70.73,7.77;7,150.95,635.60,77.43,7.77">Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="457" to="500" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<publisher>JAIR</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,142.61,646.13,321.88,7.77;7,150.95,657.08,139.48,7.77" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mccrae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Costa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="7,248.17,646.13,216.31,7.77">Personality in Adulthood: A Five-Factor Theory Perspective</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York; Guildford</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.61,119.96,337.98,7.77;8,150.95,130.92,300.54,7.77;8,150.95,141.88,322.31,7.77;8,150.95,152.84,208.17,7.77" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,295.94,141.88,144.73,7.77">Scikit-learn: Machine learning in Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Pedregosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Varoquaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gramfort</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Thirion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Grisel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Blondel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Prettenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Weiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Dubourg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vanderplas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Passos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Cournapeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brucher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Perrot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Duchesnay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,446.86,141.88,26.40,7.77;8,150.95,152.84,110.80,7.77">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2825" to="2830" />
			<date type="published" when="2011-10">Oct 2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.61,163.80,316.40,7.77;8,150.95,174.76,319.51,7.77;8,150.95,185.71,308.39,7.77;8,150.95,196.67,271.98,7.77;8,150.95,208.47,328.17,6.31" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,347.32,163.80,111.69,7.77;8,150.95,174.76,121.39,7.77">Our twitter profiles, our selves: Predicting personality with twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Quercia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kosinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Stillwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Crowcroft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpls/abs_all.jsp?arnumber=6113111&amp;tag=1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,289.93,174.76,180.53,7.77;8,150.95,185.71,308.39,7.77;8,150.95,196.67,123.87,7.77">Proceedings of the Third International Conference on Social Computing (SocialCom) and the Third International Conference on Privacy, Security, Risk and Trust (PASSAT)</title>
		<meeting>the Third International Conference on Social Computing (SocialCom) and the Third International Conference on Privacy, Security, Risk and Trust (PASSAT)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011-10">Oct 2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="180" to="185" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.61,218.59,326.22,7.77;8,150.95,229.55,329.64,7.77;8,150.95,240.51,246.03,7.77" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,371.59,218.59,97.25,7.77;8,150.95,229.55,89.53,7.77">Overview of the 3rd author profiling task at pan 2015</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Daelemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="-WS.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,458.67,229.55,21.92,7.77;8,150.95,240.51,93.16,7.77">CLEF 2015 Labs and Workshops</title>
		<title level="s" coord="8,250.60,240.51,85.63,7.77">Notebook Papers. CEUR</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cappellato</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gareth</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>San Juan</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.61,251.47,304.42,7.77;8,150.95,262.43,309.51,7.77;8,150.95,273.39,281.95,7.77" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,150.95,262.43,257.79,7.77">Computational modeling of uncertainty avoidance in consumer behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Roozmand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ghasem-Aghaee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Nematbakhsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Baraani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hofstede</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,414.65,262.43,45.82,7.77;8,150.95,273.39,196.53,7.77">International Journal of Research and Reviews in Computer Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2011-04">April 2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.24,284.34,299.77,7.77;8,150.95,295.30,121.79,7.77;8,150.95,307.11,236.71,6.31" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,270.20,284.34,122.93,7.77">A survey of personality computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vinciarelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mohammadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/TAFFC.2014.2330816</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TAFFC.2014.2330816" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,399.44,284.34,42.57,7.77;8,150.95,295.30,40.36,7.77">T. Affective Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="273" to="291" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
