<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,230.76,166.71,153.90,14.80">Contextual Suggestion</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2012-10-16">October 16, 2012</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,266.04,198.03,83.06,11.56"><forename type="first">Abhishek</forename><surname>Mallik</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,271.44,258.87,71.33,11.56"><forename type="first">Mandar</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Enginerring IIT Bombay Powai</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>400076</postCode>
									<settlement>Mumbai</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Unit ISI Kolkata Kolkata</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>700 108</addrLine>
									<country>India Kripabandhu</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Ghosh Computer Vision and Pattern Recognltion Unit ISI Kolkata</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>700 108</postCode>
									<settlement>Kolkata</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,230.76,166.71,153.90,14.80">Contextual Suggestion</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2012-10-16">October 16, 2012</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">30290D8481FDB7C92C27DA89D41646EE</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:07+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The goal of this project is to build a Contextual Suggestion system that will recommend the usel a lanked list of suggestions depending on user's context as well as her preferences.  In this context we pr€6ent an algorithm based on the regular expression for extra.ting time and address information from different websites for the places. Then we have suggested a ranking function that can utilize these timing and address information of those places as well as the users' context and preferences to rank the places. Here the page6 are unstructured but the address is structured i.e. template based as we have worked with only the plaaes located at Toronto, Canada.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="601.56" lry="784.44"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="600.48" lry="784.8"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="600.48" lry="784.44"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="600.84" lry="785.16"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="602.64" lry="785.52"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="605.16" lry="784.08"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="601.56" lry="783.72"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="601.56" lry="784.44"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="600.48" lry="784.8"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Main motivation behind this task is to build future information retrieval systems that must anticipate user needs and respond with information appropriate to the current context without the user having to enter an explicit query. In a mobile context such a system might take the form of an application that recommends irrteresting places and activities based on the user's location and time a"nd other factor such as her preference etc.</p><p>Step 3 Google Map also gives some status messages along with the result regarding whether the place is closed or not. So we check if there is an associated status message saying that "The plare is permanently closed".</p><p>Ifnot, we add the address to the address list 2 ofthat place. So by utlizing this feature of Google Map we have made our algorithm more reliable.</p><p>Step 4 Repeat step 2 and 3 until end of the la,st result of the page is encountered (when there axe multiple such results on the page).</p><p>Step 5 If any address is found in the above steps, then stop, else goto next step.</p><p>Step 6 Repeat Step 1 with Google search3 to ffnd the address and down-Ioad first result page.</p><p>Step 7 R€sult page basically consists of a collection of URLs with asso ciated titles and snippets. We apply a.ddress extraction step to search for potential address patterns in those snippets of the results, starting from the top of the result page.</p><p>Step 8 If the best matched address pattern returned by the address extraction step contains full a.dress then we stop. Otherwise if partial address is found in the snipper, then that URL associated with the snippet is crawled with the hope of finding the full address.</p><p>Step 9 So if full address found then stop, if again a partial address found after crawling the UR.L, go to next step, else go to step 10.</p><p>Step 10 Qrety uruw.yelp.caa with the title name and partial address, return the full address if found, otherwise the pa.rtial address, that has been found earlier, is returned.</p><p>Step 11 Here we crawl the UR-L of the example itself (that is also given with each exmaple in the flle exanples. txt) upto depth 25 and then applied the following address extraction step on the crawled pages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Address Extraction</head><p>Step For that step, we have surveyed quite a la"rge number of addresses in Canada (as all the examples are taken from Toronto, Onatrio). We have found that most of them follow a particular template as follows: They start with street number (in digit) followed by street Narne followed by one of these termns Street, St., Road, Rd,, Bouleward, Blvd., Avenue, Ave., Parkway, Pky, Highway, Hwy, Broadway, Way, Wy, Drive, Dr, T\.rrnpike followed by one of these 2There may be more than ooe outlets of a shop or restau&amp;nt in a city 3http://www. google.com 4ye1p.ca is a well established aggregstor site itr Canda that contarns informatiotr about restaurants in Canada sUsually for all of such websites addresse€ are found at depth &lt; 2 terms North, South, East, West followed by term Toronto then Ontario/ON and then postal code which is in alpha-numeric format followed by Country Name.   But sometimes they deviate from this by certain amount, for example Courtry Nane, the direction Nolth, Soutb, East and West are not present in all of them. So we have made a regula.r expression using the above heuristic but not made the above requir€ments stringent. As a result with the valid address expressions a few meaningless expressions a.lso have got returned which have nothing to do with an address. So those matched expressions was again scored, based on how much they are close to the above template, Expression having maximum score is returned, which is nothing but the va.lid postal address we are looking for.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Temporal Interval Extraction Algorithm</head><p>Temporal Intervals of geographic entities are expressed in rarious forms. Some of the motiwting examples are as follows: To extract timing, we have used several heuristics in our algorithm as follows:</p><p>.</p><p>Step 1 Query Google with the title of the example appended with "Toronto6 hours of operation", for example if the title is "CN Tower", we have formu- lated the query as "CN Tower Toronto hours of operation" and download the fust result page. We have chosen the phrase "hours of operation" because mostly in the websites of places like restaurant, hotel, cafe, art gallery etc. timing information is specified as "hours of operation". o Step 2 Parse the downloaded result page to collect URLs, titles and snippets of all results, store them in sepa.rate files.</p><p>. Step 3 Examine the UR.Ls collected in the above step one by one from top to check if any of them conains the url of the example itself or contains the term ttfad', as index page of a site and an url containing the term " fad' a,re more Iikely to contain the timing information. If any such URL is found, downloa.d the page at this URL, else, goto step 5.</p><p>o Step 4 Apply timing information extraction step (this will be described Iater in this report) on the downloaded page.</p><p>o Step 5 If any timing expression is found in the above step then stop, else goto next step. r Step 6 Check rest of the results one by one fron top whether its title contains title of concerned example or its associated UR.L contains the URL of the concerned exa.ruple. If any of these ts'o satisfies, goto next step else goto step 10. 6As here we are concerned with city of Toronto and th€re may be outlets of a bratrd (for example, Pizza Hut) all over the world, otherwise ll'e may get erroneous result</p><p>Step 7 Associated snippet che&amp;ed to see if it contains certain phrases like hours of operation/operating hours/timing/hour, am/pm and rnonf tue/wedf thu/ .../daily etc. Ifyes, then the associated page from which this snippet has been generated is more Iikely to contain the timing information. So page at the associated URL is downloaded and then we goto next step else, goto step 10,</p><p>Step 8 Apply timing information extraction step on the page which we have just downloaded in the above step.</p><p>Step 9 If auy tirning expression is found in step 8 then stop, else goto next step.</p><p>Step 10 This is again a fallback step. Here we crawl the URJ, of the concerned example itself upto depth 27.</p><p>Step 11 Pa,rse a.ll these web pages that we have crawled at step 10 and applied timing information extraction step on the crawled pages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Timing Extraction</head><p>Step Similar to address extraction step, we have tried to come up with a regular expression for extraating timings also.</p><p>As we have seen earlier timing information i.e. temporal interval may appear in several forms, that is why we have to turn and twist the regula.r expression severa,l times in ord€r to capture the interval accurately. So it is clear from this discussion so far that this temporal interval extraction requires a considerable amount of marual intervention.</p><p>Then we have scored the expressions that have matched with our final regular expression to determine which expression is most fit to appear as temporal interval of a geographic entity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Computation of Geo-Temporal Match</head><p>To compute the geG-temporal match between the example place and user's context we shall first discuss about how we have utlized the addresses ofthe example places to determine their proximity with respect to the geographic contexts of the users, then we shall discuss about matching between the temporal intervals of the geographic entities and the tempora,l contexts of the users. So to utlize the users' geographic context, v!'e have followed the approach as follows:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2.3,1 Finding geographical match</head><p>We cannot directly process the address directly, so to utlize them in ranking we have to map them to the geographic distance of that place. In order to do this, each of the postal address found in the above steps is passed as pararnet€r to Yahoo! geocoding API8 to find correspondiug Iatitude and longitude and TThe same logic in cas€ of address extra.tion is spptcable here i.e. usually all 6uch webEit€s contain timing information at depth &lt; 2 shttp://api.maps.yahoo.com/ajax/geocode?appid=onestep&amp;qt=1 &amp;id=m&amp;qs="address" then the geographic distance is calculated from user's location to that place by a.pplying Vincent's formula, that ta.kes latitudes and longitudes of two plarces and computes the geographic distance.</p><p>There are places having more than one outlets in a city and each of the outlet has a postal address. So for each of them we calculate the distance to the user's current geographic context and select the outlet with the minimum distance, which is only taken as the distance of the entity in the user's current context.</p><p>Fllrther we normalize the distances as follows: for each context of the user, after getting its dista.nce to each of the example place in the above step, we find the maximum distance nax among them and divide each distance that I have computed ea.rlier by rnax. As a result the resulting distances fall in the range between 0 and 1. So ftom the discussion so far, it is clear that we a.re successfully able to utilize user's geographic contxet.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.2">Finding temporal match</head><p>Here like a.ddress we also postprocess the temporal interval th&amp;t we have ex- tracted in the earlier steps, as follows: Suppose for one place hours of operation is as follows: "Mon-Fri: llam-10pm Sat and Sun : 11arn -8prn". As we cannot incorporate timing information in this format in our ranking function, so it is converted to the following expression: weekday, 1, morning, 1,4, afternoon,0,5, evening, 0,2, weekend, 1, morning, 2, 3, afternoon, 0, 5, evening,0,2 Here we have followed the format as follows: weekday terml, morning, term2, term3, afternoon, term4, term3, evening, terms, term3, weekend, term6, morning, term2, term3, afternoon, term4, term3, evening, term5, term3  The meaning of each of the terms are given as follows: (duration the location is opened during this 5 hours)</p><p>(opening time of the location -1 pm)</p><p>(opening time of the location -6 pm)</p><p>While converting the timing information that we have extracted ftom the pages to the format (that we have shown above) we have fa.ced a challenge. The timing information we have extrapted for places are basically da1'wise of a week.</p><p>But here in this task we ale concerned with only "weekday" and "weekend".</p><p>gAccording to assumption in this tra.k, morning session starts at I am! afternoon session starts &amp;t I pm, evening session starts at 6 pm and duration of eaah session is 5 hour6 number of weekdavs the location is o mrmber of weekends the location is o There are places where the buiness hours vary daywise in each week. So for ha.ndling that, we have simply taken the maximum of the opening times and minimum of the closing times for each place for weekdays and weekends sep arately and consider them a.s starting times and closing times of those places.</p><p>We illustrate this with a simple example as follows:</p><p>Suppose there is a place A for which business hour is as follows: Mon-Wed: 10 AM-11PM, Thu and Fli: 11AM-9PM, Sat: 10AM-9PM, Sun: 10AM-5PM. In that case for "weekday", according to our logic we take opening time of A as 11 AM and closing time as g PM and for "weekend" we take opening time as 10AM and closing time as 5PM.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Ranking F\rnction</head><p>To rank the example places first we have to determine how the spatial infor- mation and temporal information, that we have gathered already, can influence ranking function individually and then fina.lly we shall combine their influences. So, we shall present first the ranking fuuction itself and then explain influence of each of them separatelv.</p><p>-,,\ lh x(-t2 +t3+(1 -d)), ir 2o L,, ' t tr -I (Id), Timing information is not found/ \r'r 3.1 Incorporating Geographic Information In Ranking Fbnc- tion While considering the spatial information only, we can easily conclude that farther a place is ftom an user's geographiic context, lower is its rank a.nd vice versa. We have incorporated the contribution of the distance in ranking function r/0 as follows:</p><p>If the normalized distance (that we have talked about earlier) from a place to an user's geographic context is computed as d, then the contribution of the distance to ranling function r/0 is (td) and that appea.rs in the ranking function r/0 as &amp;n + term in the equation 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Incorporating Temporal Information</head><p>In R-anking F\rnc- tion Now we shall discuss the influence of timing information on the ranking function r/0. Like spatial information, timing information also plays a crucial role in the ranking function r/0. Timing information will come in three different forms in the ranking function: First and most important thing is the probability that a place is opened on a "weekday" or a "weekend" (as these axe the only two days of a week we are interested in the current task). We have calculated this probability t1 as follows: For weekdays t1 is the number of days between Monday to Fliday, the place is opened divided by 5 (which is the number of weekdays) and for weekend t1 is number of days between Saturday &amp;nd Sunday, it is opened divided by 2 (which is the number of weekends in a week). This term is the most important in the ranking function for the following simple reason i.e. if the place is not available in that day i.e. weekday or weekend, then whatever the distance between this place and current context is, it should get a score of 0. So we can incorporate the contribution of timing information in this probability form in ranking function r/0 as follows: If the probability is t1, then we can write its contribution to the ranking function r/0 as f1 itself and it appears as an AND i.e a product term as shown in the above equation J.</p><p>Second important thing is the time gap between the time a session (i.e. roorDilg, afteraoo! or eveuing whichever is applicable with respect to user's context) staxts and time the place is available in that session, which is basically captured by one among term2, termS and term4 depending upon the user's t€mporsl context. Larger this time gap is, less is the availability ofthe associated place in the current user's context. So later the place opens in a session, which is an user's current context, lower its rank will be in the ranked list. So it is quite clear that, ranking function r/0 should be decreasing fuuction of this time gap. So we have incorporated the contribution of this this time gap in ra.uking function r/0 in equation 1 as follows: If the time gap is t, which is nothing but, one among term2, term4 or term\, depending on the user's cu[ent context, then the contribution of timing information in norma.lized form to the ranking function r/0 is -11 (where ir : r/5) and it appeaxs as a + term in equation 1.</p><p>The last form, by which the timing information can influence the ranking function r/0, can be explained as follows: in a session that is appropriate to user's current context, more duration a place is opened, more will it gets score, so higher will be its rank in the ranked list of places. It is quite clear that ranking function r/0 should be increasing function of this time duration. So we have incorporated the contribution of temporal interval in the form of time duration in our ranking function r/0 in equation 1 as follows:</p><p>Here we have taken the norma.lized time duration, which is nothing but termSf 5 (term3 is actual time duration vrith which the place is opened in that session and according to ssumption of this task duration of each session is 5 hours). So if it is t3, then the contribution of timing information in this form to the ranking function rJQ is t3 i.e. the time duration in the normalized form itself and that also appears as a + term as shown in equation 1.</p><p>But there are few places, where we could not extract the timing information due to the reason of unavailability of this information or it was embedded in such a format we could not extract it.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>In this section we describe the results. There are 3 evaluation measures. The measures are P@5 for each of the following combinations of results:</p><p>WGT, GT and W. Due to space constraint, we are reporting here the result for only the dimension P@5-W (As for other two dimensions we have got worst result). Here following table shows per-context statistics based on mean scores over profrles.  Above table shows a best, median and worst values over all runs submitted to this track, as well as the same va.lue for our run for the measure P@5-W per context. It is clear from the t&amp;ble that, almost in all the cases P@5-W for our run is close to the best result. Now in the following tables we have reported per-profile statistics based on mean scores over contexts. Above table shorrs a best, median and worst va,lues over all runs submitted to this traak, as well as the same value for our run for the measure P@5-W per context. It is clear from the table that, almost in all the cases P@5-W for our run is close to the best result.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="8,196.92,180.50,211.95,453.40">V P(5)@ヽ V Context Best Median Worst Our value ３ ４ ９ ■ １ ２ -３ -４ -５ -６ ・ ８ ・ ９ ２ ０ ２ ３ ８ ９ ０ １ ２ ３ ４ ５ ６ ３ ７ ３ ８ ３ ９ ４ ０ ４ - ４ ２ ４ ３ ４ ４ ６ ４ ６ ４ ７ ５ ０ ´２ ２ ２ ２ ３ ３ ３ ３ ３ ３ ３<label>08000</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>In this report we have seen how to extract temporal and address information ftom web pages having heterogeneous strcuture, that is having no template common to each other and utlizing these extracted information suggest a ranked list of places to user depending on her context.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="5,160.92,469.46,25.55,10.64;5,160.92,490.70,26.12,9.25;5,160.92,511.22,25.56,9.25;5,160.92,530.66,26.84,9.71;5,161.28,551.18,25.56,9.25;5,161.28,575.30,25.56,9.25;5,220.32,487.82,168.48,12.50"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>of the location -I am e)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="8,221.40,183.10,148.75,8.50"><head>Table l :</head><label>l</label><figDesc>Table for the metric P@5̲ヽ</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="9,198.72,205.34,211.95,271.28"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Table for the metric P@5̲ヽ V</figDesc><table coords="9,198.72,226.87,211.95,249.76"><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>P(5)@W</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Context</cell><cell>Best</cell><cell cols="2">ヽ 〔 edian ヽ Morst</cell><cell>Our value</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>06667</cell><cell>04000</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>06667</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell>07333</cell><cell>02667</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>07333</cell></row><row><cell>6</cell><cell>08000</cell><cell>04000</cell><cell>0.0667</cell><cell>08000</cell></row><row><cell>8</cell><cell>08667</cell><cell>04667</cell><cell>02000</cell><cell>07333</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>07333</cell><cell>02667</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>06667</cell></row><row><cell>14</cell><cell>06667</cell><cell>04000</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>06000</cell></row><row><cell>16</cell><cell>10000</cell><cell>04000</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>10000</cell></row><row><cell>17</cell><cell>06000</cell><cell>04000</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>06000</cell></row><row><cell>18</cell><cell>08000</cell><cell>04000</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>08000</cell></row><row><cell>19</cell><cell>03000</cell><cell>01000</cell><cell>0 0CIC10</cell><cell>01000</cell></row><row><cell>21</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>0011C10</cell><cell>00000</cell></row><row><cell>22</cell><cell>07333</cell><cell>02000</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>07333</cell></row><row><cell>23</cell><cell>04000</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>02000</cell></row><row><cell>25</cell><cell>08667</cell><cell>06000</cell><cell>02667</cell><cell>08667</cell></row><row><cell>26</cell><cell>08000</cell><cell>03000</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>07000</cell></row><row><cell>27</cell><cell>07333</cell><cell>05333</cell><cell>00667</cell><cell>04000</cell></row><row><cell>28</cell><cell>06000</cell><cell>02000</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>00000</cell></row><row><cell>31</cell><cell>10000</cell><cell>04000</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>10000</cell></row><row><cell>33</cell><cell>06000</cell><cell>03333</cell><cell>00000</cell><cell>02667</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
