<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,85.32,70.96,430.96,18.29;1,114.84,90.76,372.23,18.40">Microblog Search and Filtering with Time Sensitive Feedback and Thresholding based on BM25</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,131.40,136.46,45.85,11.00"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
							<email>wgao@qf.org.qa</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Qatar Computing Research lnstitute Oatar Foundation Doha</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="QA">Qatar</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,266.04,136.46,68.62,10.64"><forename type="first">Zhongyu</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
							<email>zywei@se.cuhk.edu.hk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">The Chinese University ol Hong</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kong Shatin, Hong Kong</settlement>
									<region>N.T</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,408.24,136.46,77.56,10.64"><forename type="first">Kam-Fai</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
							<email>kfwong@se.cuhk.edu.hk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">The Chinese University ol Hong</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kong Shatin, Hong Kong</settlement>
									<region>N.T</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,85.32,70.96,430.96,18.29;1,114.84,90.76,372.23,18.40">Microblog Search and Filtering with Time Sensitive Feedback and Thresholding based on BM25</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">34AAAAD202AFAE25848D7ABEBEDA0737</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:07+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure t</head><p>The work flow of Tt{itt€r search syst4m for real-tjme adhoc task. We output 4 runs: Bl\415, BM2sPRF, BM2STRF   and MergedRun, vious 3 runs, respectively.</p><p>. Real-time filtering task: We chose a typical adaptive filtering algorithm YFilter [8] as the baseline, which used BM25 with Rocchio fctdback [6] as the basic scoring function. The reason to choose it is it's a gre€dy and purely real-time algo- rithm without fie ne€d of any offiine training. Then its tlrc€ variants are used to Tbe€ts201l corpus for experiments, rcsulting in QFilRunl, QFilRun2 and QFilRun3 for submis- sion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">SYSTEMS OVERVIEW</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Real-time adhoc search system</head><p>The archite{ture of search system is described in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="1,525.24,558.37,2.50,5.55">1</ref>.</p><p>The incoming twe€ts are nrstly preprocessed with some basic normalization steps before indexing. All the English tweets are au- tomatically identified using a language detection toolkit. A1l words were convened to lowercase and stemmcd using Krovetz stemmer, the puncEations were removed, the words in the hastag '#' were duplicate4 but we didn't removed the stop words.</p><p>To simulate the requirement of not using future information, we indexed only the tweets post€d before the querytweet time for each query for avoiding the influence from fuhrre twe.ts on IDF.</p><p>We tried two types ofblind fe€dback for query expansion. One is the traditional ps€udo-relevance feedback (PRD which assumes the top-n tweets in the initial search Esult as relevant, and the other is the temporal relevance feedback (TRD which assumed the tweets falling into the laryest peak detected from the initial results as rel-ABSTRACT Microblogs such as Twitter are considered faster Rrst-hand sources of information with many real-tim€ fashions. We report our work in the real-time adhoc search and filtering tasks of TREC 2012 microblog tlack. Our system is built based on the traditional BM25 relevance model, in which specific techniques are tried out to respond to the ne.ed of frnding relevant tweets, ln thc real-time adhoc task, we applied a peak detection algorithm for the process of blind fe€dback, We also tried to automatically combine the search results of multiple retrieval techniques. In the real-time filtering pilot task, we examine the effectiveness of some typical filtering methods pre- viously used in TREC filtering track.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="605.88" lry="781.92"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="605.52" lry="780.84"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="603.36" lry="780.84"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="604.44" lry="781.2"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="608.76" lry="781.2"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">INTRODUCTION</head><p>This year comes the second eiition of the TREC Microblog track following the evaluation for real-time tasks on Tlveets2ol I corpus.</p><p>Like the real-time adhoc task in 20ll's edition, the system is re- quired to retum the most recent relevant twe€ts for 60 newly creaied topics, posted earlier than thc time each query was issued In addition, Microblog track 2012 infoduced a real-time iltering pilot task for the nrst time thought of as onhogonal to the real-time adhoc task. ln this task, the goal is to selert relevant tweets that are subsequently posted after a query issued at a particular time. This caters for the need of a user to monitor a developing topic on TWitter.</p><p>we participated in both of the tasks and submitted 4 runs for the adhoc and 3 runs for the filtering, all of which used the traditional BM25 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,76.68,505.10,10.01,8.32" target="#b5">[5]</ref> as the core relevance model. The reason to use BM25 is that its score function performs more effectively for IR in gen- eral. By this participation, wc are hoping to create some baseling rnethods and then try to improve upon them.</p><p>. Real-time adhoc task: The 4 runs we submitted for this task ale 8M25, BM25PRF, BM25TRF, and MergedRun, which   conespond to the bas€line using BM25 scodng function, BM25 plus blind (pseudo-relevance) feedback, BM25 plus blind feedback favoring the tweets fell into the temporally detected peaks, and the weighted merge of result lists from the pre- Permission to make digital or hard copies of all or pan of this woik for personal or classroom use is gmnted without fee provided that copies are not made or distnbuted for profit or commercial advantage ard that copies bear this notic! add the full citation on the first page. To copy otherwise, [o republish, to post on serveN ot 0o rcdistribute to lisls, requires prior spccific p€rmission andor a fee.</p><p>Copyrisht 20XX ACM X-XXXXX-XX-X/XX/XX ...$10.00.  evant. We applied the peak-finding algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="2,221.40,285.50,10.01,8.32" target="#b2">[2]</ref> to automatically discover the main lraks from the results.</p><p>Based on the results of 8M25, PRF and TRF, we merged the tlue€ result lists into a single list for the Mcrg€dRun using a weighted score combination method <ref type="bibr" coords="2,153.72,326.18,10.42,9.25">[7]</ref>. We utilized the queries and rele- vance judgement of Microblog track 201 I ro t:ain the weights of the lists for maximizing the MAP measure as did in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,240.84,348.14,8.86,7.86">[7]</ref>.</p><p>The detailed method of peak-find-based blind feedback is presented in Section 4.1 and the result combination is given in Sec- tion 4.2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Real-time filtering system</head><p>The workflow of the filtering system is described in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,274.68,409.69,2.92,6.48" target="#fig_0">2</ref>.</p><p>The procedure was an variant of YFilter <ref type="bibr" coords="2,210.24,419.78,9.38,8.32" target="#b8">[8]</ref>. The algorithm did not ne€d any prior training data. Instead, it continuously updarcd the threshold of relevancy and the profile of queries with the incoming tweet streams. Initially, each query is profiled only based on the query words, and then the profile is updated automatically us- ing Rocchio feedback <ref type="bibr" coords="2,132.12,470.54,9.45,7.86" target="#b6">[6]</ref> according to the decision of selection and the rclcvancy of the cunent tweet. The scoring function is based on BM25.</p><p>We output 3 runs. QFill used the twe€ts in the corpus that are out of the time range between the lowest querytwe€ttime and the highest querynewesttweet of 4ll queries for calculating prior IDF values, considered as using limited future information. QFil2 used only tweets that €re up to the currcn! incoming tweet for computing prior IDF values. QFil3 is based on QFil2 and placed more srrict threshold update nrles. The details of the algorithm are desc.ibed in Secrion 4.3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">DATASETAND STATISTICS</head><p>The Tw€et2ol I corpus contains tweets of two weeks from Jan. 23rd to Feb, 8th, 201 l. According to the policy of Ttvitter, twerts corpus is not allowed to redisbibute. Therefore, TREC Microblog dataset only contains the ids ofover 16 million tweets, and the participants ale re4uired to crawl tweets content separately. Howevet the availability of past tweets is unc€rtain berause twitter authors can delete their posts. Besides, the twe€ts downloaded by different groups may not be identical due to diffet€nt quality of network connection. The statistics ofour obtained dataset are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,286.92,690.50,2.50,8.33">I</ref> and Table <ref type="table" coords="2,88.56,701.66,3.13,6.94">2</ref>. As shown in Thble 1, among total 16,141,812 HTTP requests, we successfully downloaded 15,598,190 valid tweets. Since the task focus€s on English tweets only, we eliminated all the non-English tweets first using the language identifier tool provided by Nutchr, resulting ir 6,246,970 English tweets in our corpus.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="2,346.68,320.06,4.45,7.40">2</ref> indicatcs that in our English tweets, therc are 3,845,290 mentions (with preaedilg symbol '@', which is used to dhecUy refer to other us€rs' twe€ts), 1,483,349 hash tags and 1,560,068 LrRLs. Totally, there are 80,009,364 words.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">TECHNICALDETAILS</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Peak-Find-basedblindfeedback</head><p>Microblog streams are in the form of continuous incoming data nows, which is analogous !o the network data ransmission where care must tre take for controlling crnjestion. Peak-finding algo- rithm [2] was inspired by the similar problem encountered in TCP's conjcction control mechanism. The gosl is to determine whether a window (a nxed period of time) contains an usually large number of tweets in it. Unlike the pseudo-relevance feedback, we assume that only those twerts in the peaks of the initial search result list are rclevant which can be used for guiding the blind feedback pro- cess. The rationalc is that it is more likely those relevant terms to be found in the peaks oftweets for doing query expansion.</p><p>The peak-finding algorithm first groups the tweets into a histogram by time. We used hour as the basic unit and a whole day (24 hours) as a bin in our implementation. We counted the tweet-arrival rate in each bin starting from the querytweettime to the time of the oldest retriev€d tweet. Then the detection process goes as follows (see <ref type="bibr" coords="2,331.56,573.86,9.45,7.86" target="#b2">[2]</ref> for details):</p><p>e When the algorithm encounters a significant increasc in bin count relative to the historical mean, it starts a new window and follows the increase to its maximum.</p><p>. The algorithm ends the peak's window once the bin count retums to the same level it started at, or wh€n it encounteB another signifi cant increase.</p><p>In Figue 3, we illustate the correlation between the peaks of event and the relevant tweets according to the relevance judgement.</p><p>:-'https : // j.ssues, apache. orgl j ira /bEowse / NUTCH-623</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,81.36,275.42,4.17,9.25">3</ref>: The clos€ corr€lation of burst patterns between the retrievcd tweets about the query and the relevart tweets from relevance Judgement.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,78.48,338.05,3.89,6.48">3</ref> shows three real-time adhoc task topics in Microblog track 201 I when we used it to dcvelop the system, where the curves at the lefl side are the count of relevant twe€ts (including highly relevant ones) in each day after the query is issued, and the histograms at the right side are the bursts of tweets of each day automatically identified by peak-finding from fte initial search results. We can clearly observe such conelation betwe€n the bunty pattems of two sides.</p><p>After the initial retrieval, we &amp;pplied peak-finding to the toF 1000 search results and extracted those tweets falling into the first and sccold larg€st peaks, which are deemed as feedback docu- merlts used for query expansion. We output the results ofthe secondround retrieval using the expanded queries, referred to as BM25TRF.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Merge of different result lists</head><p>To improve the ranking of search result, many rctrioval systems used score combination approach to merge the result lists produced by different r€t ieval methods. The basic assumption of improving ranking accuracy by combining ranked lists is that relevant docu- ments are generally retrieved by multiple retriel'al algorithms while different retrieval algorithms tend to retrieve different irrelevant documents <ref type="bibr" coords="3,94.32,555.14,10.42,9.25">[7]</ref>. Similar idea has be€n used in Metasearch, fedgr- ate search and multilingual information retrieval (MLIR). Si and Callan [7j introduced a leaming based merge algorithm for MLIR, where they used training data to leam the weights of each result list by direcdy optimizing the mean average precision (MAP) mea- sure of the combined ralking result. We applied this approach io merge the results of our first thre€ runs, i.e., 8M25, BM25PRR and BM25TRF.</p><p>Suppose there are ,|/ ranked lists to combine, we first normalized the retrieval scores of the each ranked list using Min-Max algo- riihm. Then the final combined scores for each tweet t is calculated as follows:</p><p>wherE ecare(t) is the final combined score, scorei(t) is the nor- malized score of t in the i-th ranked list, {tu1} and {r1} are thc model parameters.</p><p>The panmeters {rr1} and {r;} are estimated by maximizing MAP cliterion which is interpolat€d with two regularization terms for the parameters to avoid overfitting:</p><p>( N l(ror -1)' (r, -r)'l I (to;,r;)':TgiTjbs*n-If * -% l( (ur.rr) ( r=t L -" JJ where (t,;, ri is the opdmal model panmeters and (a, b) are two regularization factors. ln this work, we set a : b : 3.0 empir- ically, and the model parameters are estimated using the Powell's search method <ref type="bibr" coords="3,370.44,200.90,8.90,7.40" target="#b3">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,381.96,198.74,6.30,7.86" target="#b4">4]</ref>.</p><p>We trained the model parameters using the 50 topics and the relevance judgement from the data of Microblog track 2011. Then the nnking scores of twe€ts in MergedRun on the 2012 topics was calculated using Eq. l.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Greedy algorithn for online fiItering</head><p>We implemented thc profile updating algorithm of YFilter <ref type="bibr" coords="3,542.16,273.62,8.86,7.86" target="#b8">[8]</ref>, which includes the process of indexing, profiling, relevance scor- ing, Ricchio's feedback and thleshold updating as shown in Fig- Unlike information retrieval, indexing for filtering is simpler in a s€nse that only certain statistics on document frequency (DF) arc needed, and complex index structure can be ignored. We used hash map lo store word DF. Note that the DF table should be updated once an incoming tweet is received.</p><p>The profiling proce$s creates and maintains the information of a topic and its expansion, which is initialized with the original query words and is updated with the expansion words extracted from fcedback twe€ts.</p><p>The scoring function for relevance is based on BM25 formula <ref type="bibr" coords="3,543.60,407.90,9.45,7.86" target="#b5">[5]</ref> with regard to profile words and tweet words, where we set the common BM25 palameters as &amp;1 : 1.2, *2 : 0, /t3 : 8 and 6 : 0.75. An incoming tweet is selected or filtered out depending on whether its relevance score is greater than the theshold.</p><p>Ricchio's feedback is used to update tho profile. Whenever a relevant tweets is selected, all words in the tweets aro added to the profile's candidate word list and then weighted using the incre- mental Rocchio formula (see <ref type="bibr" coords="3,423.00,489.26,10.01,8.32" target="#b8">[8]</ref> for derails). We set the common Ricchio parameters as d : 1.0, p : 0.5, and ? : 0.25.</p><p>The threshold is dynamically updated depending on thc nature of a selected tweet. If the selected twert is not rclevant, we increase the thrcshold to make it morc strict. Ifthe selected twc€t has no feedback at all, we delrease the thrcshold in a small scale to allow for a higher chance to see the tweets with feedback information (see <ref type="bibr" coords="3,331.20,560.90,9.45,7.86" target="#b8">[8]</ref> for details).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">EXPERIMENTSANDRESULTS</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Topics and Statistics</head><p>The test dataset of real-time adhoc task (qrels) was established by pooling all the mns from the participating groups. There are 60 new topics in total this year. Like last yoar, three levels of relevancy are defined-highly relevant, relevant and non-rclevant. Retweets without further information were removed from the pool as they were assumed non-relevant.</p><p>The evaluation was done by considering only the highly relevant as relevant tweets. However, topic 53,69 aIId 105 did not contain any highly rolevant twerts in the pool, thus was discarded from the  Thble 4: Statisdcs of the tesa dataset (qrels) in rral-time filtering i{sk with 50 topics. evaluation resulting in 57 topics. We retrieve 10,000 tweets p€r query.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,104.40,667.30,183.92,44.79">… 0=井 喜 叫 -m.。</formula><p>The statistics of the adhoc tatk test datas€t ar€ shown in Thble 3, where the missing column reports the number of tweets missed in our cor?us due to download failurc.</p><p>The test dataset in real-time nltering task consists ofthe 50 topics in the 20ll adhoc task and the same relevance judgement. The statistics of the filtering task lest dataset are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,267.84,342.38,3.13,6.94">4</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.1">Result of real-time adhoc task</head><p>BM25 is the baseline run. The results of all 4 runs are shonT in Thble 5 in terms of Precison@30, MAP and R-Prec. The ROC curves I I ] of the 4 runs are given in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,208.08,413.66,3.13,6.94">4</ref>.</p><p>As we can observe, the performance of all our best runs (the bolded) is higher than the median. In terms of MAP and ROC curve, MergedRun outperforme.d other runs. T-test showed that its b€tter performance over BM25 and BM2sTRF is statistically significant (95% confidence level). But according ro P@30 and R-Prec, BM25PRF performed the best. Howevet it's not signifi- cantly better than others exc€pt for BM25. This may suggest that the MergcdRun has obvious advantage than other approaches.</p><p>Although BM25PRF outperformed BM25TRF in terms of the three measues, we didn't nnd it statistically significant. This indicales that the relevance feedback based on the busty event detection using peak-frnding a.lgorithm can achieve comparable effec- tiveness as the commonly usgd pseudo-relevance feedback. Also as we can see, BM25TRF retumed the most numbr of relevant twe€ts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.2">Resuh of real-time rtbering task</head><p>We submitted 3 similar runs in this task, in which QFill used limited amount of future information, QFil2 didn't use any future tweets, and QFil3 imposed some extra colstraints on thrcshold updating to make it more strict than the original rule of YFilter The results of all runs are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,185.76,640.46,3.13,6.94">6</ref>.</p><p>We found our results are generally poor in terms of all measures except for the excellent performance on the recall. This is actually caused by the large number of retliev€d results we rehrmcd due to the conservative threshold setting, which let pass most of the relevant tweets but also much more irrelevant ones. For example, both QFill and QFil2 retumed over 200K tweets. QFil3  over 60K due to its relalively strict threshold setting strategy, and this obviously improvcd the result a lot.</p><p>We did an additional experiment by simply aggressively increasing the initial threshold valuc by 60% afler the ofncial result was released. The numbers in the row of"Posf in Thblc 6 indicate some significant improvement on the thrce measues over oul b€st result with wide margin. There also could be other factors adjustable for fMher improvement, such as the magnitude of increase or decrease ofthe thrcshold when feedback is obtained. This suggests a large room for us to imprcve the thresholding in the futule.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">CONCLUSTONS</head><p>We describe our microblog search and nltering systcms for par- ticipating in microblog track 201I which were built based on the traditional BM25 model. For the real-time adhoc task, we applied a peak detection algorithn for the process of blind feedback. We also tried to automatically combine the search rcsults of multiple retrieval techniques. Results suggested that lhe reEult merging per- Thble 6: The fltering p€rformance of our subnrltted runs com- psred to the results of tle estimsted best rnd medisn. ﹃ 聾 formed the best, and the temporally detected bursts can be helpful to the relevanc€ feedback, archiving comparable effectiveness as the commonly used pseudo-relevance feedback. In the real-time filtering pilot task, we examine the effectiveness of some typical filtering methods previously used in TREC filtering track, The method didn't work well due to our lenient threshold updating strategy. However, more aggressive update on threshold did demonstmte some improvement. We will continue to tune our systems.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,54.00,234.38,238.04,10.23;2,54.00,245.54,69.43,8.58"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The work flow of TVitter fllterlng system for r€al- time ffltcritrg task.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="4,180.36,159.50,110.99,8.12;4,77.76,169.63,72.84,8.06;4,59.76,180.02,109.56,7.86;4,71.64,190.82,85.44,7.40;4,64.08,200.90,100.92,7.40;4,195.84,168.77,24.00,8.00;4,201.96,179.21,12.00,8.00;4,198.36,189.72,18.75,7.50;4,196.20,200.16,22.50,7.50;4,259.56,169.56,18.75,7.50;4,266.40,180.50,6.50,6.50;4,265.32,190.08,7.50,7.50;4,259.56,200.52,18.75,7.50;4,339.12,612.07,10.50,7.00;4,380.88,612.94,9.00,6.00;4,407.52,610.27,130.78,9.50;4,537.87,618.05,0.25,0.50;4,344.16,608.18,2.88,16.50;4,344.52,615.02,2.88,16.50;4,344.52,622.94,2.88,16.50;4,344.52,630.86,2.88,16.50;4,374.40,622.37,21.83,5.50;4,374.40,629.50,21.00,6.00;4,375.84,637.42,18.00,6.00;4,375.84,644.11,17.50,7.00;4,419.40,609.05,2.88,15.50;4,412.56,615.89,15.48,19.46;4,419.04,623.81,2.88,15.50;4,418.68,631.73,2.88,15.50;4,451.44,618.12,6.00,5.00;4,451.44,624.96,6.00,5.00;4,450.36,632.88,9.60,5.36;4,445.32,632.88,2.88,5.00;4,445.68,640.80,2.88,5.00;4,482.76,613.37,12.60,10.50;4,482.76,620.21,9.00,10.50;4,482.40,636.05,16.20,10.50;4,474.12,618.55,5.40,4.50;4,474.48,625.39,5.40,4.50;4,474.48,633.31,5.40,4.50;4,474.48,641.23,5.40,4.50;4,508.32,611.64,5.40,12.50;4,508.32,626.40,5.40,12.50;4,508.32,634.32,5.40,12.50;4,524.88,622.37,15.14,5.50;4,524.88,628.56,15.00,7.50;4,524.88,636.48,15.00,7.50;4,524.88,644.47,14.00,7.00;4,326.52,660.61,37.04,7.66;4,451.80,649.66,14.00,6.00;4,452.16,655.78,14.00,6.00;4,472.32,659.88,15.00,7.50;4,507.24,650.52,2.88,5.00;4,505.44,657.00,6.12,5.00"><head>Full</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,347.76,57.26,176.70,59.60"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>HTTP Response Code # ol tweets downloaded</figDesc><table coords="2,347.76,67.32,152.70,49.54"><row><cell>zuo (corect)</cell><cell>14,451,657</cell></row><row><cell>301</cell><cell>763</cell></row><row><cell>302</cell><cell>1,146,533</cell></row><row><cell>403</cell><cell>146,696</cell></row><row><cell>404 (connection error)</cell><cell>396,163</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="2,316.44,137.81,237.82,109.57"><head>Table l :</head><label>l</label><figDesc>Stausucs oF t■ eets dow」 ond in the danset Thblc 2: Statlstics of downloaded English arve€ts in ah€ datasel</figDesc><table coords="2,335.88,154.80,198.04,61.57"><row><cell></cell><cell>#with freq</cell><cell cols="2">Unlquc# #Ofmccts</cell></row><row><cell>Mention</cell><cell>3,845,290</cell><cell>1,933,002</cell><cell>2,968,353</cell></row><row><cell>Hashlag URL</cell><cell>1483,349 1,560,068</cell><cell>356,172</cell><cell>1,073,085 1,537,608</cell></row><row><cell>RcmcctcRT)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>304,391</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell>80,009,364</cell><cell>385,742</cell><cell>6,246,970</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="4,54.00,126.14,237.52,19.24"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Stausは OF the test dataset(qrels)in real-血 e adhoc task Ⅲth 60 new topics.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="4,261.00,53.21,282.40,655.02"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>retumc.d   </figDesc><table coords="4,327.96,53.21,215.44,73.36"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>Rcl Rct(2,572)</cell><cell cols="3">P@30 MAP R-Prec</cell></row><row><cell>BM25 BM25PRF BM25TRF</cell><cell>1,052 1,875 1,9117</cell><cell>0150 0.182 0171</cell><cell>O133 0154 0150</cell><cell>0152 0.188 0183</cell></row><row><cell>MergcdRun</cell><cell>1,902</cell><cell>0178</cell><cell>0.157</cell><cell>0176</cell></row><row><cell>Best(cst)</cell><cell></cell><cell>0392</cell><cell>0414</cell><cell>04」υ</cell></row><row><cell>Mcdian(cst)</cell><cell></cell><cell>0181</cell><cell>0149</cell><cell>0187</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="4,315.72,147.62,238.93,230.59"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>The adhoc tlsk performance of our submitted runs comprr€d to the r€sults of the esdmated best ttrd medlan. The bold numbers indicrie our best runs-Flgure 4: The ROC curves of the 4 adhoc rurs. The curve closesa to tbe upper left corner i9 deemcd the best performance.</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,59.71,146.56,7.51,16.65;5,73.44,151.22,78.59,10.64" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>References</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,71.64,165.98,219.13,8.12;5,72.00,176.06,205.96,8.12" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,237.24,165.98,53.53,7.86;5,72.00,176.06,74.03,8.12">lntroduction to Information Refieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Raghalan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Schtltze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<publisher>Combridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,72.00,187.58,196.34,7.86;5,72.00,197.66,192.15,8.02;5,72.00,207.74,176.35,8.58;5,71.64,216.03,90.26,11.56" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,204.48,198.02,59.67,7.40;5,72.00,208.46,160.76,7.86">Aggregating and Visualizing Microblogs for Event Exploration</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Marcus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bemstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Badar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Karger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Madden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Twirlnfo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,71.64,216.03,90.26,11.56">Proceedings of CHI 201 l</title>
		<meeting>CHI 201 l</meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,72.00,230.06,185.36,7.91;5,72.00,240.50,183.17,7.86;5,71.64,250.94,206.18,7.86;5,72.72,261.74,18.77,6.94" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,132.12,230.06,125.24,7.86;5,72.00,240.50,183.17,7.86;5,71.64,251.30,76.17,7.40">An efficient method for finding the minimum of a function of several variables without calculating derivatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J D</forename><surname>Powell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,155.88,251.30,61.86,7.40">Computer Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="162" />
			<date type="published" when="1964">1964</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,71.64,271.82,200.43,8.12;5,72.00,281.90,198.91,8.22;5,71.64,292.34,213.06,8.12;5,72.72,303.50,17.79,7.40" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Press</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Teukolsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Vetterling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Flamery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="5,107.28,281.90,163.63,8.22;5,71.64,293.06,38.68,7.40">Numerical Recipes in C: The Art of scientific Computing</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>t992</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,72.00,313.94,155.80,8.32;5,72.00,324.02,205.72,8.58;5,72.00,335.54,204.71,7.40" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hancock-Beaulieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gatford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="5,203.04,324.02,74.68,8.48;5,72.00,335.54,180.01,7.40">Okapi at TREC-3. ln Prceedings of the Third Text REtreival Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,72.00,345.98,201.40,8.48;5,72.00,356.78,170.36,7.66" xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,109.80,345.98,163.60,8.48;5,72.00,356.78,109.38,7.66">The SMART retrieval system: experiments in automatic document processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="323" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,72.00,378.02,208.42,8.33;5,71.64,387.74,181.75,8.58;5,72.00,398.90,98.32,7.40" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,142.20,378.02,138.22,7.86;5,71.64,388.46,167.84,7.86">CLEF 2005: Multilingual Retrieval by Combining Multiple Multilingual Ranked Lists</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Si</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">,</forename><surname>Callan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,72.00,398.90,94.57,7.40">Proceedings of CLEF 2005</title>
		<meeting>CLEF 2005</meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,72.00,408.98,216.36,9.15;5,72.00,420.86,154.13,7.40" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,157.68,409.70,63.39,7.86">YFilter at TREC-g</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Callan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,239.04,408.98,49.32,8.79;5,72.00,420.86,126.78,7.40">Prce€dings of the Ninth Text REtreival Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
