<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,131.83,79.15,351.22,10.75">The Siena College Medical Information Retrieval System (MIRS)</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2012-08-11">August 11, 2012.</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,232.12,99.31,74.37,10.75"><forename type="first">Larry</forename><surname>Medsker</surname></persName>
							<email>lmedsker@siena.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">The Siena College Institute for Artificial Intelligence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Siena College</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>12211</postCode>
									<settlement>Loudonville</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,312.70,99.31,70.06,10.75"><forename type="first">Sharon</forename><surname>Small</surname></persName>
							<email>ssmall@siena.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">The Siena College Institute for Artificial Intelligence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Siena College</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>12211</postCode>
									<settlement>Loudonville</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,151.21,113.23,125.43,10.75"><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Rivadeneira</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">The Siena College Institute for Artificial Intelligence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Siena College</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>12211</postCode>
									<settlement>Loudonville</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,282.23,113.23,92.97,10.75"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Reynolds</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">The Siena College Institute for Artificial Intelligence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Siena College</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>12211</postCode>
									<settlement>Loudonville</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,402.91,113.23,60.76,10.75"><forename type="first">Mara</forename><surname>Afzali</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">The Siena College Institute for Artificial Intelligence</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Siena College</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>12211</postCode>
									<settlement>Loudonville</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,131.83,79.15,351.22,10.75">The Siena College Medical Information Retrieval System (MIRS)</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2012-08-11">August 11, 2012.</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">542A77C8C615A4F5CF186C2957AD9848</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:07+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>TREC 2012</term>
					<term>Lucene</term>
					<term>Weka TREC 2012</term>
					<term>medical records</term>
					<term>information retrieval</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The work done by our MIRS team of three students and two faculty mentors resulted in a baseline system for content--based medical record retrieval. We also made significant progress on an alternative system based on neural computing concepts. The task for the Medical Records TREC in 2012 was to process a list of thirty--four randomly selected queries against a large medical records database to simulate searches for patients who meet the criteria for participating in various clinical trials. The task was to analyze a data set of over 100,000 reports associated with hospital visits and identify patients whose situations were relevant to the queries. Our text retrieval process was done in two separate ways: one used an index created from standard Information Retrieval (IR) software called Lucene and an alternate method based on principles of neural computing. We submitted three runs to the TREC competition, two using our standard Lucene--based approach and one that used elements of neural network analysis. The MIRS team was provided the code necessary to download the Medical Records corpus, consisting of an average of 15 reports from each of approximately 100K patient visits to a hospital. Teams were also provided a training set of 34 sample topic statements from TREC 2011. The records, which comprised one month of reports from multiple hospitals, came from the University of Pittsburgh NLP Repository and were de--identified in regard to specific patient names. The Medical Record track organizers from TREC also provided year 2011 judgment sets, produced by medical professionals at the Oregon Health Science University, that we then used in testing our MIRS software at different states of development. For each topic the system was required to search the medical records data corpus and return a ranked list of the top 10 relevant hospital visits, which were proxies for specific patients whose personal identification was made anonymous by the TREC organizers. It is not yet clear how traditional IR should perform on the identification of patients suitable for the clinical trials. Our first logical step was to run an experiment using traditional simple keyword informational retrieval. We used the open source IR system Lucene to index the NIST--supplied Medical Records corpus and to run our baseline experiments. This Lucene version became the first version of our MIRS system and these results were used as our baseline. Modules were proposed and implemented to improve the keyword identification. Then, the first round of experimentation was run with full error analysis. Modules were modified based on this error analysis, run again on the training collection and finally run on the test collection. Results were submitted to NIST before the deadline of</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>In May 2012, the Siena College Institute for Artificial Intelligence (SCIAI) formed a team comprising two faculty and three undergraduate students to work on the MIRS project. The team designed unique modules involving untried techniques that they hoped would increase the precision of results over the baseline run. They were required to assess the state of the art prior to proposing their module to the entire team.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Research Outcomes for the Summer 2012</head><p>The open source IR system Lucene was downloaded and installed locally on our server. The NIST Medical Records corpus was formatted to the specifications required by Lucene [1] and an index was generated. The group then experimented with the baseline system using the 34 training topics. The software was run on sample queries from the 2011 TREC competition, and a full round of error analysis on the results for each topic statement was completed. This involved analyzing what worked when a relevant record was found and what was not working when an irrelevant record was returned or a relevant one was missed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Part One: Andrew Reynolds and Chris Rivadeneira, in collaboration with Mara</head><p>Afzali and Drs. Medsker and Small, designed and developed software that used the open source IR system Lucene to index the NIST--supplied Medical Records corpus and to run our baseline experiments. Modules were proposed and implemented, and rounds of experimentation were run with full error analysis. They generated a Lucene index for each topic statement and judged whether a record was relevant based on the Lucene score for the match with keywords and phrases found in the patients' hospital visit records. 2.2 Part Two: Mara Afzali and Larry Medsker, designed a process for translating indexed words and phrases into a format suitable for analysis by neural computing software. The process started with the Phase One output, which comprised a table of keywords extracted from each topic statement. That table was then expanded so that each keyword was mapped to an equivalent subset of medical keywords.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,124.34,600.04,5.68,9.68">1</ref>: Example of an expansion of initial keywords and translation to a format that is suitable for neural network analysis. Each subset was used to produce a table of ones and zeros such that an entry from each subset produced a valid pattern of keywords representing text that was relevant to a particular topic statement. This table then became the data set that could be used for training a neural network. Furthermore, grouping the digital results for all the records associated with one patient visit for a given topic statement gave a complete picture for a given patient and allowed the neural analysis to take advantage of statistical features in determining relevance of a patient to the topic statement for a given clinical trial. The trained neural network could then be used to identify patterns in a record if the latter were similarly mapped to the ones and zeroes format. Because this medical records application work was started from scratch and required detailed study and creativity, we were not able in the length of time available to complete the use of neural computing software; however, we were able to use statistical treatments on the neural network input data to get very encouraging results on the 2011 data used for testing our system. We therefore produced a run using a modified statistical method on the neural computing data for the 2012 records data and submitted the results to the TREC competition as a possible improvement on the Lucene method used in the other two submitted runs.</p><p>The judging showed our best run to be at 49.79% precision. We have identified in this work clear next steps for building on the 2012 summer work and exploring further the neural computing approach.</p><p>For both methods, we used the judged set of 2011 Medical Records data from the TREC organizers to test the software we developed for each of the two approaches. One result of our work is a design for a comprehensive process that uses initial analysis of statements and medical records and then branches to a traditional IR approach and to a technique based on neural computing ideas (see Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,508.40,291.31,5.45,10.75" target="#fig_0">2</ref>). Another result of our work is a better understanding of the challenges and location of the chokepoint for producing excellent results, namely the identification of the proper keywords from topic statements to accurately and efficiently reflect the significance of the various patient records. More specifically, the challenge is to map the important words in a statement into an expanded set of medically equivalent words that are relevant, and not misleading, for use in the automated searches.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Summary</head><p>We developed a model for future work: a hybrid system that uses traditional text retrieval components plus elements of neural computing techniques. Test runs using topic statements from the 2011 TREC competition, and run against the 2012 data, gave very encouraging results that is in excess of the relevance rates found by groups in the 2011 competition. In this research, we have identified a crucial need for building a comprehensive database of medical keywords and phrases that can link topic statements to medical reports. We have also created a preliminary hybrid model that may lead to effective integration of neural computing techniques with conventional text analysis capabilities. Further work on this research could lead to enhanced clinical care and improved medical trials and epidemiological studies. Also, importantly, we now have a working prototype for our Medical Information Retrieval System, which will be the basis for future research at SCIAI and for participation in future TREC competitions. This broader impact of our 2012 Summer Scholars research will benefit additional Siena students beyond the ones who participated in the summer 2012 program. Our work, along with others in the summer 2012 IR work, also became the basis for a proposal to NSF for a Research Experiences for Undergraduates (REU) Site at Siena College that would bring top students from other colleges to work with us in the summers.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,90.12,659.56,434.39,9.68;3,139.62,672.52,377.17,9.68;3,104.83,147.53,402.73,509.19"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. Structure of the overall MIRS process that uses a common initial text analysis and then branches to the standard Lucene or alternative neural computing methods.</figDesc><graphic coords="3,104.83,147.53,402.73,509.19" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" coords="2,90.12,463.03,432.00,134.02"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="2,90.12,463.03,432.00,134.02" type="bitmap" /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
