<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,80.52,122.52,439.46,22.58;1,204.00,146.40,192.62,22.58">Entity Profile based Approach in Automatic Knowledge Finding</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,245.04,190.78,54.00,10.99"><forename type="first">Xitong</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<email>xtliu@udel.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Delaware Newark</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>DE</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,308.06,190.78,47.38,10.99"><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
							<email>hfang@udel.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Delaware Newark</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>DE</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,80.52,122.52,439.46,22.58;1,204.00,146.40,192.62,22.58">Entity Profile based Approach in Automatic Knowledge Finding</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">129A39659C9887609A2E748EC54E9883</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:07+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>We focus on the problem of profile building in this year's KBA track and proposed two methods. The first method is a baseline, which selects the stream items that has exact string match with the query entity. All the matched documents are assigned with the same relevance score. In the second method, we propose to use the related entities to help us identify the information related to the query entity. In particular, we retrieve the wikipedia pages for the query entities and extract the anchor text in all the internal links within the wikipedia page. These anchor text are treated as the related entities of the query entity and they are used to build the profile of the query entity. Given a stream item (i.e., a document), the relevance score is estimated by integrating the match with the query entity and the match with the related entities. Results on the training data show that the second method is more effective.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Entity Profile Building</head><p>The input query set for the KBA system is a list of 29 entities from English collection of Wikipedia. All the entities are manually selected by the KBA organizers and most of the entities are celebrities and selected from the Living people category. A few of them are organizations. Moreover, the organizers "focused on entities with complex link graphs of relationships with other active entities". Therefore, it means each entity has rich link relation with other entities in the Wikipedia, which makes it possible for us to exploit such relations to build the entity profiles.</p><p>To solve the first challenge, i.e., entity profile building, we propose a general approach by collecting the internal links with the Wikipedia page of each query entity e q and use the anchor text of the internal links as related entities of e q .</p><p>Given an entity, the first thing is to retrieve its Wikipedia page. Fortunately, as the query set were selected from the Wikipedia collection directly, each entity are defined by its so-called urlname. The URL of the entitys Wikipedia page can be constructed by just appending the entity name to a Wikipedia base URL ( i.e., http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ ). For instance, one of the 29 query entities is "Basic Element (music group)", we can get its authentic Wikipedia URL as "http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basic Element (music group)". Instead of retrieving the HTML Wikipedia page directly, we utilize the API provided by Wikipedia to dump the raw content in json format. Given a query entity e q , the API accepts urlname as input and returns the English Wikipedia page wiki(e q ) in Wiki markup 1 format. The reason to parse Wiki markup instead of HTML is that we think it is much easier to identify and extract the internal links.</p><p>With the retrieved Wikipedia page, we then apply a python based parser to parse the Wiki markup document and extract the related entities. Basically there are two types of links for a Wikipedia page: internal link and external link. The former connects the entities within Wikipedia and the the latter provides supplemental information with regard to the entity. An internal link between two entities indicates there are some relation between them. Therefore by following the internal links from the query entity e q , we can get a list of entities which can be treated as related entities. More specifically, the internal link in Wiki markup document would be denoted as shown in the following example:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,80.52,183.64,434.35,20.36">'''Basic Element''' is a [[Sweden|Swedish]] [[eurodance]] [[hip-hop]] group formed in 1993.</formula><p>There are three internal links in the example above, each of which is embraced by double square bracket. The first link [[Sweden|Swedish]] contains two parts, separated by a vertical bar. The first part is the urlname, and the second part is the anchor text of the link shown on the rendered HTML page. Therefore, this link would be rendered as a link to http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sweden with the anchor text "Swedish". The following two links <ref type="bibr" coords="2,330.12,265.24,63.31,8.48">[[eurodance]</ref>] [ <ref type="bibr" coords="2,406.67,265.24,47.48,8.48">[hip-hop]</ref>] just have one part, and the text within the double square bracket serves as both the urlname and the anchor text. Therefore, we can extract three related entities from the markup text above, i.e., Sweden, eurodance and hip-hop. Formally, given a Wikipedia page wiki(e q ), we can extract a set of related entities rel(e q ) = {e|e ∈ E(wiki(e q ))} where E(wiki(e q )) denotes all the Wikipedia entities in wiki(e q ).</p><p>With the set of related entities, we define the entity profile prof ile(e q ) as follows:</p><p>prof ile(e q ) = {e q , rel(e q )}.</p><p>(1)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Entity Profile based Stream Filtering</head><p>We now discuss how to use the entity profile prof ile(e q ) to do stream filtering. Given a stream document d, we need to estimate how likely the document is relevant to the query entity e q . As shown in Equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="2,140.70,426.67,3.87,9.62">1</ref>), an entity profile prof ile(e q ) consists of the entity itself e q and its related entities rel(e q ), therefore, the relevance of the document should be determined by both e q and rel(e q ). To reflect this, we propose the following method to estimate the relevance between d and prof ile(e q ):</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,180.72,474.90,339.16,21.24">score(d, e q ) = α • mention(d, e q ) + β • e∈rel(eq ) occ(d, e),<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where mention(d, e q ) is an function which identifies the document d mentions e q and it is defined as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,209.04,530.83,306.58,21.62">mention(d, e q ) = 1 if d mentions e q , 0 otherwise. (<label>3</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,515.62,536.95,4.25,9.62">)</formula><p>Moreover, occ(d, e) denotes the occurrences of e in d. α and β are the coefficients which assign different weights to different score components to balance their influences. The main idea behind Equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="2,511.40,576.79,4.25,9.62" target="#formula_1">2</ref>) is that we want to capture whether the document mentions e q as well as any related entities in rel(e q ). The first component (α • mention(d, e q )) checks whether e q is discussed in d, and the second component (β • e∈rel(eq ) occ(d, e)) serves as the complementary information to the relevance score under the assumption that the more related entities occur in d, the more likely d is relevant to e q .</p><p>Since the first component is the main body of the relevance score, α should be much larger than β to reflect it.</p><p>With the relevance score calculated, we then set a threshold T to determine whether the document is relevant to the query topic e q or not. The stream document with the relevance score above T will be kept and others will be discarded. 4 Experiment Results</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Submitted Runs</head><p>We submitted four official runs to the KBA track. The main difference between them are α, β in Equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="3,127.75,323.47,4.25,9.62" target="#formula_1">2</ref>) and filtering threshold T . The detail description are summarized as follows.</p><p>1. UDInfo-KBA EX: α = 1000, β = 0 and T = 0. It is a special case and Equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="3,489.90,343.39,4.25,9.62" target="#formula_1">2</ref>) falls back to score(d, e q ) = 1000 • mention(d, e q ), which means the relevance score is estimated based on whether there is an exact match of query entity e q in document d. If there is an exact match, the relevance score would be 1000. Otherwise, it would be 0. This run serves as a baseline.</p><p>2. UDInfo-KBA WIKI1: α = 100, β = 1 and T = 101. The main idea of this method is that besides the exact match, we also want to capture the match of the related entities. T is set empirically based on the results of training data.</p><p>3. UDInfo-KBA WIKI2: α = 100, β = 1 and T = 102.</p><p>4. UDInfo-KBA WIKI3: α = 100, β = 1 and T = 103.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Results Analysis</head><p>The results of all the runs are summarized in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,318.13,509.23,3.90,9.62" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. We can find that all of our four runs can reach good results among all the submitted runs. Moreover, by incorporating the match of the related entities into the estimation of relevance score, the performance can be improved, showing the effectiveness of related entities in the entity profile based filtering.</p><p>To better understand the performance of each query, we plot the maxF per query on both central and central+relevant to compare them side by side, as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,396.13,568.99,4.98,9.62">1</ref> and Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,455.67,568.99,3.90,9.62" target="#fig_0">2</ref>, respectively. We can find that generally our entity profile based filtering method can outperform both the baseline and all-mean on most queries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>It is the first year of KBA track, and the task is relatively simple as the organizers want to get first impression on how the data would fit the task of knowledge base acceleration. We propose an entity profile based filtering framework and derive two methods to solve this year's task. Experiment results on the testing data show that our methods are effective to select the relevant documents. We find that by incorporating the related entities into the entity profile can improve the performance, showing that the related entities are important on finding the relevant documents.  </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="4,150.60,690.55,299.41,9.62"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: maxF of each topic on the testing data (central+relevant).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,80.52,87.79,439.71,159.26"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Results of official runs. The maxF and maxSU measures are reported by the official evaluation program, which collects the maximum F1 and SU for each topic at certain relevance score cutoff and report the average then. all-mean and all-median are the mean and median of results aggregated from all the submitted runs in this year's KBA track respectively.</figDesc><table coords="3,139.44,87.79,321.52,100.10"><row><cell>Evaluation Set</cell><cell cols="2">Central</cell><cell cols="2">Central+Relevant</cell></row><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>maxF</cell><cell>maxSU</cell><cell>maxF</cell><cell>maxSU</cell></row><row><cell>all-mean</cell><cell>0.220</cell><cell>0.311</cell><cell>0.404</cell><cell>0.498</cell></row><row><cell>all-median</cell><cell>0.289</cell><cell>0.333</cell><cell>0.553</cell><cell>0.554</cell></row><row><cell>UDInfo-KBA EX</cell><cell>0.297</cell><cell>0.154</cell><cell>0.605</cell><cell>0.580</cell></row><row><cell>UDInfo-KBA WIKI1</cell><cell>0.342</cell><cell>0.331</cell><cell>0.639</cell><cell>0.611</cell></row><row><cell>UDInfo-KBA WIKI2</cell><cell>0.354</cell><cell>0.331</cell><cell>0.636</cell><cell>0.617</cell></row><row><cell>UDInfo-KBA WIKI3</cell><cell>0.355</cell><cell>0.331</cell><cell>0.597</cell><cell>0.592</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
