<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,217.00,71.53,162.96,15.50;1,206.00,87.53,183.99,15.50">English-Dutch CLIR Using Query Translation Techniques</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,270.00,127.09,57.01,11.07"><forename type="first">Mirna</forename><surname>Adriani</surname></persName>
							<email>mirna@dcs.gla.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computing Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Glasgow</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>G12 8QQ</postCode>
									<settlement>Glasgow</settlement>
									<country key="GB">Scotland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,217.00,71.53,162.96,15.50;1,206.00,87.53,183.99,15.50">English-Dutch CLIR Using Query Translation Techniques</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">14DE618FF13D2F2FE8BA69CC68D07477</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We present a report on our participation in the English-Dutch bilingual task of the 2001 Cross-Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF). We attempted to demonstrate that good cross language query translation results can be obtained by combining a dictionary based and parallel corpus based techniques. A parallel corpus based technique was used to choose the best sense from all possible senses found in the dictionary. However, our results demonstrate that a pure dictionary based technique produces the best query translation than a parallel corpus based and the combined techniques. We also show that improvement in retrieval effectiveness can be obtained using a query expansion technique.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This year we, the University of Glasgow IR-group, participate in the bilingual 2001 Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF) task, i.e., the English-Dutch CLIR. We employ a dictionary based query translation technique using a publicly available dictionary on the Internet. We learned from our previous year's work that this dictionary does not provide good translation terms, as its vocabulary is very limited. We hoped that we could improve on the result using other resources. As a parallel corpus was made available for this forum, we opted to use it for this purpose.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The Query Translation Process</head><p>Our dictionary-based query translation technique translates each term in a given query to another language by replacing it with the senses of that term in the dictionary. There are well known problems with such translation techniques, mainly, the term ambiguity problem, the phrase translation problem, and the problem with terms not found in the dictionary, such as acronyms or technical terms. These problems result in very poor retrieval performance of the translation queries. Since the parallel corpus was created automatically from documents found on the Internet, there are misclassified documents where Dutch documents are classified as English and vice versa, or English documents contain Dutch words and vice versa. We filtered out mis-classified sentences using stopwords. If a Dutch sentence contains at least one English stopword then it is discarded, and so is an English sentence that contains at least one Ducth stopword. Although this technique may exclude correctly classified source sentences that happen to contain one or two terms of the target language, the detrimental effect of using a mis-classified sentence is worse than incorrectly excluding a sentence. After this clean up process, the parallel corpus contains 62,536 sentences.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">The Glossary Table</head><p>The glossary table entry is created using the following formula:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,107.00,126.09,117.00,11.07">PT = tfED / ( tfE + tfD -tfED )</formula><p>where PT = the probability that an English term is a translation of a Dutch term tfED = the frequency of both the English and the Dutch terms occur together tfE = the occurrence frequency of the English term tfD = the occurrence frequency of the Dutch term</p><p>For each English term in the sentence, we obtain the Dutch translation term from the parallel sentences with the highest PT. Below are some sample entries in the glossary table and their PT values:</p><p>4.5946 find-vind 5.5946 human-humaan 6.6868 indian-indisch 6.7637 russia-rusland</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Choosing the Best Translation Term</head><p>The dictionary based query translation technique produces one or more translation terms in the target language for each term in the source language. A sense disambiguation technique is used to choose the best possible translation term. We perform the sense disambiguation process as follows:</p><p>1. Obtain the Dutch translation terms of the given English term from the dictionary. 2. Obtain entries in the glossary table for the same English term.</p><p>3. Select the Dutch translation term from terms obtained in step 1 that has the highest PT value in the entries obtained in step 2. 4. If the English term is not found in the dictionary but has entries in the glossary table then select the Dutch term from the glossary entries that has the highest PT value. 5. If the English term is not found in either the dictionary or the glossary table then it is taken without translation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Query Expansion Technique</head><p>Expanding translation queries has been shown to improve the CLIR effectiveness. One of the query expansion techniques is called the pseudo relevance feedback. This technique is based on an assumption that the top few documents retrieved are indeed relevant to the query, and so they must contain other terms that are also relevant to the query. The query expansion technique adds such terms into the translated queries. We applied this technique in this work. In choosing the good terms from the top ranked documents, we use the tf*idf term weighting formula <ref type="bibr" coords="2,147.89,609.09,10.63,11.07" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. We add a certain number of terms that have the highest weight values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiment</head><p>The Dutch document collection contains 190,604 documents from two Dutch newspapers, the Algemeen Dagblad and the NRC Handelsblad. We participate in the bilingual task using the English topics. We opted to use the query title and the description for all of the available 50 topics. In addition to the combined dictionary and parallel corpus based technique we also conducted an experiment using a pure dictionary based query translation technique, and an experiment using a pure parallel corpus based query translation.</p><p>The query translation process is performed fully automatic. Stopwords are removed from the English queries and the remaining terms are stemmed using the Porter stemmer. For the pure dictionary based translation technique, we simply include all possible translation terms found in the dictionary, i.e., without any sense disambiguation. If phrases in the queries are not found in the dictionary, they are translated by translating the individual constituent terms. For the pure parallel corpus based translation technique, we simply select the translation term in the glossary entry that has the highest PT value. In these two techniques, English terms that are not found in the dictionary or in the glossary table are taken without translation.</p><p>We use a machine-readable dictionary downloaded from the Internet at http://www.freedict.com . This dictionary contains short translations of English words in a number of languages. We realized that the dictionary is not ideal for our purpose, as most of its entries contain only one or two senses. However, its free availability outweighs its limitation. We reformatted the dictionary files so that our query translator program can read them. The dictionary contains 9,972 entries.</p><p>Then we apply the pseudo relevance feedback query expansion technique to the combined dictionary and parallel corpus based technique. We used the top 20 and 30 documents to extract the expansion terms.</p><p>In these experiments, we used the INQUERY information retrieval system to index and retrieve the documents. Terms in the Dutch queries and documents are stemmed using the Dutch stemmer from the Muscat system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>Our work concentrates on the bilingual task using English queries to retrieve documents from the Dutch collections. The result that we submitted (code-named glaenl) is the one from the combined dictionary and parallel corpus based technique. Table <ref type="table" coords="3,231.84,337.09,5.00,11.07" target="#tab_1">1</ref> shows the result of our experiments. The retrieval performance of the translation queries obtained using the dictionary based technique falls 34.55% below that of the monolingual query (see Table <ref type="table" coords="3,143.00,359.09,3.63,11.07" target="#tab_1">1</ref>). The performance of the query translation using parallel corpus only is the worst, i.e., 60.46% below that of the monolingual query. The retrieval performance of the combined method is 40.80% below the monolingual performance. This indicates that the parallel corpus based sense disambiguation technique drops the performance of the dictionary based translation queries by 5.25%.   The performance of the translated queries using only the dictionary is better than that of using only the glossary table. This correlates with the number of Dutch query terms that are not found the dictionary and the glossary table. Out of 569 English terms, there are 135 terms that are not found in the dictionary and 260 terms that are not found in the glossary table.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task</head><p>Dutch is a language that contains compound words as German. It has been shown that applying a compoundword splitter results in better retrieval performance <ref type="bibr" coords="4,283.00,179.09,10.65,11.07" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Unfortunately, we do not have any Dutch compoundword splitter which could have improved the entries of our glossary table. In our previous work <ref type="bibr" coords="4,483.28,190.09,10.85,11.07" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="4,499.16,190.09,7.24,11.07" target="#b1">2]</ref>, we showed that German queries can be better translated to English than Spanish queries because German compound words have exact meanings in English as compared to Spanish phrases which have to be translated word by word using a dictionary. In other words, the degree of ambiguity of the German queries is less than that of the Spanish queries. On the other hand, translating queries from English to German is a difficult task as it involves translating multi-word terms into single-word compound terms is a very difficult task. Such is also the difficulty in translating English queries to Dutch.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="1,71.00,627.09,455.07,33.07"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>This year we use the RALI parallel corpus (Dutch and English) to create a glossary table. The parallel corpus has been aligned at sentence level. The glossary table contains all possible Dutch translation for each English term found in the corpus.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,114.00,426.09,291.04,189.85"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Average retrieval precision of the monolingual runs and the bilingual runs using English queries that are translated to Dutch using dictionary only, parallel corpus only, and combined dictionary and parallel corpus.</figDesc><table coords="3,117.00,426.09,270.00,189.85"><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>P/R</cell><cell></cell><cell>% Change</cell></row><row><cell>Monolingual</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.3238</cell><cell></cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>Dictionary</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.2119</cell><cell></cell><cell>-34.55</cell></row><row><cell>Parallel corpus</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.1280</cell><cell></cell><cell>-60.46</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Dictionary &amp; P corpus</cell><cell>0.1917</cell><cell></cell><cell>-40.80</cell></row><row><cell>Query translation</cell><cell>5 terms</cell><cell>10 terms</cell><cell>20 terms</cell><cell>30 terms</cell></row><row><cell>using Dict &amp; PC</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.1917</cell><cell>0.2002</cell><cell>0.2003</cell><cell>0.2048</cell><cell>0.2074</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(+4.43%)</cell><cell>(+4.49%)</cell><cell>(+6.86%)</cell><cell>(+8.20%)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="3,112.00,637.09,292.00,85.85"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Average retrieval precision of the query expansion using the top 30 document method.</figDesc><table coords="3,112.00,681.98,292.00,40.96"><row><cell>Query translation</cell><cell>5 terms</cell><cell>10 terms</cell><cell>20 terms</cell><cell>30 terms</cell></row><row><cell>using Dict &amp; PC</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.1917</cell><cell>0.2123</cell><cell>0.2111</cell><cell>0.2116</cell><cell>0.2205</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(+10.72%)</cell><cell>(+10.13%)</cell><cell>(+10.39%)</cell><cell>(+15.01%)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="4,107.00,70.98,298.01,19.96"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Average retrieval precision of the query expansion using the top 2 0 document method.</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_0" coords="4,107.00,294.31,52.00,13.28;4,71.00,323.09,455.00,11.07;4,71.00,334.09,455.01,11.07;4,71.00,345.09,455.02,11.07;4,71.00,356.09,455.01,11.07;4,71.00,367.09,276.04,11.07"><p>SummaryOur results demonstrate that using freely available bilingual dictionaries can produce superior cross-language retrieval performance as compared to using more expensive parallel corpora. However, this also depends on the breadth of topic coverage of the dictionary and the parallel corpus used. Given more sophisticated linguistic tools such as compound-word splitter and part of speech taggers, a parallel corpus based technique is likely to perform as effective, if not more, than the dictionary based approach.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,74.88,438.09,413.15,11.07;4,89.00,449.09,426.02,11.07;4,89.00,460.09,351.04,11.07" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,240.74,438.09,247.30,11.07;4,89.00,449.09,85.87,11.07">Term Similarity Based Query Expansion for Cross Language Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Adriani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Rijsbergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,192.41,449.09,322.60,11.07;4,89.00,460.09,133.15,11.07">Proceedings of Research and Advanced Technology for Digital Libraries, Third European Conference (ECDL&apos;99)</title>
		<meeting>Research and Advanced Technology for Digital Libraries, Third European Conference (ECDL&apos;99)<address><addrLine>Paris</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999-09">September 1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="322" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,74.88,471.09,424.11,11.07;4,89.00,482.09,153.99,11.07" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,139.54,471.09,234.09,11.07">Ambiguity Problem in Multilingual Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Adriani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,391.73,471.09,107.26,11.07;4,89.00,482.09,38.66,11.07">CLEF 2000 Working Note Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Portugal</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000-09">September 2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,74.88,493.09,428.20,11.07;4,89.00,504.09,426.01,11.07;4,89.00,515.09,108.02,11.07" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,389.47,493.09,113.61,11.07;4,89.00,504.09,258.14,11.07">Twenty-One at CLEF-2000: Translation resources, merging strategies and relevance feedback</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Djoerd</forename><surname>Hiemstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wessel</forename><surname>Kraaij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Renee</forename><surname>Pohlmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Thijs</forename><surname>Westerveld</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,364.65,504.09,145.59,11.07">CLEF 2000 Working Note Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Portugal</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000-09">September 2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,74.88,526.09,450.11,11.07;4,89.00,537.09,45.00,11.07" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,248.30,526.09,183.61,11.07">Introduction to Modern Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gerard</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Mcgill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983">1983</date>
			<publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
