<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,139.67,70.34,334.12,11.78">Query Expansion Techniques for the CLEF Bilingual Track</title>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">CREST of JST (Japan Science and Technology)</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_TCVNN46 #_fd5nZjb #_HzStKk4">
					<orgName type="full">Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology, Japan</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,131.76,94.88,56.19,8.53;1,189.83,93.12,1.52,5.48"><forename type="first">Fatiha</forename><surname>Sadat</surname></persName>
							<email>fatia-s@is.aist-nara.ac.jp</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology (NAIST</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>8916-5 Takayama</addrLine>
									<postCode>630-0101</postCode>
									<settlement>Ikoma</settlement>
									<region>Nara</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">CREST</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Science and Technology Corporation</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,197.27,94.88,58.44,8.53;1,257.51,93.12,10.24,5.48"><forename type="first">Akira</forename><surname>Maeda † † †</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology (NAIST</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>8916-5 Takayama</addrLine>
									<postCode>630-0101</postCode>
									<settlement>Ikoma</settlement>
									<region>Nara</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">CREST</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Science and Technology Corporation</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,272.63,94.88,96.59,8.53;1,371.27,93.12,1.52,5.48"><forename type="first">Masatoshi</forename><surname>Yoshikawa</surname></persName>
							<email>yosikawa@is.aist-nara.ac.jp</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology (NAIST</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>8916-5 Takayama</addrLine>
									<postCode>630-0101</postCode>
									<settlement>Ikoma</settlement>
									<region>Nara</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute of Informatics (NII)</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">CREST</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Science and Technology Corporation</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,397.18,94.88,79.80,8.53;1,478.78,93.12,1.52,5.48"><forename type="first">Shunsuke</forename><surname>Uemura</surname></persName>
							<email>uemura@is.aist-nara.ac.jp</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nara Institute of Science and Technology (NAIST</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>8916-5 Takayama</addrLine>
									<postCode>630-0101</postCode>
									<settlement>Ikoma</settlement>
									<region>Nara</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">CREST</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Science and Technology Corporation</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,139.67,70.34,334.12,11.78">Query Expansion Techniques for the CLEF Bilingual Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">8AD1AA8511E6D4DFAB26ECF80F6254E6</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Cross-Language Information Retrieval</term>
					<term>Query Translation</term>
					<term>Dictionary-based Method</term>
					<term>Disambiguation</term>
					<term>Mutual Information</term>
					<term>Training Corpora</term>
					<term>Domain Keywords</term>
					<term>Relevance Feedback</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper evaluates the effectiveness of a query translation and disambiguation as well as expansion techniques on CLEF Collections, using SMART Information Retrieval System.</p><p>We focus on the query translation, disambiguation and methods to improve the effectiveness of an information retrieval. Dictionary-based method with a combination to statistics-based method is used, to avoid the problem of translation ambiguity. In addition, two expansion strategies are tested on their ability to improve the effectiveness of an information retrieval, an expansion via a relevance feedback before and after translation as well as an expansion via a domain feedback after translation. This method achieved 85.30% of the monolingual counterpart, in terms of average precision.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This first participation in the Cross-Language Evaluation Forum <ref type="bibr" coords="1,379.18,454.87,49.61,8.53">(CLEF 2001</ref>) is considered as an opportunity to better understand issues in Cross-Language Information Retrieval (CLIR) and evaluate the effectiveness of our approach and techniques. We worked on the bilingual track for French queries to English runs, with a comparison to the monolingual French and English tasks.</p><p>In this paper, we focus on the query translation, disambiguation and expansion techniques, to improve the effectiveness of an information retrieval by different combinations. Bilingual Machine Readable Dictionary (MRD) is considered as a prevalent method to Cross-Language Information Retrieval. However, simple translations tend to be ambiguous and give poor results. A combination with statistics-based approach for a disambiguation can significantly reduce the error associated with polysemy<ref type="foot" coords="1,389.26,539.26,3.05,5.48" target="#foot_0">1</ref> in dictionary translation. Query expansion is our second interest <ref type="bibr" coords="1,217.67,552.07,9.88,8.53" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. As a main hypothesis, combination of query expansion methods before and after the query translation will improve the precision of an information retrieval as well as the recall. Two sorts of query expansion were evaluated: Relevance feedback and Domain feedback, which is an original point in this study. These expansion techniques did not show an improvement comparing to the translation method, as expected.</p><p>We have evaluated our system by using SMART Information Retrieval System (version 11.0), which is based on a vector space model, as it is considered to be more efficient than Boolean or probabilistic model.</p><p>The rest of this paper is organized as follows. Section 2 gives a brief overview of the dictionary-based method and the disambiguation method. The proposed query expansion and its effectiveness in information retrieval are described in Section 3. An evaluation and results of the conducted experiments are described and discussed in section 4. Section 5 concludes the paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Query Translation via Dictionary-based Method</head><p>Dictionary-based method, where each term or phrase in the query is replaced by a list of all its possible translations, represents a simple and an acceptable first pass for a query translation in Cross-Language Information Retrieval.</p><p>In our approach <ref type="bibr" coords="2,170.87,125.36,10.06,8.53" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, a stopping phase for French queries, by using a stop list was performed to remove stop words and stop phrases and avoid the undesired effect of some terms, such as pronouns, ... Etc.</p><p>A simple stemming process of query terms was performed before the query translation, to replace each term with its inflectional root, to remove most plural word forms, to replace each verb with its infinitive form and to reduce headwords to their inflectional roots. The next step is a term-by-term translation using a bilingual machine-readable dictionary. An overview of the Query Translation and Disambiguation Module is shown in Fig <ref type="figure" coords="2,108.48,190.16,3.58,8.53">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fig 1. Query Translation and Disambiguation Module Phases</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Query Term Disambiguation using Statistics-based Method</head><p>A Word is Polysemous, if it has senses that are different but closely related; as a noun, for example, right can mean something that is morally approved, or something that is factually correct, or something that is due one. In the proposed system, a disambiguation of the English translation candidates is performed, by selecting the best English term, equivalent to each French query term, by applying a statistical method based on the co-occurrence frequency. For the purpose of this study, we decided to use the mutual information <ref type="bibr" coords="2,425.98,505.99,10.08,8.53" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, which is defined as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,93.60,549.19,83.92,8.99">MI (W 1 , W 2 ) = Log 2</formula><p>Where N is the size of the corpus, f (w) is the number of times the word w occurs in the corpus and f (w 1, w 2 ) is the number of times both w 1 and w 2 occur together in a sentence bead.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Query Expansion in Cross-Language Information Retrieval</head><p>Query expansion, which modifies queries using judgments of the relevance of a few highly ranked documents, has been an important method for increasing the performance of an information retrieval.</p><p>In this study, we have proposed two sorts of query expansion: a relevance feedback before and after the translation and disambiguation of query terms, and a domain feedback after the translation and disambiguation of query terms. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Query Translation Module</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Translations</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Terms Stemming</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Term-by-term Translation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Two Terms Disambiguation Stop List</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>One Language</head><p>Stemmer</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,199.19,537.91,50.67,30.83">N f (w 1 ,w 2 ) f (w 1 ) f (w 2 )</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Relevance Feedback before and after Translation</head><p>We apply an automatic relevance feedback, by fixing the number of retrieved documents and assuming the top-ranking documents obtained in an initial retrieval. This approach consists to add some term concepts, about 10 terms from a fixed number of the top retrieved documents (about 50 top documents), which occur frequently in conjunction with the query terms, on a presumption that those documents are relevant, to make a new query. One advantage of the use of a query expansion, such as an automatic relevance feedback is to create a stronger base for short queries in the disambiguation process, in the purpose of using co-occurrence frequency approach.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Domain Feedback</head><p>We introduced a domain feedback as a query reformulation strategy, which consists of extracting a domain field from a set of retrieved documents (top 50 documents), through a relevance feedback. Domain key terms will be used to expand the original query set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Information Retrieval Evaluation</head><p>The evaluation of the effectiveness of the French-English Information Retrieval System, was performed by using the following linguistic tools :</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Monolingual Corpus</head><p>The monolingual English part of the Canadian Hansard corpus (Parliament Debates) was used in the disambiguation process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Bilingual Dictionaries</head><p>A bilingual French-English COLLINS Electronic Dictionary Data, version 1.0 was used for the translation of French queries to English. Missing words in the dictionary, which are essential for the correct interpretation of the query, such as Kim, Airbus, Chiapa was not compensated. We just kept the original source words as target translations, by assuming that missing words could be proper names, such as Lennon, Kim, etc…</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Stemmer and Stop Words</head><p>The stemming part was performed by the English Porter<ref type="foot" coords="3,306.47,401.26,3.05,5.48" target="#foot_1">2</ref> Stemmer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Retrieval System</head><p>SMART Information Retrieval System 3 was used to retrieve English and French documents. SMART is a vector model, which has been used in many researches for Cross-Language Information Retrieval.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Submission for the CLEF 2001 Main Tasks</head><p>We submitted 4 runs for the bilingual (non-English) task with French as a topic language, and one run for the Monolingual French task : Query topics were constructed manually by selecting terms from fields &lt;title&gt; and &lt;description&gt; of the original set of queries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Results and Performance Analysis</head><p>Our participation in CLEF 2001 showed two runs, which contributed to the relevance assessment pool:</p><p>RunindexTR, the translation and disambiguation method, and RunindexFR, the monolingual French retrieval.</p><p>The rest of bilingual runs were not judged, because of limited evaluation resources, the result files did not directly contribute to the relevance assessment pool. However, the runs were subject to all other standard processing, and are still scored as official runs. Table <ref type="table" coords="4,294.67,515.11,4.74,8.53" target="#tab_1">1</ref> shows the average precision for each run.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Discussion</head><p>In our previous research <ref type="bibr" coords="4,199.40,563.59,10.06,8.53" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, we tested and evaluated two types of feedback loops: a combined relevance feedback before and after translation and a domain feedback after translation. In terms of average precision, we noticed a great improvement of the two methods, comparing to the translation-disambiguation method. As well, the proposed translation-disambiguation method showed an improvement, comparing to a simple dictionary translation method. As a conclusion, a disambiguation method improved the average precision. Moreover, query expansion via the two types of feedback loops, showed greater improvement <ref type="bibr" coords="4,383.70,617.58,10.09,8.53" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p><p>However in this study, the submitted bilingual runs did not show any improvement in terms of average precision for a query expansion via a relevance feedback before and after translation or a domain feedback after translation. The proposed translation and disambiguation method RunindexTR, achieved 85.30% accuracy of the monolingual performance RunindexORG (English information retrieval) and 77.23% of the monolingual performance RunindexFR (French information retrieval). This accuracy is higher than that of relevance feedback or domain feedback, as shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,248.39,682.38,3.46,8.53" target="#tab_1">1</ref>. The relevance feedback before and after translation RunindexFEED showed a second best result in term of average precision, 78.69% and 71.25% of the monolingual English and French retrieval, respectively. RunindexDOM, the domain feedback showed a less effective result in terms of average precision, with 76.92% and 69.64% of the monolingual English and French retrieval, respectively. Fig <ref type="figure" coords="5,515.02,79.77,4.74,8.53" target="#fig_0">2</ref> shows the precision-recall curves for the submitted runs to CLEF 2001.</p><p>These results were less effective than we expected. This is because; first the bilingual dictionary does not cover technical terms and proper nouns, which are the most useful in improving the total IR accuracy. In this study, the French query set contains 11 untranslated English terms. Using Collins French-English Bilingual dictionary as the only resource for term translations puts the burden of discovering the right translation of proper nouns, which are used in Clef query set. When a word is not found in the dictionary, we just kept the original source word as a target translation one. This method should be successful for some proper names, such as Lennon, Kim, etc…but not for others, such as Chiapa. Missing words in the bilingual dictionary is one major reason to introduce noise into our results. The second reason is due to the selection of terms to expand the original queries, domain keywords for a domain feedback or terms that occur most often with the original query terms. This made the expansion methods ineffective, comparing to our previous work <ref type="bibr" coords="5,420.93,199.52,10.06,8.53" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. We hope to be able to improve the effectiveness of an information retrieval, as explained below:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Bilingual Translation</head><p>The bilingual dictionary should be improved to cover all terms described in the original queries. One solution to this problem is to extract terms and their translations through parallel or comparable corpora (non-parallel), and extend the existing dictionary with that terminology, in Cross-Language Information Retrieval.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Terms Extraction for a Feedback Loop</head><p>According to previous researches <ref type="bibr" coords="5,221.70,307.52,11.07,8.53" target="#b0">[1]</ref> [4], query expansion before and after translation improves the effectiveness of an information retrieval. In our case, we used the mutual information <ref type="bibr" coords="5,368.58,318.32,11.07,8.53" target="#b1">[2]</ref> to select and add those terms, which occur most often with the original query terms. Previous results showed that results based on the mutual information are significantly worst that those based on the log-likelihood-ratio or chi-square test or modified dice coefficient <ref type="bibr" coords="5,136.58,350.47,10.06,8.53" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. For an efficient use of the term co-occurrence frequency in the relevance feedback process, we will select the log-likelihood-ratio for further experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Domain Feedback</head><p>A combination of the proposed domain feedback method to a relevance feedback before or after translation could be a solution, to improve the effectiveness of an information retrieval. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>Our conclusion at this point can only be partial. We still need to perform more experiments to evaluate the proposed query expansion methods. The purpose of our investigation was to determine the efficacy of translating and expanding a query by different methods. The study compares the retrieval effectiveness using the original monolingual queries, translated and disambiguated queries and the alternative expanded user queries on a collection of 50 queries, via a relevance feedback or a domain feedback techniques. An average precision measure is used as the basis of the experiments evaluation.</p><p>However, the proposed translation and disambiguation method showed the best result in terms of average precision, comparing to the query expansion methods: via a relevance feedback before and after query translation and disambiguation and via a domain feedback after query translation and disambiguation.</p><p>What we presented in this paper is a rather simple study, which highlights some areas in Cross-Language Information retrieval. We hope to be able to improve our researches and find more solutions to fulfill the needs for Information retrieval cross languages.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="5,129.84,689.20,353.94,9.34"><head>Fig 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig 2. A Precision-Recall curves for the submitted Bilingual and Monolingual runs</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,93.60,525.67,426.17,129.48"><head>Table 1 . Results of the Submitted CLEF Bilingual and Monolingual Runs</head><label>1</label><figDesc>RunindexORG : The original English query topics are searched against the English Collection (Los Angeles Times 1994 : 113,005 documents , 425 MB). RunindexTR : The original French query topics are translated to English, disambiguated by the proposed strategy and then searched against the English Collection.</figDesc><table coords="3,141.59,525.67,245.93,74.76"><row><cell>Bilingual task</cell><cell>Language</cell><cell>Run Type</cell><cell>Priority</cell></row><row><cell>RunindexTR</cell><cell>French</cell><cell>Manual</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>RunindexDOM</cell><cell>French</cell><cell>Manual</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>RunindexFEED</cell><cell>French</cell><cell>Manual</cell><cell>3</cell></row><row><cell>RunindexORG</cell><cell>French</cell><cell>Manual</cell><cell>4</cell></row><row><cell>Monolingual Task</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>RunindexFR</cell><cell>French</cell><cell>Manual</cell><cell>1</cell></row></table><note coords="4,93.60,325.28,426.15,8.53;4,93.60,336.07,426.34,8.53;4,93.60,346.87,39.09,8.53;4,93.60,357.67,426.01,8.77;4,93.60,368.71,208.51,8.53;4,93.60,379.51,426.19,8.53;4,93.60,390.31,305.97,8.53"><p>RunindexFEED : The original French query topics are expanded by a relevance feedback, translated and disambiguated by the proposed method and again expanded, before the search against the English data collection. RunindexDOM : The translated disambiguated query topics are expanded by a domain feedback, after translation and searched against the English Collection. RunindexFR : The original French query topics are searched against the French Collection (Le Monde 1994 : 44,013 documents, 157 MB and SDA French 1994 : 43,178 documents , 86 MB).</p></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,101.28,701.00,188.36,7.72"><p>Polysemy is a word, which has more than one meaning.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="3,100.80,684.20,159.06,7.72;3,101.28,701.00,111.11,7.72"><p>http://bogart.sip.ucm.es/cgi-bin/webstem/ stem ftp://ftp.cs.cornell.edu/pub/smart</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgment</head><p>This work is partially supported by the <rs type="funder">Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology, Japan</rs>, under grants <rs type="grantNumber">11480088</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">12680417</rs> and <rs type="grantNumber">12208032</rs>, and by <rs type="funder">CREST of JST (Japan Science and Technology)</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_TCVNN46">
					<idno type="grant-number">11480088</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_fd5nZjb">
					<idno type="grant-number">12680417</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_HzStKk4">
					<idno type="grant-number">12208032</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,107.28,316.64,412.67,8.53;6,93.60,327.43,172.25,8.53;6,265.91,325.43,4.73,5.48;6,272.63,327.44,159.56,8.53" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,239.15,316.64,280.80,8.53;6,93.60,327.43,80.59,8.53">Phrasal Translation and Query Expansion Techniques for Cross-Language Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ballesteros</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,184.31,327.43,81.53,8.53;6,265.91,325.43,4.73,5.48;6,272.63,327.44,91.61,8.53">Proceedings of the 20 th ACM SIGIR Conference</title>
		<meeting>the 20 th ACM SIGIR Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="84" to="91" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,108.24,349.03,407.20,8.53;6,515.50,347.03,4.49,5.48;6,93.60,359.83,261.07,8.53" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,230.60,349.03,193.95,8.53">Identifying word correspondences in parallel texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Church</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,435.10,349.03,80.33,8.53;6,515.50,347.03,4.49,5.48;6,93.60,359.83,183.86,8.53">Proceedings of the 4 th DARPA Speech and Natural Language Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the 4 th DARPA Speech and Natural Language Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991">1991</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="152" to="157" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,107.04,381.43,412.91,8.53;6,93.60,392.23,265.85,8.53;6,359.51,390.46,4.73,5.48;6,368.15,392.23,151.60,8.53;6,93.60,403.03,209.48,8.53" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,315.66,381.43,204.29,8.53;6,93.60,392.23,172.65,8.53">Query Term Disambiguation for Web Cross-Language Information Retrieval using a Search Engine</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Maeda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Sadat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Yoshikawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Uemura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,278.63,392.23,80.81,8.53;6,359.51,390.46,4.73,5.48;6,368.15,392.23,151.60,8.53;6,93.60,403.03,118.12,8.53">Proceedings of the 5 th International Workshop on Information Retrieval with Asian Languages</title>
		<meeting>the 5 th International Workshop on Information Retrieval with Asian Languages</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000-10">Oct 2000</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="32" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,110.16,427.51,409.78,8.53;6,93.60,438.79,426.16,8.53;6,93.60,450.07,312.20,8.53" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,351.11,427.51,168.83,8.53;6,93.60,438.79,181.83,8.53">Cross-Language Information Retrieval via Dictionary-based and Statistical-based Methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Sadat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Maeda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Yoshikawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Uemura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,288.23,438.79,231.53,8.53;6,93.60,450.07,248.32,8.53">Proceedings of the 2001 IEEE Pacific Rim Conference on Communications, Computers and Signal Processing (PACRIM&apos;01)</title>
		<meeting>the 2001 IEEE Pacific Rim Conference on Communications, Computers and Signal Processing (PACRIM&apos;01)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-08">August 2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
