<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,73.60,75.49,448.05,12.64">NTU at CLEF 2001: Chinese-English Cross-Lingual Information Retrieval</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,226.84,112.60,59.19,8.96"><forename type="first">Hsin-Hsi</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<email>hh_chen@csie.ntu.edu.tw</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Information Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Taiwan University Taipei</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>TAIWAN R.O.C</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,305.29,112.60,63.33,8.96"><forename type="first">Wen-Cheng</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Information Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National Taiwan University Taipei</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>TAIWAN R.O.C</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,73.60,75.49,448.05,12.64">NTU at CLEF 2001: Chinese-English Cross-Lingual Information Retrieval</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">317FCCC2A941D48F2E625A2CA41E7E67</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper reports the work of NTU on bilingual-retrieval task at CLEF 2001. We proposed five models.</p><p>Model 1 used co-occurrence information to disambiguate translation equivalents; Model 2 augmented restriction terms to the original queries; Model 3 used C-E WordNet to translate queries; Model 4 combined Model 3 with Model 2; Model 5 merged the queries constructed by Model 2 and 3. The best one is Model 5. The average precision of Model 5 is 0.1135, which is 53.06% of monolingual information retrieval.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>National Taiwan University (NTU) Natural Language Processing Laboratory (NLPL) participated bilingual-retrieval task at CLEF 2001. In this experiment, we used Chinese queries to retrieve English documents and query translation was adopted to unify the language of queries and documents.</p><p>In our previous works, several approaches were proposed. <ref type="bibr" coords="1,348.48,436.60,94.97,8.96" target="#b0">Bian and Chen (1998)</ref> proposed a hybrid approach that integrated both lexical and corpus knowledge to translate queries. A bilingual dictionary provides the translation equivalents of each query term, and the word co-occurrence information trained from a target language text collection is used to disambiguate the translation. Target polysemy is another problem in CLIR. <ref type="bibr" coords="1,106.24,508.60,112.53,8.96" target="#b2">Chen , Bian and Lin (1999)</ref> augmented a pseudo context to a query term to restrict its use in the target language. The contextual information is trained from a source language text collection. <ref type="bibr" coords="1,447.96,526.59,76.60,8.96;1,70.96,544.59,26.68,8.96" target="#b3">Chen, Lin and Lin (2000)</ref> proposed a method to construct a Chinese-English WordNet automatically. We used this C-E WordNet and a bilingual dictionary to translate queries. In this paper, we propose a combined approach that use C-E WordNet and augmented restrictions to construct target queries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Resources</head><p>In this work, we used four linguistic resources:</p><p>(1) Chinese-English dictionary The bilingual dictionary is integrated from four sources, including LDC Chinese-English dictionary, Denisowski's CEDICT, BDC Chinese-English dictionary v2.2 and a dictionary used in query translation in MTIR project <ref type="bibr" coords="1,230.04,706.60,90.02,8.96" target="#b1">(Bian and Chen, 2000)</ref>. The dictionary gathers 200,037 words, where a word may have more than one translation.</p><p>(2) ASBC <ref type="bibr" coords="1,144.41,742.60,83.32,8.96" target="#b7">(Huang, et al., 1995)</ref> Academic Sinica Balanced Corpus (abbreviated as ASBC corpus) is a POS-tagged Chinese balanced corpus. The major topics include philosophy (10%), science (10%), society (35%), art (5%), life (20%), and literary (20%). This corpus is composed of five million words.</p><p>(3) TREC6 text collection <ref type="bibr" coords="2,208.41,130.60,63.75,8.96" target="#b6">(Harman, 1997)</ref> The text collection contains 556,077 English documents, and is about 2.2G bytes.</p><p>(4) Chinese-English WordNet In our previous work <ref type="bibr" coords="2,218.44,184.22,122.06,9.94" target="#b3">(Chen, Lin and Lin, 2000)</ref>, we proposed a method to construct a Chinese-English WordNet automatically. Chinese words in tong2yi4ci2ci2lin2 ("同義詞詞林") <ref type="bibr" coords="2,115.96,220.60,81.87,8.96" target="#b8">(Mei, et al., 1982)</ref> are mapped into WordNet <ref type="bibr" coords="2,321.42,220.60,70.62,8.96" target="#b5">(Fellbaum, 1998)</ref>. Following the structures of WordNet, a Chinese WordNet and a Chinese-English WordNet are derived.</p><p>The co-occurrence information of Chinese and English words was trained from ASBC corpus and TREC6 text collection respectively. We adopted mutual information (MI) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,342.45,274.60,86.40,8.96" target="#b4">(Church, et al., 1989)</ref> to measure its strength.</p><p>For each word, we collected its mutual information with other words within a window of size 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Query translation</head><p>We adopted query translation to unify the language of queries and documents. The Chinese queries were translated into English. The translated English queries were used to retrieve English documents using a monolingual information retrieval system. We proposed four models to translate queries. Model 1 uses co-occurrence information trained from a text collection in source language to select the best translation equivalents of source language query terms. Model 2 tries to resolve the target polysemy problem by augmenting some restriction words. Model 3 uses automatic constructed C-E WordNet to translate queries.</p><p>Model 4 combines Model 2 and 3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Model 1 -CO Model</head><p>At first, the Chinese queries were segmented. For each Chinese word, we collected the translation equivalents by looking up a Chinese-English bilingual dictionary. Then the best translation equivalents were selected by using the co-occurrence information. The mutual information was trained from a text collection in target language, i.e. TREC6 text collection. For a query term, we compare the MI values of all the translation equivalent pairs (x, y), where x is the translation equivalent of this term, and y is the translation equivalent of another query term within a sentence. The word pair (x i , y j ) with the highest MI value is extracted, and the translation equivalent x i is regarded as the best translation equivalent of this query term. Selection is carried out based on the order of the query terms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Model 2 -Resolving Target Polysemy Problem</head><p>In order to resolve target polysemy problem, we augmented some words to restrict the use of a translated query term in target language. In this model, the Chinese queries were translated by CO model, and the translation equivalents of augmented words were added to target language queries. The augmented restriction words of a source language query term are those words that frequently co-occur with it within a window. The co-occurrence information was trained from ASBC corpus, and the mutual information was used to measure the strength. We collected the co-occurred terms that have only one translation as the candidates. Then we apply CO model to the translations of these candidates and select one term for each original query term.</p><p>The translations of original query terms and augmented restriction terms were assigned different weights.</p><p>They were determined by the following formula:</p><p>weight</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,79.96,165.02,87.34,52.37">(E i ) = ∑ = n k k m 1 weight(EW ij ) = 1</formula><p>Where n is number of words in a query Q; E i is the translation of query term C i; EW ij is the translation of augmented restriction term CW ij and m k is the number of words in a restriction for C k .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Model 3 -Using Chinese-English WordNet</head><p>In this model, Chinese-English WordNet was used to construct English queries. First, a Chinese query was tagged by a POS tagger. After removing stop words, we looked up the Chinese-English WordNet for the remaining Chinese words. A set of synsets was retrieved for each Chinese query term. We computed the mutual information for the sets of synsets, and selected a synset for each Chinese query term. The mutual information of two synsets is defined as follows. Let synset 1 and synset 2 be synsets for two query terms.</p><p>Assume synset 1 and synset 2 are composed of m and n English words, respectively.</p><p>Where t i is the English word in synset i . The MI values of any two English words are trained from TREC-6 corpus. All English words in the selected synsets were used to construct the target query. The translation equivalents in the selected synsets were assigned larger weights. The weights of translation equivalents in the selected synsets were 3 and that of other words were 1.</p><p>When looked up Chinese-English WordNet , some query terms can't be found. For these query terms, we add their translation equivalents to the English query. The weights of these translation equivalents were 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4.">Model 4 -Combined Approach</head><p>Consider the terms that can't be found in Chinese-English WordNet in Model 3, we used translations and restriction terms obtained in Model 2 instead of all translation equivalents retrieved from our bilingual dictionary. The weights of these translations were 3 and that of restriction terms were 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">IR system</head><p>Our Information Retrieval system is based on vector space model. The index terms are English words, and the term weighting function is tf*idf. When a query is submitted to this IR system, it computes the similarities of this query and all documents, then returns top rank documents. We adopt cosine vector similarity formula to measure the similarity of a query and a document. Higher score means that the query and the document are</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,80.92,169.52,389.18,267.45">(1) (2) ) /( ) , ( ) , ( 2 1 1 1 2 1 n m t t MI synset synset MI j m i n j i × ∑ ∑ = = =</formula><p>(3) more similar.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Results</head><p>We submitted four runs: NTUco, NTUa1wco, NTUaswtw and NTUtpwn. The English queries of these four runs were constructed by Model 1, 2, 3 and 4, respectively. In our experiments, only the Title and Description fields were used to generate queries. The results are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,369.13,166.60,3.75,8.96" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. There were some bugs in our IR system. Only the documents in January, February and March were indexed. We re-indexed all documents and did four new runs: CO, A1WCO, ASWTW and TPWN. We also did an unofficial run: MONO, a monolingual run. The results are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,274.49,220.60,3.76,8.96" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. The average precision of run CO is 0.1108, which is 51.8% of monolingual information retrieval. The performances of some queries were very bad. Word segmentation errors may be one of the reasons. Take "史 特加" as an example. The word "史特加" (Schneider) was segmented into "史", "特" and "加", and were translated into "history", "unusual" and "recruit" respectively. Dictionary coverage is another problem. Some proper nouns are not included in our bilingual dictionary. For example, "歐斯基爾肯" (Euskirchen) is not included in the dictionary. Because the lack of the translation of "歐斯基爾肯", the relevant document of query 75 can't be retrieved.</p><p>The performance of run A1WCO is almost the same as run CO. In Model 2, we add some restriction terms to the original queries. The augmented restriction terms help us to retrieve more relevant documents, but the average precision decrease. When we add words to the original queries, we may also introduce noises.</p><p>Some augmented restriction terms are related to the query terms that the restriction terms are augmented to, but it is not relevant to the queries. Thus, these terms become noises.</p><p>When we used C-E WordNet, the performance is not good. While constructing C-E WordNet, some Chinese words may have been mapped to wrong synsets. For example, "中國" (China) was mapped to the synset that only contain "Kyushu". Thus we can't find any document that relevant to "Chinese Currency Devaluation". In Model 3, we used all translation equivalents of the words that are not included in C-E WordNet. In this way, some inappropriate translations were also added to the target queries. In Model 4, we used the translations and restriction terms that obtained from Model 2. The result shows that the performance is improved. The average precision of run TPWN is 0.1080, which is 50.49% of monolingual information retrieval. It is better than run ASWTW, but still worse than other runs. We try another combination method.</p><p>We simply merge the target queries that constructed by Model 2 and 3. The last row of Table <ref type="table" coords="5,452.51,238.59,4.98,8.96" target="#tab_1">2</ref> shows the result.</p><p>The average precision of run TPWN2 is 0.1135.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusions</head><p>In CLEF 2001, we proposed five models. Model 1 used a hybrid approach that integrated both lexical and corpus knowledge to translate queries. The word co-occurrence information is used to disambiguate translation equivalents; Model 2 augmented some restriction terms to the original queries to deal with target polysemy problem; Model 3 used C-E WordNet to translate queries; Model 4 combined Model 3 with Model 2; Model 5 merged the queries constructed by Model 2 and 3. The best one is Model 5. The average precision of Model 5 is 0.1135, which is 53.06% of monolingual information retrieval.</p><p>Dictionary coverage is a problem while translating queries. Since the important words of some queries are not included in our bilingual dictionary, the performances of these queries were bad. Word segmentation error is another problem. If a word is not segmented correctly, we can't find it's correct translation. In Model 3, we found that the C-E WordNet has errors. Some Chinese words may have been mapped to wrong synsets. In the future, we will refine the bilingual dictionary and C-E WordNet and conduct more precise error analysis.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,79.96,256.04,395.65,101.92"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Results of official runs</figDesc><table coords="4,111.16,275.08,364.45,82.88"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>Average precision</cell><cell>R-Precision</cell><cell>Rel_ret</cell></row><row><cell>NTUco</cell><cell>0.0254</cell><cell>0.0292</cell><cell>134</cell></row><row><cell>NTUa1wco</cell><cell>0.0255</cell><cell>0.0297</cell><cell>135</cell></row><row><cell>NTUaswtw</cell><cell>0.0224</cell><cell>0.0328</cell><cell>149</cell></row><row><cell>NTUtpwn</cell><cell>0.0195</cell><cell>0.0301</cell><cell>141</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,79.96,385.04,395.65,139.00"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results of new runs</figDesc><table coords="4,115.48,404.08,360.13,119.96"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>Average precision</cell><cell>R-Precision</cell><cell>Rel_ret</cell></row><row><cell>MONO</cell><cell>0.2139</cell><cell>0.2039</cell><cell>611</cell></row><row><cell>CO</cell><cell>0.1108 (51.8%)</cell><cell>0.1214 (59.54%)</cell><cell>482</cell></row><row><cell>A1WCO</cell><cell>0.1107 (51.75%)</cell><cell>0.1198 (58.75%)</cell><cell>485</cell></row><row><cell>ASWTW</cell><cell>0.0816 (38.15%)</cell><cell>0.0814 (39.92%)</cell><cell>472</cell></row><row><cell>TPWN</cell><cell>0.1080 (50.49%)</cell><cell>0.1172 (57.48%)</cell><cell>491</cell></row><row><cell>TPWN2</cell><cell>0.1135 (53.06%)</cell><cell>0.1201 (58.90%)</cell><cell>512</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.96,544.60,453.36,8.96;5,80.92,562.60,443.44,8.96;5,80.92,580.60,227.68,8.96" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,244.56,544.60,279.76,8.96;5,80.92,562.60,186.17,8.96">Integrating Query Translation and Document Translation in a Cross-Language Information Retrieval System</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Bian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,286.24,562.60,174.00,8.96">Machine Translation and Information Soup</title>
		<title level="s" coord="5,467.68,562.60,56.68,8.96;5,80.92,580.60,81.78,8.96">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Spring-Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1529</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="250" to="265" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.96,598.60,453.56,8.96;5,80.92,616.60,327.74,8.96" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,235.22,598.60,289.30,8.96;5,80.92,616.60,30.35,8.96">Cross language information access to multilingual collections on the Internet</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Bian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,128.92,616.60,210.27,8.96">Journal of American Society for Information Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="281" to="296" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.96,634.60,453.54,8.96;5,80.92,652.60,443.69,8.96;5,80.92,670.60,147.41,8.96" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,279.09,634.60,245.41,8.96;5,80.92,652.60,158.47,8.96">Resolving Translation Ambiguity and Target Polysemy in Cross-Language Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Bian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,270.52,652.60,254.09,8.96;5,80.92,670.60,105.06,8.96">Proceedings of 37th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>37th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="215" to="222" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.96,688.59,453.46,8.96;5,80.92,706.59,443.56,8.96;5,80.92,724.59,171.54,8.96" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,267.16,688.59,257.26,8.96;5,80.92,706.59,33.36,8.96">Construction of a Chinese-English WordNet and Its Application to CLIR</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,150.04,706.59,374.44,8.96;5,80.92,724.59,41.88,8.96">Proceedings of the Fifth International Workshop on Information Retrieval with Asian Languages</title>
		<meeting>the Fifth International Workshop on Information Retrieval with Asian Languages<address><addrLine>Hong Kong</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="189" to="196" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,70.96,76.60,453.42,8.96;6,80.92,94.60,299.93,8.96" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,204.22,76.60,293.60,8.96">Parsing, Word Associations and Typical Predicate-Argument Relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Church</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,80.92,94.60,257.28,8.96">Proceedings of International Workshop on Parsing Technologies</title>
		<meeting>International Workshop on Parsing Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989">1989</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="389" to="398" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,70.96,112.60,416.62,8.96" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,190.00,112.60,167.87,8.96">WordNet: An Electronic Lexical Database</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Fellbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,70.96,130.60,276.81,8.96" xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="6,159.28,130.60,83.44,8.96">TREC-6 Proceedings</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, Maryland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,70.96,148.60,453.39,8.96;6,80.92,166.60,81.06,8.96" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,184.96,148.60,202.62,8.96">Introduction to Academia Sinica Balanced Corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,418.00,148.60,106.35,8.96;6,80.92,166.60,14.95,8.96">Proceedings of ROCLING VIII</title>
		<meeting>ROCLING VIII<address><addrLine>Taiwan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="99" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,70.96,184.60,290.48,8.96" xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,165.64,184.60,73.64,8.96">tong2yi4ci2ci2lin2</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1982">1982</date>
			<publisher>Shanghai Dictionary Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
