<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,222.63,178.13,184.44,22.20;1,163.59,200.09,302.28,22.20">CLEF 2001 Bilingual Task Simple Dictionary-Based Query Translation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,226.71,233.36,82.32,16.40"><forename type="first">Marine</forename><surname>Carpuat</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,335.67,233.36,67.08,16.40"><forename type="first">Pascale</forename><surname>Fung</surname></persName>
							<email>pascaleg@ee.ust.hk</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">HKUST Human Language Technology Center</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering Science and Technology Clear Water Bay</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Hong Kong</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,222.63,178.13,184.44,22.20;1,163.59,200.09,302.28,22.20">CLEF 2001 Bilingual Task Simple Dictionary-Based Query Translation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">17E69D0B5DFAA1F8F0089A3D2756DE6F</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper, we describe our approach to the French English Bilingual Task in CLEF 2001. A simple dictionary-based method is used to translate the French query into a bag of weighted English words, the English query, which is submitted to the SMART retrieval engine. Despite the simplicity of the method, the results happen to be reasonable.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>For our rst participation to CLEF, our goal was to evaluate what level of performance can be expected from a simple CLIR system, which does not make use of sophisticated resources. We d e c i d e t o w ork on a fully automatic method, based on freely available resources. We participated to the French-English bilingual task and present the results obtained using a simple dictionary-based query translation method.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2.1</head><p>Dictionary-Based Keyword Translation</p><p>The easiest and most common way t o cross the language boundary for CLIR is to translate the original query in the target language and to input this new query to a monolingual IR Sytem. In this work, French queries are simply translated into English by dictionary look-up. Our "bilingual dictionary" is in fact a bilingual word list generated from a free online Bilingual French-English dictionary 3]. The lists consists of around 200,000 entries, but many di erent forms are listed for each F rench w ord ( singular/plural, male/female, tenses ). The number of terms actually represented is therefore much lower. Multiple translations are all included according to the online dictionary. This naive construction of the bilingual lexicon allows us to perform very little pre-processing on the French queries. We only focus on keyword selection. In order to translate meaningful terms, we try to remove as many stopwords or function words as possible. We chose a basic stoplist 5] and augmented it.</p><p>CLEF2000 French topics are used to identify function words that are used to express the information need but do not carry information themselves. These words typically occur in a large number of queries with a low frequency in each query, whereas content-bearing words occur in fewer queries with a h i g h frequency in each query. Potential function words are therefore easily selected with tf.idf information.</p><p>The English query is a simple bag of words, taking into account all the possible translation of the keywords given by the dictionary. If no translation candidate can be found in the dictionary, the French w ords are directly copied and pasted in the English query. For closely related languages such a s F rench and English, keeping the original word in the source language is helpful, since the missing translations happen to be proper nouns, English words included in French topics or cognates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Text Retrieval Engine</head><p>The Text Retrieval Engine used in this work is the well-known IR sytem Smart 2] 6].</p><p>It is well adapted to index and query a large corpus such as the CLEF Los Angeles Times corpus. Smart implements the vector space model, in which queries and documents are represented by vectors containing tf.idf weights. English queries consist of all the translation candidates found for the French topics keywords, weighted by the frequency of the original French keyword and the translation probability when multiple candidayes are found. We assume these translation probabilities are uniform.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head><p>Our experiment w as conducted using the title and description elds of the topics only. We obtain average results, which are reasonable given the simplicity of the method used. The majority of unique translation candidates given by our lexicon happen to be correct. When multiple translations are proposed, co-occurence with the translation of other keywords performs a simple disambiguation. Not surprisingly however, when the number of translation candidates grows larger and when the terms are more ambiguous, the query results drop below the average. Improvements could be achieved by adding a statistical disambiguation method 1] and making use of a more sophisticated translation weighting scheme.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Recall Precision</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>In summary, our simple dictionary-based keyword translation method performs reasonably well with a simple lexicon. Of course, query expansion and disambiguation methods are much needed to improve these results. But this shows that even a simple lexicon based on the most frequent translations is a reasonable basis for Bilingual Information Retrieval.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,210.63,599.51,208.56,165.24"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Interpolated Recall-Precision Averages</figDesc><table coords="2,280.11,599.51,68.04,133.32"><row><cell>0.00 0.10 0.20 0.30 0.40 0.50 0.60 0.70 0.80 0.90 1.00</cell><cell>0.5634 0.4996 0.4388 0.3630 0.3040 0.3234 0.2010 0.1743 0.1554 0.1302 0.0932</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="3,220.23,323.87,266.28,13.80;3,220.23,336.02,266.28,13.60;3,220.23,347.75,266.40,13.80;3,220.23,359.75,266.40,13.80;3,220.23,371.75,266.40,13.80;3,220.23,383.63,266.40,13.80;3,220.23,395.63,261.48,13.80" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,381.63,324.02,104.88,13.60;3,220.23,336.02,266.28,13.60;3,220.23,347.90,37.48,13.60">Phrasal Translation and Query Expansion Techniques for Cross-Language Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ballesteros</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,286.83,347.75,199.80,13.80;3,220.23,359.75,266.40,13.80;3,220.23,371.75,266.40,13.80;3,220.23,383.63,217.32,13.80">Proceedings of the Association for Computing Machinery Special Interest Group on Information Retrieval (ACM/SIGIR) 20th International Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the Association for Computing Machinery Special Interest Group on Information Retrieval (ACM/SIGIR) 20th International Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval<address><addrLine>Philadelphia, PA. New York, NY</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997-07-25">1997. 1997 July 25-31. 1997</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="84" to="91" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,220.23,415.55,266.16,13.80;3,220.23,427.55,266.40,13.80;3,220.23,439.43,266.64,13.80;3,220.23,459.35,266.52,13.80;3,220.23,471.35,171.48,13.80" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="3,301.47,415.70,184.92,13.60;3,220.23,427.70,66.62,13.60">Implementation of the smart information retrieval system</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>85-686</idno>
		<ptr target="http://sun-recomgen.univ-rennes1.fr/FR-Eng.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985-05">1985. May 1985</date>
			<pubPlace>Ithaca, New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Computer Science Department, Cornell University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">T echnical Report</note>
	<note>English-French bilingual dictionary</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,220.23,491.27,266.40,13.80;3,220.23,503.27,266.64,13.80;3,220.23,515.15,258.36,13.80;3,220.23,535.07,35.04,13.80;3,282.15,535.07,7.92,13.80;3,312.27,535.07,12.96,13.80;3,347.55,535.07,73.68,13.80;3,443.43,535.07,43.20,13.80;3,220.23,547.07,158.64,13.80;3,207.51,566.99,246.12,13.80" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,331.83,491.27,154.80,13.80;3,220.23,503.27,81.10,13.80">The Problem of cross-language information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Grefenstette</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.up.univ-mrs.fr/~veronis6Smart.Available:ftp://ftp.cs.cornell.edu/pub/smart" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,417.03,503.27,69.84,13.80;3,220.23,515.15,89.62,13.80">Cross Language Information retrieval</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Grefenstette</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
