<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,118.02,112.92,375.45,15.49">Building an Arabic Stemmer for Information Retrieval</title>
				<funder ref="#_d9VjkMW">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">DARPA Information Technology Office</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_gt8VK4C">
					<orgName type="full">Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,278.58,145.37,54.78,10.76"><forename type="first">Aitao</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,277.38,207.17,57.18,10.76"><forename type="first">Fredric</forename><surname>Gey</surname></persName>
							<email>gey@ucdata.berkeley.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information Management and Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California at Berkeley</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94720-4600</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">UC Data Archive &amp; Technical Assistance (UC DATA</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California at Berkeley</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94720-5100</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,118.02,112.92,375.45,15.49">Building an Arabic Stemmer for Information Retrieval</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">5D047A2B2F13510D3AF82CABF16E43B2</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T14:59+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In TREC 2002 the Berkeley group participated only in the English-Arabic cross-language retrieval (CLIR) track. One Arabic monolingual run and three English-Arabic cross-language runs were submitted. Our approach to the crosslanguage retrieval was to translate the English topics into Arabic using online English-Arabic machine translation systems. The four official runs are named as BKYMON, BKYCL1, BKYCL2, and BKYCL3. The BKYMON is the Arabic monolingual run, and the other three runs are English-to-Arabic cross-language runs. This paper reports on the construction of an Arabic stoplist and two Arabic stemmers, and the experiments on Arabic monolingual retrieval, English-to-Arabic cross-language retrieval.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Background</head><p>Arabic has much richer morphology than English. Arabic has two genders, feminine and masculine; three numbers, singular, dual, and plural; and three grammatical cases, nominative, genitive, and accusative. A noun has the nominative case when it is a subject; accusative when it is the object of a verb; and genitive when it is the object of a preposition. The form of an Arabic noun is determined by its gender, number, and grammatical case. The definitive nouns are formed by attaching the Arabic article ¢¡ to the immediate front of the nouns. As an example, the Arabic word £ ¤ ¦¥ § © ¨¡ means the student (feminine). Sometimes a preposition, such as § (by) and (to), is attached to the front of a noun, often in front of the definitive article. For example, the Arabic word ¥ § © ! " ¨means to the students (masculine). Besides prefixes, a noun can also carry a suffix which is often a possessive pronoun. For example, the Arabic word # %$ § © '&amp; § (by my student) can be analyzed as ( + ) § © 0 + § , with one prefix § (by) and one pronoun suffix ( (my). In Arabic, the conjunction word 1 (and) is often attached to the following word. For example, the word © 2 43 § © '&amp; § 1 means and by her student (masculine). Arabic has two kinds of plurals: sound plurals and broken plurals. The sound plurals are formed by adding plural suffixes to singular nouns. The plural suffix is £ ¡ for feminine nouns in all three grammatical cases, 5 1 for masculine nouns in nominative case, and 6 for masculine nouns in genitive and accusative cases. For example, the word 5 87 @9 A 8B DC (teachers, masculine) is the plural form of E A FB GC (teacher, masculine) in nominative case, and 9 A 8B GC (teachers, masculine) is the plural form of E A FB DC (teacher, masculine) in genitive or accusative case. The plural form of £ ¤ 9 A FB GC (teacher, feminine) is £ © 9 A HB GC (teachers, feminine) in all three grammatical cases. The dual suffix is £ ¡ for the nominative case, and 6 for the genitive or accusative. The word 5 © 9 A FB GC means two teachers. The formation of broken plurals is more complex and often irregular; it is, therefore, difficult to predict.</p><p>Furthermore, broken plurals are very common in Arabic. For example, the plural form of the noun I P 0 (child) is</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The examples presented in this secion show that an Arabic noun could potentially have a large number of variants, and some of the variants can be complex because of the prefixes, suffixes, and infixes. As an example, the word © § 4© P 0 ¨ © 1 (and to her children) can be analyzed as © + © P 0 ¡ + + 1 . It has two prefixes and one suffix.</p><p>Like nouns, an Arabic adjective can also have many variants. When an adjective modifies a noun in a noun phrase, the adjective agrees with the noun in gender, number, case, and definiteness. An adjective has a masculine singular form such as B 6 B § (new), a feminine singular form such as £ £ B 6 B § (new), a masculine plural form such as B " § (new), and a feminine plural form such as £ ¡ B 6 B § (new). For example, B 6 B § ¡ E A FB ¡ means the new teacher (masculine), and B " § ¡ 5 87 9 A 8B ¡ means the new teachers (masculine). The adjective has the feminine singular form when the plural noun denotes something inanimate. As an example, the word £ £ B 6 B § (new) in £ £ B 6 B § ¡ ) § £ ¥ ¨¡ (the new books) is the feminine singular form. Arabic verbs have two tenses: perfect and imperfect. Perfect tense denotes actions completed, while imperfect denotes incompleted actions. The imperfect tense has four mood: indicative, subjective, jussive, and imperative <ref type="bibr" coords="2,525.35,285.58,10.56,8.97" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. Arabic verbs in perfect tense consist of a stem and a subject marker. The subject marker indicates the person, gender, and number of the subject. The form of a verb in perfect tense can have subject marker and pronoun suffix. The form of a subject-marker is determined together by the person, gender, and number of the subject. Take E A (to study) as an example, the perfect tense is £ ) 9 A for the third person, feminine, singular subject, ¡ 7 @9 A for the third person, masculine, plural subject. A verb with subject marker and pronoun suffix can be a complete sentence. For example, the word ¤ £ ¥ 9 A has a third-person, feminine, singular subject-marker £ (she) and a pronoun suffix £ (him), it is also a complete sentence, meaning "she studied him." Often the subject-makers are suffixes, but sometimes a subject-marker can be a combination of a prefix and a suffix. For example, the word study in a negative sentence is # $ "! A B £ 6 (did not study). For verbs in imperfect tense, in addition to the subject-marker, a verb can also have a mood-marker.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Test Collection</head><p>The document collection used in TREC 2002 cross-language track consists of 383,872 Arabic articles from the Agence France Press (AFP) Arabic Newswire during the period from 13 May, 1994 to 20 December, 2000. There are 50 English topics with Arabic translations. A topic has three tagged fields: title, description, and narrative. The newswire articles are encoded in Unicode (UTF-8) format, while the topics are encoded in ASMO 708.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Preprocessing</head><p>Because the texts in the documents and topics are encoded in different schemes, we converted both the documents and topics to Windows CP-1256 encoding. The set of valid characters include the Arabic letters and the English letters in both lower and upper cases. The Arabic punctuation marks, # , $ , and % , were considered as delimiters. A consecutive sequence of valid characters was recognized as a word in the tokenization process. The words that are stopwords were removed during documents and topics indexing. We say a word is minimally normalized when </p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,410.80,655.85,53.57,21.10">£ £ ¡ ¤ C ¡ or £ £ ¡ ¤ C ¡</formula><p>. The Arabic shadda character is sometimes dropped in spelling. For example, for the word E A FB GC (teacher) is sometimes spelled as E A B DC .</p><p>At TREC 2001, we created an Arabic stopword list consisting of Arabic pronouns, prepositions, and the like that are found in an elementary Arabic textbook <ref type="bibr" coords="3,259.35,110.26,11.57,8.97" target="#b3">[4]</ref> and the Arabic words translated from an English stopword list.</p><p>For TREC 2002, we first collected all the Arabic words found in the Arabic document collection. The number of unique Arabic words found in the collection after minimal normalization is 541,681. We then translated the Arabic words, word-by-word, into English using the Ajeeb online English-Arabic machine translation system available at http://www.ajeeb.com. From this Arabic-English bilingual wordlist, we created an Arabic stopword list consisting of the Arabic words whose translations consists of only English stopwords. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">MT-based stemmer</head><p>We built a MT-based Arabic stemmer from the Arabic words found in the Arabic documents and their English translations using the online Ajeeb machine translation system. We partitioned the Arabic words into clusters based on the English translations of the Arabic words. The Arabic words whose English translations, after removing English stopwords, are conflated to the same English stem form one cluster. And all the Arabic words in the same cluster are conflated to the same Arabic word, the shortest Arabic word in the cluster. For example, an English stemmer usually changes plural nouns into singular, so children is changed to child. In order to change the variants of the Arabic word for child or children to the same Arabic stem, we first grouped all the Arabic words whose English translations contain the headword child or children. Then in stemming, all the Arabic words in this group are changed to the shortest Arabic word in the group. The Arabic adjectives and verbs were stemmed in the same way. For English, we used a morphological analyzer <ref type="bibr" coords="3,178.37,498.76,11.57,8.97" target="#b1">[2]</ref> to map plural nouns into singular form, verbs into the infinitive form, and adjectives into the positive form. This stemmer changes the broken plural forms of an Arabic word into its singular form. The broken plural forms are common and irregular, so it is generally difficult to write a stemmer to change the broken plural forms to singular forms. For example, Table <ref type="table" coords="3,283.75,534.64,4.97,8.97">1</ref> presents part of the Arabic words whose English translations contain the headword child or children. All the Arabic words shown in table <ref type="table" coords="3,380.64,546.58,4.97,8.97">1</ref> belong to the same cluster since, after removing the English stopwords, the English translations consist of either the word child or children, both being conflated to the same word by the English morphological analyzer. In stemming, the Arabic words shown in table <ref type="table" coords="3,519.51,570.52,4.97,8.97">1</ref> are conflated into the same word I P 0 . The English translations were produced using the online Ajeeb machine translation system. One can also create an Arabic stemmer from English/Arabic parallel texts or bilingual dictionaries. With a large English/Arabic parallel corpus available, one can first align the texts at the sentence level, then use a statistical machine translation toolkit such as GIZA++ to create an Arabic-to-English translation table. If we keep only the most likely English translation for an Arabic word, then we have a bilingual wordlist. Using this bilingual wordlist, we can translate all the Arabic words found in the Arabic document collection into English. We can create an Arabic stemmer by partitioning the Arabic words into clusters, each consisting of the Arabic words whose English translations are conflated to the same word by the English morphological analyzer. Stemmers for other languages can also be automatically generated using this method as long as some translingual resources, such as MT, parallel texts, or bilingual dictionaries, are available. word translation word translation word translation word translation </p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="4,91.00,90.50,415.58,136.70">¢¡ ¤£ ¥ §¦ © children £ ¤ ¡ ¤£ ¥ ¦ their children £ ¥ ! " by child # $ &amp;% £ ¥ ' ¡ (£ ) then the child 0 ¡ 1£ ¥ 2¦ © children 3 4 5 ¡ ¤£ ¥ 2¦ my children # $ 6% £ ¥ ' ! " by child £ ¥ £ ) then child ¡ £ 7 ¡ £ ¥ §¦ our children ¢¡ £ ¥ §¦ ¨0 children ¡ £ 7 # 7 % £ ¥ ' ! " by our child ¢¡ £ ¥ 8¦ ¨¡ 9 as children $ ¡ ¤£ ¥ ¦ © and his children ¢¡ ¤£ ¥ §¦ 0 children $ # 7 % £ ¥ ' ! " by his child £ ¥ ¡ 9 as the child $ ¡ ¤£ ¥ ¦ his children £ ¥ the child $ @% £ ¥ 2 ! " by his child ¢¡ ¤£ ¥ §¦ ¨0 to children ¡ 1 ¡ 1£ ¥ ¦ © her children £ A ©B £ ¥ 2 the children ¡ % £ ¥ ! " by her child ¡ % £ ¥ to her child C ¤ ¡ ¤£ ¥ 8¦ their children # $ 6% £ ¥ ' the child ¡ D % £ ¥ E ! " by their child # $ &amp;% £ ¥ ' GF % to the child £ 1 ¡ ¤£ ¥ ¦ © their children £ A ¡ # 7 % £ ¥ ' the children £ IH 4 % £ ¥ ' ! " by children ¡ £ 7 ¡ 1£ ¥ §¦</formula><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="4,90.30,334.30,434.91,66.00">$ ¡ ¤£ ¥ ¦ his children £ ¥ 2 ¡ X " by the child £ A ¡ # 7 % £ ¥ '¦ children $ 7 4 % £ ¥ '¦ IP and his children ¡ 1 ¡ 1£ ¥ ¦ her children # $ &amp;% £ ¥ d ¡ X " by the child # $ # 7 % £ ¥ '¦ his child ¡ Q 1R 4 % £ ¥ '¦ IP and her children C ¤ ¡ ¤£ ¥ 8¦ their children £ H 4 # 7 % £ ¥ d ¡ X " by the children ¡ £ 7 # 7 % £ ¥ '¦ our child ¡ 1 ¡ ¤£ ¥ b¦ ¨0 P and to her children ¡ D 1 ¡ 1£ ¥ 8¦ their children £ H 4 % £ ¥ d ¡ X " by the children $ # 7 % £ ¥ '¦</formula><p>his child £ ¥ F % P and to the child Table <ref type="table" coords="4,150.04,413.86,3.87,8.97">1</ref>: Arabic words whose English translations contain the headword child or children.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Light stemmer</head><p>We developed a second Arabic stemmer called light stemmer that removes only prefixes and suffixes. We identified one set of prefixes and one set of suffixes that should be removed based on the grammatical functions of the affixes, their occurrence frequencies among the Arabic words found in the Arabic document collection, the English translations of the affixes, and empirical evaluation using the test collection of the previous CLIR track. We generated three lists consisting of the initial, the first two, or the first three characters, respectively, of the Arabic words in the document collection, and three lists consisting of the final, the last two, or the last three characters, respectively, of the Arabic words. We then sorted the six lists of suffixes or prefixes in descending order by the number of unique words in which a prefix or suffix occurs. Table <ref type="table" coords="4,195.76,557.32,4.97,8.97" target="#tab_3">2</ref> presents the most frequent one-, two-, and three-character prefixes among the unique Arabic words found in the document collection. The frequency shown in the table is the number of unique Arabic words that begins with a specific prefix. Table <ref type="table" coords="4,267.76,581.26,4.97,8.97" target="#tab_4">3</ref> shows the most frequent one-, two-, and three-character suffixes among the unique Arabic words. The frequency count for a given suffix is the number of unique Arabic words that end with that suffix. We identified 9 three-character, 14 two-character, and 3 one-character prefixes that should be removed in stemming, and 18 two-character, and 4 one-character suffixes that should be removed in stemming. The 9 three-character prefixes are ¢¡ 1 (and the), © 6 § (by the), © ¡ (then the), © e (as the), I ¨1 (and to the), © C , ¢¡ ¡ , © 9 , © . The 14 two-character prefixes to be removed are the most frequent ones as shown in table 2. Our light stemmer shares many of the prefixes and suffixes that should be removed with the light stemmer developed by Larkey et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="4,510.51,657.40,11.57,8.97" target="#b4">[5]</ref> and the light stemmer developed by Darwish <ref type="bibr" coords="4,230.02,669.34,13.04,8.97" target="#b2">[3]</ref>.</p><p>The stemmer non-recursively removes the prefixes in the pre-defined set of prefixes, and recursively removes the suffixes in the pre-defined set of suffixes in the following sequence. </p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="5,97.30,528.45,442.63,41.60">¢¡ , ¡ 1 , © 6 § , I ¨, ' 1 , £ 1 , § 1 , © , # $ "! , E 1 , ( 1 , 1 , © e , © ¡ .</formula><p>3. If the word is at least four-character long and begins with 1 , remove the initial letter 1 .</p><p>4. If the word is at least four-character long and begins with either § or , remove § or only if, after removing the initial character, the resultant word is present in the Arabic document collection.</p><p>5. Recursively strips the following two-character suffixes in the order of presentation if the word is at least fourcharacter long before removing a suffix: In our implementation, the suffix # ( is removed only if the word is at least four-character long and the resultant word after removing the suffix is present in the Arabic document collection. The prefix © 6 § 1 is often the combination of three prefixes 1 (and), § (by), and ¢¡</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="5,260.70,642.85,234.81,23.90">© , £ ¤ 6 , ¢ , © 6 , © C , ¡ 1 , © 6 , # ( , © 6 , , ¢ , ¢ , ) £ , £ 6 , 6 , 5 ¡ , £ ¡ ,<label>5</label></formula><p>(the), and should be removed. The light stemmer we used for the TREC 2002 experiments did not remove this prefix combination. We decided to remove the initial letter WAW (1 ) since it the most frequent initial letter and often is the conjunction word attached to the following word. The other two initial letters that were removed are BEH ( § ) and LAM ( ). The prefix § is sometimes a preposition prefix, meaning by, and the prefix is also sometimes a preposition prefix, meaning to. Our light stemmer removes § and only when, after removing the prefix, the resultant stem is also a word in the collection.</p><p>Among the two-letter suffixes to be removed, six are pronoun suffixes ( © , ¢ , © 6 , , ¢ , ¢</p><p>); four are plural suffixes ( 6 , 5 ¡ , £ ¡ , 5 1 ); and three are subject markers (</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="6,301.60,562.95,34.71,22.20">¡ 1 , ) £ , £<label>6</label></formula><p>). The suffix £ ¤ 6 is a nisba ending. The single-letter suffix £ £ is the feminine ending, £ a pronoun suffix, ( a pronoun suffix, and £ a subject marker. Sometimes the suffix £ £ is inseparable since, if removed, the resultant word is completely a different word. As an example, the word £ ¤ " ¡ means the queen, after removing the suffix £ £ , the resultant word ¤ " ¡ means the king.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Experimental Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1">Retrieval system</head><p>The retrieval system we used for the experiments is an implementation of the retrieval algorithm presented in <ref type="bibr" coords="6,508.62,700.96,10.56,8.97" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. For term selection, we assume the top-ranked ¥ documents in the initial search are relevant, and the rest of the documents in the collection are irrelevant. For the terms in the documents that are presumed relevant, we compute term relevance weighting <ref type="bibr" coords="7,114.31,88.00,11.57,8.97" target="#b5">[6]</ref> as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="7,232.80,100.20,307.13,28.72">¢¡ ¤£ ¥ §¦ ©¨¥ ¡ ¡ ¥ ¥ ¡ "! ¥ ¥ ¡ #! ¡ $ ¥ ¡ #! (1)</formula><p>where is the number of documents in the collection, ¥ the number of top-ranked documents after the initial search that are presumed relevant, ¥ ¡ the number of documents among the ¥ top-ranked documents that contain the term % , and &amp;¡ the number of documents in the collection that contain the term % . Then all the terms found in the top-ranked ¥ documents are ranked in decreasing order by relevance weight '¡ . The top-ranked ( terms are weighted and then merged with the initial query terms to create a new query. Some of the selected terms may be in the initial query. For the selected top-ranked terms that are not in the initial query, the weight is set to 0.5. For those top-ranked terms that are in the initial query, the weight is set to 0.5*% 0) , where % ") is the occurrence frequency of term % in the initial query.</p><p>The selected terms are merged with the initial query to formulate an expanded query. When a selected term is one of the query terms in the initial query, its weight in the expanded query is the sum of its weight in the initial query and its weight assigned in the term selection process. For a selected term that is not in the initial query, its weight in the final query is the same as the weight assigned in the term selection process, which is 0.5. The weights for the initial query terms that are not in the list of selected terms remain unchanged.</p><p>A query, like a document, is normally represented in our retrieval system by a set of unique words in the query with within-query term frequency. For the experiments reported in this paper, a word occurring times in a query is represented by occurrences of the same word with within-query frequency of one.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2">Monolingual Retrieval Results</head><p>The BKYMON run is our only official Arabic monolingual run in which only the title and desc fields in the topics were indexed. After removing stopwords from both documents and topics, the remaining words were stemmed using Berkeley light stemmer as described in section 6.2. The stopword list used in this run was the one created from the translations of Arabic document words using the online Ajeeb machine translation. The development of the Arabic stoplist was described in section 5. The stopword list has 2,942 words after light normalization. Table <ref type="table" coords="7,484.27,404.80,4.97,8.97" target="#tab_5">4</ref> presents the evaluation results for additional retrieval runs. The monolingual run mon0 was produced without stemming. The words were lightly normalized and stopwords removed. Two runs were performed using overlapping trigram indexing, one without word boundary crossing (mon1) and the other with word boundary crossing (mon2) . For example, without word boundary crossing, the following trigrams are produced from the phrase © 1 7 " 6 § £ ¤ 6 © ¥ 2 : © ¥ 32 , 5 © 6 , £ ¤ 6 ¡ , 7 " 6 § , 4 7 ¨, © 1 1 . But with word boundary crossing, two additional trigrams, § £ ¤ 6 and I 6 § £ £ , are produced. The words were lightly normalized and the stopwords were removed before trigrams were generated from the normalized words.</p><p>The monolingual run mon3 used the light stemmer named Al-Stem, developed by Darwish <ref type="bibr" coords="7,447.23,507.88,10.60,8.97" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. The numeric digits from '0' to '9' are treated as part of a token in Darwish's stemmer which also reduces 616 unnormalized words found in the Arabic documents to empty string, effectively treating them as stopwords. The stemmer also normalizes words. For the run mon3, words were aggressively normalized within the stemmer. For all other runs, the numeric digits were treated as word delimiters, and the words were normalized using our own light normalizer.</p><p>For the run mon4, the words were stemmed using the automatically generated MT-based stemmer. The words were first normalized and then the stopwords removed.</p><p>For the runs, mon0, mon3, mon4, and BKYMON, 20 words were selected from the top-ranked 10 documents for query expansion; and for the runs, mon1 and mon2, 40 trigrams were selected from the top-ranked 10 documents for query expansion.</p><p>The increase in performance without query expansion is substantial, however, the difference remains small after query expansion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.3">Cross-language Retrieval Results</head><p>Our approach to cross-language retrieval was to translate the English topics into Arabic, and then search the translated Arabic topics against the Arabic documents. The source English topics were translated into Arabic using two online English-Arabic machine translation systems: Ajeeb and Almisbar, available at http://www.almisbar.com/. We submitted three official cross-language runs: BKYCL1, BKYCL2, and BKYCL3. The BKYCL1 run was produced by merging the results of two English-to-Arabic retrieval runs: cl1 and cl2. The first run used the Ajeeb English-to-Arabic translations, and the second run used the Almisbar English-to-Arabic translations. For both intermediate runs, the words were stemmed using Berkeley's light stemmer after removing stopwords. For query expansion, 20 terms were selected from the top-ranked 10 documents. When two runs were merged topic by topic, the estimated probabilities of relevance were summed for the same documents. The merged list of documents was sorted by the combined estimated score of relevance, and the top-ranked 1000 documents per topic were kept to produce the official run BKYCL1. Only the title and desc fields in the topics were used to produce the BKYCL1 run. The average precision for run cl2 is 0.2782 with overall recall of 4823/5909. The average precision for run cl1 is 0.2962 with overall recall of 4441/5909.</p><p>The BKYCL2 run was produced by merging the results of three English-to-Arabic retrieval runs. The first two intermediate runs, cl1 and cl2, were the same two runs that were merged to produce BKYCL1 run. The third intermediate run, named cl3, was produced using the English-to-Arabic bilingual dictionary created from the U.N. English/Arabic parallel texts. The bilingual dictionary was provided as part of the standard translation resources for the cross-language track. Readers are referred to <ref type="bibr" coords="8,193.78,402.28,11.63,8.97" target="#b6">[7]</ref> for details on the construction of the bilingual dictionary. The English texts of the parallel corpus was stemmed using Porter stemmer, while the Arabic texts was stemmed using the Al-Stem stemmer which is part of the standard resources created for the cross-language track. Each entry in the English-to-Arabic bilingual dictionary consists of one stemmed English word and a list of stemmed Arabic words with the probabilities of translating the English word into the Arabic words. We translated the English topics into Arabic by looking up each English word after stemming using the same English porter stemmer in the English-to-Arabic bilingual dictionary, and keeping the two Arabic words of the highest translation probabilities. That is, the two most likely Arabic translations for each English word. Since only two Arabic translations were retained, the sum of their translation probabilities is at most one. In the case where the sum is less than one, the word translation probabilities were normalized so that the sum of the translation probabilities of the retained two Arabic words is one. The within-query term frequency of an English word is distributed to the retained Arabic words proportionally according their translation probabilities. For the cl3 run, we indexed the Arabic documents using the Al-Stem stemmer. The intermediate run cl3 was produced using the bilingual dictionary-translated topics. The average precision for run cl3 is 0.3072 with overall recall of 4826/5909. The official run BKYCL2 was produced by merging cl1, cl2, and cl3 runs. The estimated probabilities of relevance were summed during merging.</p><p>The official run BKYCL3 was produced again by merging two intermediate runs, cl3 and cl4. The cl3 run was described in the previous paragraph. The intermediate run cl4 was produced using the Ajeeb-translated topics like the cl1 run. The only difference is that the standard light stemmer, Al-Stem, was used in cl4. The average precision for run cl4 is 0.2710 with overall recall of 4350/5909.</p><p>The unofficial run, bkycl4, was produced like the official run BKYCL1 except that the MT-based stemmer was used here. The run bkycl4 was produced by merging cl5 and cl6. The cl5 run used the Ajeeb topic translations, while the cl6 run used the Almisbar topic translations. For both runs, the MT-based stemmer automatically constructed from Ajeeb-translated words was used. The average precision for run cl5 is 0.2733 with overall recall of 4118/5909, and the average precision for run cl6 is 0.2751 with overall recall of 4735/5909.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="8,110.98,689.20,4.97,8.97" target="#tab_6">5</ref> shows the overall precision for the five runs. There are a total of 5,909 relevant documents for all 50 topics. The run BKYCL3 used standard resources only. Like the monolingual run, all cross-language runs were produced with query expansion in which 20 terms were selected from the top-ranked 10 documents after the initial search. cross-language performance is 87.94% of the monolingual performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Conclusions</head><p>In summary, we performed one Arabic monolingual run and three English-Arabic cross-language retrieval runs, all being automatic. We took the approach of translating queries into document language using two machine translation systems. Our best cross-language retrieval run achieved 87.94% of the monolingual retrieval performance. We developed one MT-based Arabic stemmer and one light Arabic stemmer. The Berkeley light stemmer worked better than the automatically created MT-based stemmer. The experimental results show query expansion substantially improved the retrieval performance.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,78.40,66.85,20.30,17.30;2,95.88,77.80,202.20,8.97;2,302.50,66.85,23.19,13.40;2,306.18,77.80,87.68,8.97;2,398.00,66.85,18.22,13.40;2,399.26,77.80,117.88,8.97;2,524.50,70.75,19.89,13.40;2,531.00,70.25,19.89,13.40;2,533.00,75.55,19.89,13.40;2,532.70,70.25,19.89,13.40;2,535.30,66.15,19.89,13.40;2,72.00,90.25,49.25,17.20;2,120.20,95.05,6.66,13.40;2,119.90,89.75,6.66,13.40;2,122.80,85.65,6.66,13.40;2,129.96,97.30,181.28,8.97;2,315.10,86.35,18.22,13.40;2,316.28,93.95,91.09,13.40;2,403.30,86.35,8.27,13.40;2,403.10,92.15,12.77,14.10;2,413.40,86.35,8.27,13.40;2,417.00,94.05,54.35,13.40;2,468.50,89.75,15.55,13.40;2,483.12,97.30,56.81,8.97;2,72.00,111.82,267.24,8.97"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, which is formed by attaching the prefix ¡ and inserting the infix ¡ . The plural form of the noun § © £ ¥ ¢ (book) is ) § £ ¥ ¢ (books), which is formed by deleting the infix ¡ . The plural form of £ £ ¡ ¤ C ¡ (woman) is ¥ © ¦ &amp; (women). The plural form and the singular form are almost completely different.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="4,89.70,211.10,426.82,129.40"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>©P and our children</figDesc><table coords="4,89.70,224.30,425.80,116.20"><row><cell>3 4 5 ¡ 1£ ¥ 2¦ my children ¢¡ ¤£ ¥  §¦ children 0 ¡ 1£ ¥ 2¦ children V ¡ 1£ ¥ 8¦ your children Y ` ¡ ¤£ ¥  §¦ your children £ ` ¡ 1£ ¥ 8¦ your children ¡ £ 7 ¡ ¤£ ¥  §¦ our children</cell><cell>£ H 4 # 7 % £ ¥ ' the children $ @% £ ¥ 2 the child £ H 4 % £ ¥ ' the children ¢¡ ¤£ ¥  §¦ W¨¡ X " by children $ ¡ ¤£ ¥ ¦ ¨¡ X " by his children ¡ ¤ ¡ ¤£ ¥ b¦ W¨¡ X " by her children ¢¡ ¤£ ¥  §¦ ¨0 ¡ X " by the children</cell><cell>¡ Q ¤R 4 % £ ¥ ' ! " by her children £ ¥ 2¦ child B £ ¥ E¦ child £ A ©B £ ¥ E¦ children ¡ a B £ ¥ E¦ her children # $ 6% £ ¥ '¦ child # c % £ ¥ '¦ child</cell><cell>¢¡ S£ ¥  §¦ ¨0 P and the children £ ¥ T " UP and by child £ H 4 % £ ¥ ' T " UP and by children # $ 6% £ ¥ '¦ IP and child £ A ¡ # 7 % £ ¥ '¦ IP and children ¡ £ 7 % £ ¥ '¦ IP and our child ¡ % £ ¥ ¦ IP and her child</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="4,84.48,701.25,455.57,21.10"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>1. If the word is at least five-character long, remove the first three characters if they are one of the following: Most frequent initial character strings.</figDesc><table coords="4,525.20,701.25,14.85,21.10"><row><cell>¢¡ 1 ,</cell></row></table><note coords="5,103.30,507.15,31.56,16.30;5,107.82,514.66,2.51,8.97;5,119.90,507.15,4.21,13.40;5,124.92,514.66,2.51,8.97;5,137.00,507.15,3.31,13.40;5,142.37,511.45,7.84,13.40;5,154.10,507.15,2.40,13.40;5,161.34,514.66,2.51,8.97;5,173.10,507.15,4.21,15.80;5,179.21,514.66,2.51,8.97;5,184.40,503.75,16.10,13.40;5,194.86,514.66,2.51,8.97;5,206.40,507.15,4.21,13.90;5,214.41,514.66,2.51,8.97;5,226.00,503.25,2.51,13.40;5,231.98,514.66,2.51,8.97;5,84.48,539.44,429.55,8.97"><p><p>© 6 § , © ¡ , © e , I ¨1 , © C , ¢¡ ¡ , © 9 , © . 2.</p>If the word is at least four-character long, remove the first two characters if they are one of the following:</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="5,84.48,651.25,455.09,50.70"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Most frequent last character strings.</figDesc><table coords="6,149.34,74.82,313.03,303.81"><row><cell>Rank</cell><cell>Final Frequency</cell><cell>Last two Frequency</cell><cell>Last three Frequency</cell></row><row><cell>1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20</cell><cell>character £ A 69574 91571 4 52418 # 44683 34288 # 33351 ¡ 27346 25748 P 21123 18531 ¢ 14668 13352 12037 £ £ 11265 ¦ 9278 " 8863 £ 6973 ¢ 6777 ¢ 6777 5987</cell><cell>characters ¡ a 26412 £ X 4 24601 £ A T 19089 # 17612 £ A ©P 15724 # $ X 4 13877 C a 13570 ¡ £ X 11794 ¡ 8811 P 8276 ¡ X 4 7702 3 4 £ ¢ 7553 $ # X 7379 4 5187 3 4 5 5090 5027 £ X 4 4869 $ X 4 4611 3 4 # ¢ 4377 X 4 4268</cell><cell>characters ¡ Q # 6544 ¡ D a 6286 £ H 4 # X 4591 £ F H 4 4262 C Q # 3836 £ A ¡ X 4 2960 # ¡ X 4 2747 £ A ¡ # X 2722 3 4 £ ¢ 2534 £ A " X 4 2443 # 2250 £ A ¡ 2056 $ # X 2050 ¡ £ 7 # X 1953 £ X 4 1918 # $ 7 4 £ X 1833 ¡ a 1805 ¡ Q £ 1801 ¡ £ 7 X 4 1775 ¡ ¤ 1759</cell></row></table><note coords="5,499.70,651.25,7.41,13.40;5,84.48,677.80,455.09,8.97;5,96.90,686.35,229.91,15.60"><p><p><p>1 .</p>6.</p>Recursively strips the following one-character suffixes in the order of presentation if the character is at least three-character long before removing a suffix: £ £ , £ , ( , £ .</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="8,72.00,74.80,467.45,127.17"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Monolingual retrieval performances. The number of relevant documents for all 50 topics is 5909. Only the title and description fields were indexed.</figDesc><table coords="8,367.14,74.80,150.55,8.97"><row><cell>without expansion</cell><cell>with expansion</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" coords="8,505.29,713.14,34.22,8.97"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Performances of the CLIR runs.</figDesc><table coords="8,505.29,713.14,34.22,8.97"><row><cell>Our best</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="9">Acknowledgements</head><p>This research was supported by research grant number <rs type="grantNumber">N66001-00-1-8911</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">Mar 2000-Feb 2003</rs>) from the <rs type="funder">Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency</rs> (<rs type="programName">DARPA) Translingual Information Detection Extraction and Summarization (TIDES) program</rs> within the <rs type="funder">DARPA Information Technology Office</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_d9VjkMW">
					<idno type="grant-number">N66001-00-1-8911</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_gt8VK4C">
					<idno type="grant-number">Mar 2000-Feb 2003</idno>
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">DARPA) Translingual Information Detection Extraction and Summarization (TIDES) program</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="9,88.61,448.06,450.86,8.97;9,88.62,460.00,450.84,8.97;9,88.62,472.00,50.87,8.97" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,245.78,448.06,293.69,8.97;9,88.62,460.00,84.45,8.97">Full text retrieval based on probabilistic equations with coefficie nts fitted by logistic regression</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Gey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,284.04,460.00,194.78,8.97">The Second Text REtrieval Conference (TREC-2)</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994-03">March 1994</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="66" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,88.61,491.92,450.87,8.97;9,88.62,503.86,136.63,8.97" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,267.48,491.92,268.09,8.97">A freely available wide coverage morphological analyzer for english</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zaidel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Karp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Schabes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Egedi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,99.35,503.86,95.47,8.97">Proceedings of COLING</title>
		<meeting>COLING</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,88.61,523.78,233.10,8.97" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Darwish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.glue.umd.edu/kareem/research/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,88.61,543.70,417.80,8.97" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,215.48,543.70,143.98,8.97">Elementary modern standard Arabic</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Abboud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983">1983</date>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>et al.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,88.61,563.62,450.82,8.97;9,88.62,575.62,440.92,8.97" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,268.62,563.62,270.80,8.97;9,88.62,575.62,134.08,8.97">Improving Stemming for Arabic Information Retrieval: Light Stemming and Co-occurrence Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Larkey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ballesteros</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Connell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,241.13,575.62,36.06,8.97">SIGIR&apos;02</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Tampere, Finland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">August 11-15, 2002. 2002</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="282" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,88.61,595.54,450.84,8.97;9,88.62,607.48,216.64,8.97" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,242.55,595.54,145.65,8.97">Relevance weighting of search terms</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">Sparck</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,396.45,595.54,142.99,8.97;9,88.62,607.48,78.81,8.97">Journal of the American Society for Information Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="146" />
			<date type="published" when="1976-06">May-June 1976</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,88.61,627.40,450.90,8.97;9,88.62,639.34,411.15,8.97" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,301.11,627.40,157.45,8.97">Trec 2001 cross-lingual retrieval at bbn</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jinxi</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Fraser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Weischedel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,196.35,639.34,144.63,8.97">The Tenth Text Retrieval Conference</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>TREC</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001-05">2001. May 2002</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="68" to="77" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
