<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,190.81,148.79,221.39,15.48;1,90.00,170.71,423.00,15.48">TCD-DCU at LogCLEF 2009: An Analysis of Queries, Actions, and Interface Languages</title>
				<funder ref="#_rdM8taU">
					<orgName type="full">Science Foundation of Ireland</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Centre for Next Generation Localisation</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,117.82,204.99,67.79,8.64"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rami Ghorab</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,219.91,204.99,74.03,8.64"><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Leveling</surname></persName>
							<email>jleveling@computing.dcu.ie</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,328.24,204.99,45.66,8.64"><forename type="first">Dong</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<email>dongzhou1979@hotmail.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,408.19,204.99,70.32,8.64"><forename type="first">Gareth</forename><forename type="middle">J F</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
							<email>gjones@computing.dcu.ie</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,270.23,218.94,55.87,8.64"><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Wade</surname></persName>
							<email>vincent.wade@cs.tcd.ie</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Centre for Next Generation Localisation Knowledge and Data Engineering Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Trinity College</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dublin, Dublin</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<address>
									<country key="IE">Ireland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Centre for Next Generation Localisation</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Dublin</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">City University Dublin</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IE">Ireland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,190.81,148.79,221.39,15.48;1,90.00,170.71,423.00,15.48">TCD-DCU at LogCLEF 2009: An Analysis of Queries, Actions, and Interface Languages</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">3705D9D0C6A7BF74F92D33CD265E1F3A</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:21+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.3.1 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: Content Analysis and Indexing-Indexing methods</term>
					<term>Linguistic processing</term>
					<term>H.3.3 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: Information Search and Retrieval-Query formulation</term>
					<term>Search process Experimentation, Measurement Cross-Language Information Retrieval, Log File Analysis, Query Reformulation, Action Patterns</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the collaborative participation of Trinity College Dublin and Dublin City University in the Log Analysis for Digital Societies (LADS) task of LogCLEF 2009 track. An analysis of multilingual search logs was carried out with the objectives of investigating how users from different linguistic or cultural backgrounds behave in search, and how the discovery of patterns in user actions could be used for community identification. Our findings suggest that there is scope for further investigation of how search logs can be exploited to personalise and improve cross-language search as well as improve the TEL search system.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The Log Analysis for Digital Societies (LADS) task is part of the LogCLEF track at the Cross-Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2009). The task is based on query logs from The European Library 1 (TEL), which is a portal forming a single interface for searching across the content of many European national libraries. In contrast to most other tasks at CLEF, LADS does not follow the standard procedure to measure the performance of a retrieval system, rather it aims at analysing multilingual search behaviour.</p><p>This participation is undertaken as part of ongoing research activities within the: Centre for Next Generation Localisation (CNGL) <ref type="foot" coords="2,206.33,158.23,3.69,6.39" target="#foot_1">2</ref> . The CNGL is investigating novel technologies that address the key localisation challenges of volume, access and personalisation. The Digital Content Management (DCM) track is a subdivision of the CNGL project and is, in part, directed towards advancements in the personalisation of Cross-language Information Retrieval.</p><p>The LogCLEF dataset contains log entries for different types of user interactions (hereafter: actions) with the TEL portal, collected between January 2007 and June 2008. A more detailed description of the task and the dataset can be found in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,234.43,231.89,11.62,8.64" target="#b1">[2]</ref> and at the LogCLEF web page <ref type="foot" coords="2,370.56,229.96,3.69,6.39" target="#foot_2">3</ref> .</p><p>We analysed the logs to investigate the following hypotheses:</p><p>• Users from different linguistic or cultural backgrounds behave differently in search.</p><p>• There are patterns in user actions which could be useful for stereotypical grouping of users.</p><p>• User queries reflect the mental model or prior knowledge of a user about a search system.</p><p>We believe that the findings of such investigations can be exploited to personalise and improve crosslanguage search. The remainder of this paper is organised as follows: Section 2 gives a brief description of the logs and the preprocessing operations performed on them, Section 3 discusses the log analysis along with the obtained results, and the paper ends with conclusions and outlook to future work in Section 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Brief Description of Logs and Preprocessing Operations</head><p>A log entry is created in correspondence with every user action. The log entry contains the type of action performed, together with attributes such as the interface language, query, and timestamp. The experiments focused on the following attributes: lang (interface language selected by the user), action, and query. The main actions that the study focused on were:</p><p>• search sim: simple text box search.</p><p>• search adv: advanced search by the specific fields of title, creator (i.e. author, composer, etc), subject, type (e.g. text, image, etc), language, ISBN, or ISSN.</p><p>• view brief: clicking on a certain library's collection to view its brief list of results.</p><p>• view full: clicking on a title link in the list of brief records to expand it.</p><p>• col set theme: specifying a certain collection to search within.</p><p>• col set theme country: specifying multiple collections for searching or browsing.</p><p>A first analysis of the provided sample log data revealed that the data set had to be preprocessed to solve problems including character encodings, syntactically malformed queries (missing quotation marks, additional parentheses), and actions and attribute values that were not described in the guidelines.</p><p>The following were deleted from the dataset: entries having unrecorded session ids (empty or null value), search attempts having empty queries, sessions with missing actions, and sessions having unrecorded or malformed language acronyms. The original number of records was 1,866,330 records, which was reduced to 1,632,044 after the cleaning process (approximately 12.6% of the records were deleted). Furthermore, inconsistencies in the format of the stored queries were dealt with, such as trimming unnecessary brackets, quotations, and white spaces. Moreover, query keywords were extracted and stored separately in an additional table for performing term-based statistics.</p><p>A major part of data preprocessing was the reconstruction of user sessions. The log entries contain anonymised user IDs and abbreviated IP addresses of the computers used to access the TEL system as well as session IDs. In addition, there is a timestamp attached to each logged action. As the IP address is not sufficient to distinguish between single users and the user ID may be associated with a guest account, session reconstruction was solely based on the session IDs. The session ID was used to reconstruct the actions in single sessions and the timestamp was then used to sort the actions. Session duration was calculated as the time interval between the timestamp of the first action and the timestamp of last action in the session. To identify the first action in a session, a login action was added before the first logged action.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Analysis of Log File Entries</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">General Statistics</head><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="3,113.78,272.59,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_0">1</ref> and Table <ref type="table" coords="3,160.72,272.59,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_1">2</ref> present descriptive statistics of the logs. Only a small proportion of the actions were performed by signed-in users (0.76%) compared to the number of actions recorded for guest users (99.34%). This may indicate that users find it easier, and /or perhaps more secure, not to register and sign into a web search system. Such behaviour sets a challenge to fine-grained personalisation (individual user profiling). The logs exhibited outliers, such as the existence of sessions with either a very large number of actions or just a single action (max: 1,093; min: 1), sessions with extremely long or short duration (max: 116 days; min: 1 second), and sessions with a large number of queries (max: 179; min: 1).</p><p>User actions were classified into four broad categories: Search (query actions), Browse (browsing / navigating result pages of TEL web site, excluding following links leading to the browsing of external web sites), Collection (actions involving limiting the search scope by the selection of a collection, theme or subject), and Other (all other actions).</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="3,130.20,649.40,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_2">3</ref> shows the distribution of actions along the broad classification. It was observed that search actions formed nearly half of the browsing actions. Further experimentation will look into the effect of query adaptation on the ratio between the number of search and browsing actions.</p><p>A large number of user actions (11%) were performed before attempting the search, including the specification of certain collections or subjects for search. This indicates the diversity of user preferences, where users seek to customise the search environment according to their needs. User profiling may help to save user effort by automatically adjusting the search environment where the user or group can be identified.</p><p>The study focused on the six actions mentioned in the previous section, as they had a high frequency, which indicates typical behaviour for library search. In regards to searching, it was found that there was a great inclination towards using the simple search feature of the TEL portal (16.14% of total actions) compared to using the advanced search feature (4.35% of total actions). Further investigation is required to determine the degree of success of using the simple search feature compared to the advanced search feature in terms of satisfying the search with a fewer number of queries. Another inclination in user actions was found for the pre-selection of a single collection for search, which occurred considerably more frequently than the pre-selection of multiple collections (col set theme was 7.13% of total actions and col set theme country was 2.72%). This suggests that users who seek to limit their search tend to be very specific in selecting a designated collection. This may arise from their previous experience with the search portal, where users found that certain collections have a higher degree of satisfying their information needs. This finding may suggest further research towards performing a re-ranking operation for the list of collections depending on collection selection history in the logs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Query Reformulation</head><p>Query reformulations, within each session, were classified into term addition, term deletion, term modification, and term change. Term modifications are term changes for queries containing a single search term. Query reformulation can also be classified by the type of the term(s) it affects or the type of transformation between two terms (e.g. translation). For this analysis, no differentiation was made between queries submitted under different interface languages of the portal, because i) the major part of the queries were submitted under English, and so, the data for other interface languages might not be sufficient, and ii) some query changes were manually observed as changing a query to another language (translation).</p><p>There are several types of reformulation of successive user queries: focusing on search terms and disregarding Boolean operators, a term can be added, deleted, or modified. For advanced search, in addition, a field can be added, deleted, or changed (of course, some of the latter actions co-occur with modifying search terms). As some users switch from the simple to the advanced search interface of the TEL portal, related queries are difficult to identify if different types of queries are considered. For the following experiment, search terms were extracted from all queries in the logs in order to identify how users typically modified a query. Only successive searches on the same topic were considered. To identify queries that were about the same search topic, the following approach was used: consecutive queries must have at least one search term in common (if the query contains more than one search term) or the search term in the queries must have a Levenstein distance <ref type="bibr" coords="4,251.36,582.05,11.62,8.64" target="#b2">[3]</ref> less than three. A query parser was implemented to extract the search terms from the query log and identify the type of query modification and the most frequent changes.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="4,130.71,605.96,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_3">4</ref> shows the reformulation classes based on the top-50 reformulations. It was observed that 16% of term additions, 24% of term deletions, and 28% of term changes were stopwords or changes to stopwords (e.g. prepositions). Such changes might make sense under the assumption that people sometimes do copy and paste to directly insert a number of search terms in a search box, and so they might have just pasted some unwanted stopwords into the TEL search box by mistake. However, if the underlying indexing/retrieval system of TEL ignores stopwords, then adding or changing them will have no effect on search results, and would be considered a waste of effort for TEL users.</p><p>It was observed that proper nouns and single characters (mostly denoting initials of names) made up 62% of term additions, 46% of deletions, 20% of modifications, and 10% of changes. In contrast, term modification mostly affect morphological variations (e.g. plural forms, derivation, etc) and translations (26% and 24%, respectively). Such modifications would not have any effect on the search results if the TEL system performs stemming. It was also observed that special characters (e.g. wildcards, which are used for more complex query operations) were rarely used. Moreover, a small number of changes involved the use of related terms (including narrower terms or broader terms). Also, only a small number of changes involved changing Boolean operators (e.g. "AND" → "OR"), dates ("2005" → "2006"), or numerals ("i" → "1").</p><p>Furthermore, it was observed that 20% of term changes involved changing the language code. It seemed that users had an inclination of specifying the language (interface language of the whole portal and/or the language field of the advanced search page) in combination with the specification of a collection to search within. Such behaviour may indicate that users were not generally aware of the purpose of the features concerning the change of the language. For example, concerning the language field in advanced search, it might be the case that they interpreted it as a means of automatically translating query terms into a different language instead of a means of filtering out books which were not written in the specified language.</p><p>The analysis of query reformulations supports our hypothesis that some users have little knowledge of the search system, as they include stopwords and even change them (assuming TEL ignores stopwords as is commonly done by search engines). It can be inferred that the query edit behaviour of such users is focused more on domain, rather than on IR. This group will correspond to novice users. On the other hand, a small group of users used advanced query operators such as wildcards in their queries, which corresponds to experienced users.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Interface Languages</head><p>In an attempt to investigate the relation between language and search behavior, several variables were studied across the interface language selected by users of the portal. Recorded actions were distributed among 30 languages. Hereafter, the study focuses on the top five languages in terms of the number of actions. The top language was English (86.47% of the actions), followed by French (3.44%), Polish (2.17%), German (1.48%), and Italian (1.39%). It is worth mentioning here that the selection of an interface language does not necessarily imply the language of the query that the user inputs. One possible cause for the bias towards English, aside from its inherent popularity, is that it is the default language in the portal. Possible ways to avoid this bias would be to force the user to specify a language before attempting the search, or to have the default language automatically specified according to client machine's IP address.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="5,129.62,679.71,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_4">5</ref> states the average and median for the number of actions and queries per session. Users of the English language exhibited the lowest average in both measures. This may suggest that users who used the TEL portal in languages other than English had to submit more queries to satisfy their information needs.</p><p>Among the rest of the languages, the Slovenian language stood out as an exceptional case where the average number of actions per session was 27.43 (median: 13) and the average number of queries per session was 6.82 (median: 3). Further investigation is required to determine the cause of this observation. The frequency distribution of the six main actions across each of the five interface languages is shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,114.50,266.71,3.74,8.64" target="#tab_5">6</ref>. It was found that for Italian, the ratio between the number of simple search actions and advanced search actions was 2.34, while the ratio for the other four languages was 3.51 on average. A probable cause for this may be that a greater number of queries submitted under the Italian language were not satisfied through simple search, and users had to reformulate their queries through advanced search. Further investigation is needed to validate this assumption.</p><p>It was also found that users of the Polish language seem to have a higher rate than others in using the feature of specifying a single collection before attempting the search. On the other hand, English was found to have the lowest rate of usage of this feature. This finding supports our hypothesis that users from different linguistic or cultural backgrounds behave differently in search. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Term Frequencies and Categories</head><p>As part of the analysis, the number of terms per query and the top queried terms, for both, simple search and advanced search were studied. Table <ref type="table" coords="6,256.50,551.14,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_6">7</ref> shows the number of terms per query, starting at queries made up of one term and up to queries made up of six or more terms. The percentage of queries made up of three terms or less was 83.12% in simple search and 69.42% in advanced search. For both types of search, the frequency of query length was inversely proportional to the number of terms per query, with only one exceptional value for advanced search at three terms per query. This trend of users entering fewer search terms increases the ambiguity of the query, and thus sets challenges for query disambiguation.</p><p>In advanced search, the percentages of queries made up of three or more terms surpass those of simple search. This may suggest that users are encouraged to enter more search terms by the availability of multiple input fields. However, it is important to point out here that throughout the experiments, Boolean connectors were not removed from queries. This might be another reason behind the difference in percentages as the advanced search feature automatically adds connectors between search fields; thus it would naturally incur more connectors than simple search. Nevertheless, part of the analysis revealed that users still used connectors in simple search, although they have no effect (treated as normal terms).</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="6,129.44,706.56,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_7">8</ref> shows the average and median of the number of terms per query across interface languages. It can be seen that German showed the lowest average in both types of search (simple search: 1.77; advanced search: 2.6). Moreover, part of the analysis revealed that German exhibited the largest distribution of queries made up of just one term, while English exhibited the smallest. This may be because the German language allows noun compounds written as single words, which can express complex topics as a single word. Such differences between languages forms an important point of focus for our ongoing research. We compared the average number of terms per query of simple search with the results reported in <ref type="bibr" coords="7,498.90,425.06,10.58,8.64" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, which was a similar study applied on search logs from AlltheWeb.com<ref type="foot" coords="7,378.30,435.09,3.69,6.39" target="#foot_3">4</ref> (a European web search engine that allows limiting the search to documents in a language of choice). With the exception of English, the averages for the languages were found to be approximately the same for both, TEL and AlltheWeb.com logs, in spite of the fact that the former is a library search system and the latter is a general search engine.</p><p>Part of the log analysis, involved the extraction of the top twenty occurring search terms for each interface language, excluding stopwords. A term was only counted once in a session, even if it appeared multiple times in the session. This was done to avoid bias towards terms that were repeatedly searched for in the same session. Furthermore, terms were divided into five categories: creator (author, composer, artist, etc), location (cities, countries, etc), subject (as per Dewey Decimal Classification ), title (including proper nouns and common nouns), and type (document types, such as: text, image, sound, etc). These categories were mostly based on the fields of the advanced search in TEL portal, except for the location category.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,134.37,568.52,4.98,8.64" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows the average category distribution of the five languages combined. In simple search, most of the search terms came under the creator and title categories (30% and 28% respectively). The same was exhibited for advanced search, though with a greater inclination towards the creator category (45%). This may indicate that user searches were better satisfied by including document creator in the query.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,134.70,616.34,4.98,8.64" target="#fig_1">2</ref> shows category distribution of the top twenty search terms for each of the five languages in simple search and advanced search. A large difference was observed in user search behaviour between different languages. For example, in English, 40% of the terms were subjects and 10% were creators, while in German, rather contrasting values were observed where 45% of the terms were creators, and only 10% of the terms were subjects. Such findings reflect the differences between users of different languages and will contribute towards further research in multilingual query adaptation, perhaps suggesting a different adaptation strategy for each language or group of languages.   Figure <ref type="figure" coords="8,133.75,440.05,4.98,8.64" target="#fig_4">4</ref> shows the frequency of two subsequent actions taken by the users. The most frequent action sequences consist of searching and viewing results, searching and changing options, and switching between results views (e.g. view brief-view full).  Table <ref type="table" coords="9,129.49,370.65,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_8">9</ref> and Table <ref type="table" coords="9,178.75,370.65,9.96,8.64" target="#tab_9">10</ref> show patterns of two and three subsequent actions. Each table points out the top most occurring pattern, as well as some other interesting patterns that have a rather high frequency. Related patterns are grouped together in the tables. It is observed that more users, after performing a search action, seem to go directly to view a full record (click for expansion) rather than clicking on a collection first (view brief) then clicking to view full. The reason for this may be that the collection they wanted was already highlighted (TEL automatically highlights the top most collection in alphabetical order). This may indicate that more people prefer to specify collections before they perform the search so as to directly jump to view full without having to click on a collection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Action Sequences and Durations</head><p>It can also be observed that users seem to get confused between two features (available as combo boxes) that both appear on the main page of the TEL web site. The two features are: col set theme (choose a single collection) and col set theme country (browse collections/choose multiple collections, which redirects the user to another page). This was observed as user actions subsequently alternated between the two features. Based on the pattern frequencies and the findings presented in subsection 3.1 it can be inferred that users prefer the feature of choosing a single collection (col set theme). Perhaps deeper analysis of such patterns may introduce certain changes to the TEL portal's GUI. This paper has described an analysis of the multilingual search logs from TEL. The results of the analysis support our hypotheses that: (1) users from different linguistic or cultural backgrounds behave differently in search; (2) the identification of patterns in user actions could be useful for stereotypical grouping of users; and (3) user queries reflect the mental model or prior knowledge of a user about a search system. The results suggest that there is scope for further investigation of how search logs can be exploited to personalise and improve cross-language search. One suggestion concerning the logs would be to include the results that the users viewed. Such logs would be more informative and thus would contribute to a more thorough analysis.</p><p>Furthermore, the results also suggest that there is scope for improving the TEL system in a number of ways: (1) integrating a query adaptation process into TEL, where queries can be automatically adapted in order to retrieve more relevant results (term expansion, deletion, or modification); (2) offering focused online help if a user spends an uncharacteristically long time between some actions while using the TEL system or if a user performs a sequence of actions that may logically be inconsistent or opposite to each other; (3) highlighting elements in the TEL GUI as a default action or a typical next action; and (4) identifying the type of user for the sake of search personalisation.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="8,218.22,219.08,166.55,8.64;8,188.96,108.86,222.60,91.80"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Distribution of term categories.</figDesc><graphic coords="8,188.96,108.86,222.60,91.80" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="8,183.36,341.50,236.27,8.64;8,132.86,239.68,334.80,83.40"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Distribution of term categories across languages.</figDesc><graphic coords="8,132.86,239.68,334.80,83.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="8,90.00,392.23,423.00,8.64;8,90.00,404.18,423.00,8.64;8,90.00,416.14,423.00,8.64;8,90.00,428.09,220.33,8.64;8,104.94,440.05,408.06,8.64;8,90.00,452.00,423.00,8.64;8,90.00,463.96,161.96,8.64"><head>Figure 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3 shows the average time between actions. Most of the time is spent before changing search options (e.g. col set desc, col set subj, etc.), which is illustrated by the bright areas in the diagram. The dark areas correspond to actions taken almost immediately after another (e.g. search sim as the first action after login), or to two actions which never follow each other.Figure4shows the frequency of two subsequent actions taken by the users. The most frequent action sequences consist of searching and viewing results, searching and changing options, and switching between results views (e.g. view brief-view full).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="8,209.82,712.06,183.36,8.64"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Analysis of time to next user action.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="9,196.27,338.61,210.47,8.64"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Analysis of most frequent next user action.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,159.43,339.32,284.14,103.47"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Descriptive Statistics.</figDesc><table coords="3,159.43,357.42,18.26,8.64"><row><cell>Item</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,159.43,480.92,284.14,65.58"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Central Tendencies.</figDesc><table coords="3,159.43,497.00,284.14,49.51"><row><cell>Item</cell><cell cols="2">Average Median</cell></row><row><cell>Actions per session</cell><cell>8.39</cell><cell>4</cell></row><row><cell>Queries per session</cell><cell>2.81</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>Session duration (mm:ss)</cell><cell>17:20</cell><cell>01:35</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="4,159.43,119.13,284.14,77.54"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Broad classification of actions.</figDesc><table coords="4,159.43,135.21,284.14,61.46"><row><cell>Classification</cell><cell>Percentage</cell></row><row><cell>Search</cell><cell>28.17</cell></row><row><cell>Browse</cell><cell>56.78</cell></row><row><cell>Collection</cell><cell>11.34</cell></row><row><cell>Other</cell><cell>3.70</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,95.98,119.13,411.05,187.15"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Top-50 changes to terms in subsequent related queries.</figDesc><table coords="5,95.98,137.23,411.05,169.06"><row><cell cols="2">type brief description</cell><cell>example</cell><cell cols="4">add del mod chg</cell></row><row><cell>ST</cell><cell>use of stopwords</cell><cell>"a" → "the"</cell><cell cols="2">8 12</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>14</cell></row><row><cell>BL</cell><cell>use of Boolean operators</cell><cell>"AND" → "OR"</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>6</cell></row><row><cell>CC</cell><cell>change of lowercase or uppercase</cell><cell>"europe" → "Europe"</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>SC</cell><cell>spelling change</cell><cell>"wolrd" [!] → "world"</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>CH</cell><cell>use of special characters</cell><cell>"*" at the end of term</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>LC</cell><cell>language code change</cell><cell>"ita" → "eng"</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>10</cell></row><row><cell>RT</cell><cell>related terms</cell><cell>"triangulum" → "quadratum"</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">MO morphologic variant</cell><cell>"city" → "cities"</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>13</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>TR</cell><cell>translation or transliteration</cell><cell>"power" → "kraft"</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>PN</cell><cell>change proper noun/name</cell><cell>"mozart" → "amadeus"</cell><cell cols="2">21 13</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>4</cell></row><row><cell>PI</cell><cell>single character (initials)</cell><cell>"elzbieta" → "e"</cell><cell cols="2">10 10</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>DT</cell><cell>date/number change</cell><cell>"1915" → "1914"</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>3</cell></row><row><cell>OT</cell><cell>unknown change/other</cell><cell>"test" → "toto"</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>3</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="6,159.43,119.13,284.15,108.27"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Actions and queries per session across interface languages.</figDesc><table coords="6,159.43,137.23,284.15,90.17"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Actions per session Queries per session</cell></row><row><cell>Language</cell><cell cols="4">Average Median Average Median</cell></row><row><cell>English</cell><cell>7.97</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>2.7</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>French</cell><cell>9.2</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>3.01</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>Polish</cell><cell>8.63</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>3.14</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>German</cell><cell>9.37</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>3.03</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>Italian</cell><cell>11.3</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>3.73</cell><cell>2</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="6,95.98,393.22,411.04,91.51"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Actions distribution across languages.</figDesc><table coords="6,95.98,411.31,411.04,73.42"><row><cell cols="7">Language search sim search adv view brief view full col set theme col set theme country</cell></row><row><cell>English</cell><cell>16.48%</cell><cell>4.32%</cell><cell>25.79%</cell><cell>30.65%</cell><cell>6.79%</cell><cell>2.66%</cell></row><row><cell>French</cell><cell>14.27%</cell><cell>4.46%</cell><cell>27.34%</cell><cell>23.55%</cell><cell>10.86%</cell><cell>3.12%</cell></row><row><cell>Polish</cell><cell>15.18%</cell><cell>4.23%</cell><cell>26.99%</cell><cell>21.95%</cell><cell>13.58%</cell><cell>3.39%</cell></row><row><cell>German</cell><cell>14.75%</cell><cell>4.31%</cell><cell>28.96%</cell><cell>23.53%</cell><cell>9.46%</cell><cell>2.93%</cell></row><row><cell>Italian</cell><cell>14.44%</cell><cell>6.16%</cell><cell>24.81%</cell><cell>28.39%</cell><cell>9.35%</cell><cell>2.78%</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" coords="7,159.43,119.13,284.14,120.22"><head>Table 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Number of terms per query.</figDesc><table coords="7,159.43,137.23,284.14,102.13"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Simple Search</cell><cell cols="2">Advanced Search</cell></row><row><cell>Terms</cell><cell cols="4">Frequency Percentage Frequency Percentage</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell>108,049</cell><cell>41.03%</cell><cell>20,038</cell><cell>28.23%</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>76,993</cell><cell>29.24%</cell><cell>13,867</cell><cell>19.54%</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell>33,855</cell><cell>12.86%</cell><cell>15,364</cell><cell>21.65%</cell></row><row><cell>4</cell><cell>17,893</cell><cell>6.79%</cell><cell>7,595</cell><cell>10.70%</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell>10,267</cell><cell>3.90%</cell><cell>6,086</cell><cell>8.58%</cell></row><row><cell>6+</cell><cell>16,295</cell><cell>6.19%</cell><cell>8,020</cell><cell>11.30%</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" coords="7,159.43,265.53,284.14,108.27"><head>Table 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Number of terms per query across interface languages.</figDesc><table coords="7,159.43,283.63,284.14,90.17"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Simple Search</cell><cell cols="2">Advanced Search</cell></row><row><cell>Language</cell><cell cols="4">Average Median Average Median</cell></row><row><cell>English</cell><cell>2.38</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3.05</cell><cell>3</cell></row><row><cell>French</cell><cell>2.09</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2.85</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>Polish</cell><cell>1.89</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2.59</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>German</cell><cell>1.77</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2.6</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>Italian</cell><cell>2.09</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3.17</cell><cell>2</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8" coords="9,159.43,568.89,284.15,125.43"><head>Table 9 :</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Sequential action patterns for two subsequent actions.</figDesc><table coords="9,159.43,586.99,284.15,107.33"><row><cell>Action 1</cell><cell>Action 2</cell><cell>Frequency</cell></row><row><cell>view full</cell><cell>view full</cell><cell>153,952</cell></row><row><cell>search sim</cell><cell>view full</cell><cell>112,562</cell></row><row><cell>search sim</cell><cell>view brief</cell><cell>86,625</cell></row><row><cell>search adv</cell><cell>view full</cell><cell>32,356</cell></row><row><cell>search adv</cell><cell>view brief</cell><cell>28,732</cell></row><row><cell>col set theme</cell><cell>search sim</cell><cell>40,044</cell></row><row><cell>col set theme country</cell><cell>search sim</cell><cell>12,397</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9" coords="10,90.00,119.13,417.02,162.26"><head>Table 10 :</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Sequential action patterns for three subsequent actions.</figDesc><table coords="10,90.00,137.23,417.02,144.16"><row><cell>Action 1</cell><cell>Action 2</cell><cell>Action 3</cell><cell>Frequency</cell></row><row><cell>view full</cell><cell>view full</cell><cell>view full</cell><cell>79,346</cell></row><row><cell>col set theme</cell><cell>search sim</cell><cell>view full</cell><cell>18,562</cell></row><row><cell>col set theme</cell><cell>search sim</cell><cell>view brief</cell><cell>16,446</cell></row><row><cell>col set theme country</cell><cell>search sim</cell><cell>view brief</cell><cell>2,530</cell></row><row><cell>col set theme country</cell><cell>search sim</cell><cell>view full</cell><cell>8,458</cell></row><row><cell>col set theme</cell><cell>col set theme country</cell><cell>col set theme</cell><cell>4,735</cell></row><row><cell>col set theme country</cell><cell>col set theme</cell><cell>search sim</cell><cell>3,159</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">4 Summary and Outlook</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,104.35,747.58,143.97,6.64"><p>http://www.theeuropeanlibrary.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,104.35,737.77,80.45,6.64"><p>http://www.cngl.ie/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="2,104.35,747.58,152.93,6.64"><p>http://www.uni-hildesheim.de/logclef</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_3" coords="7,104.35,707.78,105.85,6.64"><p>http://www.alltheweb.com/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This research is supported by the <rs type="funder">Science Foundation of Ireland</rs> (grant <rs type="grantNumber">07/CE/I1142</rs>) as part of the <rs type="funder">Centre for Next Generation Localisation</rs> (www.cngl.ie) at <rs type="institution">Trinity College Dublin</rs> and <rs type="institution">Dublin City University</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_rdM8taU">
					<idno type="grant-number">07/CE/I1142</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="10,106.60,576.59,406.40,8.64;10,106.60,588.37,276.61,8.82" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,269.94,576.59,243.06,8.64;10,106.60,588.55,19.14,8.64">An analysis of web searching by European AlltheWeb.com users</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bernard</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Jansen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><surname>Spink</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="10,133.15,588.37,156.02,8.59">Information Processing &amp; Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="361" to="381" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,106.60,608.47,406.40,8.64;10,106.60,620.25,281.61,8.82" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,264.53,608.47,127.85,8.64">Overview of the LogCLEF track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Mandl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Giorgio</forename><surname>Di</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nunzio</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,252.97,620.25,106.14,8.59">CLEF 2009 Working Notes</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Francesca</forename><surname>Borri</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Nardi</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carol</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,106.60,640.17,406.40,8.82;10,106.60,652.31,86.61,8.64" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,261.99,640.35,216.06,8.64">An extension of the string-to-string correction problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Roy</forename><surname>Lowrance</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="10,485.75,640.17,21.80,8.59">JACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="183" />
			<date type="published" when="1975">1975</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
