<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,57.64,93.18,480.55,15.63">The University College London at TREC 2008 Enterprise Track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,265.82,140.57,63.94,10.42"><forename type="first">Jianhan</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
							<email>j.zhu@adastral.ucl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University College London</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Adastral Park Campus</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>IP5 3RE</postCode>
									<settlement>Ipswich</settlement>
									<country key="GB">U.K</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,57.64,93.18,480.55,15.63">The University College London at TREC 2008 Enterprise Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">7FA9957C1315617BB7466588C3AD4AD9</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:04+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The University College London Information Retrieval Group participated in both the Expert Search and Document Search tasks in the TREC2008 Enterprise Track. We used a generic two-stage approach, which consists of a document retrieval stage followed by an expert association discovery stage, for expert finding. Since document search is an integral part of our expert finding approach, we have studied the relationship between document search and expert search. Due to the existence of rich features that can potentially contribute to expert finding, our expert finding approach integrates these features including anchor texts, indegree, and multiple levels of associations between experts and query terms. Our experimental results show that the introduction of features has helped improve the expert finding performance.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.28" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.28" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.28" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.28" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">I TRODUCTIO</head><p>Same as in TREC2007 Enterprise Track, the domain for TREC2008 Enterprise Track is the website of the CSIRO (Australian Commonwealth Scientific and Research Organization). The topics were developed in order to reflect the requests of information received by the CSIRO Enquiries staffers. The aim of the two tasks is to find a number of key pages and experts on a topic that can help the staffers to answer each request. For example, find key experts and key pages to answer the request for information on "cane toad".</p><p>Based on our approach that integrates multiple features in a two-stage expert finding model <ref type="bibr" coords="1,249.29,568.85,11.46,9.58" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, we have continued investigating the effects of these features as follows in expert finding.</p><p>Anchor texts: anchor texts of a document often highlight its key topic. Sometimes, keywords for identifying a document's topic may even be missing in the document itself but exist in its anchor texts, e.g. the BMW homepage does not mention "car", but anchor texts pointing to the page often do. We have studied the effect of anchor texts in both expert and document search.</p><p>Indegree: Typically, the number of inlinks of a document is an indicator of the document's author-ity. Previous work shows that there is a strong correlation between the number of inlinks and PageRank <ref type="bibr" coords="1,315.37,228.32,11.46,9.58" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, and PageRank and indegree help document search on the Web <ref type="bibr" coords="1,402.62,240.92,11.46,9.58" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. We will study the effect of indegree in both document and expert search.</p><p>Multiple levels of associations: We have continued using our multiple window based cooccurrence model <ref type="bibr" coords="1,397.22,293.95,11.46,9.58" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. The assumption is that there are multiple levels of associations between an expert and query terms in documents. We give higher weights to co-occurrences in smaller windows and lower weights to co-occurrences in larger windows. We have studied different window selections and combinations.</p><p>In <ref type="bibr" coords="1,349.09,384.54,11.46,9.58" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, we studied the relationship between ad hoc retrieval and expert finding via three parameters, namely, a background smoothing parameter in a language model, and anchor texts and indegree. Our experiments on the TREC 2007 Enterprise Track CSIRO dataset have shown that improvement in document retrieval does not necessarily lead to improvement in expert finding.</p><p>Firstly, smoothing language model by a background collection model can significantly improve ad hoc retrieval performance, but does not help or even hurt expert finding. Accordingly, we give background smoothing different weights for expert and document search, respectively.</p><p>Secondly, anchor text does not help document retrieval, and hurts document retrieval when weighted high in document retrieval, and indegree only slight helps ad hoc retrieval. Therefore, anchor texts and indegree have different effect in intranet search than in Web search <ref type="bibr" coords="1,431.30,628.85,11.46,9.58" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p><p>The reason might be that, in document retrieval, documents are largely judged as relevant or not regardless of their authoritativeness, and anchor text and indegree may introduce more noise than useful information in document retrieval.</p><p>However, both anchor text and indegree help expert finding. Since people appearing in authorita-tive documents are more likely to be experts than those appearing in ordinary documents, anchor text and indegree, which bias towards authoritative documents, can help expert finding. Therefore, we used anchor text and indegree for expert search, but not for document search.</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows. We present our two-stage approach for expert fining in Section 2, report experimental results in Section 3, and conclude in Section 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">TWO-STAGE EXPERT FI DI G</head><p>Given a set of documents d, a query topic q, and a set of candidates c, the aim of expert finding is to estimate p(c|q) for ranking the candidates. Since p(c|q) = p(c,q)/p(q) and p(q) does not affect ranking, the task is to estimate p(c,q).</p><p>We adopt a document-centric generative approach, and represent the joint as a weighted average of the document models as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,68.79,346.03,207.91,20.17">( , ) ( , | ) ( ) ( | , ) ( | ) ( ) d d p c q p c q d p d p c q d p q d p d = = ∑ ∑<label>(1)</label></formula><p>The document prior p(d) is estimated by the indegree of d, and p(d) ∝ f indegree <ref type="bibr" coords="2,191.91,384.48,11.37,9.77">(d)</ref>, where f indegree (d) is the transformation function for indegree.</p><p>We use Craswell et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,169.36,412.26,12.22,9.58" target="#b1">[2]</ref>'s sigm transformation function for estimating f indegree (d):</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,112.71,439.76,167.12,24.64">g ( ) ( ) ( ) a inde ree a a indegree d f d w k indegree d ∝ +<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where w, a and k are parameters, and indegree(d) is the indegree of d. We use the same parameters that were used in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,111.16,496.37,11.46,9.58" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, and set the values of w, a and k as 3.7, 0.2, and 5 respectively. p(q|d) is estimated by inferring a document language model θ d for each document d as</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,128.19,550.90,100.26,13.03">( , ) ( ) ( ) n t q d d t q p q p t θ θ ∈ = ∏</formula><p>(3) where t is a query term and n(t,q) is the number of times it is used in q. We smooth the document language model with the background model, and take into account anchor texts by using a mixture of document content and anchor text to represent each document, therefore </p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,60.39,653.65,201.75,9.65">( | ) (1 )( ( | ) ( | )) ( ) d c</formula><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="2,356.17,187.28,190.52,12.11">d q c c p c p c q d p c θ θ µ µ = - +<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where p(c) is the probability of candidate c. We estimate p(c) as</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="2,383.04,248.92,163.64,32.33">' ' 1 ( , ') ( ) ( ', ') d c c C f c d p c df f c d ∈ = ∑ ∑<label>(7)</label></formula><p>where f(c,d') is the frequency of candidate c in document d' and df c is the document frequency of c. We use a Dirichlet prior for the smoothing parameter µ c ' ( ', ')</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="2,395.41,341.09,147.08,32.41">c c f c d κ µ κ = + ∑ (<label>8</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_7" coords="2,542.49,344.35,4.19,9.58">)</formula><p>where κ is the average term frequency of all candidates in the corpus. We use a multiple window based approach in estimating p(c|d,q). We assume that small windows often lead to more probable associations, and large windows result in nosier associations, and weight smaller windows higher than larger ones.</p><p>Given a list W consisting of windows {w} of different sizes, we estimate p(c|d,q) as</p><formula xml:id="formula_8" coords="2,380.16,499.73,166.52,20.07">( | , ) ( ) ( | , , ) w p c d q p w p c d q w = ∑<label>(9)</label></formula><p>where p(w) is the probability for each of the window-based co-occurrence models. Given a number of text windows of size w where c co-occurs with q as {w i }, we estimate p(c|q,d,w) as follows ' <ref type="figure" coords="2,452.65,593.40,9.74,8.23">( ,</ref><ref type="figure" coords="2,468.96,593.40,2.30,8.23">,</ref><ref type="figure" coords="2,477.12,593.40,2.30,8.23">,</ref><ref type="figure" coords="2,489.00,593.40,3.06,8.23;2,379.69,599.40,20.29,8.23">)  ( | ,</ref><ref type="figure" coords="2,405.84,599.40,2.30,8.23">,</ref><ref type="figure" coords="2,415.44,599.40,3.06,8.23;2,456.96,606.60,12.14,8.23">)  ( ',</ref><ref type="figure" coords="2,475.68,606.60,2.30,8.23">,</ref><ref type="figure" coords="2,483.84,606.60,2.30,8.23">,</ref><ref type="figure" coords=""></ref> )</p><formula xml:id="formula_9" coords="2,374.76,593.24,171.92,29.50">i i w i c f c d q w p c d q w f c d q w = ∑ ∑<label>(10)</label></formula><p>where f(c,d,q,w i ) is the frequency of c in a text window, and ' ( ', , , ) i c f c d q w ∑ is the total frequency of candidates in the window.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">EXPERIME TAL RESULTS</head><p>There is not a given list of candidates. By utilizing the pattern that most of the CSIRO staff's email addresses follow the pattern "firstname.lastname@csiro.au", we have extracted a list of candidates. By considering that one person may have several emails and aliases, we developed a method for aligning different emails and name variants. Document search and expert search are two important tasks in an enterprise environment. Based on our previous findings on the TREC2007 CSIRO collection, we adapt our approach to document and expert search, respectively.</p><p>Firstly, based on the finding that background smoothing is very helpful to document search but may harm expert finding when the background smoothing is too much, we used the Dirichlet smoothing language model where the smoothing parameter μ is given a small value, such as 100, for expert search.</p><p>Secondly, based on the finding that anchor texts and indegree are more helpful to expert search than document search, we did not incorporate anchor texts and indegree in document search, but instead integrated them in our expert finding approach.</p><p>Based on the above decisions, we submitted four document search runs, and four expert search runs, and the results are summarized in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,226.85,404.58,5.35,9.58" target="#tab_1">1</ref> and<ref type="table" coords="3,253.13,404.58,4.04,9.58" target="#tab_2">2</ref>.</p><p>Descriptions of the four submitted document search runs are as follows.</p><p>Ucl01: Title only automatic run, we used Dirichlet smoothing language model where the smoothing parameter μ is set as 2000.</p><p>Ucl02: Title only automatic run, we used Dirichlet smoothing language model where the smoothing parameter μ is set as 3000.</p><p>Ucl03: Title only automatic run, we used Dirichlet smoothing language model where the smoothing parameter μ is set as 2500.</p><p>Ucl04: Title only automatic run, we used the BM25 model where the parameters K 1 is 1.4, b is 0.6, and K 3 is 8.</p><p>We varied the Dirichlet smoothing parameter, and compared the Dirichlet smoothing model with the BM25 model for document search. We can see from Table <ref type="table" coords="3,104.08,650.80,5.35,9.58" target="#tab_1">1</ref> that the Dirichlet smoothing where the parameter is set as 2000 leads to the best performance on both infAP and infNDCG metrics. The BM25 model performed slightly worse than the Dirichlet smoothing language model Firstly, we have compared the effect of different window sizes, and the run UCLex01 with window size 450 outperforms the run UCLex02 with window size 600 in terms of the MAP, MRR, and P@5. This shows that smaller windows lead to more accurate associations, and larger windows may introduce more noise. However, the run UCLex02 has achieved higher num_rel_ret and P@100 than the run UCLex01, showing that larger windows can discover more expert associations with the queries.</p><p>Secondly, we have compared multiple windows with single windows, and different window combinations. Our two multiple window based runs both outperformed the two single window based runs, showing that weighting expert associations based on windows sizes can help improve expert finding performance. A finer-grained multiple window approach, i.e., UCLex04, achieved the highest performance on a number of metrics including MAP, R-Prec, Bpref, P@5, and P@10. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">CO CLUSIO S</head><p>We have participated in both document and expert search tasks of TREC 2008 Enterprise Track. We have continued using a two-stage expert finding approach which integrates features including anchor texts, indegree, and multiple levels of associations. Our submitted runs to TREC2008 have shown the effectiveness of multiple windows and effect of window selections. Document search is an integral part of our expert finding approach. Based on our previous findings that background smoothing is helpful to document search but may hurt expert finding, and anchor texts and indegree are both helpful to expert finding but less helpful to document search, we adapted our approach to expert and document search, respectively.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,315.38,91.41,227.78,198.81"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Document Search Results (The best results for each measure is in bold)</figDesc><table coords="3,315.38,116.84,227.78,173.38"><row><cell>Runs</cell><cell>Ucl01</cell><cell>Ucl02 Ucl03 Ucl04</cell></row><row><cell>infAP</cell><cell cols="2">0.3246 0.3158 0.3205 0.3031</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">inf DCG 0.5175 0.5141 0.5172 0.4965</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Descriptions of the four submitted expert search</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">runs are as follows.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">UCLex01: Window size 450, anchor text, and</cell></row><row><cell>indegree</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">UCLex02: Window size 600, anchor text, and</cell></row><row><cell>indegree.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">UCLex03: Multiple windows 40, 400, and 800,</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">anchor text, and indegree.</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">UCLex04: Multiple windows 40, 200, 400, and</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">800, anchor text, and indegree.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="3,302.90,552.77,240.97,134.27"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Expert Search Results (The best results for each measure is in bold)</figDesc><table coords="3,302.90,578.20,240.97,108.84"><row><cell>Runs</cell><cell cols="4">UCLex01 UCLex02 UCLex03 UCLex04</cell></row><row><cell>MAP</cell><cell>0.3360</cell><cell>0.3346</cell><cell>0.3433</cell><cell>0.3476</cell></row><row><cell>MRR</cell><cell>0.6789</cell><cell>0.6737</cell><cell>0.6748</cell><cell>0.6759</cell></row><row><cell>um_rel_ret</cell><cell>335</cell><cell>342</cell><cell>347</cell><cell>346</cell></row><row><cell>R-prec</cell><cell>0.3332</cell><cell>0.3340</cell><cell>0.3330</cell><cell>0.3378</cell></row><row><cell>Bpref</cell><cell>0.3740</cell><cell>0.3782</cell><cell>0.3781</cell><cell>0.3816</cell></row><row><cell>P@5</cell><cell>0.4400</cell><cell>0.4327</cell><cell>0.4364</cell><cell>0.4473</cell></row><row><cell>P@10</cell><cell>0.3164</cell><cell>0.3164</cell><cell>0.3145</cell><cell>0.3164</cell></row><row><cell>P@100</cell><cell>0.0609</cell><cell>0.0622</cell><cell>0.0631</cell><cell>0.0629</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,70.11,286.02,210.21,8.65;4,70.00,297.42,210.21,8.65;4,70.00,308.82,210.39,8.65;4,70.00,320.34,98.40,8.65" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,70.00,297.42,210.21,8.65">Predicting Fame and Fortune: PageRank or Indegree?</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Upstill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Craswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hawking</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,83.19,308.82,197.19,8.65;4,70.00,320.34,74.00,8.65">Proc. of the Australasian Document Computing Symposium ADCS</title>
		<meeting>of the Australasian Document Computing Symposium ADCS</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003. 2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,70.11,331.74,210.32,8.65;4,70.00,343.26,210.44,8.65;4,69.99,354.66,210.45,8.65;4,70.00,366.06,14.67,8.65" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,137.67,343.26,142.77,8.65;4,69.99,354.66,67.08,8.65">Relevance weighting for query independent evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Craswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zaragoza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,156.28,354.66,82.25,8.65">Proc. of SIGIR 2005</title>
		<meeting>of SIGIR 2005</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="416" to="423" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,70.11,377.58,210.14,8.65;4,69.99,388.98,210.44,8.65;4,69.99,400.37,210.44,8.65;4,69.99,411.89,210.37,8.65;4,69.99,423.29,22.71,8.65" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,128.91,377.58,151.34,8.65;4,69.99,388.98,210.44,8.65;4,69.99,400.37,30.26,8.65">A study of the relationship between ad hoc retrieval and expert finding in enterprise environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,118.00,400.37,162.44,8.65;4,69.99,411.89,130.97,8.65">Proc. of the CIKM workshop on Web Information and Data Management</title>
		<meeting>of the CIKM workshop on Web Information and Data Management</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>WIDM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008. 2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="30" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,70.11,434.81,212.64,8.65;4,69.99,446.21,210.46,8.65;4,69.99,457.61,210.44,8.65;4,69.99,469.13,189.03,8.65" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,110.31,446.21,170.14,8.65;4,69.99,457.61,125.25,8.65">The Open University at TREC 2006 Enterprise Track Expert Search Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rüger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Eisenstadt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Motta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,214.84,457.61,65.60,8.65;4,69.99,469.13,130.54,8.65">Proc. of the Fifteenth Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>of the Fifteenth Text REtrieval Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>TREC</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2007. 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
