<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,223.38,148.88,159.80,15.48">RSLIS/AAU at CHiC 2013</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,152.22,188.05,46.44,11.09"><forename type="first">Mette</forename><surname>Skov</surname></persName>
							<email>skov@hum.aau.dk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Communication and Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Aalborg University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Nyhavnsgade 14</addrLine>
									<postCode>9000</postCode>
									<settlement>Aalborg</settlement>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,206.65,188.05,54.19,11.09"><forename type="first">Toine</forename><surname>Bogers</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Royal School of Library and Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Birketinget 6</addrLine>
									<postCode>2300</postCode>
									<settlement>Copenhagen</settlement>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,268.71,188.05,54.83,11.09"><forename type="first">Haakon</forename><surname>Lund</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Royal School of Library and Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Birketinget 6</addrLine>
									<postCode>2300</postCode>
									<settlement>Copenhagen</settlement>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,331.47,188.05,43.68,11.09"><forename type="first">Maj</forename><surname>Lauge</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,377.59,188.05,51.35,11.09"><forename type="first">Ward</forename><surname>Jensen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Royal School of Library and Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Birketinget 6</addrLine>
									<postCode>2300</postCode>
									<settlement>Copenhagen</settlement>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,437.18,188.05,17.17,11.09;1,240.96,199.57,32.25,11.09"><forename type="first">Erik</forename><surname>Wistrup</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Royal School of Library and Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Birketinget 6</addrLine>
									<postCode>2300</postCode>
									<settlement>Copenhagen</settlement>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,295.84,199.57,55.34,11.09"><forename type="first">Birger</forename><surname>Larsen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Royal School of Library and Information Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Copenhagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Birketinget 6</addrLine>
									<postCode>2300</postCode>
									<settlement>Copenhagen</settlement>
									<country key="DK">Denmark</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,223.38,148.88,159.80,15.48">RSLIS/AAU at CHiC 2013</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">EC3DE5C50199C2ACC04F25D43EFDDC09</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:33+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Interactive IR</term>
					<term>Europeana</term>
					<term>cultural heritage</term>
					<term>digital humanities</term>
					<term>information retrieval</term>
					<term>evaluation</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper, we describe our participation in the interactive and adhoc tracks of CHiC 2013.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="11" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="12" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In this paper, we describe our participation in interactive and ad-hoc tracks of the Cultural Heritage at CLEF lab organized at CLEF 2013. The structure of this paper is as follows. We start in Section 2 by describing our participation in the CHiC Interactive track. Our participation in the CHiC Ad-hoc track is described in Section 3. We provide general conclusions to our results in Section 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">CHiC Interactive track</head><p>This section describes a combined qualitative and quantitative study aiming at providing insight into users' non-intentional interaction with digital cultural heritage resources -in this case records form the European Digital Library (EDL). The following research questions guided this part of the study: RQ1: What motivate participants' interaction with the EDL? RQ2: How did participants react to the open and non-intentional work task situation? RQ3: What grabbed the attention of participants in the browsing-based interface?</p><p>The first research question is motivated by numerous calls (e.g., <ref type="bibr" coords="1,415.48,645.61,55.22,11.09;1,124.74,657.13,60.05,11.09" target="#b5">Ingwersen &amp; Järvelin, 2005)</ref> stressing the importance of including context dimensions in interactive information retrieval (IIR) together with a continued interest in understanding the motivation of museum audiences both online (e.g., <ref type="bibr" coords="1,332.46,680.11,133.99,11.09" target="#b4">Fantoni, Stein &amp; Bowman (2012)</ref>: <ref type="bibr" coords="2,124.74,147.67,115.32,11.09">Goldman &amp; Schaller, 2008)</ref> and in the physical museum (e.g., <ref type="bibr" coords="2,389.22,147.67,81.39,11.09;2,124.74,159.13,63.74,11.09" target="#b2">Ellenbogen, Falk &amp; Goldman, 2008)</ref>. Here focus is on exploring user study participants' motivation at two different levels. Firstly, we look at participants' motivation for visiting EDL compared to motivations for visiting museums in general. Secondly, we study what motivates participants' interaction with the EDL at session level.</p><p>The second research question concerns methodological aspects of using simulated work task situations. The concept of simulated work task situations is a component in a framework for IIR systems evaluation (e.g., <ref type="bibr" coords="2,316.86,239.65,60.32,11.09" target="#b0">Borlund, 2000)</ref>. Since then simulated work task situations have been applied in numerous IIR studies (see review in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,124.74,262.63,121.48,11.09" target="#b1">Borlund &amp; Schneider, 2010)</ref>. However, only a limited number of studies have addressed task structure (exceptions include <ref type="bibr" coords="2,311.39,274.15,76.42,11.09" target="#b6">Toms et al. (2007)</ref>). Accordingly it is relevant to study how participants react to the non-intentional and open work task situation used in the present study. Finally, we investigate what parts of the browsingbased interface that grabbed the attention of participants, and how they switched between interface components. This is motivated by the fact that little is known about user behaviour in relation to this type of interfaces.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Methodology</head><p>Data from the online questionnaire was used to answer the two research questions in this section. We used data from a total of 200 respondents: 160 online respondents and 40 in-lab respondents (10 from Sheffield and 30 from Denmark). It should be noted that the questionnaire answered by online and in-lab participants was identical. We focused on the part of the questionnaire on participants' engagement, experience, and motivation. Three follow-up questions were asked to 10 in-lab participants <ref type="bibr" coords="2,124.74,456.61,301.56,11.09">(participant numbers 531, 551, 554, 558, 560, 565, 577, 578, 582, and 583)</ref> in order to further explore their motivations and search experience:</p><p>1. What motivated your interaction with the EDL? 2. Why did you add the chosen items to the Bookbag? 3. How realistic did you find this exploratory task? (Very realistic, partly realistic, not at all realistic) The three follow-up questions expanded on the online survey responses and thus provided additional qualitative data.</p><p>The questionnaire data was analysed using mainly descriptive statistics. In addition chi-squared tests were used to calculate the statistical association between variables of experience and engagement (significance level α is set to 0.05). It was a hypothesis to find an association between a high level of experience with European culture and heritage and a high level of engagement. For example if a user is very interested in reading and examining things about European culture and heritage or frequently visits museums or galleries, then the user is expected to be very interested in the exploration task and to be absorbed in exploring etc.</p><p>The following variables were tested:</p><p>- Hypothesis testing did not include the experience variable on how often EDL is searched since the majority of test participants (81 %) has never used the EDL. Further, engagement related to aesthetics variables and perceived usefulness variables was considered out of scope in relation to the research questions. Before chi-squared tests were calculated answer choices (agree -disagree) related to the engagement variables were reduced from 5 to 3 categories to avoid too small subgroups.</p><p>Finally, a qualitative categorization of free text answers to the question "can you elaborate on why you looked for these particular objects?" was mapped to 7 categories of motivation. Participants were asked to answer this question for each of the objects added to the Bookbag. A total of 291 answers were identified. If a participant had specifically explained his motivations for looking at, for example, 3 objects then this answer was split into 3 parts. Out of the total 291 answers 222 answers were qualitatively analysed. The remaining 69 answers were omitted because they did not relate to user motivation or gave too little information ("no", "out of interest", "I did not use the function", "I liked them" etc.). A literature review by <ref type="bibr" coords="3,124.74,423.79,119.21,11.09">Goldman and Schaller (2004)</ref> served as starting point for developing the categories of motivation in the present study. They characterize the most common motivations from museum web site visits as:</p><p>1. Gathering information for an upcoming visit to the physical museum 2. Engaging in very casual browsing 3. Self-motivated research for specific content information 4. Assigned research (for job or study) for specific content information Lately, a fifth motive has been added by <ref type="bibr" coords="3,288.42,515.77,139.41,11.09" target="#b4">Fantoni, Stein and Bowman (2012)</ref>: 5. Make a transaction on the web site</p><p>The 5 categories of motivations were not directly applicable to the present study. Firstly, based on the free text answers to why objects were added to the Bookbag it was not possible to distinguish between casual browsing and research for specific content information (motivation number 2 and 3 above). Secondly, the fifth motivation category is not relevant to this study. Instead the above categories served as a starting point and were expanded based on a bottom-up approach (see the 7 categories in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,209.06,619.27,3.62,11.09" target="#tab_2">2</ref>). In this way we aim to answer a call by <ref type="bibr" coords="3,399.24,619.27,71.31,11.09;3,124.74,630.79,25.01,11.09" target="#b2">Ellenbogen et al. (2008)</ref>. They suggest that motivations of visitors to museum web sites differ significantly from the motivations of visitors to physical museums. Therefore they call for further studies to elaborate our understanding of online visitors' motivation.  No statistical significant associations were found between participants' frequency of visits to museums and their agreement with the 18 engagement variables.</p><p>Finally, answers to one of the three follow-up questions (How realistic did you find this exploratory search task?) also provided insight into how participants' experience with the non-intentional task. The follow-up questions were asked to 10 in-lab participants. 5 participants found the task highly realistic, 1 participant found it partial realistic, and 4 participants found the non-intentional task unrealistic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.2">Analysis</head><p>Understanding user motivation is a key variable in understanding their experiences and interaction online <ref type="bibr" coords="7,215.73,330.49,83.51,11.09" target="#b4">(Fantoni et al., 2012)</ref>. The results from the questionnaire about participants' motivation for visiting the EDL (see Table <ref type="table" coords="7,368.62,341.95,4.18,11.09" target="#tab_1">1</ref>) show that user study participants rarely use the EDL to follow up on or prepare for an in-person visit to a museum. Likewise, only one single user statement (out of 222) on motivations concerns visit to a physical museum or art gallery (see the Bowie-fan example in Table <ref type="table" coords="7,150.68,387.97,3.62,11.09" target="#tab_2">2</ref>). This contrasts with previous research (e.g., <ref type="bibr" coords="7,342.98,387.97,82.81,11.09" target="#b4">Fantoni et al., 2012)</ref> where trip planning is the primary motivation for visiting a site. A possible explanation to this is that the EDL portal covers collections across multiple cultural heritage institutions and is thus not closely linked to in-person visits.</p><p>The categorization of participants' motivations based on a bottom-up approach resulted in an elaborated categorization. Table <ref type="table" coords="7,317.73,445.45,5.01,11.09" target="#tab_2">2</ref> shows that 'Personal interest' is by far the most frequently identified motive. Motives related to 'My…family/university/city/country' and 'Places that I have visited/are going to visit' can be seen as sub-categories to personal interest. However, earlier research <ref type="bibr" coords="7,124.74,491.47,166.23,11.09" target="#b2">(Ellenbogen, Falk &amp; Goldman, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="7,297.62,491.47,50.32,11.09" target="#b3">Falk, 2009)</ref> stresses the importance of uncovering identity-related motivations for visiting museums and other cultural heritage organizations. As such the sub-categories provide an additional level of information and can to some extent be mapped to identity-related motivations. For example, user statements representing an aesthetic or visual experience can reflect a recharger (using <ref type="bibr" coords="7,205.82,548.95,59.69,11.09" target="#b3">Falk's (2009)</ref> terminology) motivated by the yearning to emotionally and intellectually recharge in a beautiful and refreshing environment. Likewise, an explorer's (again using <ref type="bibr" coords="7,276.42,572.65,54.74,11.09" target="#b3">Falk's (2009)</ref> terminology) interaction is driven by a need to satisfy personal curiosity and interest in a challenging environment. For example illustrated by the example "Hunting for old objects is interesting" in Table <ref type="table" coords="7,463.24,595.69,3.74,11.09" target="#tab_2">2</ref>. The research design of the present study does not fully support identifying identityrelated motivations and it could be interesting to further explore in future research.</p><p>The second part of the study addresses how participants reacted to the open and non-intentional work task situation given. Firstly, we look at the positive reactions:</p><p>5 out of 10 in-lab participants answered that the task was highly realistic. This is supported by participants' high level of agreement with variables on "The content of the website incited my curiosity" and "I felt interested in my exploration task" (see Figure <ref type="figure" coords="8,154.02,147.67,3.61,11.09">1</ref>). Further, it is inspiring to see the huge variety in patterns and directions of user interaction.</p><p>Secondly, looking at the challenges the high level of disagreement with 3 variables related to focused attention (see section 2.3.1) indicates that participants are not fully absorbed in the non-intentional task. 4 of 10 in-lab participants found the task unrealistic. They explained that they lacked a search motivation and direction. A quote from a questionnaire response reflect this view: "I would have to be wanting to look and research a subject to want to use this website. It got boring within about 30 seconds due to no desire to research anything at the time".</p><p>Future research design could include asking the users whether (s)he finds the nonintentional task realistic. In this way we can analyse whether this variable significantly influence the search experience. Further, given the high percentage of non-Europeana users (81 %) in the present experiment, it would be very interesting to study if the search experience differs depending on whether real users or test persons are included.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.3">Investigation of participant attention</head><p>We present the results as an analysis of sequence charts, average number of fixations over AOIs as well as a tiled view AOI analysis.</p><p>The sequence charts such as the sample one shown below in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="8,421.17,387.61,5.01,11.09">2</ref> shows the order in which users inspect individual Areas of Interest (AOIs). We defined six AOIs according to the logical division of the CHIC user interface. Overall the sequence charts show a common pattern between users and how they navigate the CHIC interface. The first AOI accessed is the assignment given to the participant followed closely by an inspection of the result AOI and the category browser. The item detail AOI, book bag AOI and search box AOI tended to be visited more frequently later in the sessions when participants have chosen an item for closer inspection, or in the case of the search box, trying to locate items by searching after the have tried using the category browser.</p><p>The sequence charts also show how participants jump between the AOIs or revisit them over the session. The result AOI is the one showing the highest number of visits (and revisits) and also the AOI were most time is spent followed by the item detail AOI and category browser AOI. Users also return to the assignment AOI at various intervals during the test. Table <ref type="table" coords="8,255.50,548.59,5.01,11.09" target="#tab_3">3</ref> shows the average number of fixations for the 10 participants distributed over AOIs. We see that by far the most time is spent on results followed by item detail.  This section describes our participation in both the monolingual and multilingual tasks of the CHiC ad-hoc retrieval track.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Methodology</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Monolingual retrieval</head><p>In all our monolingual retrieval experiments, we used the language modeling approach with Jelinek-Mercer (JM) smoothing as implemented in the Indri 5.1 toolkit. We set λ to 0.4 and did not perform stemming or stopword filtering. For each topic we retrieved up to 1000 documents. We indexed each language collection separately and ran the topic translations for each language against these 13 indexes in turn.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Multilingual retrieval</head><p>For our participation in the multilingual task, we explored two different approaches.</p><p>In the first approach we ran topics in each language against all 13 indexes at the same time. For example, first we ran the English topics against all 13 indexes combined.</p><p>Then we ran the French topics against all 13 indexes combined, and so on, until we had 13 different runs, one for each topic language. The rationale behind running monolingual topics against a multilingual index is that Europeana content is divided over the 13 different indexes by country of origin, not by the actual language used in the metadata descriptions. By running the topic set in a particular language against all 13 indexes at the same time instead of just one, it is possible that more relevant documents from the other language indexes will be retrieved. Each of these 13 runs were performed using Jelinek-Mercer smoothing with λ set to 0.4, no stemming, and no stopword filtering, similar to the monolingual runs.</p><p>For our second approach we investigated the benefits of fusing multiple retrieval runs into a single run. We specifically focus on collection fusion, where the results of one or more algorithms on different document collections are integrated into a single results list <ref type="bibr" coords="10,169.19,507.43,92.51,11.09">(Voorhees et al., 1995)</ref>. In our case, we fuse the 13 different monolingual runs together. As different retrieval runs can generate wildly different ranges of similarity values, so we apply normalization to each retrieval result to map the score into the range [0, 1]. We normalize the original retrieval scores using the maximum and minimum retrieval scores and according to the formula proposed by Lee (1997):</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>=</head><p>.</p><p>(1)</p><p>Over the past two decades, many different fusion methods for retrieval runs have been proposed. In our experiments, we restrict ourselves to two of the most effective unweighted combination methods proposed by <ref type="bibr" coords="10,316.98,642.55,79.88,11.09">Fox &amp; Shaw (1994)</ref>: CombSUM and CombMNZ. The CombSUM method fuses runs by taking the sum of similarity values for each document separately; the CombMNZ method does the same, but boosts this sum by the number of runs that actually retrieved the document. Because of a limit on the number of runs that could be submitted, we fused together the English, French and German runs from the first approach to multilingual retrieval using both CombSUM and CombMNZ.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Results &amp; Analysis</head><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="11,150.66,226.63,5.01,11.09" target="#tab_4">4</ref> below shows the results for the 13 different monolingual runs. The language for which we obtained the best performance was German with a MAP score of 0.0613. Other performances with relatively good performance are Dutch, Norwegian, and French. Furthermore, the results also show that most of the languages with smaller groups of native speakers, such as Finnish, Greek, Hungarian and Slovenian-with the exception of Norwegien-fare less well with MAP scores between 0.0030 and 0.0079. This could be due to smaller numbers of available relevant documents in Europeana for these languages. Overall, there does seem to be room for improvement: a MAP score of 0.0613 is not likely to translate into satisfactory search engine performance for real-world users of Europeana. The results of our multilingual runs show improvements compared to the monolingual runs. Our three multilingual runs for English, French, and German, where we ran these three topic sets against the complete multilingual index achieved MAP scores of 0.0370, 0.403, and 0.679 respectively. These increases in performance ranging from 11.1% to 48.5% appear to confirm our hypothesis that collections in different languages also contain many documents in other languages.</p><p>Our two fusion runs with the CombSUM and CombMNZ methods show an additional increase in performance at 0.0836 and 0.0837 respectively. This shows that combining different retrieval runs indeed results in better performance. It is likely that combining runs for all 13 different languages would have resulted in additional performance increases.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="6,426.72,445.63,44.20,11.09;6,428.82,457.15,42.14,11.09;6,429.12,468.67,41.82,11.09;6,433.14,480.13,37.82,11.09;6,427.62,491.65,43.39,11.09;6,427.38,503.17,43.58,11.09;6,432.54,514.63,38.40,11.09;6,426.78,526.15,44.19,11.09;6,428.28,583.99,27.87,11.09;6,427.14,595.63,41.56,11.09;6,428.04,641.83,42.91,11.09;6,426.54,653.29,44.44,11.09;7,142.74,147.26,325.57,11.74;7,160.74,159.31,28.36,11.09;7,142.74,170.42,279.00,11.74"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>out things around me when I was exploring this website (p-value = 0.054).-The content of the website incited my curiosity (p-value = 0.125)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="9,124.80,595.46,34.62,9.96;9,124.80,605.78,36.51,9.96;9,136.14,622.27,26.17,11.09;9,124.80,633.73,35.59,11.09;9,124.80,645.25,35.02,11.09"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3. fixation, a Figure indicates attention</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,124.74,665.29,345.94,11.09"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>They especially point to the importance of identity-related motivations, which has F</figDesc><table coords="4,124.80,147.73,346.21,381.13"><row><cell cols="5">proven to o strongly infl luence the lea arning and beh haviour of ph hysical museum um visitors</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">(Ellenbog gen et al, 2008 8, p. 193).</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">To ans swer research</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">question 3 w we tracked the</cell><cell>gaze behavio our and mouse e clicks of</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">a subset o of 10 of the pa articipants fro om Denmark u using a binocu ular RED-M re emote eye</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">tracker fr rom SensoMo otoric Instrum ments (SMI) se et at a sampli ing rate of 12 20Hz. The</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">eye track ker allows for</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">a head move ement of appro oximately 32</cell><cell>by 21 cm at</cell><cell>a distance</cell></row><row><cell>from the</cell><cell cols="4">monitor of 6 60 cm. Accord ding to the pr roducer the a ccuracy is 0.5 5 degrees.</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">The stud dy was execut ted at the Ro oyal School o of Library and d Information n Science,</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Universit ty of Copenh agen in a qu uiet setting. T The test leader rs were prese ent during</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">tests. We e analysed the</cell><cell>eye tracking</cell><cell>results by de efining a numb ber of Areas o of Interest</cell></row><row><cell>(AOIs)</cell><cell cols="4">following th he logical d division of t the CHIC e experimental</cell><cell>interface.</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Furtherm more we did a</cell><cell cols="3">qualitative in nspection of th he gaze pattern ns as well as</cell><cell>extraction</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">of data de escribing key</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">metrics as tim me on AOIs an nd number of</cell><cell>fixations on A AOIs.</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">2.3 Resu ults</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="4">2.3.1 M Motivation and d reaction to</cell><cell>open-ended w work tasks</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">As descri ibed earlier th he first researc ch question on n user motiva tion was stud died at two</cell></row><row><cell>different</cell><cell cols="4">levels. Firstly y, we look at t motivation a at a general le evel. Table 1</cell><cell>compares</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">frequency y of visits to</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">the EDL to f frequency of</cell><cell>visits to mus eums and art t galleries.</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Table 1 s shows that the e majority (81 1 %) of the re spondents has s never visited d the EDL</cell></row><row><cell>and 15.5</cell><cell cols="4">% of the resp pondents visit t EDL less fre equently than</cell><cell>a few times p per month.</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">In contra st only a singl le respondent</cell><cell>(0.5 %) has n never visited a a museum or a art gallery</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">and 81 % % visit museum ms less frequ uently than few w times per m month. Further er, Table 1</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">compares s the main rea ason for visitin ng the EDL a and museums</cell><cell>in general res spectively.</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Table 1 s shows that pe ersonal intere est and enjoym ment is the m main reason fo or visiting</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">museums s and art galle eries (69.1 %) ), whereas par rticipants' mo tivation for v visiting the</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">EDL is m more sided wit th personal int terest, research h for study an nd for work as s top-3.</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Frequency of vi isit to and moti ivation for visit ting the EDL an nd museums an nd galleries</cell></row><row><cell>(n = 200)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,124.80,147.73,346.24,541.73"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>C objects an</figDesc><table coords="5,124.80,563.41,40.83,126.05"><row><cell>The seco</cell></row><row><cell>work task</cell></row><row><cell>agreemen</cell></row><row><cell>statement</cell></row><row><cell>novelty. I</cell></row><row><cell>are all re</cell></row><row><cell>around m</cell></row><row><cell>in this ex</cell></row><row><cell>continued</cell></row><row><cell>my curio</cell></row><row><cell>experienc</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="8,124.74,588.98,345.94,99.30"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>The average number of fixations distributed over AOIs for the 10 eyetracked participants.</figDesc><table coords="8,219.06,615.68,168.62,72.60"><row><cell></cell><cell>Fixations (avg.)</cell></row><row><cell>book bag</cell><cell>55,8</cell></row><row><cell>item details</cell><cell>443,3</cell></row><row><cell>results</cell><cell>1320,8</cell></row><row><cell>search box</cell><cell>45,2</cell></row><row><cell>category browser</cell><cell>150,5</cell></row><row><cell>assignment</cell><cell>37,4</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="11,124.74,353.54,302.23,169.08"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Results of the monolingual runs for the 13 different Europeana languages.</figDesc><table coords="11,216.42,377.54,135.26,145.08"><row><cell>Language</cell><cell>MAP</cell></row><row><cell>ENG (English)</cell><cell>0.0249</cell></row><row><cell>FIN (Finnish)</cell><cell>0.0030</cell></row><row><cell>FRE (French)</cell><cell>0.0301</cell></row><row><cell>GER (German)</cell><cell>0.0613</cell></row><row><cell>GRE (Greek)</cell><cell>0.0063</cell></row><row><cell>HUN (Hungarian)</cell><cell>0.0070</cell></row><row><cell>ITA (Italian)</cell><cell>0.0293</cell></row><row><cell>NLD (Dutch)</cell><cell>0.0422</cell></row><row><cell>NOR (Norwegian)</cell><cell>0.0369</cell></row><row><cell>POL (Polish)</cell><cell>0.0156</cell></row><row><cell>SLV (Slovenian)</cell><cell>0.0079</cell></row><row><cell>SPA (Spanish)</cell><cell>0.0221</cell></row><row><cell>SWE (Swedish)</cell><cell>0.0133</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="4">Conclusions</head><p>We described the <rs type="institution">Royal School of Library and Information Science and Aalborg University</rs> participation in the CLEF 2013 CHIC interactive and ad hoc tracks.</p></div>
			</div>			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="12,124.74,252.14,345.89,9.96;12,136.08,262.46,210.99,9.96" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="12,202.52,252.14,268.11,9.96;12,136.08,262.46,59.16,9.96">Experimental components for the evaluation of interactive information retrieval systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Borlund</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="12,201.36,262.46,92.08,9.96">Journal of Documentation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="90" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="12,124.74,272.84,345.91,9.96;12,136.08,283.16,334.56,9.96;12,136.08,293.54,334.54,9.96;12,136.08,303.86,131.25,9.96" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="12,272.07,272.84,198.58,9.96;12,136.08,283.16,171.94,9.96">Reconsideration of the simulated work task situation: evaluation of information retrieval interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Borlund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="12,448.00,283.16,22.63,9.96;12,136.08,293.54,267.76,9.96">IiX&apos;10 Proceeding of the Third Symposium on Information Interaction in Context</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Belkin</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New Brunswick, NJ, USA; New York; AC</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="164" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="12,124.74,314.24,345.88,9.96;12,136.08,324.56,334.53,9.96;12,136.08,334.94,256.31,9.96" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="12,313.90,314.24,156.72,9.96;12,136.08,324.56,33.94,9.96">Understanding the motivations of museum audiences</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ellenbogen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Falk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Goldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="12,314.34,324.56,156.27,9.96;12,136.08,334.94,100.76,9.96">Museum informatics: people, information, and technology in museums</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Marty</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Routledge</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="187" to="194" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="12,124.74,345.26,345.81,9.96;12,136.08,355.64,18.98,9.96" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Falk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="12,186.04,345.26,161.59,9.96">Identity and the museum visitor experience</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Walnut Creek, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Left Coast Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="12,124.74,365.96,345.93,9.96;12,136.08,376.34,334.47,9.96;12,136.08,386.66,309.07,9.96" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="12,311.13,365.96,159.54,9.96;12,136.08,376.34,203.47,9.96">Exploring the relationship between visitor motivation and engagement in online museum audiences</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Fantoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Bowman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="12,136.08,386.66,79.84,9.96">Museums and the web</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Trant</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bearman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Toronto</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Archives &amp; Museum Informatics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012. 2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="12,124.74,397.04,345.84,9.96;12,136.08,407.36,208.10,9.96" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="12,260.78,397.04,209.80,9.96;12,136.08,407.36,34.43,9.96">The turn: Integration of information seeking and retrieval in context</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ingwersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Järvelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Dordrecht, The Netherlands</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="12,124.74,417.74,345.86,9.96;12,136.08,428.06,334.52,9.96;12,136.08,438.44,334.54,9.96;12,136.08,448.76,334.60,9.96;12,136.08,459.14,166.48,9.96" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="12,178.48,428.06,194.31,9.96">Task effects on interactive search: The query factor</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Toms</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>O'brien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mackenzie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Freund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Toze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Dawe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Macnutt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="12,268.75,438.44,201.87,9.96;12,136.08,448.76,241.91,9.96">Proceedings of the 6th International Workshop of the Initiative for the Evaluation of XML Retrieval (INEX)</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Fuhr</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lalmas</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Trotman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the 6th International Workshop of the Initiative for the Evaluation of XML Retrieval (INEX)<address><addrLine>Dagstuhl, Germany; Berlin/Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="359" to="372" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
