<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,134.77,115.96,345.83,12.62;1,222.76,133.89,169.84,12.62;1,178.37,151.82,258.62,12.62">Classification of ICD10 Codes with no Resources but Reproducible Code. IMS Unipd at CLEF eHealth Task 1</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,253.17,189.49,74.99,8.74"><forename type="first">Giorgio</forename><forename type="middle">Maria</forename><surname>Di</surname></persName>
							<email>giorgiomaria.dinunzio@unipd.it</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Information Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Padua</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,134.77,115.96,345.83,12.62;1,222.76,133.89,169.84,12.62;1,178.37,151.82,258.62,12.62">Classification of ICD10 Codes with no Resources but Reproducible Code. IMS Unipd at CLEF eHealth Task 1</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">6B910721880EB2DB3349DD8A5C49EAE8</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:52+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper, we describe the second participation of the Information Management Systems (IMS) group at CLEF eHealth 2018 Task 1. In this task, participants are required to extract causes of death from multilingual death reports (French, Hungarian and Italian) and label them with the correct International Classification Diseases (ICD10) code. We tackled this task by focusing on the reproducible code, that we published last year, which produces a clean dataset that can be used to implement more sophisticated approaches.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In this paper, we report the experimental results of the second participation of the IMS group to the CLEF eHealth Lab <ref type="bibr" coords="1,316.75,399.74,9.96,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, in particular to Task 1: "Multilingual Information Extraction -ICD10 coding" <ref type="bibr" coords="1,333.66,411.69,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. This task consists in automatically labelling death certificates written in different languages (French, Hungarian, and Italian) with International Classification Diseases (ICD10) codes.</p><p>The main goal of our participation to the task this year was to test the effectiveness of the reproducible code made available by <ref type="bibr" coords="1,381.17,459.51,10.52,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref> which builds a classification system that i) converts raw data into a cleaned dataset following a 'tidyverse' approach <ref type="foot" coords="1,221.81,481.85,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref> , ii) implements a set of manual rules to split sentences and translate medical acronyms, and iii) implement a lexicon based classification approach <ref type="bibr" coords="1,177.68,507.34,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p><p>The contribution of our experiments to this task can be summarized as follows:</p><p>-A study of a reproducibility framework to explain each step of the pipeline from raw data to cleaned data; -An evaluation of the application of a classification system prepared for a language (French) and applied without any additional training or changes to the source code to two different languages (Hungarian and Italian).</p><p>We submitted three official runs, one for each language and prepared a number of additional unofficial runs that we will evaluate and compare in order to study the change in performance when adding more information in the pipeline. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Method</head><p>In this section, we summarize the pipeline used in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,355.62,292.34,10.52,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref> that has been reproduced in this work for each run.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Pipeline for Data Cleaning</head><p>In order to produce a clean dataset, we followed the same pipeline for data ingestion and preparation for all the experiments:</p><p>read a line of a death certificate, split the line according to the expression listed in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,397.72,399.18,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>; remove extra white space (leading, trailing, internal); transform letters to lower case; remove punctuation; expand acronyms (if any); correct common patterns (if any).</p><p>Acronym Expansion Acronym expansion is a crucial step to normalize data and make the death certificate clearer and more coherent with the ICD10 codes. For the French experiments, we used. the original list of 1179 acronyms prepared by a semi-automated approach by <ref type="bibr" coords="2,286.22,533.67,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>.</p><p>We show the first ten acronym expansions in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,375.18,545.70,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. We want to stress the fact that this particular implementation of the expansion selects, in those cases where there is more than once choice (for example "aa"), only the first choice. This is part of our current work in order to improve this step of the pipeline.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Classification</head><p>We used a simple unsupervised lexicon based approach to label each (segment of a) line of a death certificate <ref type="bibr" coords="2,269.68,644.16,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. The procedure to assign an ICD10 code that does not require any training is the following: for each term in the (segment of a) line, sum one for each ICD10 label that contains the term, for each (segment of a) line compute the score of each ICD10 label; group the ICD10 labels that have the maximum score; assign the most frequent code within this group.</p><p>The score of each label is the sum of the binary weights. In those cases where two or more classes have the same number of entries with the maximum score, the first class in the list is assigned by default. This is another part of the pipeline that requires more effort in order to improve the effectiveness of the classifier. In Table <ref type="table" coords="3,176.27,521.46,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_2">3</ref>, we show an example of the first three steps, while in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,457.62,521.46,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_3">4</ref> the definition of the ICD10 codes that received the highest score.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments and Results</head><p>We submitted three official runs, one for each language: French, Hungarian, and Italian. The idea of these experiments was to test the effectiveness of the original French ICD10 classifier on two new languages without any modification to the source code. That is, acronym expansion and sentence splitting are done using French resources. We used only the raw dataset for all the languages. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Official Runs</head><p>The results of the three experiments are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,397.14,399.49,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_4">5</ref>. The French run performed sufficiently well, and comparable to the results presented in <ref type="bibr" coords="4,446.67,411.45,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. The F1 measure is close to the average of the results of all the participants in this task. This confirms that a solid clean dataset is a good starting point to build a classifier, even a simple classifier like the one we implemented.</p><p>The Hungarian and Italian results are, as we expected, worse than the average scores (much worse for Italian). However, it seems that the Hungarian dataset was in a sense "easier" compared to the our results of our experiments in the Italian subtask. We are going to investigate the reasons for this large difference in performance as future work. Another interesting fact is that, while for the French task Precision was much higher than Recall, for the Hungarian and Italian dataset these two measures seem more "balanced". This may suggest that a better acronym expansion and better sentence splitting may favour Precision over Recall.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Unofficial Runs</head><p>As part of current and future work, we have prepared a set of unofficial runs. A first set of runs study the effect of an alternative weighting scheme, tf-idf instead of binary weighting, another set of runs (for Hungarian and Italian) explore the effectiveness of splitting the sentence with the correct words, see Table <ref type="table" coords="4,441.35,644.16,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_5">6</ref>, as well as expand acronym with the appropriate language. More runs will be created a seguito di összefüggésben conseguentemente a után dopo ",", ";", "/" ",", ";", "/" with additional parameters concerning the multiple label assignment and a better acronym expansion algorithm.</p><p>At present time, we have been able to evaluate the effectiveness of some combinations of these parameters. In particular, we tested the binary weighting approach vs the tf-idf approach, using the original French source code ('inappropriate' acronyms and sentence splitting), results are shown in the first two lines of Table <ref type="table" coords="5,194.10,471.82,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_6">7</ref>. These results confirms that for Hungarian and Italian the binary weighting approach performs better than tf-idf (the only language that showed some improvement in this task with the tf-idf weights was English <ref type="bibr" coords="5,426.95,495.73,10.79,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>) Then, we performed an experiment with binary weights and a 'correct' sentence splitting (see Table <ref type="table" coords="5,252.26,524.61,4.43,8.74" target="#tab_5">6</ref>) with or without the French acronym expansion. Results are shown in the last two rows of Table <ref type="table" coords="5,345.28,536.57,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_6">7</ref>. The fact that we used a language specific sentence splitting did not produce any significant change in the performance of the classifier. This is probably due to the fact that the Hungarian and Italian death certificates are much more structured (from a language standpoint) than French ones. For example, we could rarely find complex sentences with words or terms listed in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,296.64,596.34,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_5">6</ref> in the Italian certificates. It seems that punctuation marks work sufficiently well for these two languages. Moreover, by removing the French acronym expansion, we obtained a slight improvement due to the fact that we removed the noise introduced by a module in the pipeline (the acronym expansion). In this case, results are better in terms of both Precision and Recall compared to the official runs.</p><p>The aim of our second participation to the CLEF eHealth Task 1 was to test the reproducibility of the source code of the lexicon based classifier that was implemented the previous year. The performance of the French run was good and we consider to use it as a baseline to build a new and improved classifier. The application of this classifier to two different language gave interesting results: the results of the Hungarian run was surprisingly high and close to the average of the results of the participant. However, the high value of the median of F1 (close to 90%) suggests that this subtask may be easier than the French one. For the Italian run, we obtained a worse performance the reasons of which we will investigate in a failure analysis.</p><p>As current and future work, we are studying the adaptation of the pipeline to the two new languages (better split sentence and acronym expansion <ref type="bibr" coords="6,257.77,294.34,10.30,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>); the possibility to include multiple acronym expansions; how to assign multiple labels to the same line (when scores are tied).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,134.77,115.91,345.82,114.59"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Expressions in French or punctuation marks used to split a line of a death certificate.</figDesc><table coords="2,267.20,145.53,80.95,84.97"><row><cell>French</cell></row><row><cell>avec</cell></row><row><cell>sur</cell></row><row><cell>par</cell></row><row><cell>suite à un[e]</cell></row><row><cell>dans un contexte de</cell></row><row><cell>après</cell></row><row><cell>",", ";", "/"</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,175.69,116.41,263.98,138.75"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Acronym table (fist 10 rows) used to expand acronyms.</figDesc><table coords="3,225.84,137.31,163.67,117.85"><row><cell cols="2">acronym expansion</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">5-hiaa acide 5-hydroxyindolactique</cell></row><row><cell>5-ht</cell><cell>5-hydroxytryptamine</cell></row><row><cell>5-ht</cell><cell>srotonine</cell></row><row><cell>a1at</cell><cell>alpha-1-antitrypsine</cell></row><row><cell>a1at</cell><cell>a1-antitrypsine</cell></row><row><cell>aa</cell><cell>aorte ascendante</cell></row><row><cell>aa</cell><cell>affection actuelle</cell></row><row><cell>aa</cell><cell>acide amin</cell></row><row><cell>aa</cell><cell>antiarthrosique</cell></row><row><cell>aaa</cell><cell>anvrisme de l'aorte abdominale</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="3,134.77,282.52,345.82,70.75"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Example of classification of a line of a certificate. The definition of the ICD10 labels are shown in Table 4</figDesc><table coords="3,175.01,312.13,265.33,41.14"><row><cell>step</cell><cell>data</cell></row><row><cell>line</cell><cell>pneumopathie infectieuse lobaire inférieure droite</cell></row><row><cell>terms</cell><cell>pneumopathie, infectieuse, lobaire, inferieure, droite</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ICD10 scores J181 = 7, J13 = 1</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="4,149.35,116.41,316.65,116.83"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Example of definitions (translitterated) of ICD10 selected in Table3</figDesc><table coords="4,205.01,137.31,205.34,95.93"><row><cell cols="2">ICD10 definition</cell></row><row><cell>J13</cell><cell>pneumopathie franche lobaire inferieure</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">J181 pneumopathie commune lobaire inferieure</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">J181 pneumopathie infectieuse lobaire aigue</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">J181 pneumopathie infectieuse lobaire moyenne</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">J181 pneumopathie infectieuse lobaire superieure</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">J181 pneumopathie lobaire inferieure</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">J181 pneumopathie lobaire inferieure aigue</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">J181 pneumopathie lobaire inferieure bilaterale</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="4,164.03,257.43,287.29,82.51"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Results for the official runs</figDesc><table coords="4,164.03,276.09,287.29,63.85"><row><cell></cell><cell>French</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Hungarian</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Italian</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Pre</cell><cell>Rec</cell><cell>F-1</cell><cell>Pre</cell><cell>Rec</cell><cell>F-1</cell><cell>Pre</cell><cell>Rec</cell><cell>F-1</cell></row><row><cell cols="9">runs 0.6534 0.3963 0.4933 0.7609 0.7482 0.7545 0.5353 0.4844 0.5086</cell></row><row><cell cols="9">baseline 0.3410 0.2005 0.2525 0.2425 0.1735 0.2023 0.1648 0.1723 0.1685</cell></row><row><cell cols="9">average 0.7228 0.4102 0.5066 0.8266 0.7830 0.8025 0.8441 0.7606 0.7992</cell></row><row><cell cols="9">median 0.7981 0.4750 0.5790 0.9221 0.8972 0.9095 0.8995 0.8239 0.8630</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="5,134.77,115.91,345.83,81.71"><head>Table 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Expressions in Hungarian and Italian or punctuation marks used to split a line of a death certificate.</figDesc><table coords="5,245.19,145.53,113.91,52.10"><row><cell>Hungarian</cell><cell>Italian</cell></row><row><cell>a</cell><cell>con</cell></row><row><cell>tovább</cell><cell>a causa di</cell></row><row><cell>által</cell><cell>per</cell></row><row><cell>után a</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" coords="5,172.83,263.98,269.69,83.85"><head>Table 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Results for the unofficial runs, tf-idf vs binary weighting</figDesc><table coords="5,172.83,284.38,269.69,63.45"><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Hungarian</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Italian</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Pre</cell><cell>Rec</cell><cell>F-1</cell><cell>Pre</cell><cell>Rec</cell><cell>F-1</cell></row><row><cell>official</cell><cell cols="6">0.7609 0.7482 0.7545 0.5353 0.4844 0.5086</cell></row><row><cell>official + tf-idf</cell><cell cols="6">0.6870 0.6720 0.6794 0.3642 0.3195 0.3404</cell></row><row><cell>binary</cell><cell cols="6">0.7559 0.7478 0.7519 0.5353 0.4878 0.5104</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">binary w/o acronym exp 0.7729 0.7652 0.7690 0.5495 0.5061 0.5269</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,144.73,657.44,117.68,7.47"><p>https://www.tidyverse.org</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,373.72,342.25,7.86;6,146.91,384.68,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,395.64,254.51,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,218.97,373.72,210.79,7.86">Unsupervised learning for lexicon-based classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Eisenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,447.41,373.72,33.18,7.86;6,146.91,384.68,271.53,7.86">Proceedings of the Thirty-First AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<meeting>the Thirty-First AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence<address><addrLine>San Francisco, California, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">February 4-9, 2017. 2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3188" to="3194" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,406.60,342.24,7.86;6,146.91,417.56,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,428.52,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,439.47,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,450.43,66.58,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,268.04,417.56,212.55,7.86;6,146.91,428.52,318.39,7.86">Clef ehealth 2018 multilingual information extraction task overview: Icd10 coding of death certificates in french, hungarian and italian</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Névéol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Grippo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Morgand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Orsi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Pelikán</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ramadier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Rey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Zweigenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="CEUR-WS.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,146.91,439.47,264.89,7.86">CLEF 2018 Evaluation Labs and Workshop: Online Working Notes</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-09">September 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,461.39,342.24,7.86;6,146.91,472.35,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,483.31,333.67,7.86;6,146.91,494.27,266.14,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,164.67,472.35,315.93,7.86;6,146.91,483.31,58.04,7.86">A lexicon based approach to classification of ICD10 codes. IMS unipd at CLEF ehealth task 1</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Giorgio</forename><surname>Maria</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Di</forename><surname>Nunzio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Federica</forename><surname>Beghini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Federica</forename><surname>Vezzani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Geneviève</forename><surname>Henrot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,228.96,483.31,251.63,7.86;6,146.91,494.27,70.55,7.86">Working Notes of CLEF 2017 -Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">September 11-14, 2017. 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,505.23,342.24,7.86;6,146.91,516.19,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,527.15,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,538.10,182.77,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,284.50,505.23,196.09,7.86;6,146.91,516.19,77.89,7.86">Detection and expansion of abbreviations in hungarian clinical notes</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Borbála</forename><surname>Siklósi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Attila</forename><surname>Novák</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,476.49,516.19,4.10,7.86;6,146.91,527.15,238.45,7.86">itors, Advances in Artificial Intelligence and Its Applications</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Félix</forename><surname>Castro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Gelbukh</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><surname>González</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin, Heidelberg; Berlin Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="318" to="328" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,549.06,342.25,7.86;6,146.91,560.02,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,570.98,333.67,7.86;6,146.91,581.94,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,592.90,253.67,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,323.27,570.98,157.32,7.86;6,146.91,581.94,38.52,7.86">Overview of the CLEF eHealth Evaluation Lab</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hanna</forename><surname>Suominen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Liadh</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lorraine</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Evangelos</forename><surname>Kanoulas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Leif</forename><surname>Azzopardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Rene</forename><surname>Spijker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Aurélie</forename><surname>Névéol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lionel</forename><surname>Ramadier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Aude</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Guido</forename><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Joao</forename><surname>Palotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,214.70,581.94,261.03,7.86">CLEF 2018 -8th Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<title level="s" coord="6,146.91,592.90,140.53,7.86">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018-09">2018. September 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
