<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,150.98,115.96,313.41,12.62;1,155.53,133.89,304.29,12.62;1,219.58,151.82,176.21,12.62">QUT IElab at CLEF 2018 Consumer Health Search Task: Knowledge Base Retrieval for Consumer Health Search</title>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Lembaga Pengelola Dana Pendidikan / LPDP)</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Indonesia Endowment Fund for Education</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,256.69,189.49,60.96,8.74"><forename type="first">Guido</forename><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
							<email>g.zuccon@qut.edu.au</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Brisbane</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Surabaya (UBAYA)</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Surabaya</settlement>
									<country key="ID">Indonesia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,328.20,189.49,72.37,8.74"><forename type="first">Bevan</forename><surname>Koopman</surname></persName>
							<email>bevan.koopman@csiro.au</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Brisbane</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Australian E-Health Research Centre</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">CSIRO</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Brisbane</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,150.98,115.96,313.41,12.62;1,155.53,133.89,304.29,12.62;1,219.58,151.82,176.21,12.62">QUT IElab at CLEF 2018 Consumer Health Search Task: Knowledge Base Retrieval for Consumer Health Search</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">979827D4961BE00CE6B16DA359FE095B</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:53+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper we describe our participation to the CLEF 2018 Consumer Health Search Task, sub task IRTask1. This track aims to evaluate and advance search technologies aimed at supporting consumers to find health advice online. Our solution addressed this challenge by extending the Entity Query Feature Expansion model (EQFE), a knowledge base (KB) query expansion method. In previous work we showed that Wikipedia, UMLS and CHV can be effective as basis for CHS query expansions within the EQFE model. To obtain the query expansion terms, first, we mapped entity mentions to KB entities by performing exact matching. After mapping, we used the Title of the mapped KB entities as the source for expansion terms. For our first three expanded query sets, we expanded the original queries sourcing expansion terms from each of Wikipedia, the UMLS, and the CHV. For our fourth expanded query set, we combined expansion terms from Wikipedia and CHV.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The CLEF 2018 Consumer Health Search (CHS) Task aims to retrieve information relevant to people seeking health advice on the web <ref type="bibr" coords="1,407.11,512.66,15.50,8.74" target="#b10">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,424.27,512.66,11.62,8.74" target="#b12">13]</ref>, and is a continuation of the similar task in CLEF 2017 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,352.52,524.61,10.52,8.74" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,364.70,524.61,7.01,8.74" target="#b7">8]</ref>, but with a new, more focused document corpus in place of the more general Clueweb12B document corpus. To address this task we applied and extended the Entity Query Feature Expansion model (EQFE), a knowledge base (KB) query expansion method <ref type="bibr" coords="1,467.31,560.48,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, which we have recently found performing competitively on the previous CLEF e-Health IR challenges <ref type="bibr" coords="1,234.61,584.39,9.96,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. By producing query expansions using EQFE, we seek to overcome the common issue of poor query formulation in CHS; EQFE does so by reformulating the consumer's health query with more effective terms (e.g., less ambiguous, synonyms, etc.).</p><p>One of the major challenges in CHS is the vocabulary mismatch between people's query terms and the terms used in high quality health web resources. One source of high quality health related terms is the Unified Medical Language System (UMLS) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,209.71,328.40,10.52,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref> -in our approach we use the UMLS as one of the sources for query expansion. However, UMLS concepts are rarely mentioned in consumer health queries: Keselman et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,269.06,352.31,10.52,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref> showed that only 8.1% of the possible n-grams constructed from consumer queries can be mapped (i.e., exact match) to UMLS concepts.</p><p>In constrast, Wikipedia is a crowdsourced, general purpose KB allowing people to promote and describe new concepts or augment existing concepts. While general purpose, Wikipedia contains considerable and detailed health information that has been effectively used in health related information retrieval <ref type="bibr" coords="2,452.64,424.04,10.52,8.74" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,464.82,424.04,7.75,8.74" target="#b8">9]</ref> in our approach we use Wikipedia as one of the sources for query expansion.</p><p>In addition to UMLS and Wikipedia, we also used the Consumer Health Vocabulary (CHV) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,207.93,459.90,15.49,8.74" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,225.08,459.90,7.75,8.74" target="#b5">6]</ref> which was built to provide a mapping between consumer health terms and UMLS concepts. This mapping was constructed by extracting n-grams from MedlinePlus queries and various health-focused bulletin boards; then, automatically mapping these n-grams to UMLS via exact match comparison. Any un-mapped n-grams are then manually mapped to the UMLS <ref type="bibr" coords="2,441.75,507.72,9.96,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. From 2007, the CHV is available as part of the UMLS entries with CHV" as source (i.e., tuples in table MRCONSO with attribute "SAB" equal to "CHV").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Our KB Query Expansion Model for CLEF 2018</head><p>We implemented the Entity Query Feature Expansion model for retrieval on the Wikipedia, UMLS, and CHV as the KB. For the Wikipedia KB, a single entity is represented by a single Wikipedia page (the page title identifies the entity). Beyond titles, Wikipedia also contains many page features useful in a retrieval scenario: entity title (E), categories (C), links (L), aliases (A), and body (B). As for the UMLS and CHV KBs, a single entity is represented by the most frequently used terms for a single concept unique identifier (CUI). Features of</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Run Id Source of Expansion Terms 1</head><p>The title of Wikipedia KB entities 2</p><p>The title of UMLS KB entities 3</p><p>The title of CHV KB entities 4</p><p>The combination of expansion terms from Wikipedia and CHV KBs a UMLS and CHV KB entity are aliases (A), body (B), parent concepts (P), and related concepts (R). Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,280.89,232.64,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows the features we used for mapping the queries to entities in the KB and as the source of expansion terms. We formally define the query expansion model as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,252.99,274.18,227.61,22.77">θq = M f λ f ϑ f (EM,SE)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where M are the entity mentions and contain uni-, bi-, and tri-gram generated from the query; f is a function used to extract the expansion terms. λ f (0, 1) is a weighting factor. ϑ f (EM,SE) is a function to map entity mention M to the KB features EM (e.g., "Title", "Aliases", "Links", "Body", etc.) and extract expansion terms from source of expansion SE (e.g.,"Title", "Aliases", etc.).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Description of Runs</head><p>We submitted 4 runs as described in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,320.89,398.86,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. To produce this submission, we indexed the CLEF2018 corpus using Elasticsearch 5.1.1, with stopping and Porter stemming. As underlying retrieval model we used BM25F, with b title = 0.90, b body = 0.45 and k1 = 1.2 as these settings were found to be optimal for the CLEF 2016 eHealth collection. Further, BM25F allows to specify boosting factors for matches occurring in different fields of the indexed web page. We consider only the title field and the body field, with boost factors 1 and 3, respectively. These were found to be the optimal weights for BM25F for the CLEF 2016 eHealth collection <ref type="bibr" coords="3,215.73,494.50,10.52,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref> -and we hope these values do translate well into the new CLEF 2018 CHS collection.</p><p>To obtain Run 1, we: 1. indexed Wikipedia pages with Medicine infobox type and pages with infobox containing links to medical terminologies such as Mesh, UMLS, SNOMED CT, etc. 2. extracted uni-, bi-, tri-grams of the original query that matched CHV entities. 3. exact matched the extracted n-grams to the Wikipedia's aliases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">used the title of the matched entities as expansion terms</head><p>To obtain Run 2, we:</p><p>1. indexed all English and non-obsolete UMLS concepts. 2. extracted uni-, bi-, tri-grams of the original query that matched entities in the UMLS (via QuickUMLS <ref type="bibr" coords="4,277.89,261.68,14.76,8.74" target="#b9">[10]</ref>). 3. exact matched the extracted n-grams to the UMLS's aliases. 4. used the title of the matched entities as expansion terms.</p><p>To obtain Run 3, we:</p><p>1. indexed English and non-obsolete CHV concepts that associated to the four key aspects of medical decision criteria (i.e., symptoms, diagnostic test, diagnoses, and treatments) as used in <ref type="bibr" coords="4,310.57,355.45,9.96,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. 2. extracted uni-, bi-, tri-grams of the original query that matched entities in the CHV. 3. exact matched the extracted n-grams to the CHV's aliases. 4. used the title of the matched entities as expansion terms.</p><p>To obtain Run 4, we combined expansion terms obtained from the Wikipedia and CHV KBs (run 1 and run 3). Using CLEF 2016 collection, we found that this combination performed the best when compared to other possible combinations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Discussion</head><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="4,161.78,516.82,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref> shows the pairwise Kendall's τ b correlation coefficient between our runs. To compute the correlation coefficient score between two runs, first, we combined query-document pairs from both runs and retain only the unique pairs. Then, we determined the rank of each document pair in each run. Query-document pairs with the same score (i.e., ties), were assigned their minimal rank. If a querydocument pair was not found in one run, then the query-document pair will be assigned rank 1001 (i.e. the full length of the ranking, plus one). Finally, we used R to compute the pairwise Kendall's τ b correlation coefficient between rank list from both runs <ref type="foot" coords="4,204.06,610.89,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref> .</p><p>As shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,232.32,624.54,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref>, rank correlations among our runs are generally low (no correlation) -with the only exception of Run 3 and Run 4 which are instead highly (positively) correlated. This may have been because queries in Run 4 may have been expanded using mostly by terms from the CHV KB (as used in Run 3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions</head><p>In this working notes paper we have discussed the methods used by the QUT IElab team in their participation to the CLEF 2018 Consumer Health Search task (subtask 1 -ad-hoc retrieval). We submitted a total of four runs; evaluation results are not available at this stage.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,152.09,286.22,311.18,7.89"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Summary of expansion sources for our extension of the EQFE model.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,161.27,177.88,292.82,7.89"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Summary of the runs submitted to CLEF 2018 CHS, IRTask1.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,160.45,121.59,294.46,93.25"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Pairwise Kendall's τ b rank correlation coefficient between runs.</figDesc><table coords="4,194.84,121.59,222.60,75.24"><row><cell></cell><cell>Run 1</cell><cell>Run 2</cell><cell>Run 3</cell><cell>Run 4</cell></row><row><cell>Run 1</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0.0424</cell><cell>0.2503</cell><cell>0.2886</cell></row><row><cell>Run 2</cell><cell>0.0424</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0.1706</cell><cell>0.1610</cell></row><row><cell>Run 3</cell><cell>0.2503</cell><cell>0.1706</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0.9046</cell></row><row><cell>Run 4</cell><cell>0.2886</cell><cell>0.1610</cell><cell>0.9046</cell><cell>-</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="4,144.73,656.80,210.18,7.86"><p>https://github.com/jimmyoentung/RunsCorrelation</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>Acknowledgment: <rs type="person">Jimmy</rs> conducted this research as part of his doctoral study which is sponsored by the <rs type="funder">Indonesia Endowment Fund for Education</rs> (<rs type="funder">Lembaga Pengelola Dana Pendidikan / LPDP)</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.96,353.99,337.63,7.86;5,151.52,364.95,287.43,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,220.54,353.99,260.05,7.86;5,151.52,364.95,62.44,7.86">The unified medical language system (umls): integrating biomedical terminology</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Bodenreider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,221.17,364.95,88.22,7.86">Nucleic acids research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">suppl 1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="D270" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.96,376.68,337.64,7.86;5,151.52,387.64,183.57,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,277.32,376.68,203.27,7.86;5,151.52,387.64,42.36,7.86">Entity Query Feature Expansion Using Knowledge Base Links</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dalton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Dietz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Allan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,215.11,387.64,35.66,7.86">SIGIR&apos;14</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="365" to="374" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.96,399.36,337.63,7.86;5,151.52,410.32,329.07,7.86;5,151.52,421.28,329.07,7.86;5,151.52,432.24,164.06,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,289.78,410.32,171.46,7.86">Clef 2017 ehealth evaluation lab overview</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Suominen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Névéol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kanoulas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Spijker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Palotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,151.52,421.28,329.07,7.86;5,151.52,432.24,40.25,7.86">International Conference of the Cross-Language Evaluation Forum for European Languages</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="291" to="303" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.96,443.97,337.63,7.86;5,151.52,454.93,220.92,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,296.63,443.97,183.96,7.86;5,151.52,454.93,89.22,7.86">Boosting Titles Does Not Generally Improve Retrieval Effectiveness</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Zuccon</forename><surname>Jimmy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Koopman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,261.73,454.93,35.05,7.86">ADCS&apos;16</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="32" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.96,466.65,337.63,7.86;5,151.52,477.61,329.07,7.86;5,151.52,488.57,91.18,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,322.02,466.65,158.57,7.86;5,151.52,477.61,94.47,7.86">Choices in knowledge-base retrieval for consumer health search</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Zuccon</forename><surname>Jimmy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Koopman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,268.81,477.61,191.16,7.86">European Conference on Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="85" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.96,500.30,337.64,7.86;5,151.52,511.26,329.07,7.86;5,151.52,522.22,329.07,7.86;5,151.52,533.18,25.60,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,204.22,511.26,276.38,7.86;5,151.52,522.22,30.45,7.86">Consumer health concepts that do not map to the umls: where do they fit</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Keselman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Divita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Browne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Leroy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Zeng-Treitler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,188.24,522.22,230.54,7.86">Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="496" to="505" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.96,544.90,337.64,7.86;5,151.52,555.86,329.07,7.86;5,151.52,566.82,226.49,7.86" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,333.91,544.90,146.68,7.86;5,151.52,555.86,123.62,7.86">Inferring conceptual relationships to improve medical records search</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Limsopatham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,295.79,555.86,184.81,7.86;5,151.52,566.82,161.17,7.86">Proceedings of the Tenth Conference on Open Research Areas in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the Tenth Conference on Open Research Areas in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.96,578.55,337.64,7.86;5,151.52,589.51,329.07,7.86;5,151.52,600.47,124.09,7.86" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,167.77,589.51,293.90,7.86">CLEF 2017 Task Overview: The IR task at the ehealth evaluation lab</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Palotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Jimmy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lupu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hanbury</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="s" coord="5,151.52,600.47,95.43,7.86">CEUR-WS Proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.96,612.19,337.64,7.86;5,151.52,623.15,329.07,7.86;5,151.52,634.11,158.14,7.86" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,404.52,612.19,76.07,7.86;5,151.52,623.15,153.62,7.86">Retrieving medical literature for clinical decision support</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Soldaini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cohan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Yates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Goharian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Frieder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,328.25,623.15,152.34,7.86;5,151.52,634.11,34.93,7.86">European Conference on Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="538" to="549" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.62,645.84,337.98,7.86;5,151.52,656.80,214.30,7.86" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,262.74,645.84,217.86,7.86;5,151.52,656.80,73.14,7.86">Quickumls: a fast, unsupervised approach for medical concept extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Soldaini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Goharian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,245.75,656.80,66.85,7.86">MedIR workshop</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.62,119.67,337.98,7.86;6,151.52,130.63,329.07,7.86;6,151.52,141.59,329.07,7.86;6,151.52,152.55,329.07,7.86;6,151.52,163.51,71.19,7.86" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,442.94,130.63,37.65,7.86;6,151.52,141.59,137.18,7.86">Overview of the clef ehealth evaluation lab</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Suominen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kanoulas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Azzopardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Spijker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Névéol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ramadier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Palotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Jimmy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,317.97,141.59,162.62,7.86;6,151.52,152.55,99.06,7.86">CLEF 2018 -8th Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<title level="s" coord="6,259.20,152.55,173.99,7.86">Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNCS</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018-09">2018. September 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.62,174.47,337.97,7.86;6,151.52,185.43,294.32,7.86" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,233.34,174.47,219.72,7.86">Exploring and developing consumer health vocabularies</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tse</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,459.46,174.47,21.13,7.86;6,151.52,185.43,212.93,7.86">Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.62,196.39,337.98,7.86;6,151.52,207.34,329.07,7.86;6,151.52,218.30,168.25,7.86" xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,369.59,196.39,111.00,7.86;6,151.52,207.34,122.86,7.86">Overview of the CLEF 2018 Consumer Health Search Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Zuccon</forename><surname>Jimmy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Palotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,297.58,207.34,183.02,7.86;6,151.52,218.30,87.99,7.86">CLEF 2018 Evaluation Labs and Workshop: Online Working Notes</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CEUR-WS</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
