<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,155.30,150.75,284.45,12.64;1,265.73,166.83,63.86,12.64;1,202.97,182.79,189.36,12.64">Multi feature space combination for authorship clustering: Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2016</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,127.70,225.76,117.15,9.94"><forename type="first">Muharram</forename><surname>Mansoorizadeh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Engineering Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Bu-Ali Sina University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Hamedan</settlement>
									<country key="IR">Iran</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,253.73,225.76,99.83,9.94"><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Aminiyan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Engineering Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Bu-Ali Sina University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Hamedan</settlement>
									<country key="IR">Iran</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,362.59,225.76,65.63,9.94"><forename type="first">Taher</forename><surname>Rahgooy</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Engineering Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Bu-Ali Sina University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Hamedan</settlement>
									<country key="IR">Iran</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,436.27,225.76,31.31,9.94;1,275.57,238.36,44.08,9.94"><forename type="first">Mahdy</forename><surname>Eskandari</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Engineering Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Bu-Ali Sina University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Hamedan</settlement>
									<country key="IR">Iran</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,155.30,150.75,284.45,12.64;1,265.73,166.83,63.86,12.64;1,202.97,182.79,189.36,12.64">Multi feature space combination for authorship clustering: Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2016</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">1C3F41D38109B1CF7FF7A024DCE72B35</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:45+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>authorship clustering</term>
					<term>authorship link</term>
					<term>tf-idf</term>
					<term>feature space combintion</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The Author Identification task for PAN 2016 consisted of three different Sub-tasks: authorship clustering, authorship links and author diarization. We developed a machine learning approaches for two of three of these tasks. For the two authorship related tasks we created various sets of feature spaces. The challenge was to combine these feature spaces to enable the machine learning algorithms to detect these difference authors across multiple feature spaces. In the case of authorship clustering we combine these feature spaces and use a two-step approach for clustering. Then we use results of the clustering, and employ new feature space to determine links between documents in given problems.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In the following we provide a detailed description of our approaches to solve the two subtasks of the Author Identification track of PAN 2016. The problem instance is a tuple &lt;K; U; L&gt; where K is a set of documents &lt;k1, k2, k3,…, kn&gt; authored by the different authors, U is the genre of the document and L is the enumerated value specifying the language of the documents: English, Dutch or Greek. All documents in a problem instance are in the same language and same genre. This lab report is structured as follows: In section 2 we propose a number of different features that characterize documents from widely different points of view: character, word, part-of speech, sentence length, punctuation. We construct non-overlapping groups of homogeneous feature. In section 3 we present the two-step unsupervised method for authorship clustering task by employing a graph based approach and the standard k-means++ algorithm. Then we employ new feature space to determine links between documents. Finally, in section 4 we describe our results on the training corpus and the final evaluation corpus of PAN-2016.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Preprocessing</head><p>We extract a number of different features from each document. For ease of presentation, we group homogeneous features together, as described below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Features</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Word ngrams (WG):</head><p>We convert all characters to lowercase and then we transform the document to a sequence of words. We consider white spaces, punctuation characters and digits as word separators. We count all word ngrams, with n ≤ 3, and we obtain a feature for each different word ngram which occurs in the training set documents of a given language <ref type="bibr" coords="2,412.27,334.75,11.79,9.94" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. It should be mentioned that, we use word unigrams and 2-gram in clustering task and preprocesses related to it and word 3-gram only used in link computation phase.</p><p>In order to normalize these set of features we use term frequency-inverse document frequency (tf-idf) for each set of documents (each problem) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,429.94,397.99,14.01,9.94" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>POS (part-of-speech) tag ngrams (PG):</head><p>We apply a part of speech (POS) tagger on each document, which assigns words with similar syntactic properties to the same POS tag. We count all POS ngrams, with n≤ 2, and we obtain a feature for each different POS ngram which occurs in the training set documents of a given language <ref type="bibr" coords="2,242.93,461.23,11.79,9.94" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Sentence lengths (SL): We transform the document to a sequence of tokens, a token being a sequence of characters separated by one or more blank spaces. Next, we transform the sequence of tokens to a sequence of sentences, a sentence being a sequence of tokens separated by any of the following characters: ., ;, :, !, ?. We count the number of sentences whose length in tokens is n, with n {1,..,15}: we obtain a feature for each value of n <ref type="bibr" coords="2,358.51,537.33,11.70,9.94" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Punctuation ngrams (MG):</head><p>We transform the document by removing all characters not included in the following set: {,, ., ;, :, !, ?, "}-the resulting document thus consists of a (possibly empty) sequence of characters in that set. We then count all character ngrams of the resulting document, with n≥2, and we obtain a feature for each different punctuation ngrams which occurs in the training set documents of a given language <ref type="bibr" coords="2,332.47,613.29,11.79,9.94" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p><p>In order to preprocess documents we use python NLTK 3.0 package <ref type="bibr" coords="2,455.14,625.89,11.70,9.94" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. After creating the feature space we simply separate word 2grams for authorship link task and use the rest of features for clustering. We assume that word 2grams consist of very specific relation which can effect better inside of each cluster for determining the level of similarity between documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Data normalization</head><p>After feature extraction, we normalize value of each feature using min-max normalization in order to remove the impact of different scale spaces:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,126.61,235.41,344.09,23.43">old new X Max X Max Min   <label>(1)</label></formula><p>Where old X is the old value of X and Max is the maximum value of feature X and Min is the Minimum value for feature X.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Two-step unsupervised method</head><p>In order to solve the task, we use two step method.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Step 1: Determining the number of authors</head><p>Considering the fact that number of authors is unknown first we have to determine the number of authors for each problem, namely, we have to determine number of clusters for clustering algorithm. The number of clusters should be set by the developer based on specifications of problem. Assigning a proper number is a challenging task. A document similarity graph (DSG) algorithm has been used. DSG is an undirected graph showing similarity relations between documents based on their contents <ref type="bibr" coords="3,346.15,491.85,11.69,9.94" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. The nodes of this graph are documents and the edges between documents are defined by the similarities and dissimilarities between them using (2):</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,136.68,540.60,195.10,65.27">        1 2 2 1 1 , . . ,<label>1 1 . 1 , 0 ,</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="3,124.39,539.56,346.30,68.29">n i i i n n i i i i mat i j xy XY Z i j x y Z i j VS X ij Y Z                     <label>(2)</label></formula><p>Where x k and y k are features of X i and Y j documents respectively and δ is the threshold which define the existence of the similarity between two documents. In this paper, the δ parameter is set to 0.5. Also Z is the cosine similarity between two documents <ref type="bibr" coords="3,259.73,657.36,11.77,9.94" target="#b4">[5]</ref>.</p><p>The number of clusters has been determined using the number of sub graphs resulted with DSG. To find the number we just count the nodes with value more than 65 percent of number of all document for example if we have 100 documents in problem folder, we count nodes which have more than 65 incoming edges.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Step 2: clustering and computing links</head><p>After calculating the number of clusters, we use k-means++ <ref type="bibr" coords="4,405.31,239.08,12.78,9.94" target="#b5">[6]</ref> scikit-learn python package in order to perform clustering task.</p><p>When clustering completed, we collect the result and employ simple similarity task in each of clusters. We compute similarity based word 3grams features and cosine similarity (2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>In order to evaluate our work, we use training corpus and the final evaluation corpus of PAN-2016. These datasets consist of set of problems, each problem comes with different number of documents in specific language (English, Dutch and Greek) and two different genres (newspaper articles and reviews). The clustering output will be evaluated according to BCubed Fscore <ref type="bibr" coords="4,153.12,423.31,12.82,9.94" target="#b6">[7]</ref> and the ranking of authorship links will be evaluated according to Mean Average Precision (MAP) <ref type="bibr" coords="4,282.26,435.91,11.81,9.94" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. In order to evaluate our work, first the software has been executed on TIRA platform <ref type="bibr" coords="4,330.75,448.51,11.77,9.94" target="#b8">[9]</ref>.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="4,164.27,473.85,5.52,9.94" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows the result of train dataset. It is obvious that our method have high Bcubed recall hence we can say the method cluster same items almost great in each cluster but by investigating our method's Bcubed precision, we can clearly say that the number of cluster or even the way we measure similarity does not tune well.  <ref type="table" coords="5,229.42,326.95,4.14,9.94" target="#tab_2">2</ref>, results of test dataset, also illustrates, high level of Bcubed recall in most of problem sets, in contrast with Bcubed precision which is not high. But it is obvious that results from test dataset are better than train data. It shows ability of system to generalize new problems. But the major defect of system with lower Bcubed precision than recall one still exists.</p><p>Notice that you can find complete evaluation on overview <ref type="bibr" coords="5,394.14,390.19,16.86,9.94" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion and future works</head><p>In this research we propose a two-step unsupervised method in order to perform author clustering. In our approach we combine different feature spaces and use them to cluster documents based on their authors. Then, we rank documents based on their cosine similarity using new set of feature which are different from the set we use for clustering.</p><p>Results illustrates that our work have a good Bcubed recall. But major problem of our method was its Bcubed precision. The problem may come from cluster number selection or the feature space. Hence as a future work, we suggest researchers work on a way of better cluster parameter selection. Also, it would be suggested that the task tested on more complex clustering method without the need on parameter selection like self-organized map (SOM) and so on.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,132.14,548.80,327.18,131.61"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Results of test dataset</figDesc><table coords="4,132.14,559.96,327.18,120.45"><row><cell>problem</cell><cell>language</cell><cell>Genre</cell><cell>F-Bcubed</cell><cell>R-Bcubed:</cell><cell>P-Bcubed</cell><cell>Average Precision</cell></row><row><cell>problem01</cell><cell>English</cell><cell>Articles</cell><cell>0.71947</cell><cell>0.71333</cell><cell>0.72571</cell><cell>0.00083612</cell></row><row><cell>problem02</cell><cell>English</cell><cell>Articles</cell><cell>0.58281</cell><cell>0.50444</cell><cell>0.69</cell><cell>0.00022599</cell></row><row><cell>problem03</cell><cell>English</cell><cell>Articles</cell><cell>0.58665</cell><cell>0.87333</cell><cell>0.44167</cell><cell>0.00052301</cell></row><row><cell>problem04</cell><cell>English</cell><cell>Reviews</cell><cell>0.76012</cell><cell>0.69583</cell><cell>0.8375</cell><cell>0.0015432</cell></row><row><cell>problem05</cell><cell>English</cell><cell>Reviews</cell><cell>0.2648</cell><cell>0.97083</cell><cell>0.15331</cell><cell>0.0028001</cell></row><row><cell>problem06</cell><cell>English</cell><cell>Reviews</cell><cell>0.24887</cell><cell>0.89667</cell><cell>0.14449</cell><cell>0.017832</cell></row><row><cell>problem07</cell><cell>Dutch</cell><cell>Articles</cell><cell>0.45478</cell><cell>0.96491</cell><cell>0.2975</cell><cell>0.0084819</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,159.97,326.95,65.72,9.94"><head>Table 1 ,</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Table</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,132.74,426.50,329.94,250.07"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results of test dataset</figDesc><table coords="5,132.74,443.66,329.94,232.91"><row><cell>problem</cell><cell>language</cell><cell>Genre</cell><cell>F-Bcubed</cell><cell>R-Bcubed:</cell><cell>P-Bcubed</cell><cell>Average Precision</cell></row><row><cell>problem01</cell><cell>English</cell><cell>Articles</cell><cell>0.4492</cell><cell>0.77619</cell><cell>0.31605</cell><cell>0.0045282</cell></row><row><cell>problem02</cell><cell>English</cell><cell>Articles</cell><cell>0.51302</cell><cell>0.6165</cell><cell>0.43929</cell><cell>0.018634</cell></row><row><cell>problem03</cell><cell>English</cell><cell>Articles</cell><cell>0.45086</cell><cell>0.9381</cell><cell>0.29674</cell><cell>0.0022228</cell></row><row><cell>problem04</cell><cell>English</cell><cell>Reviews</cell><cell>0.46821</cell><cell>0.80833</cell><cell>0.32955</cell><cell>0.0033492</cell></row><row><cell>problem05</cell><cell>English</cell><cell>Reviews</cell><cell>0.54696</cell><cell>0.92083</cell><cell>0.38902</cell><cell>0.00076857</cell></row><row><cell>problem06</cell><cell>English</cell><cell>Reviews</cell><cell>0.4896</cell><cell>0.64458</cell><cell>0.3947</cell><cell>0.0046202</cell></row><row><cell>problem07</cell><cell>Dutch</cell><cell>Articles</cell><cell>0.06261</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>0.032318</cell><cell>0.017739</cell></row><row><cell>problem08</cell><cell>Dutch</cell><cell>Articles</cell><cell>0.33159</cell><cell>0.95906</cell><cell>0.2004</cell><cell>0.0053791</cell></row><row><cell>problem09</cell><cell>Dutch</cell><cell>Articles</cell><cell>0.15954</cell><cell>0.94987</cell><cell>0.087</cell><cell>0.032996</cell></row><row><cell>problem10</cell><cell>Dutch</cell><cell>Reviews</cell><cell>0.33115</cell><cell>0.89667</cell><cell>0.20308</cell><cell>0.00097662</cell></row><row><cell>problem11</cell><cell>Dutch</cell><cell>Reviews</cell><cell>0.31324</cell><cell>0.56167</cell><cell>0.21718</cell><cell>0.0022789</cell></row><row><cell>problem12</cell><cell>Dutch</cell><cell>Reviews</cell><cell>0.3371</cell><cell>0.73167</cell><cell>0.219</cell><cell>0.00074413</cell></row><row><cell>problem13</cell><cell>Greek</cell><cell>Articles</cell><cell>0.43173</cell><cell>0.76429</cell><cell>0.3008</cell><cell>0.02234</cell></row><row><cell>problem14</cell><cell>Greek</cell><cell>Articles</cell><cell>0.46847</cell><cell>0.7119</cell><cell>0.34909</cell><cell>0.015947</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,136.10,675.19,80.67,8.10"><p>mansoorm@basu.ac.ir</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="1,136.10,686.23,94.75,8.10"><p>M.Aminiyan@Gmail.com</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,132.67,465.88,337.57,8.10;6,141.74,476.92,329.12,8.10;6,141.74,487.84,70.91,8.10" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,363.59,465.88,106.64,8.10;6,141.74,476.92,171.01,8.10">A generalized topic modeling approach for automatic document annotation</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Tuarob</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Pouchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Giles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,318.91,476.92,151.95,8.10;6,141.74,487.84,9.16,8.10">International Journal on Digital Libraries</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,132.67,498.88,338.02,8.10;6,141.74,509.92,328.89,8.10;6,141.74,520.84,329.12,8.10;6,141.74,531.79,329.00,8.19;6,141.74,542.92,268.56,8.10" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,459.82,498.88,10.86,8.10;6,141.74,509.92,328.89,8.10;6,141.74,520.84,42.10,8.10">An Author Verification Approach Based on Differential Features-Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2015</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alberto</forename><surname>Bartoli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Dagri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Lorenzo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Medvet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Fabiano</forename><surname>Tarlao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="CEUR-WS.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,159.86,531.79,254.58,8.19">CLEF 2015 Evaluation Labs and Workshop -Working Notes Papers</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Linda</forename><surname>Cappellato</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gareth</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>San</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Juan</forename></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Toulouse, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-09">8-11 September. September 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>editors</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,132.67,553.84,338.19,8.10;6,141.74,564.88,56.31,8.10" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,285.29,553.84,146.97,8.10">Natural language processing with Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Klein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Loper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<publisher>O&apos;Reilly Media, Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,132.67,575.83,337.90,8.19;6,141.74,586.75,328.70,8.19;6,141.74,597.79,305.74,8.19" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,288.88,575.83,181.68,8.19;6,141.74,586.75,82.28,8.18">PRISM : Concept-preserving Social Image Search Results Summarization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Seah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bhowmick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,244.49,586.84,225.95,8.10;6,141.74,597.79,232.46,8.19">Proceedings of the 37th international ACM SIGIR conference on Research &amp; development in information retrieval -SIGIR &apos;14</title>
		<meeting>the 37th international ACM SIGIR conference on Research &amp; development in information retrieval -SIGIR &apos;14</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="737" to="746" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,132.67,608.92,338.19,8.10;6,141.74,619.84,40.84,8.10" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,283.61,608.92,94.18,8.10">Encyclopedia of distances</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Deza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Elena</forename><surname>Marie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Deza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Berlin Heidelberg</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,132.67,630.88,338.19,8.10;6,141.74,641.92,328.96,8.10;6,141.74,652.84,63.74,8.10" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,248.41,630.88,183.14,8.10">k-means ++ : The Advantages of Careful Seeding</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Arthur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Vassilvitskii</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,438.59,630.88,32.26,8.10;6,141.74,641.92,282.86,8.10">Proceedings of the eighteenth annual ACMSIAM symposium on Discrete algorithms</title>
		<meeting>the eighteenth annual ACMSIAM symposium on Discrete algorithms</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006. 2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1027" to="1035" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,132.67,663.91,338.19,8.10;6,141.74,674.95,329.00,8.10;6,141.74,685.87,15.79,8.10" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,354.56,663.91,116.29,8.10;6,141.74,674.95,203.60,8.10">A comparison of extrinsic clustering evaluation metrics based on formal constraints</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Amigó</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gonzalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Artiles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Verdejo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,349.01,674.95,73.65,8.10">Information retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="461" to="486" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,132.67,149.99,338.07,8.10;7,141.74,161.03,238.85,8.10" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Raghavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Schütze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="7,341.71,149.99,129.03,8.10;7,141.74,161.03,6.46,8.10">Introduction to information retrieval</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Cambridge university press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">496</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,132.67,172.07,338.04,8.10;7,141.74,182.90,328.54,8.18;7,141.74,194.03,328.54,8.10;7,141.74,205.07,329.12,8.10;7,141.74,215.99,328.54,8.10;7,141.74,227.03,250.35,8.10" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,418.02,172.07,52.69,8.10;7,141.74,182.90,328.54,8.18;7,141.74,194.03,61.17,8.10">Improving the Reproducibility of PAN&apos;s Shared Tasks: Plagiarism Detection, Author Identification, and Author Profiling</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gollub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,252.13,205.07,218.72,8.10;7,141.74,215.99,328.54,8.10;7,141.74,227.03,10.77,8.10">Information Access Evaluation meets Multilinguality, Multimodality, and Visualization. 5th International Conference of the CLEF Initiative (CLEF 14)</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kanoulas</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lupu</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sanderson</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hanbury</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Toms</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014-09">Sep 2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="268" to="299" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,132.40,238.07,337.92,8.10;7,141.74,248.99,328.65,8.10;7,141.74,260.03,328.57,8.10;7,141.74,271.07,96.75,8.10" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,191.01,248.99,204.27,8.10">Clustering by Authorship Within and Across Documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tschuggnall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Verhoeven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Daelemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Specht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="-WS.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,414.83,248.99,55.57,8.10;7,141.74,260.03,161.62,8.10">Working Notes Papers of the CLEF 2016 Evaluation Labs</title>
		<title level="s" coord="7,311.37,260.03,158.94,8.10;7,141.74,271.07,19.91,8.10">CEUR Workshop Proceedings, CLEF and CEUR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-09">Sep 2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
