<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,170.71,88.06,264.87,12.62">IRIT at TREC Microblog Track 2013</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,227.47,126.59,84.07,8.74"><forename type="first">Lamjed</forename><forename type="middle">Ben</forename><surname>Jabeur</surname></persName>
							<email>jabeur@irit.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Toulouse 3 -Paul Sabatier -IRIT/SIG 118 route de Narbonne</addrLine>
									<postCode>F-31062</postCode>
									<settlement>Toulouse cedex 9</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,319.52,126.59,53.65,8.74"><forename type="first">Firas</forename><surname>Damak</surname></persName>
							<email>damak@irit.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Toulouse 3 -Paul Sabatier -IRIT/SIG 118 route de Narbonne</addrLine>
									<postCode>F-31062</postCode>
									<settlement>Toulouse cedex 9</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,114.29,138.55,60.98,8.74"><forename type="first">Lynda</forename><surname>Tamine</surname></persName>
							<email>tamine@irit.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Toulouse 3 -Paul Sabatier -IRIT/SIG 118 route de Narbonne</addrLine>
									<postCode>F-31062</postCode>
									<settlement>Toulouse cedex 9</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,183.61,138.55,83.58,8.74"><forename type="first">Guillaume</forename><surname>Cabanac</surname></persName>
							<email>cabanac@irit.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Toulouse 3 -Paul Sabatier -IRIT/SIG 118 route de Narbonne</addrLine>
									<postCode>F-31062</postCode>
									<settlement>Toulouse cedex 9</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,275.56,138.55,98.79,8.74"><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Pinel-Sauvagnat</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Toulouse 3 -Paul Sabatier -IRIT/SIG 118 route de Narbonne</addrLine>
									<postCode>F-31062</postCode>
									<settlement>Toulouse cedex 9</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,401.65,138.55,90.35,8.74"><forename type="first">Mohand</forename><surname>Boughanem</surname></persName>
							<email>boughanem@irit.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Toulouse 3 -Paul Sabatier -IRIT/SIG 118 route de Narbonne</addrLine>
									<postCode>F-31062</postCode>
									<settlement>Toulouse cedex 9</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,170.71,88.06,264.87,12.62">IRIT at TREC Microblog Track 2013</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">6917CF2E18428A86A2C2D94A7D3664C1</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:07+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the participation of the IRIT lab, University of Toulouse, France, to the Microblog Track of TREC 2013. Two different approaches are experimented by our team for the real-time ad-hoc search task: (i) a Bayesian network retrieval model for tweet search and (ii) a document and query expansion model for microblog search.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Seeking for information over microblogs helps to find reliable, concise and real-time information about a recently happened event (few seconds ago up to few days) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,426.31,333.82,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. In contrast of Web search, where queries are submitted for informational, transactional or a navigational propose, search within microblogs differs in content, format and the underlying motivation. It is motivated by the social activity of the person as well as current events and trends that inspire microblogging community. Relevance in this context dependent on the microblogging intention and includes several factors typically social, temporal and topical relevance <ref type="bibr" coords="1,474.99,393.60,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p><p>Microblog search is defined in TREC Microblog Track as a real-time search task is an ad-hoc retrieval task where users are interested in most recent and relevant information <ref type="bibr" coords="1,491.13,418.37,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Results of 2011 and 2012 editions of TREC Microblog Track show that the relevance of tweets may depends on several features in addition to the textual similarity to the query such as the number of followers and followings, the freshness of information, included URLs and the user's location, etc. We investigate in this paper two different approach for microblog retrieval:</p><p>-First Bayesian network retrieval model for tweet search estimates the tweet relevance based on the microblogger influence and the temporal distribution of query terms. -Second Document and query expansion using URLs published in tweets and Rocchio pseudo-relevance Feedback to avoid the vocabulary problem.</p><p>This paper is organized as follows. Section 2 introduces the Bayesian network model for tweet search and discusses relative results. Section 3 describes the document and query expansion model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">A Bayesian Network Retrieval Model for Tweet Search</head><p>Inspired from work of Pinheiro et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="1,268.93,637.09,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, we propose to model tweet search using Bayesian network models that incorporate different sources of evidence into an integrated framework. As shown in figure <ref type="figure" coords="1,182.36,661.01,3.87,8.74">1</ref>, the topology of our Bayesian network model for tweet search is comprised of 3 connected networks: tweet network, microblogger network and period network. A detailed description of this model is presented in our previous paper <ref type="bibr" coords="1,364.93,684.92,9.96,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,210.69,92.96,189.62,148.30">q k1 k2 k3 K o1 o2 O u1 u2 S tk1 tk2 tk3 TK to1 to2 to3 TO ts1 ts2 ts3 TS t1 t2 t3</formula><p>T Fig. <ref type="figure" coords="2,231.40,254.57,4.13,7.89">1</ref>. Belief network model for tweet search</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Query evaluation</head><p>The relevance of tweet t j with respect to query q is computed according the topology of the Bayesian network for tweet search as follows: </p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,193.04,321.14,72.66,20.14">P (t j |q) ∝ k P<label>(</label></formula><p>The probability P (t j |k) that tweet t j is generated by configuration k measures the topical similarity between the tweet and the configuration. This probability is estimated as the normalized sum of all query weights w ki,tj .</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,221.81,391.78,282.59,30.52">w ki,tj = tf k i ,t j -β tf k i ,t j , if on(k i , t j ) = 1 0, otherwise<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where tf ki,tj is the frequency of term k i in tweet t j . w ki,tj reduces the weight of frequent terms. Accordingly, we give more importance to term presence rather than term repetition.</p><p>Assuming that the two events of observing microblogger u f and configuration k are independent, the probability P (t sj |k) of observing tweet t j having the social importance of corresponding microblogger is estimated as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="2,244.92,499.51,259.48,9.65">P (t sj |k) = P (t sj |u f )P (u f )<label>(3)</label></formula><p>Lets τ (u f ) be the set of tweets published by u f . P (t</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="2,338.58,516.55,149.81,14.14">sj |u f ) = 1 |τ (u f )| . Probability P (u f</formula><p>) is approximated to P ageRank(u f ), the microblogger PageRank score computed on the social network of retweets and mentions extracted from the top instantiated tweets by the query.</p><p>The probability P (t oj |k) of observing tweet t j knowing period o e and term configuration k is estimated as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="2,242.03,580.18,262.38,9.65">P (t oj |k) = P (t oj |o e )P (o e |k)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>The probability P (o e |k) of selecting period o e , having configuration k, weights the different periods. We estimate this probability based on two factors. First, we consider the time decay between period o e and query date θ q . In fact, recent tweets are more likely to interest microblog users. Second, we consider the percentage of tweets published in o e and containing the configuration k. This highlights active period of the configuration k that concurs with a real world event. Periods are weighted as followings:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7" coords="2,231.84,673.47,272.57,23.23">P (o e |k) = log(θ q -θ oe ) log(θ q -θ os ) × df k,oe df k<label>(5)</label></formula><p>with θ q , θ oe and θ os are respectively the timestamps of query q, the period o e and the period o s when the oldest tweet containing the term configuration k is published. df k,oe is the number of tweets published in o e and containing configuration k. df k is the number of tweets with a term configuration k. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Results and discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Document and Query Expansion for Microblog Search</head><p>In this approach, we propose and test several hypotheses to improve the effectiveness of microblog search engines. We mainly expanded queries and tweets since we found, by doing a failure analysis on previous track results, that the major issue of IR in microblogs was the vocabulary mismatch. This issue is mainly due to the shortness of tweets. We thus propose to extend tweets with the content of the URLs they contain, and to expand queries using Rocchio pseudo' relevance feedback <ref type="bibr" coords="3,259.30,472.30,10.52,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref> and Microsoft Bing spelling suggestion<ref type="foot" coords="3,441.78,470.72,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Design of our Approach</head><p>Our approach is composed several steps:</p><p>1. We first submitted original queries to Bing spelling suggestion API. Suggested terms were added to the original queries. 2. We then submitted the new queries to the API designed for this year's track and obtained the top 10,000 tweets for each topic. 3. We applied Rocchio pseudo-relevance feedback on resulting tweets to generate expanded queries. 4. In the next step, we submitted expanded queries to the track API, without term weights and retrieved also the top 10,000 tweets for each topic. The main goal of this step was to improve recall by enhancing our chance to get more potentially relevant tweets. 5. Then, the resulting tweets from step 2 and 4 were merged. We kept only one tweet in case of redundancy. The resulting set of tweets was composed of less than 20,000 tweets for each topic.</p><p>6. All obtained tweets were expanded with the content of the URLs they contain. We used Lucene Search engine<ref type="foot" coords="4,214.07,101.48,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_1">2</ref> to index tweets and URLs. We specified a field for the content of tweets and a second field for the URL content published in the considered tweet, if it exists. Both fields got the same weight. 7. Considering the last set of tweets, final scores were calculated using Vector Space Model <ref type="bibr" coords="4,118.82,150.81,10.52,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref> and using Rocchio expansion resulting queries resulting from the step 3. We considered the term weights in queries when querying the Lucene search engine. The top-1000 high scored tweets for each topic composed our main submitted run iritfdUrlRoc.</p><p>We did not consider Rocchio query expansion in our second submitted run iritfdUrl. Only steps 1 and 2 and 6 were proceeded for it. Final scores were calculated using vector space Model and considering queries resulting from step 2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Contribution and Experiments</head><p>Query Spelling Suggestions We noticed from previous tracks results that same namedentities are spelled differently in tweets and queries, which causes the vocabulary problem. Thus, we used Microsoft Bing spelling suggestions<ref type="foot" coords="4,323.39,289.91,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_2">3</ref> to address this issue. This API allowed us to find the other spelled forms of a named-entity. For each query-term, we added its other spelling forms to the original query. We did not differentiate between original and added terms in terms of weighting. Although this step reformulated a noticeable number of queries (6/60) in the 2012 track, among the 60 topics of this year (2013), only 1 topic has been modified. The query "US behind Chaevez cancer" became "US behind Chaevez Chavez cancer".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Rocchio Query expansion</head><p>We choose to use the improved version <ref type="bibr" coords="4,424.52,380.88,10.52,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref> of the original Rocchio's formula <ref type="bibr" coords="4,183.32,392.83,9.96,8.74" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. Since we considered only highly ranked documents resulting from the original queries, the Rocchio resulting formula is then:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8" coords="4,241.85,424.66,262.55,26.80">Q new = α.Q orig + β |R| . r∈R r<label>(6)</label></formula><p>Q new is a weighted term vector for the expanded query. Q orig is a weighted term vector for the original unexpanded query. R is the set of relevant documents. r is the TF/IDF term vector extracted from R. For our experiments, α = 1 and β = 0.75 were used. The size of R was set to 10. This choice is consistent with prior experimental studies on the TREC collections. The number of expansion terms was set to 10. This choice is based on experiments done in <ref type="bibr" coords="4,138.36,518.30,10.51,8.74" target="#b8">[9]</ref> where it is found that 10 is the best number of added terms for the microblogs search task.</p><p>The aim of query expansion with Rocchio is twofold: on one hand, it could resolve the vocabulary mismatch issue, on the other hand, it addresses the problem of the importance difference among the query terms. Using Rocchio query expansion method improves results by 8% on 2012 topics compared to a run which considers original queries, with original tweets and using Vector Space Model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Document Expansion</head><p>The main observation from previous analysis on the 2012 track results, was the vocabulary mismatch, where some relevant tweets do not contain any term among the query-terms. By focusing on URLs published in the relevant tweets, we noticed that their consideration in addition to the content of tweets improve results: we obtained 13.57% of improvement on 2012 test set when considering URLs using VSM and without modifying queries. The importance of URLs was also noticed in previous microblog Tracks <ref type="bibr" coords="5,101.89,115.01,10.52,8.74" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="5,114.07,115.01,11.62,8.74" target="#b9">10]</ref>. Table <ref type="table" coords="5,145.33,232.85,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_3">2</ref> shows results of our runs. Poor results were obtained. Additional experiments should be conducted to find the reason. The same configuration we used this year obtained p@30 = 0.2390 on the 2012 topics, which would have ranked us in third place among last year's automatic runs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Results and Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Run</head><p>Query expansion did not improve recall. However, it improved the p@30 of 4.8%. The difference is significant according to Student's t test, bilateral and paired with p &lt; 0.05.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,265.70,321.14,147.56,9.65"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>q|k)P (t kj |k)P (t sj |k)P (t oj |k)P (k)</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,101.89,173.75,402.52,159.93"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>compares results presented by different configurations of our model. BNTSrKSO represents our Bayesian network model with all features activated. IRITbnetK represents our model with only the topical feature is activated. BNTSrKS and BNTSrKO are based on the topical feature and represents our model with the social feature is activated and the temporal feature is activated, respectively. All runs were computed before relevance judgments release. First, we note that IRITbnetK results overpass all other configurations. Included temporal and social relevance features have not enhanced the retrieval ranking. These runs may be infected by computation problem.</figDesc><table coords="3,169.94,276.97,266.43,56.70"><row><cell></cell><cell>p@10</cell><cell>p@20</cell><cell>p@30</cell><cell>p@100</cell><cell>MAP</cell></row><row><cell>BNTSrK*</cell><cell>0.4617</cell><cell>0.4175</cell><cell>0.3672</cell><cell>0.2503</cell><cell>0.1952</cell></row><row><cell>BNTSrKO</cell><cell>0.3233</cell><cell>0.2558</cell><cell>0.2117</cell><cell>0.1283</cell><cell>0.0925</cell></row><row><cell>BNTSrKS</cell><cell>0.2967</cell><cell>0.2583</cell><cell>0.2222</cell><cell>0.1268</cell><cell>0.1024</cell></row><row><cell>BNTSrKSO*</cell><cell>0.2917</cell><cell>0.2342</cell><cell>0.2061</cell><cell>0.1278</cell><cell>0.1031</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="3,180.81,344.98,244.67,7.89"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Comparison of model configurations. * Official run</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,180.81,170.47,244.67,41.59"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Comparison of model configurations. * Official run</figDesc><table coords="5,185.58,170.47,204.05,30.18"><row><cell></cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>Map</cell><cell>P@30</cell></row><row><cell>iritfdUrl</cell><cell>0.2598</cell><cell>0.0648</cell><cell>0.1394</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">iritfdUrlRoc* 0.2576</cell><cell>0.0757</cell><cell>0.1461</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="3,111.85,685.60,138.83,7.86"><p>http://www.bing.com/developers/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="4,111.85,674.64,103.95,7.86"><p>http://lucene.apache.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="4,111.85,685.60,138.83,7.86"><p>http://www.bing.com/developers/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.08,348.10,394.33,7.86;5,118.64,359.06,253.35,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,174.34,348.10,187.82,7.86">Information search and retrieval in microblogs</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Miles</forename><surname>Efron</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,372.09,348.10,132.32,7.86;5,118.64,359.06,159.03,7.86">Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="996" to="1008" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.08,370.01,394.33,7.86;5,118.64,380.97,385.76,7.86;5,118.64,391.93,362.91,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,373.68,370.01,130.73,7.86;5,118.64,380.97,130.13,7.86">#twittersearch: a comparison of microblog search and web search</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jaime</forename><surname>Teevan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Ramage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Merredith</forename><surname>Ringel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Morris</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,267.96,380.97,236.45,7.86;5,118.64,391.93,164.46,7.86">Proceedings of the fourth ACM international conference on Web search and data mining, WSDM &apos;11</title>
		<meeting>the fourth ACM international conference on Web search and data mining, WSDM &apos;11<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="35" to="44" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.08,402.89,394.33,7.86;5,118.64,413.85,354.33,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,360.74,402.89,143.67,7.86;5,118.64,413.85,19.21,7.86">Overview of the trec-2011 microblog track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Iadh</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Craig</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jimmy</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Soboroff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,157.31,413.85,202.35,7.86">Proceedings of the 20th Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>the 20th Text REtrieval Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>NIST</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011. 2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.08,424.81,394.33,7.86;5,118.64,435.77,385.77,7.86;5,118.64,446.73,385.77,7.86;5,118.64,457.69,197.32,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,322.83,435.77,121.92,7.86">Bayesian belief networks for ir</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Antnio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Pinheiro</forename><surname>De Cristo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Pvel</forename><surname>Pereira Calado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>De Lourdes Da Silveira</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ilmrio</forename><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Muntz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Berthier</forename><surname>Ribeiro-Neto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,451.81,435.77,52.60,7.86;5,118.64,446.73,140.21,7.86">International Journal of Approximate Reasoning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2-3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="179" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Soft Computing Applications to Intelligent Information Retrieval on the Internet</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.08,468.64,394.33,7.86;5,118.64,479.60,385.77,7.86;5,118.64,490.56,385.76,7.86;5,118.64,501.52,40.45,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,383.85,468.64,120.55,7.86;5,118.64,479.60,259.38,7.86">Intgration des facteurs temps et autorit sociale dans un modle baysien de recherche de tweets</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lamjed</forename><surname>Ben Jabeur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lynda</forename><surname>Tamine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mohand</forename><surname>Boughanem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>21/03/12-23/03/12</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,399.37,479.60,105.04,7.86;5,118.64,490.56,203.82,7.86">Confrence francophone en Recherche d&apos;Information et Applications (CORIA)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Bordeaux</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="301" to="316" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.08,512.48,394.33,7.86;5,118.64,523.44,385.76,7.86;5,118.64,534.40,125.88,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,267.05,512.48,237.36,7.86;5,118.64,523.44,169.52,7.86">Readings in information retrieval. chapter Improving retrieval performance by relevance feedback</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gerard</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
			<publisher>Morgan Kaufmann Publishers Inc</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="364" />
			<pubPlace>San Francisco, CA, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.08,545.36,394.32,7.86;5,118.64,556.32,381.37,7.86" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,316.91,545.36,187.50,7.86;5,118.64,556.32,19.21,7.86">Lucene and juru at trec 2007: 1-million queries track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Doron</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Einat</forename><surname>Amitay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Carmel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,157.31,556.32,255.07,7.86">Proceedings of the 7th Text REtrieval Conference (TREC 2007)</title>
		<meeting>the 7th Text REtrieval Conference (TREC 2007)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.08,567.27,394.33,7.86;5,118.64,578.23,349.13,7.86" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,183.08,567.27,177.46,7.86;5,460.28,567.27,44.12,7.86;5,118.64,578.23,258.16,7.86">The Smart retrieval system -experiments in automatic document processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Rocchio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>G. Salton</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1971">1971</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="323" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Relevance feedback in information retrieval</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.08,589.19,394.33,7.86;5,118.64,600.15,385.76,7.86;5,118.64,611.11,48.63,7.86" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,304.82,589.19,199.58,7.86;5,118.64,600.15,100.61,7.86">Frequent Itemset Mining for Query Expansion in Microblog Ad-hoc Search</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Younos</forename><surname>Aboulnaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Charles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,239.50,600.15,203.05,7.86">Proceedings of the 21th Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>the 21th Text REtrieval Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>NIST</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012. 2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,109.74,622.07,394.67,7.86;5,118.64,633.03,354.33,7.86" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,360.74,622.07,143.67,7.86;5,118.64,633.03,19.21,7.86">Overview of the trec-2012 microblog track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Iadh</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Craig</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jimmy</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Soboroff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,157.31,633.03,202.35,7.86">Proceedings of the 21th Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>the 21th Text REtrieval Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>NIST</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012. 2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
