<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,149.56,115.96,316.24,12.62;1,148.52,133.89,318.31,12.62">NovaSearch at TREC 2013 Microblog Track: Experiments with reranking using Wikipedia</title>
				<funder ref="#_P5tZVev">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_N8DShbd">
					<orgName type="full">Portuguese National Foundation</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,194.53,172.12,62.86,8.74"><forename type="first">Flávio</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
							<email>flaviomartins@acm.org</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculdade de Ciências e Tecnologia Universidade Nova de Lisboa Caparica</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="PT">Portugal</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,265.32,172.12,63.71,8.74"><forename type="first">André</forename><surname>Mourão</surname></persName>
							<email>a.mourao@campus.fct.unl.pt</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculdade de Ciências e Tecnologia Universidade Nova de Lisboa Caparica</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="PT">Portugal</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,351.72,172.12,69.11,8.74"><forename type="first">João</forename><surname>Magalhães</surname></persName>
							<email>jm.magalhaes@fct.unl.pt</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculdade de Ciências e Tecnologia Universidade Nova de Lisboa Caparica</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="PT">Portugal</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,149.56,115.96,316.24,12.62;1,148.52,133.89,318.31,12.62">NovaSearch at TREC 2013 Microblog Track: Experiments with reranking using Wikipedia</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">BF534C3D48FD10417C2DB1BBBB4E2ADE</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:07+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Users engaged in microblogging services and social-media apps contribute to multiple real-time text streams which amass large volumes of messages often sparked by events reported in newswire and in other media. We explore the use of external sources to detect topic popularity surges and improve microblog search performance using timebased language models [3]. The major novelty concerns the analysis that explores Wikipedia page view streams to find topic interest spikes. We obtained promising initial results when using evidence from Wikipedia for temporal reranking with the Tweets2013 dataset.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Search over real-time stream data such as the messages generated in social-media networks (e.g. Twitter) is a killer feature of these platforms. Search functionality in these online services should favour events that are occurring now. What is occurring now is discussed in many different places in the Web at the same time. We can build on top of this observation by correlating data from multiple sources to learn more about the events detected. There are two major challenges in this approach: the first is how to assert the veracity of these information sources; the second challenge concerns the analysis across different streams of data.</p><p>Wikipedia is used by millions<ref type="foot" coords="1,276.91,527.14,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref> as a reliable and dependable source of insight in various subject matters. It is highly regarded as one of the most trustworthy encyclopedias. Nonetheless, Wikipedia is far from being just a set of static articles painstakingly collected over a period of years. Wikipedia is pretty much alive and evolves in real-time with the edits of its users. Similarly to what happens in social-media services, major events inspire the interest of the users towards related articles which, in turn, can also show an elevated number of edits and page views near the dates of an event. Thus, we propose to explore Wikipedia streams of data to improve search in microblogs.</p><p>Dakka et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,190.66,142.63,10.52,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref> discusses how to deal with time-sensitive queries. It argues that queries that favor recency are just a subset of these. Therefore, the authors propose to identify the time intervals of interest for each query and to integrate this information in the scoring scheme using a number of different techniques. They evaluated their framework on news article datasets (including TREC) and with a collection of web data annotated by Mechanical Turk workers.</p><p>One approach proposed in Peetz et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,314.52,214.36,9.96,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, leverages the temporal distribution of the documents initially retrieved. The authors hypothesize that the temporal distribution of time-sensitive document collections exhibit bursts and that documents in these bursts are more informative. Therefore, they first identify high quality documents sampled from bursty periods and then update the query model with informative terms from these documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Estimation methods for ranking recency</head><p>Efron and Golovchinsky <ref type="bibr" coords="2,248.95,323.41,10.52,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref> explores estimation methods to promote recent tweets. One of the approaches is time-based language models, proposed in Li and Croft <ref type="bibr" coords="2,182.13,347.32,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, which applies time-based exponential priors to the score of the documents. The exponential prior proposed in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,347.19,359.28,10.52,8.74" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,362.27,359.28,7.75,8.74" target="#b2">3]</ref> for recency reranking is given by formula <ref type="bibr" coords="2,211.70,371.23,11.62,8.74" target="#b0">(1)</ref>. The formula discounts the score for each tweet according to the age of the tweet in relation to the time of the query (e.g. number of days). McCreadie et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,213.84,395.14,10.52,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref> also used a variation of formula ( <ref type="formula" coords="2,380.45,395.14,3.87,8.74" target="#formula_0">1</ref>), in the 2011 TREC Microblog task to promote tweets in the first 6 hours.</p><p>Li and Croft <ref type="bibr" coords="2,207.21,419.05,10.52,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref> found that the parameter λ is query-specific in their experiments. Therefore, if a fixed value of λ is used for all queries, retrieval performance can improve in some queries but can also deteriorate the performance of others. In both papers <ref type="bibr" coords="2,206.27,454.92,10.52,8.74" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,221.32,454.92,7.01,8.74" target="#b2">3]</ref>, λ = 0.01 provides the best average performance, even though different datasets were used.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,220.95,490.78,259.65,8.74">T exp(score, age) = score • λ exp[-λage]<label>(1)</label></formula><p>3 Proposed approach</p><p>Our approach is based on the correlation of multiple information streams that carry different types of information about the same topic. We hypothesize that topics that burst on Twitter can be highly correlated with a higher page view value and higher editing frequency of related Wikipedia pages. These pages can describe the topic itself, a related event, the entities involved, etc. We use formula (2) to perform temporal reranking using the query time, as well as using time points extracted from Wikipedia evidence. This formula aims to penalize more strongly documents that are temporally far from the time of the query. In figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,188.51,261.66,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_0">1</ref>, we plotted the Texp and Texp2 functions over the domain (0 : 60) (60 days when measuring age in days). Notice that we normalized the functions to the interval (0 : 1) to facilitate the visualization. In figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,399.05,285.57,8.49,8.74" target="#fig_0">1a</ref>, we see that the Texp formula generates a very soft decay. With the Texp2 formula, we tried to make the decay in the first few days smooth so that the days next to the query time would not be penalized too much. Finally, we chose the parameters so that it would decay to 0 in about 20 days as can be seen in figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,403.12,333.39,8.86,8.74" target="#fig_0">1b</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,201.83,651.55,278.76,10.81">T exp2(score, age) = score • 0.01 exp[-0.005age 2 ]<label>(2)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experimental setup</head><p>In this real-time ad-hoc search task, the user wishes to search for the most recent and relevant posts. The task can be summarized as: at time t, find tweets about topic X. Therefore, systems should favor relevant and highly informative tweets about the query topic posted before the query time. Due to the nature of microblogs, it is likely that relevance has a temporal dimension. That is, relevant tweets are likely to have been published nearer to the time of the query. Therefore, systems should also take into account the temporality of the tweets.</p><p>This year the track ran in a Track-as-a-Service model (to adhere to Twitter's terms of service), where participants do not have access to the whole collection; they have access to the tweets by issuing queries to a search API running in a remote server administered by the track organizers. We therefore experimented with methods to rerank the ranked list of tweets returned using the search API.</p><p>Tweets2013 corpus is the new official corpus created for the TREC 2013 microblog track. This collection consists of approximately 240 million tweets (statuses), collected via the Twitter streaming API by crawling the public stream sample over a two-month period: 1 February, 2013 -31 March, 2013 (inclusive). NIST created 60 topics based on this corpus each representing a information need at a specific point in time. The assessors judged the relevance of the tweet but also considered the relevance of any URLs linked from the tweet. All assessments were conducted by NIST assessors on a three-point scale of "informativeness": not relevant, relevant and highly relevant. The primary evaluation measure for this year is MAP, however precision at rank 30 cutoff and R-prec are also reported.</p><p>Assessors consider tweets not written in the English language as not relevant. Moreover, a retweet is generally considered not revelant. It is only relevant if it is an RT-style, where the author added highly informative text to the original tweet. Therefore, our baseline run combines a language filter and a retweet filter.</p><p>Language filter. We use a language filter to remove tweets that are not written in English. Before passing the tweet to the language identification library, we put the text through some processing steps. We use twitter-text-java<ref type="foot" coords="4,434.21,236.62,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_2">2</ref> to detect and remove URLs, @mentions, lists and #hashtags from the tweet. We remove other common patterns used pervasively in Twitter, regardless of the language that could confuse the language detector: RT, \via and its variants and other prevalent microsyntax such as \by and \cc.</p><p>To detect the language of the tweets we used the library language-detection<ref type="foot" coords="4,476.12,296.96,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_3">3</ref> but relaxed the identification. We aim for a low number of false negatives: tweets that are in fact written in English but are not detected. The detector is used in a way that English must only be one of the probable languages, and doesn't have to be the language with the highest probability.</p><p>Retweet filter. The retweet filter simply discards retweets from the results. We filtered Twitter-style retweets using the available tweet metadata. We further filter out RT-style retweets that start with the word "RT", since it is standard for users to add commentary before of the retweeted text and not after. Therefore, these are tweets that will be most likely judged as not relevant by assessors. NOVAsearch00: Language and retweet filters combination. In this run we remove retweets and non-English tweets with the filters described above. This run shows an improvement from the QL Baseline of 20.6% in P30 and MAP, while R-prec improves 16.7% (see Table <ref type="table" coords="4,340.27,495.44,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref>).</p><p>NOVAsearch01: Temporal reranking using query time. The ranked list obtained using our baseline (NOVAsearch00) can be improved by reranking using only the temporal information available at query time (the actual time when the query was issued). For reranking, we selected the Texp2 function that gave us the best results for P30 in the 2011 and 2012 queries with the Tweets2011 corpus. However, this was not the case with the new dataset and this function performed poorly against Texp (see Table <ref type="table" coords="4,325.50,599.87,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref>). The Texp2 function decays too fast and penalizes posts that are perhaps too recent for the 2 month time span of the newer evaluation corpus (see Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,322.73,623.78,8.58,8.74" target="#fig_0">1b</ref>). NOVAsearch02: Temporal reranking using Wikipedia page view data.</p><p>We hypothesized that a topic bursts simultaneously in Twitter and Wikipedia. More specifically, we hypothesize that Wikipedia pages related to a topic show a surge of page views when a topic bursts on Twitter. Therefore, we leveraged page view log data from Wikipedia to estimate when a topic might have burst.</p><p>To select a related page for each topic, we simply queried the Wikipedia search API with the original topic text, as a user would, and used the first hit returned in the results. We used both the query time as well as the the page views peak date from Wikipedia (limited to up to 10 days before query time) for reranking. We show the pages selected for a small number of topics in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,429.49,354.32,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref> as well as their Wikipedia page views peak date. This information can be matched visually with the plots in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,242.08,378.23,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_1">2</ref>.</p><p>NOVAsearch03: Document expansion with linked documents. In this run we experimented with document expansion. We processed the web pages linked from the tweet messages using Goose<ref type="foot" coords="5,325.14,428.77,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_4">4</ref> in order to extract their titles and metadata. The representation of a tweet document was expanded in the index by adding a new field that contains the title of tweets' linked web documents. We reindexed only 10,000 tweets for each topic, due to the document limit of the search API. The results of this experiment were not encouraging.  Our system augments the query-likelihood model with time-based language models, using temporal exponential priors and our additional formula Texp2. With this setup, we were able to improve ranking performance by correlating the topic with Wikipedia page view data for temporal reranking. Simple and fast techniques that seamlessly integrate the temporal aspect of the queries are desirable. In query-likelihood retrieval, the time-based language model approach is most certainly one of the most straightforward techniques that integrates the temporal aspect of queries or recency in retrieval. To this effect, we will pursue in the future cross-stream analysis methods to correlate multiple streams and discover useful information to improve microblog retrieval.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,233.64,228.61,148.08,7.89"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Temporal reranking formulas</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="6,134.77,590.29,345.83,7.89;6,134.77,601.27,325.27,7.86;6,122.94,487.67,368.02,76.64"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. Temporal distribution of retrieved tweets: The horizontal axis is a timeline indexed by hours until the query time. (Relevant documents represented in red.)</figDesc><graphic coords="6,122.94,487.67,368.02,76.64" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,134.77,115.91,345.83,102.60"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Topics and Wikipedia page matching: shows the query date and the Wikipedia page views peak date.</figDesc><table coords="5,137.23,150.86,340.90,67.66"><row><cell>Topic Query</cell><cell>Wikipedia Page</cell><cell>Q-Time Wiki-Time</cell></row><row><cell>MB115 memories of Mr. Rogers</cell><cell>Fred Rogers</cell><cell>Mar 30 Mar 20</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">MB127 Hagel nomination filibustered Chuck Hagel</cell><cell>Mar 5 Feb 27</cell></row><row><cell>MB132 asteroid hits Russia</cell><cell cols="2">Asteroid impact avoidance Feb 20 Feb 15</cell></row><row><cell>MB133 cruise ship safety</cell><cell>Cruise ship</cell><cell>Mar 15 Mar 15</cell></row><row><cell>MB164 Lindsey Vonn sidelined</cell><cell>Super-G</cell><cell>Mar 30 Mar 19</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,168.36,508.82,278.64,112.41"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>TREC 2013 Microblog track: Real-time ad-hoc task results</figDesc><table coords="5,190.97,532.81,233.42,88.42"><row><cell></cell><cell>All relevant</cell><cell>Highly relevant</cell></row><row><cell>Method</cell><cell cols="2">MAP R-prec P30 MAP R-prec P30</cell></row><row><cell>QL Baseline</cell><cell cols="2">0.2044 0.2699 0.3761 0.1540 0.1946 0.1900</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">NOVAsearch00 0.2726 0.3171 0.4711 0.1941 0.2280 0.2306</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">NOVAsearch01 0.2082 0.2530 0.4367 0.1607 0.2064 0.2222</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">NOVAsearch02 0.2239 0.2738 0.4450 0.1696 0.2166 0.2267</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">NOVAsearch03 0.1612 0.2092 0.3550 0.1341 0.1651 0.1911</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,144.73,645.84,320.49,7.86;1,144.73,656.80,140.68,7.86"><p>http://www.comscore.com/Insights/Blog/comScore Releases Top 50 US Multi-Platform Properties for September</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2013" xml:id="foot_1" coords="1,288.72,656.80,18.43,7.86"><p>2013</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_2" coords="4,144.73,645.84,179.81,7.86"><p>https://github.com/twitter/twitter-text-java</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_3" coords="4,144.73,656.80,191.80,7.86"><p>https://code.google.com/p/language-detection/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_4" coords="5,144.73,656.80,158.31,7.86"><p>https://github.com/GravityLabs/goose</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work has been partially funded by the <rs type="funder">Portuguese National Foundation</rs> under the projects <rs type="grantNumber">PTDC/EIA-EIA/111518/2009</rs> and <rs type="grantNumber">UTA-Est/MAI/0010/2009</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_N8DShbd">
					<idno type="grant-number">PTDC/EIA-EIA/111518/2009</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_P5tZVev">
					<idno type="grant-number">UTA-Est/MAI/0010/2009</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,373.72,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,384.68,318.21,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,310.73,373.72,166.04,7.86">Answering general time-sensitive queries</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Dakka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gravano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ipeirotis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,146.91,384.68,227.59,7.86">IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="220" to="235" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,395.64,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,406.60,290.67,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,268.09,395.64,208.39,7.86">Estimation methods for ranking recent information</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Efron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Golovchinsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,160.99,406.60,39.61,7.86;7,251.29,406.60,39.61,7.86">SIGIR &apos;11</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">495504</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SIGIR &apos;11</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,417.56,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,428.52,157.44,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,229.13,417.56,114.04,7.86">Time-based language models</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,365.38,417.56,39.30,7.86;7,455.00,417.56,25.59,7.86;7,146.91,428.52,10.75,7.86">CIKM &apos;03</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">469475</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CIKM &apos;03</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,439.47,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,450.43,333.68,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,357.12,439.47,123.47,7.86;7,146.91,450.43,301.59,7.86">University of glasgow at TREC 2011: Experiments with terrier in crowdsourcing, microblog, and web tracks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mccreadie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,461.39,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,472.35,164.90,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,291.03,461.39,168.79,7.86">Using temporal bursts for query modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Peetz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Meij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Rijke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-07">July 2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="35" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
