<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,116.03,172.46,334.31,18.60">Fondazione Ugo Bordoni at TREC 2004</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,102.16,212.64,109.78,12.91"><forename type="first">Giambattista</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,222.10,212.64,103.17,12.91"><forename type="first">Claudio</forename><surname>Carpineto</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,359.18,212.64,105.03,12.91;1,210.37,242.28,66.72,12.91"><forename type="first">Giovanni</forename><forename type="middle">Romano</forename><surname>Fondazione</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,280.68,242.28,75.32,12.91"><forename type="first">Ugo</forename><surname>Bordoni</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,251.10,260.21,64.16,12.91"><forename type="first">Rome</forename><surname>Italy</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,116.03,172.46,334.31,18.60">Fondazione Ugo Bordoni at TREC 2004</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">0A221EFAA2F61B8A77430DEE69346092</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:00+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Our participation in TREC 2004 aims to extend and improve the use of the DFR (Divergence From Randomness) models with Query Expansion (QE) for the robust track. We experiment with a new parameter-free version of Rocchio's Query Expansion, and use the information theory based function, Info DFR to predict the AP (Average Precision) of queries. We also study how the use of an external collection affects the retrieval-performance.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>FUB participation in the robust track deals with the adaptation of the DFR modular probabilistic framework <ref type="bibr" coords="1,229.53,480.79,14.82,9.82" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,247.67,480.79,8.18,9.82" target="#b4">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,259.17,480.79,8.18,9.82" target="#b0">1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,270.66,480.79,9.09,9.82" target="#b3">3]</ref> together with query expansion based on distribution analysis <ref type="bibr" coords="1,193.91,494.34,12.81,9.82" target="#b5">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,209.45,494.34,8.18,9.82" target="#b6">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,220.35,494.34,7.88,9.82" target="#b0">1]</ref>.</p><p>In the robust track of TREC 12 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,270.07,507.89,18.17,9.82" target="#b10">[10]</ref> several approaches used external collections for the term-weighting <ref type="bibr" coords="1,250.77,521.44,11.81,9.82" target="#b7">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,266.73,521.44,12.95,9.82" target="#b11">11]</ref>, with the aim of enhancing both MAP (Mean Average Precision) and performance over poor-performing queries (e.g. MAP(X)). Therefore, we want to measure the impact of exploiting external resources in retrieving documents of the target collection.</p><p>All runs employ a new parameter-free model of QE that is presented in Section 2.3. We use a unique query-performance predictor, which is displayed in Equation 8. For each baseline run (fub04Te, fub04De and fub04TDNe) we add an additional QE processing in their analogue runs (fub04Tge, fub04T2ge, fub04Dge and fub04TDNge) before applying the final QE. More precisely, we first expand the initial query q (T, D or TDN) with the same methodology used for the baselines (and explained in Section 2.3) using the first R retrieved documents of the external collection, and thus obtain a new expanded query q 1 . Then, we submit q 1 as a new query to the target collection. This time, we retrieve R documents of the target collection. We expand the query q 1 with the same technique used for the baselines, and obtain the final ranking. For fub04Tge, fub04Dge and fub04TDNge we use a sort of oracle (a WEB search engine) to select the documents of the external collection, while we exploit the .GOV collection for the run fub04T2ge. In the runs fub04Tg, fub04Dg and fub04TDNg we do not apply a second pass QE on the target collection, but we directly retrieve documents of the target collection with the expanded query q 1 . However, we have only submitted the title field for the longest queries (TDN) in the runs using the WEB search engine for the first-pass retrieval for the queryexpansion. Similarly, we extract the most significant terms from for the onlydescription queries using the within-query term-weights of Equation 4 for the runs fub04Dge and fub04Dg. As for the longest queries, the title is submitted as it is for the query-expansion in the remaining runs fub04Tge and fub04Tg.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Term-weighting models</head><p>We use only one DFR within-document term-weighting formulas and only one model of query expansion. The term-weighting model is I(n)OL2:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,147.95,429.89,311.48,24.68">weight(t|d) = tfn tfn + 1 log 2 |D| -df + 1 df + 0.5<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,221.55,459.55,164.04,75.71">               tfn = tf(t|d) • log 2 1 + c • adl dl |D|</formula><p>is the size of the collection D df the document-frequency dl the document-length adl the average document-length</p><p>The value of the parameter c of the within-document term-weighting DFR models is set to 2 [4, 1, 2, 3]. I(n)OL2 can be seen as a generalization of the BM 25 formula <ref type="bibr" coords="2,173.51,577.18,13.63,9.82" target="#b9">[9]</ref>. To see this, we introduce a new parameter k 1 (however, we have used k 1 = 1 in all our experiments):</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,137.40,612.17,125.71,25.50">tfn tfn + k 1 log 2 |D| -df + 1 df + 0.5</formula><p>and denote dl c • adl by the variable x. Then:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="3,178.14,150.44,188.96,40.24">tfn tfn + k 1 = tf(t|d) tf(t|d) + k 1 log 2 (x + 1) -log 2 x</formula><p>The Taylor series expansion at the point x = 1 of the function</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="3,106.93,223.07,222.52,61.56">k 1 log 2 (x + 1) -log 2 x with error O(( dl c • adl -1)</formula><p>3 ) is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="3,123.30,301.28,360.42,74.97">k 1 • 1 + log 2 e • 0.5 • ( dl c • adl -1) - 1 8 log 2 e • (3 -2 log 2 e)( dl c • adl -1) 2 = = k 1 • 0.2580 + 0.7627 • dl c • adl -0.0207 • dl (c • adl) 2 If k 1 is set to 1.</formula><p>2 as the default value of k 1 in the BM 25 formula, then:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7" coords="3,175.18,387.39,194.89,28.59">tfn tfn + k 1 ∼ tf(t|d) tf(t|d) + 0.3096 + 0.9152 • dl c•adl</formula><p>that is when c = 1, I(n)OL2 formula is approximated by the BM 25 formula. In its more general form, I(n)OL2 is a generalization of BM 25 (In Terrier <ref type="bibr" coords="3,446.71,440.06,12.72,9.82" target="#b8">[8]</ref> I(n)OL2 is called DFR BM25).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Query expansion</head><p>The QE method is a parameter-free extension of that used in TREC 2003 <ref type="bibr" coords="3,426.37,508.40,11.59,9.82" target="#b3">[3]</ref>. We have evaluated this methodology with all other TREC collections achieving often better results than with the optimal Rocchio parameter β.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Old model of QE</head><p>The last TREC within-query term-weights of the expanded query q * of the original query q was obtained as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8" coords="3,182.93,626.35,276.49,25.68">weight(t ∈ q * ) = ntfq + β • Info DFR (t) MaxInfo DFR<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where: </p><formula xml:id="formula_9" coords="4,116.90,148.34,127.48,128.13">                               ntfq = tfq arg</formula><p>In particular, we use the following Bose-Einstein statistics (Bo2) as DFR model:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11" coords="4,143.80,324.83,315.63,51.36">Info Bo2 (t) = -log 2 1 1+λ -tf(t|R) • log 2 λ 1+λ [Bo2] λ = t' tf (t'|R) • tf(t|D) t' tf (t'|D)<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where R denotes the pseudo-relevant set.<ref type="foot" coords="4,285.73,386.00,3.99,7.17" target="#foot_0">1</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">New model of QE: a parameter-free expanded query</head><p>An upper bound of Info DFR (t) is when the divergence of tf(t|D) and tf(t|R) is maximum, that is when tf(t|R) = tf(t|D). Let M be the maximum value of all values</p><formula xml:id="formula_12" coords="4,142.18,489.58,317.25,35.97">M = arg max t∈q * M(t) M(t) = lim tf(t|D)→ tf(t|R) Info DFR (t)<label>(6)</label></formula><p>In different words M(t) is obtained by substituting in Info DFR each occurrence of tf(t|D) with its theoretical lower bound tf(t|R).</p><p>The new within-query term-weight in the expanded query q * of the original query q is obtained as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13" coords="4,194.19,599.56,265.24,24.68">weight(t ∈ q * ) = ntfq + Info DFR (t) M<label>(7)</label></formula><p>In the implementation we select the term t with the highest Info DFR (t), which in general has also the highest term frequency tf(t|R) in the topmost documents. Then, we compute the M(t) value as M associated to this selected terms. This technique corresponds to anautomatic way to select a query-biased value for the parameter β.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Parameters</head><p>The only parameters we use in QE are:</p><formula xml:id="formula_14" coords="5,121.38,255.88,55.34,11.52">• |R| = 8. 2</formula><p>• the number of terms N t of the expanded query is 40. <ref type="foot" coords="5,360.34,274.41,3.99,7.17" target="#foot_3">3</ref></p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Predicting topic difficulty with Info DFR</head><p>Our notion of query-difficulty is based on the same within-query term-weighting Info DFR gained after a first-pass ranking. If there is a significant divergence in the query-term frequencies before and after the retrieval, then we make the hypothesis that this divergence is caused by a query which is easy-defined. difficulty score of q = def t∈q Info DFR (t) of Formula 4 <ref type="bibr" coords="5,446.71,406.72,12.72,9.82" target="#b8">(8)</ref> where DFR is a basic model (based on the Binomial, the Bose-Einstein statistics or the Kullback-Leibler divergence measure). We use the probability of Bose-Einstein as defined in Formula ( <ref type="formula" coords="5,247.07,468.72,4.24,9.82" target="#formula_11">5</ref>) in all our runs and in all QE processes. To compute the difficulty-score of the query we first produced a first-pass ranking as it is done in QE. We took the set R of the first 8 retrieved documents and we compute the score Info DFR (t) for each term occurring in the query. We consider the query-terms which appear at least twice in these pseudo-relevant documents. This score reflects the amount of information carried by the queryterm within these pseudo-relevant documents. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>We submitted 4 title-only (the runs with the descriptor T), 3 description-only (the runs with the descriptor D), and 3 full-query runs (the runs with the descriptor TDN). Results are shown in Tables <ref type="table" coords="6,259.51,449.02,5.45,9.82" target="#tab_1">1</ref> and<ref type="table" coords="6,285.19,449.02,4.09,9.82" target="#tab_2">2</ref>. We remind that the runs whose names contain the label "g" or "ge" are those that use external collections in a first-pass retrieval. It is a matter of fact that the support of a very large additional collection, such as the whole collection of the WEB documents, improves the retrieval quality. This is achieved by further expanding the queries, already expanded with the external collection resource, with a second pseudo-relevance feedback over the target collection. This technique works independently from how long the query is obtained with the first loop of the QE process. On the other hand, the additional WEB collection resource seems to be less important or even superfluous with very long queries (TDN). In this case, the pseudo-relevance feedback over the target collection can be sufficient to obtain the maximal performance achievable with the system and the target collection.</p><p>The evaluation of the parameter-free model of QE achieves often better results than the model based on the optimal Rocchio parameter β. This can happen because we compute a sort of optimal value for β query-by-query, whilst the standard approach looks for the best-match value of the parameter β for all queries. As for the results of Table <ref type="table" coords="7,249.30,384.83,4.09,9.82" target="#tab_2">2</ref>, we also observe, but the results are not reported here, that Kendall's correlation factor is significantly lower than Spearman's correlation coefficient. Moreover, both Kendall's correlation factor and Spearman's correlation coefficient say that the Equation 8 provides a better queryperformance prediction when QE is not applied. The reason is that, if there are terms which have a high divergence between the term-frequencies within the set of pseudo-relevant documents and within the collection but are not included in the original query, then the difficult-score is lower than that if they were included. Obviously, these terms are included in the expanded query in the second-pass retrieval, and therefore the quality of the ranking is improved with respect to that of the the initial prediction.</p><p>The advantage of our predictor in Equation 8 is that has no additional computational cost if QE is adopted. Table <ref type="table" coords="7,283.54,547.42,5.45,9.82" target="#tab_2">2</ref> shows that if we eliminate 20% of all queries Equation 8 is able to raise the MAP of an average of 11.15% per run, and with an average of 29.67% achieved by Kendall's correlation factor.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,132.57,163.20,364.85,115.40"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>max</figDesc><table coords="4,132.57,163.20,364.85,115.40"><row><cell></cell><cell>t∈q</cell><cell>tfq</cell></row><row><cell>tfq</cell><cell cols="2">is the within-query term-frequency tfq of the term</cell></row><row><cell>Info DFR (t) =</cell><cell cols="2">-log 2 Prob( tf(t|R)| tf(t|D))</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">MaxInfo DFR = arg max t∈q  *  Info DFR (t)</cell></row><row><cell>tf(t|R)</cell><cell cols="2">is the term-frequency in the pseudo-relevant set R</cell></row><row><cell>tf(t|D)</cell><cell cols="2">is the term-frequency in the collection</cell></row><row><cell>Prob</cell><cell cols="2">is the probability of term-frequency computed by any DFR model</cell></row><row><cell>β</cell><cell cols="2">is a parameter in the interval [0, 1] (last year it was 0.4).</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="6,77.67,135.75,432.35,222.81"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Mean Average Precision and number of topics with no relevant document in the top 10 retrieved documents of all ten runs.</figDesc><table coords="6,83.65,188.10,426.37,170.46"><row><cell></cell><cell>old queries</cell><cell>new queries</cell><cell>hard queries</cell><cell>all queries</cell></row><row><cell>runs</cell><cell cols="4">MAP Nr top. MAP Nr top. MAP Nr top. MAP Nr top.</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">fub04T2ge 0.2870 17.0% 0.3295 16.3% 0.1331 26.0% 0.2954 16.9%</cell></row><row><cell>fub04Te</cell><cell cols="4">0.2881 17.0% 0.3322 12.2% 0.1367 26.0% 0.2968 16.1%</cell></row><row><cell>fub04Tg</cell><cell cols="4">0.2869 10.0% 0.3464 10.2% 0.1388 18.0% 0.2986 10.0%</cell></row><row><cell>fub04Tge</cell><cell cols="4">0.2985 13.0% 0.3514 12.2% 0.1450 22.0% 0.3089 12.9%</cell></row><row><cell>fub04De</cell><cell cols="4">0.2890 15.0% 0.3760 10.2% 0.1374 24.0% 0.3062 14.1%</cell></row><row><cell>fub04Dg</cell><cell cols="4">0.2954 7.5% 0.3636 8.2% 0.1470 14.0% 0.3088 7.6%</cell></row><row><cell>fub04Dge</cell><cell cols="4">0.3093 9.5% 0.3823 8.2% 0.1475 18.0% 0.3237 9.2%</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">fub04TDNe 0.3285 8.0% 0.3824 6.1% 0.1780 14.0% 0.3391 7.6%</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">fub04TDNg 0.3171 6.5% 0.3635 8.2% 0.1668 10.0% 0.3262 6.8%</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">fub04TDNge 0.3323 9.0% 0.3741 8.2% 0.1775 18.0% 0.3405 8.8%</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="7,77.67,135.75,411.02,210.56"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Kendall measure between AP ranks and query-difficulty ranks. Actual MAP, MAP without the predicted X worst queries and MAP without the actual X worst queries. fub04T2ge employs a random query-performance predictor.</figDesc><table coords="7,98.61,190.69,369.15,155.62"><row><cell>runs</cell><cell cols="3">Kendall MAP MAP -X =50 pred MAP -X=50 optimal</cell></row><row><cell>fub04T2ge</cell><cell>0.0070 0.2954</cell><cell>0.3064</cell><cell>0.3634</cell></row><row><cell>fub04Te</cell><cell>0.2770 0.2968</cell><cell>0.3273</cell><cell>0.3648</cell></row><row><cell>fub04Tg</cell><cell>0.2860 0.2986</cell><cell>0.3297</cell><cell>0.3648</cell></row><row><cell>fub04Tge</cell><cell>0.2840 0.2985</cell><cell>0.3404</cell><cell>0.3768</cell></row><row><cell>fub04De</cell><cell>0.3300 0.3089</cell><cell>0.3514</cell><cell>0.3781</cell></row><row><cell>fub04Dg</cell><cell>0.3090 0.3062</cell><cell>0.3456</cell><cell>0.3739</cell></row><row><cell>fub04Dge</cell><cell>0.2980 0.3088</cell><cell>0.3625</cell><cell>0.3934</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">fub04TDNe 0.2640 0.3391</cell><cell>0.3680</cell><cell>0.4114</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">fub04TDNg 0.3270 0.3262</cell><cell>0.3636</cell><cell>0.3945</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">fub04TDNge 0.2950 0.3405</cell><cell>0.3774</cell><cell>0.4116</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="4,95.60,633.67,188.48,8.97"><p>A new query-term must also appear at least in</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="4,295.43,633.67,193.26,8.97;4,77.67,645.62,411.02,8.97;4,77.67,657.58,45.66,8.97"><p>retrieved documents. This condition is to avoid the noise of the highly informative terms which appear only once in the set of the topmost retrieved documents.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_2" coords="5,95.60,572.15,393.09,8.97;5,77.67,584.11,399.50,8.97"><p>This parameter can be also eliminated query-by-query by choosing the number of topmost retrieved documents which maximise a normalised version of our (or any other) query-performance predictor.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_3" coords="5,95.60,596.07,393.09,8.97;5,77.67,608.02,250.43,8.97"><p>This parameter is the least important among the QE parameters. Indeed, even using many more expanded terms the performance does not change significantly.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_4" coords="8,95.60,631.85,156.20,8.97"><p>http://ir.dcs.gla.ac.uk/terrier/index.html</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The experiments were conducted using Terrier's Information Retrieval platform 4 . Terrier version 1.0.0 implements the parameter-free query expansion method described in Section 2.3 by default. Under the same setting of the run fub04Te (with c=2, N t = 40, |R| = 8), the last release of Terrier (version 1.0.0) gives better results than the official TREC results. The model used in this set of experiments is called DFR BM25 in Terrier version 1.0.0. MAP of DFR BM25 is 0.3015 with Terrier 1.0.0, if the model of query expansion is Bo2, while MAP is 0.3035, if the model of query expansion is Bo1.</p></div>
			</div>			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="8,130.97,313.93,328.46,9.82;8,130.96,327.48,328.46,9.82;8,130.96,341.03,24.55,9.82" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,228.38,313.93,231.05,9.82;8,130.96,327.48,142.06,9.82">Probability Models for Information Retrieval based on Divergence from Randomness</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Giambattista</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-06">June 2003</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Glasgow</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">PhD thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,130.97,359.56,328.46,9.82;8,130.96,373.11,328.47,9.82" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,395.26,359.56,64.17,9.82;8,130.96,373.11,323.83,9.82">FUB at TREC 10 web track: a probabilistic framework for topic relevance term weighting</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gianni</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Claudio</forename><surname>Carpineto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Giovanni</forename><surname>Romano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,130.96,386.65,328.47,9.82;8,130.96,400.20,328.47,9.82;8,130.96,413.75,186.05,9.82" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>In</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="8,351.92,386.65,107.51,9.82;8,130.96,400.20,143.10,9.82">Proceedings of the 10th Text Retrieval Conference TREC</title>
		<meeting>the 10th Text Retrieval Conference TREC<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>NIST Special Pubblication</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001. 2002</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="500" to="250" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,130.97,432.28,328.46,9.82;8,130.96,445.83,328.47,9.82;8,130.96,459.38,328.46,9.82;8,130.96,472.93,314.71,9.82" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,395.26,432.28,64.17,9.82;8,130.96,445.83,122.89,9.82">FUB at TREC 2003: Robust and web track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gianni</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Claudio</forename><surname>Carpineto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Giovanni</forename><surname>Romano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,144.10,459.38,281.21,9.82">Proceedings of the 12th Text Retrieval Conference TREC 2003</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the 12th Text Retrieval Conference TREC 2003<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="500" to="255" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,130.97,491.46,328.46,9.82;8,130.96,505.01,328.47,9.82;8,130.96,518.56,320.52,9.82" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,356.77,491.46,102.65,9.82;8,130.96,505.01,323.48,9.82">Probabilistic models of information retrieval based on measuring the divergence from randomness</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gianni</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Cornelis Joost</forename><surname>Van Rijsbergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,130.96,518.56,218.26,9.82">ACM Transactions on Information Systems (TOIS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="357" to="389" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,130.97,537.09,328.46,9.82;8,130.96,550.64,328.46,9.82;8,130.96,564.19,151.50,9.82" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,365.82,537.09,93.61,9.82;8,130.96,550.64,193.78,9.82">An information theoretic approach to automatic query expansion</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Carpineto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Mori</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Romano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Bigi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,334.81,550.64,124.61,9.82;8,130.96,564.19,65.64,9.82">ACM Transactions on Information Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,130.97,582.72,328.46,9.82;8,130.96,596.27,328.47,9.82;8,130.96,609.82,189.69,9.82" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,331.25,582.72,128.18,9.82;8,130.96,596.27,217.70,9.82">Improving retrieval feedback with multiple term-ranking function combination</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Carpineto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Romano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Giannini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,361.54,596.27,97.89,9.82;8,130.96,609.82,87.46,9.82">ACM Transactions on Information Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="290" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,130.96,130.30,328.47,9.82;9,130.96,143.85,328.47,9.82;9,130.96,157.40,328.46,9.82;9,130.96,170.95,328.47,9.82;9,130.96,184.50,39.09,9.82" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,341.09,130.30,118.34,9.82;9,130.96,143.85,173.59,9.82">TREC2003 Robust, HARD and QA track experimants using PIRCS</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Grunfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Kwok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Dinstl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Deng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,205.15,157.40,254.28,9.82;9,130.96,170.95,19.64,9.82">Proceedings of the 12th Text Retrieval Conference TREC 2003</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the 12th Text Retrieval Conference TREC 2003<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="500" to="255" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,130.97,203.03,328.46,9.82;9,130.96,216.58,328.46,9.82;9,130.96,230.13,328.46,9.82;9,130.96,243.68,106.52,9.82" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,130.96,216.58,168.69,9.82">Terrier Information Retrieval Platform</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Plachouras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,324.22,216.58,135.21,9.82;9,130.96,230.13,201.17,9.82">Proceedings of the 27th European Conference on IR Research (ECIR 2005)</title>
		<title level="s" coord="9,339.80,230.13,119.63,9.82;9,130.96,243.68,32.07,9.82">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<meeting>the 27th European Conference on IR Research (ECIR 2005)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,130.97,262.21,328.46,9.82;9,130.96,275.76,328.47,9.82;9,130.96,289.31,328.46,9.82;9,130.96,302.86,222.75,9.82" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,432.76,262.21,26.66,9.82;9,130.96,275.76,35.15,9.82">Okapi at trec-4</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Beaulieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gatford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Payne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,284.01,275.76,175.42,9.82;9,130.96,289.31,187.32,9.82">NIST Special Publication 500-236: The Fourth Text REtrieval Conference (TREC-4)</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Department of Commerce, National Institute of Standards and Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,130.97,321.39,328.46,9.82;9,130.96,334.94,328.47,9.82;9,130.96,348.48,328.46,9.82;9,130.96,362.03,158.78,9.82" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,224.95,321.39,213.67,9.82">Overview of the trec 2003 robust retrieval track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ellen</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,333.23,334.94,126.20,9.82;9,130.96,348.48,146.52,9.82">Proceedings of the 12th Text Retrieval Conference TREC 2003</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the 12th Text Retrieval Conference TREC 2003<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="500" to="255" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,130.97,380.56,328.46,9.82;9,130.96,394.11,328.47,9.82;9,130.96,407.66,328.47,9.82;9,130.96,421.21,328.46,9.82;9,130.96,434.76,314.71,9.82" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,251.88,394.11,207.55,9.82;9,130.96,407.66,114.64,9.82">Task-Specific Query Expansion (MultiTest Experiments for TREC 2003</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Yeung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Charles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gordon</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Cormack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Egidio</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Lynam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Terra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,144.10,421.21,281.21,9.82">Proceedings of the 12th Text Retrieval Conference TREC 2003</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the 12th Text Retrieval Conference TREC 2003<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="500" to="255" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
