<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,158.91,103.66,291.89,12.91;1,188.63,123.49,232.44,10.76">Novel approaches in Text Information Retrieval Experiments in the Web Track of TREC 2004</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,203.35,160.11,78.51,10.76"><forename type="first">Mohamed</forename><surname>Farah</surname></persName>
							<email>farah@lamsade.dauphine.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Paris Dauphine</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,305.10,160.11,101.26,10.76;1,191.47,174.06,40.38,10.76"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Vanderpooten Lamsade</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Paris Dauphine</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,158.91,103.66,291.89,12.91;1,188.63,123.49,232.44,10.76">Novel approaches in Text Information Retrieval Experiments in the Web Track of TREC 2004</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">716D3327725AA22BA25CCA947D930F32</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:01+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper, we report our experiments in the mixed query task of the Web track for TREC 2004. We deal with the problem of ranking Web documents within a multicriteria framework and propose a novel approach for information retrieval. We focus on the design of a set of criteria aiming at capturing complementary aspects of relevance. Moreover, we provide aggregation procedures that are based on decision rules, to get the ranking of relevant documents.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The TREC 2004 mixed query task of the Web track consists in searching a collection of about 1.25 million .Gov documents to find responses to 225 queries : 75 homepage finding (HP) queries, 75 named page (NP) finding queries and 75 topic distillation (TD) queries.</p><p>For the HP and NP finding sub-tasks, there is mainly one single document, either a homepage or not, that meets the information need behind the query. Therefore, precision-like measures such as rank reversal, are of the utmost interest. For the TD sub-task, many 'good entry points' to relevant sites can meet the information need. Consequently, a good precision-recall compromise is searched and measures such as average precision are relevant.</p><p>To deal with this task, two main approaches are conceivable. The first option is to devise a method that works whatever is the query. The second option is to conceive specific methods for each query type. This last option needs a filtering step to find to which type each unlabeled query belongs to.</p><p>Many factors or sources of evidence can be used to derive a ranking. Such factors are the document content and/or structure, the anchor text, the hyperlink structure of the collection, the URL features, etc. Existing approaches generate a ranking of documents based on a score that possibly combines many of these factors. This aggregation is done using either quite simple weighted sum or lexicographic order aggregation operator, or difficult to interpret measures.</p><p>In this first participation to the TREC conference series, we submitted one official run. We used a multicriteria approach where we focus on the design of a set of criteria aiming at capturing complementary aspects of relevance. We use 'natural procedures' to aggregate these criteria and rank documents accordingly. We conducted the experiments using a retrieval system designed and developed from scratch to support any search function that might be useful. In the experiments reported here, we process all the queries without a filtering process (option 2).</p><p>This paper is organized as follows. We first introduce the multicriteria framework where we describe the overall approach (section 2). In section 3, we describe our system specificities. Experimental results are presented in section 4. Conclusions are provided in the final section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The multicriteria framework</head><p>In this work, we acknowledge that the Web search environment is rich with multiple sources of evidence, all of which have strengths that presumably complement one another and weaknesses that can significantly deteriorate retrieval effectiveness when used by themselves. We therefore claim that being able to make effective use of the available information can significantly improve retrieval effectiveness.</p><p>We hereafter propose a formal approach for Web information retrieval where relevance is explicitly defined as multidimensional. The overall approach could be split into three phases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">The modelling phase</head><p>It consists firstly of the identification of the factors affecting relevance.</p><p>In the text information retrieval context, some factors have solidly been established as important, through extensive testing in the information retrieval literature, and could therefore be considered as the basis for criteria design <ref type="bibr" coords="1,504.44,613.14,10.79,8.97" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,516.89,613.14,7.47,8.97" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,526.03,613.14,12.44,8.97" target="#b9">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,540.14,613.14,11.82,8.97" target="#b10">11]</ref>. Such factors are :</p><p>-Term frequency (tf ) which is the number of occurrences of terms in documents. It is in fact widely accepted that the more often a term occurs within a document, the more likely it is important for that document. -Term locality (tl) which captures the presence of terms in specific structured portions of the documents such as the title or the keywords. -Document length (dl) which evaluates the information contained in documents.</p><p>-Term proximity (tp) which captures the nearness of query terms within documents since it is assumed that when query terms are close to each other, the document should best correspond to the information need behind the query.</p><p>Moreover, with the advent of the Web, factors pertaining to the popularity or visibility of documents have proven to improve performance. Such factors could be the scores induced by algorithms such as PageRank <ref type="bibr" coords="2,217.35,199.65,11.62,8.97" target="#b0">[1]</ref> or HITS <ref type="bibr" coords="2,269.59,199.65,11.62,8.97" target="#b4">[5]</ref> as well as simple measures such as documents in-degrees or out-degrees <ref type="bibr" coords="2,102.62,223.56,10.58,8.97" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. These factors are then used to develop a set of appropriate decision criteria. These criteria stand for the basis of pairwise comparisons among the potentially relevant candidate documents. Each criterion will give rise to a partial preference relation modelling the way two documents are compared.</p><p>Formally, a criterion is a real-valued function g defined on the set of candidate documents which aims at comparing any pair of documents d and d ′ , on a specific point of view, as follows :</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,80.76,374.75,184.68,10.64">g(d) ≥ g(d ′ ) ⇒ d 'is at least as relevant as' d ′</formula><p>Evaluating document according to each criterion can be affected by imprecision, uncertainty, or inaccurate determination. Moreover, There is no one best way to build criteria and different formulations can be acceptable. Therefore, a slight difference in the scores of two documents, with respect to one criterion, should not lead to discriminate them. In order to model imprecision underlying criteria design, we set the following discrimination thresholds <ref type="bibr" coords="2,226.51,480.78,11.62,8.97" target="#b6">[7]</ref> :</p><p>-An indifference threshold allows for two close-valued documents to be judged as equivalent although they do not have exactly the same performance on the criterion. The indifference threshold basically draws the boundaries between an indifference and a preference situations. -A preference threshold is introduced when we want or need to be more precise when describing a preference situation. Therefore, it establishes the boundaries between a situation of a strict preference and an hesitation between an indifference and a preference situations, namely a weak preference.</p><p>Thresholds can either be set as fixed or variable along the criterion scale.</p><p>Comparing two documents d and d ′ according to a criterion g j with an indifference threshold q j and a preference threshold p j , leads to the following preferential situations :</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,60.77,719.90,160.72,34.16">-dI j d ′ ⇔ -q j ≤ g j (d) -g j (d ′ ) ≤ q j -dQ j d ′ ⇔ -q j &lt; g j (d) -g j (d ′ ) ≤ p j -dP j d ′ ⇔ g j (d) -g j (d ′ ) &gt; p j</formula><p>where I j , Q j and P j represent respectively indifference, weak preference and strict preference relations restricted to criterion g j . These 3 relations could be grouped into an outranking relation S j such that dS j d ′ ⇔ g j (d) + q j ≥ g j (d ′ ).</p><p>Each criterion can be endowed with specific indicators of importance, namely its relative importance which gives an idea on what criteria are more important than others.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">The aggregation phase</head><p>This phase takes the partial preference structures induced by the criteria family and aggregates them into one or more overall preference relation(s) that model relevance. To do so, we use partial compensatory aggregation mechanisms that are based on the following basic principles to compare two documents d and d ′ <ref type="bibr" coords="2,397.49,279.33,11.62,8.97" target="#b7">[8]</ref> :</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,323.78,300.98,231.63,9.80">-A concordance principle : d 'is as least as relevant as' d ′</formula><p>if the majority of criteria agree with this assertion, and -A discordance principle : d 'is as least as relevant as' d ′ if none of the discordant criteria strongly refutes this assertion.</p><p>Formally, we build an overall outranking relation S, whose meaning is 'is at least as relevant as'. Therefore, dSd ′ if and only if the two above-mentioned conditions hold. These conditions may be more or less demanding, resulting in different outranking relations.</p><p>Let -F = {g 1 , . . . , g p } be a family of p criteria, -H be an overall preference relation, where H is P , Q, I or S, -H j be a partial preference relation, i.e. restricted to criterion g j , -C(dHd ′ ) = {j ∈ F : dH j d ′ } be the concordance coalition of criteria in favor of establishing dHd ′ .</p><p>We distinct two basic families of outranking relations.</p><p>If we do not have information on the relative importance of the criteria, we use conditions referring to the number of criteria supporting or refuting the outranking such as the following outranking relations :</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,385.70,625.54,170.21,10.63">dS 1 d ′ ⇔ C(dSd ′ ) = F (1)</formula><p>which is a well established relations.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="2,342.99,681.90,212.93,25.57">dS 2 d ′ ⇔ card(C(dP d ′ )) ≥ card(C(d ′ Qd)) and C(d ′ P d) = ∅<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where there should be more criteria concordant with dP d ′ than criteria concordant with d ′ Qd. At the same time, there should be no criterion concordant with d ′ P d.</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="3,72.95,114.22,219.94,10.63">dS 3 d ′ ⇔ card(C(dP d ′ )) ≥ card(C(d ′ P ∪ Q d)) (3)</formula><p>where there should be more criteria concordant with dP d ′ than criteria supporting a strict or weak preference in favor of d ′ .</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="3,83.25,187.67,209.65,10.64">dS 4 d ′ ⇔ card(C(dP d ′ )) ≥ card(C(d ′ P d))<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where there should be more criteria concordant with dP d ′ than criteria concordant with d ′ P d.</p><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_7" coords="3,129.48,249.62,81.66,10.18">S 1 ⊂ S 2 ⊂ S 3 ⊂ S 4</formula><p>since when we move from S j to S j+1 , the credibility of the comparisons gets weaker.</p><p>If the relative importance of criteria can be assessed, we can use more elaborated outranking relations that allow compensation in some directions but not others. More precisely, we can accept that a 'relatively' bad performance on one criterion g j can be compensated by a good performance on a more important criterion g i .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">The exploitation phase</head><p>In order to derive the final ranking, we need exploitation procedures that enrich the outranking relations elaborated in the aggregation phase. In fact, these relations are not necessarily transitive. To do so, we use information on how each document is compared to the other documents according to each outranking relation.</p><p>The exploitation procedure we use has its roots in the <ref type="bibr" coords="3,282.11,469.53,10.79,8.97" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,53.80,481.48,7.19,8.97" target="#b8">9]</ref>. It consists in partitioning the set of potential candidates D into r ranked classes leading to the definition of a complete preorder. Each class C h encloses documents that are considered as ex aequo where C 1 is the best class.</p><p>Each class C h results from a distillation process which is an iterative process starting from the base set E 0 = D \ {C 1 ∪ . . . ∪ C h-1 }. This process iterates over the outranking relations defined in the aggregation phase, starting from the well established relation till the less demanding one. Each iteration i tries to reduce the set of ex-aequo documents, starting from the distillate E i-1 , to get the distillate E i , as follows :</p><formula xml:id="formula_8" coords="3,58.28,630.27,234.60,22.56">1. Compute for each d ∈ E i-1 its qualification s i (d, E i-1</formula><p>), which is the difference of the number of documents that could be considered as 'better' in the one side, and 'worse' in the other side, than d according to S i , 2.</p><formula xml:id="formula_9" coords="3,58.28,689.42,172.27,21.94">s max = max d∈Ei-1 {s i (d, E i-1 )} 3. E i = {d ∈ E i-1 : s i (d, E i-1 ) = s max }</formula><p>The distillation process stops when card(E i ) = 1, otherwise, the last class will consist of the last distillate produced by the use of the less demanding outranking relation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">System description</head><p>To facilitate empirical investigation of the proposed methodology, we developed a prototype search engine implementing a basic multicriteria approach. The software is entirely implemented in java SDK1.4.1. It mainly consists of five agents (see figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,389.01,167.86,4.15,8.97" target="#fig_0">1</ref>) :</p><p>-A text parser which processes the TREC collection to get the document surrogates. In fact, document representation is based on its internal content delimited by the body tags, as well as texts in the URL, the title, keywords and description tags. Moreover, we use link anchor texts present in Web documents pointing to the current document since it is shown in <ref type="bibr" coords="3,471.31,258.73,11.62,8.97" target="#b2">[3]</ref> that such texts often provide accurate descriptions of pointed documents content. We consider only stems as index terms using the Porter algorithm to reduce the size of the inverted index. We also discard cuurent english stopwords, -A graph parser which builds the TREC graph where nodes are documents and edges are hyperlinks between documents, -An indexer which produces an inverted index of the whole collection, -A filtering agent which matches query terms with TREC documents to get the unordered base set of potentially relevant items, and -A ranking agent which implements the muticriteria algorithm.</p><p>Five criteria are considered in this study. We distinguish one-term queries having single terms from complex queries.</p><p>g 1 captures frequencies of query terms. For one-term queries, we use tf tf max where tf is the term frequency and tf max corresponds to the most frequent term in the document. For complex queries, we retain either the product or the sum aggregation operator.</p><p>g 2 captures the occurrences of query terms within the anchor text (location L 1 ), the URL (L2), the title (L 3 ), the keywords tag (L 4 ) and the description tag (L 5 ). For the one-term queries, we first compute a partial performance with respect to each location L i :</p><formula xml:id="formula_10" coords="3,350.91,665.70,187.34,10.39">g 2 (d, t, L i ) = number of occurrences of t in L i</formula><p>The overall score of each document with respect to this criterion is computed using the weighted sum operator as follows : where k i is an importance score for location L i . In fact, we suppose that some locations are more important that others.</p><formula xml:id="formula_11" coords="3,382.49,728.15,123.49,29.40">g 2 (d, t) = 5 i=1 k i g 2 (d, t, L i ) 5 i=1 k i</formula><p>For complex queries, the overall score is computed as</p><formula xml:id="formula_12" coords="4,136.34,499.49,90.94,20.35">g 2 (d, q) = t∈q g 2 (d, t)</formula><p>g 3 is a popularity measure. It is either the number of document in-links, or the authority score computed using the HITS algorithm. -g 4 aims at favoring entry points to relevant sites by determining for each document the number of its relevant children. -g 5 is a proximity criterion that is only considered for complex queries. It is inversely proportional to the minimal matching span of query terms in the document, i.e. the smallest text excerpt from the document that contains all the query terms.</p><p>It is obvious that these criteria play different roles for each specific task. Therefore, knowing to which type each topic belongs can lead to a definition of specific procedures for each query type. Since this is not the case, we consider that each criterion is neither predominant nor negligible and develop an aggregation procedure that is based on the outranking relations of equations ( <ref type="formula" coords="4,163.41,744.34,3.63,8.97">1</ref>)-( <ref type="formula" coords="4,177.93,744.34,3.63,8.97" target="#formula_6">4</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>We report here performances of the official run we submitted to the mixed query task of the Web track, as well as other runs we carried out after an expansion of our system so that it can process queries with high number of potentially relevant documents.</p><p>We begin with a detailed performance analysis on a per query type basis, then discuss overall performance of each run.</p><p>Beforehand, we begin with a brief description of the runs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">The Runs</head><p>The various runs we discuss in this paper are the followings :</p><p>-LamMcm1 : This is the official run we submitted to TREC 2004. It implements the aggregating and exploitation procedures of sections (2.2) and (2.3). Criteria g 1 to g 4 are considered where the product aggregation operator is used for the criterion g 1 . We suppose that no information on the relative importance of criteria is available. We therefore use the outranking relations of equations ( <ref type="formula" coords="4,414.64,364.56,3.73,8.97">1</ref>)-( <ref type="formula" coords="4,433.14,364.56,3.53,8.97" target="#formula_6">4</ref>). The indifference and preference thresholds are considered as variable. They are set to 20% and 50%, respectively. For each query, we only considered the first 500 processed documents from those that match query terms. This is basically due to the limitations of the prototype version of the system. -mcm1 : This is the same as LamMcm1 but uses another filtering mechanism which is based on criterion g 2 . In fact, we considered the first 1000 documents according to his criterion. This is the basic run for the followings. -mcm2 : Same as mcm1 but uses a different formulation of criterion g 1 . We used the sum operator to aggregate frequencies of the terms of the query. -mcm3 : Same as mcm1 but uses fixed thresholds. We used the following values : q = (0.05; 0; 5; 3) and p = (0.1; 0.25; 10; 6). -mcm4 : Same as mcm1 but uses criterion g 5 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">The HP/NP finding sub-tasks</head><p>HP/NP queries correspond to situations where users do not need large lists of relevant documents to search in but would rather prefer to get the URL of a specific home page (HP queries) or a non-home page document (NP queries).</p><p>Tables <ref type="table" coords="4,356.14,648.70,4.98,8.97" target="#tab_0">1</ref> and<ref type="table" coords="4,384.70,648.70,4.98,8.97" target="#tab_1">2</ref> depict various statistics based on relevance assessments of the HP and NP query tasks, respectively. They clearly show that there is one correct answer per HP/NP topic.</p><p>Tables <ref type="table" coords="4,354.17,696.51,4.98,8.97" target="#tab_2">3</ref> and<ref type="table" coords="4,378.81,696.51,4.98,8.97" target="#tab_3">4</ref> provide a summary description of the runs with respect to the HP/NP queries.</p><p>For the HP queries, using fix thresholds leads to the best run (mcm3) with MRR=56.77%, whereas using the sum aggregation operator for criterion g 1 retrieves more relevant items in the first position (S@1 = 46.67% for mcm2). Run mcm3 is also the best run to retrieve rapidly most of the correct answers (S@5=74.67% and S@10=80.00%).</p><p>For the NP queries, run mcm2 retrieves more relevant items in the top 5 and 10 retrieved list whereas run mcm1 is more efficient to get the relevant item in the first position (MRR=57.34% and S@1 = 45.20%).</p><p>Surprisingly, using criterion g 5 deteriorates performance for both the HP and TD queries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">The Topic Distillation sub-task</head><p>This task aims at retrieving 'key resources' on a given topic. There is no explicit definition of what constitutes a key resource. Nevertheless, it seems to be appropriate to return at first, father pages which have many relevant children. This is achieved by the criterion g 4 .</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="5,87.76,651.90,4.98,8.97">5</ref> provides a summary description of the runs with respect to the TD queries.</p><p>Firstly, this table shows low performance of the official run. This is principally due to the following factors:</p><p>-The run was not considered for judgment in the pooling procedure, which means that the best ranked documents of the run may not have been assessed for relevance judgements, Run AvP S@1 S@5 S@10 mcm1 13. <ref type="bibr" coords="5,424.23,106.91,8.07,8.07">25</ref>   <ref type="table" coords="5,354.89,161.54,3.36,8.07">5</ref>. description of the Runs for the TD task -In the prototype version of our system, among all the documents matching the query (the base set), only a subset of at most 500 documents could be processed. Therefore a wide number of relevant items are skipped for evaluation. In HP/NP tasks, this limitation does not have significant impact on the system performance, but in the TD task, there is an important impact on performance, -We did not use any training queries from last years to tune some parameters and especially thresholds.</p><p>Runs mcm1 and mcm2 have the best performances whereas performance falls down when the proximity criterion is used.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">The mixed-query task</head><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="5,341.19,399.95,4.98,8.97" target="#tab_6">6</ref> shows that :</p><p>-Run mcm2 is significantly better than the other runs, -Considering the proximity criterion deteriorates performance, and -The use of variant thresholds performs better.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Run</head><p>AvP S@1 S@5 S@10 mcm1 38. <ref type="bibr" coords="5,424.23,495.43,8.07,8.07">35</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>In this paper, we proposed a novel vision of the information retrieval problem and described a system that implements a multicriteria methodology. The ideas developed for the TREC collection of textual documents can be adapted to any family of criteria deemed to be relevant and respecting some properties. It also provides a general framework within which different document types could be searched and retrieved.</p><p>Further experiments are currently undertaken to help judge which criteria are more important than others or which ones are more task specific.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="4,126.59,410.69,93.51,8.07"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. System description</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,76.86,95.55,192.97,94.01"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Relevance judgment statistics for HP queries</figDesc><table coords="5,105.39,95.55,135.92,94.01"><row><cell>num_queries</cell><cell>75</cell></row><row><cell>num_rel_docs</cell><cell>83</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Mean_rel_docs / query 1.106</cell></row><row><cell>num_queries</cell><cell>75</cell></row><row><cell>num_rel_docs</cell><cell>78</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Mean_rel_docs / query 1.040</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,76.86,192.36,192.97,94.51"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Relevance judgment statistics for NP queries</figDesc><table coords="5,106.49,223.61,133.73,63.26"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>MRR S@1 S@5 S@10</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">mcm1 46.06 36.00 57.33 68.00</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">mcm2 55.67 46.67 65.33 74.67</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">mcm3 56.77 41.33 74.67 80.00</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">mcm4 35.33 29.33 41.33 49.33</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">LamMcm1 32.61 26.67 41.33 45.33</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,53.80,289.66,239.09,103.63"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Summary description of the Runs for the HP query finding task</figDesc><table coords="5,106.49,330.02,133.73,63.27"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>MRR S@1 S@5 S@10</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">mcm1 57.34 45.20 73.97 75.34</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">mcm2 56.99 41.10 79.45 82.19</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">mcm3 52.74 41.09 67.12 75.34</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">mcm4 50.79 38.35 65.75 69.86</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">LamMcm1 32.26 21.33 44.00 54.67</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,53.80,396.07,239.09,19.03"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Summary description of the Runs for the NP query finding task</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="5,369.50,495.43,132.70,51.90"><head>41.05 42.60 73.09 79.37 mcm3</head><label></label><figDesc>39.01 66.81 74.43 mcm2 39.68 34.98 69.05 76.68 mcm4 31.19 33.63 53.36 61.43 LamMcm1 22.68 21.78 41.78 48.89</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" coords="5,316.81,550.13,239.10,8.07"><head>Table 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Summary description of the Runs for the mixed-query task</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,61.65,120.36,231.24,8.07;6,69.98,131.32,222.90,8.07;6,69.98,142.28,222.91,8.07;6,69.98,153.24,61.01,8.07" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,152.13,120.36,140.75,8.07;6,69.98,131.32,66.96,8.07">Anatomy of a large-scale hypertextual web search engine</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Page</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,158.33,131.32,134.56,8.07;6,69.98,142.28,106.12,8.07">Proceedings of the 7th International World Wide Web Conference</title>
		<meeting>the 7th International World Wide Web Conference<address><addrLine>Brisbane, Australia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998-04">Apr. 1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,61.65,164.20,231.25,8.07;6,69.98,175.16,222.91,8.07;6,69.98,186.11,222.91,8.07;6,69.98,197.07,102.85,8.07" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,168.41,164.20,124.48,8.07;6,69.98,175.16,115.29,8.07">Webquery: Searching and visualizing the web through connectivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Carriere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kazman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,200.82,175.16,92.07,8.07;6,69.98,186.11,147.89,8.07">Proceedings of the 6th International World Wide Web Conference</title>
		<meeting>the 6th International World Wide Web Conference<address><addrLine>Santa Clara, California</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997-04">Apr. 1997</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,61.65,208.04,231.26,8.07;6,69.98,218.99,222.91,8.07;6,69.98,229.95,125.75,8.07" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,244.95,208.04,47.95,8.07;6,69.98,218.99,136.46,8.07">Effective site finding using link anchor information</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Crasswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hawking</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,226.72,218.99,66.18,8.07;6,69.98,229.95,40.79,8.07">Proceedings ACM SIGIR 2001</title>
		<meeting>ACM SIGIR 2001</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="250" to="257" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,61.65,240.91,231.25,8.07;6,69.98,251.87,222.92,8.07;6,69.98,262.83,222.90,8.07;6,69.98,273.79,222.91,8.07;6,69.98,284.74,20.17,8.07" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,124.12,240.91,168.78,8.07;6,69.98,251.87,149.12,8.07">Which words are particularly characteristic of a text ? a survey of statistical approaches</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kilgarriff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,238.62,251.87,54.28,8.07;6,69.98,262.83,222.90,8.07;6,69.98,273.79,92.24,8.07">Proceedings of the AISB Workshop on Language Engineering for Document Analysis and Recognition</title>
		<meeting>the AISB Workshop on Language Engineering for Document Analysis and Recognition<address><addrLine>Brighton, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996-04">Apr. 1996</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="40" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,61.65,295.71,231.24,8.07;6,69.98,306.67,217.66,8.07" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,133.64,295.71,159.25,8.07;6,69.98,306.67,36.52,8.07">Authoritative sources in a hyperlinked environnement</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kleinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,113.80,306.67,68.00,8.07">Journal of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="604" to="632" />
			<date type="published" when="1999-09">Sept. 1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,61.65,317.62,231.23,8.07;6,69.98,328.58,222.91,8.07;6,69.98,339.54,120.69,8.07" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,199.06,317.62,93.82,8.07;6,69.98,328.58,54.38,8.07">Simple proven approaches to text retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">Spark</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>356</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997-05">May 1997</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Cambridge University Computer Laboratory</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,61.65,350.50,231.24,8.07;6,69.98,361.46,222.91,8.07;6,69.98,372.41,127.76,8.07" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,107.77,350.50,185.11,8.07;6,69.98,361.46,81.64,8.07">Main sources of inaccurate determination, uncertainty and imprecision</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Roy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,163.25,361.46,129.65,8.07;6,69.98,372.41,19.42,8.07">Mathematical and Computer Modelling</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1245" to="1254" />
			<date type="published" when="1989">1989</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,61.65,383.37,231.25,8.12;6,69.98,394.34,128.23,8.07" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,173.02,383.37,119.88,8.12;6,69.98,394.34,56.46,8.07">Aide multicritère à la décision : Méthodes et cas</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Roy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Bouyssou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,133.22,394.34,38.31,8.07">Economica</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,61.65,405.29,231.24,8.07;6,69.98,416.25,222.90,8.07;6,69.98,427.21,177.73,8.07" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,166.02,405.29,126.87,8.07;6,69.98,416.25,218.74,8.07">Ranking of suburban line extension projects on the Paris metro system by a multicriteria method</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Roy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hugonnard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,69.98,427.21,105.70,8.07">Transportation Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="301" to="312" />
			<date type="published" when="1982">1982</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>A</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,61.27,438.17,231.62,8.07" xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,109.17,438.17,93.39,8.07">Automatic Text Processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1989">1989</date>
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,61.27,449.13,231.61,8.07;6,69.98,460.09,222.90,8.07;6,69.98,471.04,77.95,8.07" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,163.98,449.13,128.91,8.07;6,69.98,460.09,65.92,8.07">Term-weighting approaches in automatic text retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,142.00,460.09,146.44,8.07">Information Processing and Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="513" to="523" />
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
