<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,168.26,151.59,270.33,12.64;1,182.57,168.99,230.35,12.64">IHS-RD-BELARUS: Clinical Named Entities Identification in French Medical Texts</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,220.61,207.98,82.37,8.18"><forename type="first">Maryna</forename><surname>Chernyshevich</surname></persName>
							<email>marina.chernyshevich@ihs.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">IHS Inc. / IHS Global Belarus</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>131 Starovilenskaya St</addrLine>
									<postCode>220123</postCode>
									<settlement>Minsk</settlement>
									<country key="BY">Belarus</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,309.31,207.32,76.81,9.05"><forename type="first">Vadim</forename><surname>Stankevitch</surname></persName>
							<email>vadim.stankevitch@ihs.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">IHS Inc. / IHS Global Belarus</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>131 Starovilenskaya St</addrLine>
									<postCode>220123</postCode>
									<settlement>Minsk</settlement>
									<country key="BY">Belarus</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,168.26,151.59,270.33,12.64;1,182.57,168.99,230.35,12.64">IHS-RD-BELARUS: Clinical Named Entities Identification in French Medical Texts</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">B70D9E38DA240A0647C6F8D9DE6553C1</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:40+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Named-entity recognition</term>
					<term>Biomedical Texts</term>
					<term>Medical NLP</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper we present the results of our participation in the Task 1b of the 2015 CLEFeHealth challenge, whose goal was the identification of clinical entities of various types from medical texts in French and its normalization. We used the CRF-based system developed for disorder recognition in English and enhanced with French knowledge resources to recognize 10 types of clinic named entities from French medical texts: Anatomy, Chemical and Drugs, Devices, Disorders, Geographic Areas, Living Beings, Objects, Phenomena, Physiology and Procedures. Our system's performance in entity recognition task was evaluated at 0.70 and 0.52 Fmeasure in exact match mode and 0.80 and 0.70 F-measure in inexact match mode depending on test corpus. The obtained results are higher than the average of all submitted runs.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="842.04"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Electronic medical records are of great value for both patients and health professionals as well as for multiple related domains and industries. Providing medical domain with automated tools for plain text processing, data extraction and classification is nowadays a challenge of major importance. To facilitate the development of effective approaches for the analysis of biomedical texts, corresponding shared tasks have been organized such as CLEF 2013 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,416.47,520.69,10.66,9.05" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, SemEval 2014 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,148.64,532.21,10.72,9.05" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, and SemEval 2015 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,248.69,532.21,10.69,9.05" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. The CLEF eHealth 2015 shared task initiates the research in languages other than English and our goal was to automatically identify clinically relevant entities in medical text in French and to normalize these entities to a specific UMLS Concept Unique Identifier (CUI) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,337.27,566.90,15.39,8.96" target="#b9">[10]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" coords="1,360.12,566.90,15.39,8.96" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. The task was divided into three subtasks: plain entity recognition, normalized entity recognition and entity normalization.</p><p>Although our team participated in all subtasks our efforts were focused mainly on entities recognition task. For the normalization problem we have implemented a simple straightforward approach based on lookup in the UMLS terminology with quite poor performance. This approach needs further development.</p><p>In this paper we present a supervised CRF-based named entity recognition (NER) system that is capable of recognizing 10 types of clinical named entities from French medical texts: Anatomy, Chemical and Drugs, Devices, Disorders, Geographic Areas, Living Beings, Objects, Phenomena, Physiology and Procedures. The system was originally developed for English disorder identification in order to participate in the SemEval-2015 shared task "Analysis of clinical text" <ref type="bibr" coords="2,363.19,161.00,10.69,9.05" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Its performance was evaluated at F-measure of 0.898 for English dataset.</p><p>To adapt the system we added French lexicons and omitted some features not relevant for the proposed medical texts, for example, document section feature.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Materials and methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Data</head><p>The dataset provided by the organizers is called QUAERO French Medical Corpus and comes from the European Medicines Agency (EMEA) and Medline <ref type="bibr" coords="2,434.12,269.39,10.66,9.05" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. This dataset has been developed as a resource for named entity recognition and normalization in 2013.</p><p>The training set contains 833 MEDLINE titles and 11 EMEA documents and the test set contains 832 MEDLINE titles and 12 EMEA documents.</p><p>The annotation of clinical entities was guided by concepts in the Unified Medical Language System (UMLS) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,238.82,338.39,11.86,9.05" target="#b7">[8]</ref> and covers 10 types of clinical entities. The training set contained 5,690 annotations while the test set contained 5,237 annotations. Table <ref type="table" coords="2,465.82,349.79,4.98,9.05" target="#tab_0">1</ref> represents the distribution of the annotated entities among the categories. The entities were annotated in a comprehensive fashion, so that nested entities were marked, and entities could be mapped to more than one UMLS concept. For instance, in the phrase "infarctus du myocarde" (myocardial infarction), the mention "myocarde" (myocardium) should be annotated with category "ANATOMY" (CUI C0027061) and the mention "infarctus du myocarde" should be annotated with category "DISORDER" (CUI C0027051) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,256.85,430.33,15.34,9.05" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Entities recognition system</head><p>Clinical entity recognition can be thought of as a sequence segmentation problem: each word is a token in a sequence to be assigned a label. The most popular and powerful sequential learning model is Conditional Random Fields (CRFs)undirected statistical graphical models, a special case of which is a linear chain that corresponds to a conditionally trained finite-state machine <ref type="bibr" coords="2,360.04,671.78,10.66,8.96" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pre-processing</head><p>To facilitate feature generation for supervised CRF learning, sentences were preprocessed with French IHS Goldfire Linguistic Processor that performs the following operations: word splitting, part-of-speech tagging, parsing, noun phrase extraction, semantic role labelling within extended Subject-Action-Object (eSAO) relations <ref type="bibr" coords="3,448.57,201.56,10.66,9.05" target="#b2">[3]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Feature Set</head><p>Given a sentence S and a token under consideration , we define features over and window of 5 tokens: , , , , . 1. Lexical features: Canonical form of the token Wk itself is used as feature. In order to model local context of the word this class of features also includes canonical forms of neighbouring words in the window [-2,+2].</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Orthographic features:</head><p>This set of features is used to represent case and characters of the token . Letter case: token contains only upper case characters, token contains only lower case characters, first character is in upper case and the word is not the first in the sentence, token contains at least one upper case and one lower case characters.</p><p>Characters: token contains intra-word dash, token contains slash, token is a digit or contains a digit, token is a punctuation mark.</p><p>3. Part of speech feature: We include as features the part of speech information produced by IHS Goldfire Linguistic Processor.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Word frequency in out-of-domain corpus:</head><p>We used social media texts as an out-of-domain corpus to calculate the word frequencies. The feature has four values: very rarely, rarely, frequently and vary frequently used with a empirically determined thresholds.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Knowledge-based features:</head><p>In addition to orthography and syntactic structures, the model could also benefit from generalized semantic word groups. This sort of semantic domain knowledge can be provided in the form of lexicons. We created two types of lexicons: clinical lexicon and general lexicon.</p><p>The clinical lexicon was created using the 2014AA multilingual release of the UMLS Metathesaurus. It contains about 5 million entities for English and 2500 for French. We created dictionaries for each of 10 categories for both English and French. To comply with the annotation guidelines, each category combines many UMLS semantic types. For example, category ANATOMY encompasses following semantic types: Anatomical Structure; Body Location and Region; Body Part, Organ or Organ Component; Body Space or Junction; Body Substance; Body System; Cell; Cell Component; Embryonic Structure; Fully Formed Anatomical Structure; Tissue.</p><p>The general lexicon consists of lists of words from general domain translated automatically form English to French: materials ("métal"), units of measure ("ml"), person's professions ("infirmière"). These lexicons were originally created for English using the WordNet <ref type="bibr" coords="3,238.06,620.44,10.66,9.05" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. We have selected some top-level nodes, for example, physical property, human, process etc. and all subordinate terms were assumed to belong to the appropriate category <ref type="bibr" coords="3,264.26,643.48,10.66,9.05" target="#b5">[6]</ref>.</p><p>Using the lexicons following features were assigned to each token: Clinical lexicon features: 10 features representing presence of token or sequence of tokens in particular category. The value of the features indicates quantity of tokens in a sequence that match lexicon exactly. For example, all tokens in the phrase "infarctus du myocarde" become value 3 for a disorder feature and token "myocarde" becomes value 1 for an anatomy feature. For lexicon entries that are multi-word, all words are required to match in the input sequence.</p><p>General lexicon features: This feature represents the semantic class to which the token belongs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Classification</head><p>Based on the fact that there are nested and overlapping entities of different types we decided to model the problem as a supervised classification into two classes (target entity or not) instead of multi-class classification.</p><p>We created 10 training corpora with the same set of properties but with different entities labelled and then converted the sets into a BIO format, in which each word is assigned into one of three labels: B means the beginning of an entity, I means the inside of an entity, and O means the outside of an entity. In case of embedded entities of the same type we dismissed the entity of lower length. For example, in the training set the entity "maladie de Parkinson" is annotated as disorder and the word "maladie" is also annotated as separate disorder mention, we left only the entity "maladie de Parkinson".</p><p>We trained 10 CRF models and then simply merged the classification results of all models. We didn't use any post-processing step to analyze cases of contradicting predictions of the classifiers, for example when the same token was recognized as entity of different type.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Entities normalization</head><p>For the entities normalization subtask we implemented a simple algorithm that chooses all possible variants of normalized name for an entity. We generated putatively related strings, i.e. variants, synonyms and translations to English, and selected all CUIs that include all words from the particular entity variant. This approach generated large amount of normalized CUI variants for some ambiguous entities like "traitement" and caused thereby very low precision.</p><p>In the future we are going to implement a ranking algorithm to select the best of all CUI variants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head><p>The system's ability to correctly identify the clinical entities was evaluated using precision, recall, and F-measure.</p><p>Evaluation was carried out under two settings:  exact match: a predicted mention is considered a true positive if the predicted span is exactly the same as for the gold-standard mention;  inexact match: a predicted mention is a true positive if there is any word overlapping between the predicted mention span and the gold standard span. A total of seven teams participated in the task, submitted 10 system runs. The results of our best submitted run compared to average and median results are summarized in the table 2.</p><p>Our best run produced 0 in exact match for EMEA due to a technical issue: we submitted predictions with shifted spans of start and end positions. The results with corrected spans are included in the table 3 under "Later submitted run" title. Our system obtained very competitive results: 0.80 and 0.70 F-measure on test set under inexact match setting and 0.70 and 0.52 F-measure under exact match setting. These results are almost two times better than the Average/Median results. The official rank of submissions is not published at the time of publication. Our system performs well in recognizing chemical and drugs, living beings and disorders, but it fails in recognizing phenomena and devices. Table <ref type="table" coords="5,404.11,364.43,4.98,9.05" target="#tab_2">3</ref> provides more precise named entity classification results by categories. In order to determine the importance of individual features, ablation experiments were carried out. Table <ref type="table" coords="5,226.25,615.26,4.98,8.96" target="#tab_3">4</ref> shows the resulting changes in the F-measure in inexact match mode. Rows are ordered by features set impact on the full gold standard. Positive values indicate that a feature group has a negative impact on classification quality: results are improved by omitting the features. The most important features are knowledge-based features, closely followed by lexical features. Other features contributed relatively small individual effects, but were necessary to achieve the overall performance in combination.</p><p>As for the entities normalization subtask, our system performs poorly and needs further development. The submitted results of the system are illustrated in table 5 and are compared against the average and median results. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper we presented a supervised statistical system originally developed for English disorder recognition and adapted for French language to participate in shared task 1b of the CLEF eHealth 2015 lab on Clinical Named Entity Recognition.</p><p>Our system makes use of CRF for identifying clinical entities of 10 types: Anatomy, Chemical and Drugs, Devices, Disorders, Geographic Areas, Living Beings, Objects, Phenomena, Physiology, Procedures. The results achieved for the entity recognition subtask are quite promising: 0.80/0.70 F-measure in inexact match and 0.70/0.52 F-measure in exact match mode depending on test corpus. These results are close to the ability of our system to recognize disorder mentions in English texts: F-measure of 0.89. This fact proves promising adaptability of proposed approach to different languages. Although these results are positive, there is still room to improve the systems. In future, we would like to explore semi-supervised learning approaches to take advantage of large amount of unannotated clinical text. It would be also interesting to adapt the proposed system to other languages.</p><p>In the future we will focus especially on the entity normalization subtask to improve our result.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,167.66,453.67,236.68,142.58"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Distribution of annotated entities</figDesc><table coords="2,178.22,471.73,226.12,124.52"><row><cell></cell><cell>Training set</cell><cell>Test set</cell></row><row><cell>Anatomy</cell><cell>742</cell><cell>649</cell></row><row><cell>Chemical and Drugs</cell><cell>1073</cell><cell>1237</cell></row><row><cell>Devices</cell><cell>87</cell><cell>76</cell></row><row><cell>Disorders</cell><cell>1699</cell><cell>1350</cell></row><row><cell>Geographic Areas</cell><cell>56</cell><cell>75</cell></row><row><cell>Living Beings</cell><cell>570</cell><cell>596</cell></row><row><cell>Objects</cell><cell>98</cell><cell>85</cell></row><row><cell>Phenomena</cell><cell>79</cell><cell>59</cell></row><row><cell>Physiology</cell><cell>279</cell><cell>291</cell></row><row><cell>Procedures</cell><cell>1007</cell><cell>819</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,124.82,241.85,345.88,95.16"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>System results for entity recognition subtask under exact and inexact evaluation settings (F-measure)</figDesc><table coords="5,130.22,270.23,332.17,66.78"><row><cell></cell><cell>EMEA</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>MEDLINE</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">exact match inexact match exact match inexact match</cell></row><row><cell>Best submitted run</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.80</cell><cell>0.52</cell><cell>0.70</cell></row><row><cell>Later submitted run</cell><cell>0.70</cell><cell>0.80</cell><cell>0.52</cell><cell>0.70</cell></row><row><cell>Average</cell><cell>0.31</cell><cell>0.40</cell><cell>0.39</cell><cell>0.57</cell></row><row><cell>Median</cell><cell>0.22</cell><cell>0.55</cell><cell>0.45</cell><cell>0.66</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,124.82,399.31,345.53,201.87"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>System results for particular entity type in entity recognition subtask (F-measure)These results demonstrate the dependence of CRF classification performance on the training set volume. The types that were rarely encountered in the training set (Devices, Phenomena, Objects) have the lowest F-measure.</figDesc><table coords="5,130.22,417.37,332.97,135.81"><row><cell></cell><cell>EMEA</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>MEDLINE</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">exact match inexact match exact match inexact match</cell></row><row><cell>Anatomy</cell><cell>0.71</cell><cell>0.80</cell><cell>0.59</cell><cell>0.68</cell></row><row><cell>Chemical and Drugs</cell><cell>0.77</cell><cell>0.86</cell><cell>0.58</cell><cell>0.70</cell></row><row><cell>Devices</cell><cell>0.38</cell><cell>0.47</cell><cell>0.10</cell><cell>0.17</cell></row><row><cell>Disorders</cell><cell>0.63</cell><cell>0.79</cell><cell>0.56</cell><cell>0.80</cell></row><row><cell>Geographic Areas</cell><cell>0.45</cell><cell>0.45</cell><cell>0.46</cell><cell>0.49</cell></row><row><cell>Living Beings</cell><cell>0.82</cell><cell>0.85</cell><cell>0.54</cell><cell>0.60</cell></row><row><cell>Objects</cell><cell>0.61</cell><cell>0.56</cell><cell>0.14</cell><cell>0.15</cell></row><row><cell>Phenomena</cell><cell>0.12</cell><cell>0.11</cell><cell>0.03</cell><cell>0.07</cell></row><row><cell>Physiology</cell><cell>0.40</cell><cell>0.43</cell><cell>0.22</cell><cell>0.26</cell></row><row><cell>Procedures</cell><cell>0.74</cell><cell>0.84</cell><cell>0.48</cell><cell>0.58</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,124.82,672.94,220.46,8.18"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Results of feature ablation experiments (F-measure)</figDesc><table coords="6,138.86,151.04,296.37,89.85"><row><cell></cell><cell>EMEA</cell><cell>MEDLINE</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>inexact match</cell><cell>inexact match</cell></row><row><cell>All features:</cell><cell>0.80</cell><cell>0.70</cell></row><row><cell>-knowledge-based features</cell><cell>0.62 (-0.18)</cell><cell>0.52 (-0.18)</cell></row><row><cell>-lexical features</cell><cell>0.67 (-0.13)</cell><cell>0.58 (-0.12)</cell></row><row><cell>-orthographic features</cell><cell>0.79 (-0.01)</cell><cell>0.70 (0.0)</cell></row><row><cell>-out-of-domain frequency</cell><cell>0.79 (-0.01)</cell><cell>0.70 (0.0)</cell></row><row><cell>-part-of-speech feature</cell><cell>0.84 (+0.04)</cell><cell>0.68 (-0.02)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="6,124.82,337.61,345.88,83.66"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>System results for entity normalization subtask under exact and inexact evaluation settings (F-measure)</figDesc><table coords="6,130.22,365.99,332.13,55.28"><row><cell></cell><cell>EMEA</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>MEDLINE</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">exact match inexact match exact match inexact match</cell></row><row><cell>Best submitted run</cell><cell>0.10</cell><cell>0.69</cell><cell>0.07</cell><cell>0.57</cell></row><row><cell>Average</cell><cell>0.61</cell><cell>0.82</cell><cell>0.47</cell><cell>0.65</cell></row><row><cell>Median</cell><cell>0.87</cell><cell>0.89</cell><cell>0.67</cell><cell>0.68</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,128.23,177.23,325.46,8.10;7,142.82,187.55,321.34,8.10;7,142.82,197.87,298.24,8.10;7,142.82,208.22,151.31,8.19" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,372.91,177.23,80.77,8.10;7,142.82,187.55,291.23,8.10">The QUAERO French Medical Corpus: A Ressource for Medical Entity Recognition and Normalization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Névéol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Grouin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leixa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rosset</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Zweigenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,440.14,187.55,24.02,8.10;7,142.82,197.87,298.24,8.10;7,142.82,208.22,97.36,8.19">Fourth Workshop on Building and Evaluating Ressources for Health and Biomedical Text Processing -BioTxtM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="30" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,128.23,218.63,317.17,8.10;7,142.82,228.98,300.60,8.10;7,142.82,239.30,71.99,8.10" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,391.75,218.63,53.65,8.10;7,142.82,228.98,134.99,8.10">Introduction to WordNet: An on-line lexical database</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Beckwith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Fellbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993-03">March 1993</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Princeton. CSL Report 43</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,128.23,249.74,336.01,8.10;7,142.82,260.06,279.55,8.10" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,308.71,249.74,155.53,8.10;7,142.82,260.06,118.84,8.10">System and method for automatic semantic labeling of natural language texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Todhunter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Sovpel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Pastanohau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,267.14,260.06,40.95,8.10">U.S. Patent</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="583" to="422" />
			<date type="published" when="2013-11-12">November 12, 2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,128.23,270.38,319.70,8.10;7,142.82,280.70,315.48,8.10;7,142.82,291.14,198.03,8.10" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,298.11,270.38,149.82,8.10;7,142.82,280.70,188.68,8.10">Conditional Random Fields: Probabilistic Models for Segmenting and Labeling Sequence Data</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Pereira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,350.11,280.70,108.19,8.10;7,142.82,291.14,169.44,8.10">Proceedings of the Eighteenth International Conference on Machine Learning</title>
		<meeting>the Eighteenth International Conference on Machine Learning</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,128.23,301.46,327.49,8.10;7,142.82,311.78,316.85,8.10;7,142.82,322.10,315.62,8.10;7,142.82,332.54,258.75,8.10" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,265.61,322.10,192.83,8.10">Overview of the shARe/CLEF eHealth evaluation lab</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Suominen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Salanterä</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Velupillai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Savova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Elhadad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Pradhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>South</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Mowery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J F</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leveling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Martinez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,177.58,332.54,197.75,8.10">Proceedings of ShARe/CLEF eHealth Evaluation Labs</title>
		<meeting>ShARe/CLEF eHealth Evaluation Labs</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013. 2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,128.23,342.86,290.40,8.10;7,142.82,353.18,292.00,8.10;7,142.82,363.50,304.29,8.10;7,142.82,373.94,301.87,8.10" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,289.72,342.86,128.91,8.10;7,142.82,353.18,192.86,8.10">IHS-RD-Belarus: Identification and Normalization of Disorder Concepts in Clinical Notes</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chernyshevich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Stankevitch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,354.07,353.18,80.75,8.10;7,142.82,363.50,233.21,8.10">Proceedings of the 9th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval 2015)</title>
		<meeting>the 9th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval 2015)<address><addrLine>Denver, Colorado</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">June 4-5, 2015. c 2015. 2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="380" to="384" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,128.23,384.28,334.34,8.10;7,142.82,394.60,325.71,8.10;7,142.82,404.92,322.64,8.10;7,142.82,415.36,237.62,8.10" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,142.82,394.60,178.26,8.10">SemEval-2015 Task 14: Analysis of Clinical Text</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Elhadad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Pradhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lipsky Gorman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Manandhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Savova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,339.55,394.60,128.98,8.10;7,142.82,404.92,185.00,8.10">Proceedings of the 9th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval 2015)</title>
		<meeting>the 9th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation (SemEval 2015)<address><addrLine>Denver, Colorado</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">June 4-5, 2015. c 2015. 2105</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="303" to="310" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,128.23,425.68,340.06,8.10;7,142.82,436.00,200.43,8.10" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,205.49,425.68,262.80,8.10;7,142.82,436.00,45.05,8.10">The Unified Medical Language System (UMLS): Integrating Biomedical Terminology</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Bodenreider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,194.25,436.00,84.81,8.10">Nucleic Acids Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="270" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,128.23,446.32,330.22,8.10;7,142.82,456.76,316.37,8.10;7,142.82,467.08,201.16,8.10" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,404.83,446.32,53.61,8.10;7,142.82,456.76,118.02,8.10">SemEval-2014 Task 7: Analysis of Clinical Text</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Pradhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Elhadad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Chapman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Manandhar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Savova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,279.41,456.76,179.77,8.10;7,142.82,467.08,74.84,8.10">Proceedings of the 8th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation</title>
		<meeting>the 8th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation<address><addrLine>SemEval</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="54" to="62" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,132.40,477.40,330.80,8.10;7,142.82,487.72,306.36,8.10;7,142.82,498.16,295.02,8.10;7,142.82,508.48,159.24,8.10" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,187.85,487.72,170.32,8.10">Overview of the CLEF eHealth Evaluation Lab</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Suominen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hanlen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Névéol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Grouin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Palotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,395.34,487.72,53.84,8.10;7,142.82,498.16,228.44,8.10">Proceedings of CLEF 2015 -6th Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<title level="s" coord="7,377.95,498.16,59.89,8.10;7,142.82,508.48,90.72,8.10">Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNCS</title>
		<meeting>CLEF 2015 -6th Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015. 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,132.40,518.80,338.07,8.10;7,142.82,529.12,308.93,8.10;7,142.82,539.47,300.60,8.10" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,154.94,529.12,280.81,8.10">CLEFeHealth Evaluation Lab 2015 Task 1b: clinical named entity recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Névéol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Grouin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Tannier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hamon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Zweigenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,142.82,539.47,227.62,8.10">Proceedings of CLEF 2015. CLEF 2015 Online Working Notes</title>
		<meeting>CLEF 2015. CLEF 2015 Online Working Notes</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CEUR-WS</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
