<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,185.60,148.86,231.82,15.15">SINAI at ImageCLEF 2007</title>
				<funder ref="#_5WgrqXU">
					<orgName type="full">Spanish Government</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,153.22,182.75,80.30,8.74"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Díaz-Galiano</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Departamento de Informática Grupo Sistemas Inteligentes de Acceso a la Información Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,241.43,182.75,103.01,8.74"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Departamento de Informática Grupo Sistemas Inteligentes de Acceso a la Información Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,352.61,182.75,92.67,8.74"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Martín-Valdivia</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Departamento de Informática Grupo Sistemas Inteligentes de Acceso a la Información Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,222.55,196.70,71.68,8.74"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Montejo-Raez</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Departamento de Informática Grupo Sistemas Inteligentes de Acceso a la Información Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,302.39,196.70,78.06,8.74"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ureña-López</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Departamento de Informática Grupo Sistemas Inteligentes de Acceso a la Información Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,185.60,148.86,231.82,15.15">SINAI at ImageCLEF 2007</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">21D154153AEE95529E60A516AD388EC9</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:14+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.3 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: H.3.1 Content Analysis and Indexing</term>
					<term>H.3.3 Information Search and Retrieval</term>
					<term>H.3.4 Systems and Software Visual and textual retrieval, Information Gain, Indexing, Machine Translators, Ontologies, MeSH</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the SINAI team participation in the ImageCLEF campaign. The SINAI research group has participated in both the ad hoc task and the medical task. The experiments accomplished in both cases result from very different approaches.</p><p>For the ad hoc task the main Information Retrieval (IR) system used combines the document lists retrieved by two IR systems, and uses online translators for the bilingual experiments.</p><p>For the medical task, we have used the MeSH ontology to expand the queries. The expansion consists in searching terms of the query in the MeSH ontology in order to add similar terms. We have processed the set of collections using Information Gain (IG) in the same way as in ImageCLEFmed 2006.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This is the third participation of the SINAI research group at the ImageCLEF campaign. We have participated in the ad hoc task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,228.46,584.25,10.52,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref> and the medical task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,336.71,584.25,9.97,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p><p>The ad hoc task involves retrieving relevant images using the text associated to each image query. As a cross-language retrieval task, multilingual image retrieval based on query translation can achieve a higher performance than monolingual retrieval.</p><p>This year, a new IR module has been tested. This module works with two different IR systems and the final relevant list is the result of the combination of both IR lists. The Machine Translation Module developed last year has been updated and used for the bilingual task. English, Spanish, French, Italian and Portuguese are the languages used this year.</p><p>The goal of the medical task is to retrieve relevant images based on an image query. This year, two new collections have been introduced. We have filtered all the collections using IG to select the best tags of each one <ref type="bibr" coords="1,202.45,703.80,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Moreover, we have expanded the queries using MeSH ontology: we have selected similar terms to the query in the ontology and have added them to the query itself.</p><p>The following section describes the ad hoc experiments. In Section 3, we explain the experiments for the medical task. Finally, conclusions and futher work are presented in Section 4.</p><p>Given a multilingual query, the goal of the ad hoc task is to find as many relevant images as possible from an image collection.</p><p>The proposal of the ad hoc task is to compare results with and without pseudo-relevant feedback (PRF), with or without query expansion, using different methods of query translation or using different retrieval models and weighing functions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Experiments Description</head><p>In our experiments we have used the five following languages: English, French, Italian, Portuguese and Spanish.</p><p>This year we have combined lists of relevant documents returned by two different IR systems: Lemur<ref type="foot" coords="2,118.12,262.03,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref> and Jirs <ref type="bibr" coords="2,164.31,263.60,9.97,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p><p>As translation module we have used SINTRAM (SINai TRAnslation Module), our Meta Machine Translation system that uses some online Machine Translators for each language pair and implements some heuristics to combine the different translations <ref type="bibr" coords="2,370.86,299.47,9.96,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. After a complete research we have found that the best translators were:</p><p>• Systran for French, Italian and Portuguese</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>• Prompt for Spanish</head><p>The dataset is the collection IAPR. The IAPR TC-12 image collection consists of 20,000 images taken from different locations around the world and comprises a varying cross-section of still natural images. It includes pictures of a range of sports and actions, photographs of people, animals, cities, landscapes and many others of contemporary life.</p><p>The collections have been preprocessed using stopwords removal and the Porter's stemmer. The dataset of the collection has been indexed using both IR systems, namely, Lemur and Jirs. One parameter for each experiment is the weighing function, such as Okapi or TFIDF. Another is the use or not of PRF.</p><p>A simple fusion method has been implemented to obtain a simple list of relevant documents. In the first step, both lists are normalized between 0 and 1. Then, some heuristics are implemented:</p><p>• Weighing each list. Some experiments are based on a weighing function that gives a percentage of importance to the Lemur list and a different one to the Jirs list. The final score of each relevant document is calculated by the sum of each score multiplied by its weight. Finally, the documents are sorted by their final fusion score.</p><p>• Using a threshold. Filtering relevant documents by a threshold value is another heuristic.</p><p>If the score of a document is worse than this parameter, it is not included in the final list. Finally, the resultant list is sorted by the score of the included documents.</p><p>With the ad hoc 2006 framework (using the same collection, queries and relevance judgements) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,90.00,609.12,10.52,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref> and the heuristics already described we have evaluated several configurations in order to obtain the best ones. 4. In the case of the second heuristic, different values, from 0.1 to 0.9, are tested as threshold.</p><p>The best result was 0.1524, obtained with 0.1 value as threshold.</p><p>Finally, all the Lemur weighing functions have been tested and the best one was again Okapi with feedback, with a result of 0.1672.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Results and Discussion</head><p>With the results obtained with the 2006 framework, the new 2007 queries were run. We sent 15 runs: five runs using Lemur, five using Jirs and five with the fusion of both lists.</p><p>The results obtained with each IR system (using only text) and the best MAP for each language is shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,169.26,523.88,3.88,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p><p>Good results have been obtained this year with both IR systems. Only the English runs have obtained a loss of MAP of around 25%. Our best Spanish result is similar to the best one obtained. For Portuguese we have obtained the best one, and for French and Italian our results are a bit worse: only a loss of MAP of around 8%. The MAP values are low because only the title is used as query.</p><p>From these results we can conclude that Lemur IR system works better than Jirs, but the difference is not very significant.</p><p>The results obtained by applying the fusion method and the best MAP for each language is shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,159.24,631.48,3.88,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref>.</p><p>The main conclusion for these fusion results is that there may be a problem, because it is not logical to obtain so poor results.</p><p>Experiments with the 2006 framework gave us similar results between the ones obtained with each simple IR system and the fusion ones.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">The Medical Task</head><p>The main goal of the medical ImageCLEF task is to improve the retrieval of medical images from heterogeneous and multilingual document collections containing images and text. Queries are formulated with sample images and some textual description explaining the research goal. For the medical task we have used the list of retrieved images by FIRE<ref type="foot" coords="4,370.97,122.40,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_1">2</ref>  <ref type="bibr" coords="4,379.23,123.98,9.97,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, which was supplied by the organizers of this track.</p><p>Last year, our efforts concentrated on manipulating the text descriptions associated with these images and mixing the results partial lists with the GIFT lists <ref type="bibr" coords="4,354.57,159.84,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. We also focused on preprocessing the collection using Information Gain (IG) in order to improve the quality of results and to automatize the tag selection process. However, this year we have concentrated on improving the queries using MeSH ontology.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Preprocessing the Collection</head><p>In order to generate the textual collection we have used the ImageCLEFmed.xml file that links collections with their images and annotations. It has external links to the images and to the associated annotations in XML files. It contains relative paths from the root directory to all the related files.</p><p>The entire collection consists of six datasets (CASImage, Pathopic, Peir, MIR, endoscopic and MyPACS) containing about 66,600 images (16,600 more than the previous year). Each subcollection is organized into cases that represent a group of related images and annotations. In every case a group of images and an optional annotation is given. Each image is part of a case and has optional associated annotations, which enclose metadata and/or a textual annotation. All the images and annotations are stored into separated files. ImageCLEFmed.xml only contains the connections between collections, cases, images and annotations.</p><p>The collection annotations are in XML format and most of them are in English. We have preprocessed the collections to generate a textual document per image <ref type="bibr" coords="4,400.51,385.45,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>.</p><p>We have used the IG measure to select the best XML tags in the collection. Once the document collection was generated, experiments were conducted with the Lemur retrieval information system by applying the KL-divergence weighing scheme.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Expanding Queries with MeSH Ontology</head><p>The Medical Subject Headings (MeSH) is a thesaurus developed by the National Library of Medicine<ref type="foot" coords="4,129.02,477.97,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_2">3</ref> . MeSH contains two organization files, an alphabetic list with bags of synonymous and related terms, and a hierarchical organization of descriptors associated to the terms. A term is composed by one o more words.</p><p>We have used the bags of terms to expand the queries. If all the words of a term are in the query, we generate a new expanded query by adding all its bag of terms. To compare the words of a particular term and those of the query, we first put all the words in lowercase and we do not remove stopwords. In order to reduce the number of terms that could expand the query, we have only used those that are in A, C or E categories of MeSH (A: Anatomy, C: Diseases, E: Analytical, Diagnostic and Therapeutic Techniques and Equipment) <ref type="bibr" coords="4,340.31,575.19,9.97,8.74" target="#b7">[8]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Experiment Description</head><p>Our main objective is to investigate the effectiveness of the query expansion together with filtering tags using IG in the text collection. We have carried out these experiments using a corpus with 20%, 30%, 40%, 50% and 60% of tags for the 2007 collection, because these settings led to the best results on the 2006 corpus.</p><p>Finally, the expanded textual list and the FIRE list are merged in order to obtain one final list (FL) with relevant images ranked by relevance. The merging process was done by giving different importance to the visual (VL) and textual lists (TL): We have submitted runs with α set to 0.5, 0.6, 0.7 and 0.8. The baseline experiments contain the 100% of the tags. To compare the mixed results we have accomplished experiments with an α = 1.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="4,238.82,715.11,274.18,8.74">F L = T L * α + V L * (1 -α)<label>(1)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Results and Discussion</head><p>The total runs submitted to ImageCLEFmed2007 for textual retrieval and mixed retrieval were more than 100.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="5,133.08,507.17,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_2">3</ref> shows the best results for the groups participating in ImageCLEFmed2007. In this table we can observe that the best result obtained by our system is the experiment with 100% of the tags and α = 0.8 (80% of textual information).</p><p>In Table <ref type="table" coords="5,143.19,543.03,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_3">4</ref> we can see the results of only textual experiments. The best result obtained is 0.3668 of precision value, using 100% of tags in the collection. Surprisingly, the IG selection experiments do not improve the results. However, by using 40% of tags the loss of precision is lower than 5%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions and Further Work</head><p>This year the ad hoc task obtained good results, but always with a low MAP, because only the title was used. It could be interesting to develop a new fusion module and to apply a query expansion module based on Google, tasks on which we are already working.</p><p>This year two new collections have been included in the ImageCLEFmed2007. Adding this new information in the collection improves the results obtained with the Lemur IR system. We want to investigate what type of query (textual, visual or mixed) is influenced the most by these new collections. Moreover, our next step will focus on using the UMLS ontology<ref type="foot" coords="5,453.04,691.87,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_3">4</ref> , in order to include the multiligual features of the collections.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,102.18,641.81,410.83,95.47"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>1. The basic case, with Lemur, uses English queries, Lemur as IR system and Okapi with PRF as weighing function. It obtains a MAP value of 0.1672 2. The basic case, with Jirs, uses English queries, Jirs as IR system and Okapi with PRF as weighing function. It obtains a MAP value of 0.1513 Summary of results for the photo task: Monolingual and bilingual runs with Lemur and Jirs IR systems</figDesc><table coords="3,121.05,110.82,360.90,244.46"><row><cell>Language</cell><cell>Experiment</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell cols="3">Expansion Weight MAP Best MAP</cell></row><row><cell>English</cell><cell>EN-EN-Exp2</cell><cell cols="2">Lemur without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.1591</cell><cell>0.2075</cell></row><row><cell>English</cell><cell>EN-EN-Exp1</cell><cell>Jirs</cell><cell>without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.1473</cell><cell>0.2075</cell></row><row><cell>Spanish</cell><cell>ES-EN-Exp9</cell><cell>Jirs</cell><cell>without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.1555</cell><cell>0.1558</cell></row><row><cell>Spanish</cell><cell cols="3">ES-EN-Exp10 Lemur without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.1498</cell><cell>0.1558</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Portuguese PO-EN-Exp8 Lemur without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.1490</cell><cell>0.1490</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Portuguese PO-EN-Exp7 Jirs</cell><cell>without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.1350</cell><cell>0.1490</cell></row><row><cell>French</cell><cell>FR-EN-Exp4</cell><cell cols="2">Lemur without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.1264</cell><cell>0.1362</cell></row><row><cell>French</cell><cell>FR-EN-Exp3</cell><cell>Jirs</cell><cell>without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.1195</cell><cell>0.1362</cell></row><row><cell>Italian</cell><cell>IT-EN-Exp5</cell><cell>Jirs</cell><cell>without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.1231</cell><cell>0.1341</cell></row><row><cell>Italian</cell><cell>IT-EN-Exp6</cell><cell cols="2">Lemur without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.1198</cell><cell>0.1341</cell></row><row><cell>Language</cell><cell>Experiment</cell><cell>IR</cell><cell cols="3">Expansion Weight MAP Best MAP</cell></row><row><cell>English</cell><cell cols="3">EN-EN-Exp11 Fusion without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.0786</cell><cell>0.2075</cell></row><row><cell>Spanish</cell><cell cols="3">ES-EN-Exp15 Fusion without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.0559</cell><cell>0.1558</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Portuguese PO-EN-Exp14 Fusion without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.0423</cell><cell>0.1490</cell></row><row><cell>French</cell><cell cols="3">FR-EN-Exp12 Fusion without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.0323</cell><cell>0.1362</cell></row><row><cell>Italian</cell><cell>IT-EN-Exp13</cell><cell cols="2">Fusion without</cell><cell>Okapi 0.0492</cell><cell>0.1341</cell></row></table><note coords="2,102.18,704.64,410.82,8.74;2,114.91,716.59,398.10,8.74;2,114.91,728.55,398.09,8.74"><p>3. For the first heuristic the weight for Lemur and Jirs changes between 1 and 0.1. For instance, the experiment that weighs both lists in the same way uses 0.5 as the weight value for both Lemur and Jirs. The best result was 0.1678, using a weight of 0.6 for Lemur and 0.4 for Jirs.</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,90.00,368.41,423.00,8.74"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Summary of results for the photo task: Monolingual and bilingual runs with lists fusion.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,161.39,110.82,280.23,257.29"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Performance of official runs in Medical Image Retrieval</figDesc><table coords="5,366.50,110.82,39.52,8.74"><row><cell>Precision</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,122.21,381.24,358.58,8.74"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Performance of only textual information runs in Medical Image Retrieval</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,105.24,747.01,108.46,6.99"><p>http://www.lemurproject.org</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="4,105.24,734.60,230.41,6.99"><p>http://www-i6.informatik.rwth-aachen.de/˜deselaers/fire.html</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="4,105.24,744.10,117.89,6.99"><p>http://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_3" coords="5,105.24,724.33,193.78,6.99"><p>http://www.nlm.nih.gov/pubs/factsheets/umls.html</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="5">Acknowledgements</head><p>This project has been partially supported by a grant from the <rs type="funder">Spanish Government</rs>, project <rs type="projectName">TIMOM</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">TIN2006-15265-C06-03</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_5WgrqXU">
					<idno type="grant-number">TIN2006-15265-C06-03</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">TIMOM</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,200.56,407.50,8.74;6,105.50,212.52,407.50,8.74;6,105.50,224.47,240.66,8.74" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,440.78,200.56,72.22,8.74;6,105.50,212.52,308.47,8.74">Overview of the ImageCLEF 2006 Photographic Retrieval and Object Annotation Tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grubinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Deselaers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hanbury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,433.40,212.52,79.59,8.74;6,105.50,224.47,210.21,8.74">Proceedings of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</title>
		<meeting>the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,244.40,407.50,8.74;6,105.50,256.35,407.51,8.74;6,105.50,268.31,283.50,8.74" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,419.10,244.40,93.90,8.74;6,105.50,256.35,363.68,8.74">FIRE in ImageCLEF 2005: Combining Content-based Image Retrieval with Textual Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Deselaers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Weyand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Keysers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Macherey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,476.17,256.35,36.83,8.74;6,105.50,268.31,127.69,8.74">Working Notes of the CLEF Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Vienna, Austria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-09">September 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,288.23,407.51,8.74;6,105.50,300.19,407.50,8.74;6,105.50,312.14,149.20,8.74" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,194.25,300.19,118.31,8.74">SINAI at ImageCLEF 2006</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Díaz-Galiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Martín-Valdivia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Montejo-Raez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ureña-López</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,333.31,300.19,179.68,8.74;6,105.50,312.14,118.75,8.74">Proceedings of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</title>
		<meeting>the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,332.07,407.50,8.74;6,105.50,344.03,407.51,8.74;6,105.50,355.98,407.51,8.74;6,105.50,367.94,246.49,8.74" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,467.00,332.07,46.00,8.74;6,105.50,344.03,235.62,8.74">A Passage Retrieval System for Multilingual Question Answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gómez-Soriano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Montes-Y-Gómez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sanchis-Arnal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,349.46,344.03,163.54,8.74;6,105.50,355.98,161.22,8.74">8th International Conference of Text, Speech and Dialogue 2005 (TSD&apos;05)</title>
		<title level="s" coord="6,276.19,355.98,236.81,8.74">Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence (LNCS/LNAI</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Karlovy Vary, Czech Republic</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3658</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="443" to="450" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,387.86,407.50,8.74;6,105.50,399.82,407.50,8.74;6,105.50,411.77,269.16,8.74" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,105.50,399.82,316.57,8.74">BRUJA System. The University of Jaén at the Spanish task of QA@CLEF</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ureña-López</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Martínez-Santiago</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Perea-Ortega</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,461.03,399.82,51.97,8.74;6,105.50,411.77,238.72,8.74">Proceedings of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</title>
		<meeting>the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006. 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,431.70,407.50,8.74;6,105.50,443.65,407.50,8.74;6,105.50,455.61,74.25,8.74" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,362.35,431.70,150.65,8.74;6,105.50,443.65,124.99,8.74">Overview of the ImageCLEF 2007 Photographic Retrieval Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grubinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hanbury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,239.59,443.65,197.80,8.74">Working Notes of the 2007 CLEF Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Hungary</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-09">Sep, 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Budapest</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,475.53,407.51,8.74;6,105.50,487.49,407.51,8.74;6,105.50,499.44,334.00,8.74" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,158.71,487.49,349.75,8.74">Overview of the ImageCLEFmed 2007 Medical Retrieval and Annotation Tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Deselaers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kalpathy-Cramer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Deserno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hersh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,105.50,499.44,191.10,8.74">Working Notes of the 2007 CLEF Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Budapest, Hungary</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-09">Sep, 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,519.37,407.50,8.74;6,105.50,531.32,407.51,8.74;6,105.50,543.28,169.26,8.74" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,325.18,519.37,187.82,8.74;6,105.50,531.32,252.90,8.74">Using Ontology Dimensions and Negative Expansion to solve Precise Queries in CLEF Medical Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Chevallet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Radhouani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,366.38,531.32,146.62,8.74;6,105.50,543.28,41.15,8.74">Working Notes of the 2005 CLEF Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Vienna, Austria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-09">Sep, 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
