<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,167.73,148.86,267.54,15.15">SINAI at ImageCLEFmed 2008</title>
				<funder ref="#_wAqsuqW">
					<orgName type="full">University of Jaén</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_7zv2fWq">
					<orgName type="full">Spanish Government</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,153.22,182.75,80.29,8.74"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Díaz-Galiano</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Grupo Sistemas Inteligentes de Acceso a la Información Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,241.44,182.75,103.01,8.74"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Grupo Sistemas Inteligentes de Acceso a la Información Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,352.62,182.75,92.66,8.74"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Martín-Valdivia</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Grupo Sistemas Inteligentes de Acceso a la Información Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,222.55,196.70,75.98,8.74"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ureña-López</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Grupo Sistemas Inteligentes de Acceso a la Información Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,306.70,196.70,73.76,8.74"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Montejo-Ráez</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department Grupo Sistemas Inteligentes de Acceso a la Información Campus Las Lagunillas</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ed. A3</addrLine>
									<postCode>E-23071</postCode>
									<settlement>Jaén</settlement>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,167.73,148.86,267.54,15.15">SINAI at ImageCLEFmed 2008</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">64757C9027DBE619913502D590B806C0</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:17+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.3 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: H.3.1 Content Analysis and Indexing</term>
					<term>H.3.3 Information Search and Retrieval</term>
					<term>H.3.4 Systems and Software Visual and textual retrieval, Indexing, Ontologies, MeSH, UMLS</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the SINAI team participation in the ImageCLEF campaign.</p><p>In this paper we only explain the experiments accomplished in the medical task. We have experimented with query expansion and the text information of the collection. For expansion, we carry out experiments using MeSH ontology and UMLS separately. With respect to text collection, we have used three different collections, one with caption and title, other with caption, title and the text of the section where the image appears, and the third with the full article. Moreover, we have experimented with mixed search, textual and visual search, using the FIRE software for image retrieval.</p><p>The use of FIRE and MeSH expansion with the minimal collection (only caption and title) obtains the best results in the track.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This is the fourth participation of the SINAI research group at the ImageCLEF 2008 campaign, specifically in the medical task.</p><p>The goal of the medical task is to retrieve relevant images based on an image query. This year, a new collection have been used. It contains images from articles published in Radiology and Radiographics including the text of the captions and a link to the HTML of the full text articles. We have downloaded articles from the web and constructed a new textual collection including the text of the article section where the image appears. Besides, for the experiments, we have created two groups of expanded queries, a group expanded with MeSH ontology <ref type="foot" coords="1,435.74,654.41,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref> and other group expanded with UMLS<ref type="foot" coords="1,185.61,666.36,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_1">2</ref> .</p><p>For mixed experiment, we have used the list of retrieved images by FIRE<ref type="foot" coords="1,440.20,678.32,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_2">3</ref>  <ref type="bibr" coords="1,449.24,679.89,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, which was supplied by the organizers of this track.</p><p>The following section describes the new textual collection. In Section 3, we explain the expansion of the queries. In the next section, we comment the experiments carried out. Finally, conclusions and further work are presented in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The textual collection</head><p>This year, the old collection <ref type="bibr" coords="2,222.07,190.50,10.52,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref> used in previous years has been discarded. A new collection has been introduced, a subset of the Goldminer<ref type="foot" coords="2,298.71,200.88,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_3">4</ref> collection. The collection contains images from articles published in Radiology and Radiographics including the text of the captions and a link to the HTML of the full text article.</p><p>To create the different textual collections, first we have obtained the textual information by following the next steps:</p><p>1. Extract a list of articles URLs from the information of the collection given by the organizers.</p><p>The numbers of articles are lower that the number of images that contains the collection, because an article contains several images.</p><p>2. Download all the articles in this list.</p><p>3. Filter the downloaded articles to extract different sections in the text: title, authors, abstract, introduction, etc.</p><p>4. Mark the position of every image in the filtered articles.</p><p>The we have created three different collections. In these collections each document contains information about each image from the original collection. The information is different for each collection. These collections and the section include the following sections:</p><p>• CT: It contains caption of image and title of the article.</p><p>• CTS: Contains caption, title and text of the section where the image appear.</p><p>• CTA: Contains caption, title and text of the full article.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Query Expansion</head><p>One of the purposes of these experiments is to compare the performance of query expansion using two different ontologies: MeSH and UMLS. Experiments with the MeSH ontology have been carried out in the past <ref type="bibr" coords="2,190.03,542.85,10.52,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref> obtaining good results. The expansion method using MeSH is the same as presented last year.</p><p>On the other hand, the UMLS metathesaurus is a repository of biomedical ontologies and associated software tools developed by the US National Library of Medicine(NLM) <ref type="foot" coords="2,458.98,577.14,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_4">5</ref> . It is built from the electronic versions of many different thesauri, classifications, code sets, and lists of controlled terms used in biomedical literature and health services research. These are referred to as the source vocabularies of the Metathesaurus in UMLS literature. One of the source vocabularies is MeSH ontology.</p><p>To expand the queries we have used MetaMap program <ref type="bibr" coords="2,343.67,638.49,10.52,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref> that was originally developed for use in information retrieval. MetaMap uses the UMLS metathesaurus for concept retrieval mapping a input text. For query expansion with MetaMap, we have mapped terms in the query. In order to reduce the number of terms that could expand the query, to make it equal to that of MeSH expansion, we have used MetaMap, restricting the semantic types in the mapped terms <ref type="bibr" coords="2,489.17,686.31,10.52,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref> as follows:</p><p>• bpoc: Body Part, Organ, or Organ Component For our expansion we have used the Meta Candidate terms, because these terms provide similar terms with differences in the words. For example, the phrase "'chest CT image"' obtains following candidates: The first number is the score, the next one is the metathesaurus concept. The preferred name for a metathesaurus concept appears asided in parentheses. Between braces are the different source vocabularies where the concept appears, and between square brackets are the different semantics types of the concept.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,104.94,241.50,105.38,8.77">• 793 Image (Medical</formula><p>Prior to the inclusion of Meta Candidates terms in the queries, the term words are added to a set where repeated words are deleted. All words in the set are included in the query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments</head><p>Our main goal is to investigate the effectiveness of different expansions and different sizes in textual collections. Moreover, we have experimented with the influence of mixing visual information with our results.</p><p>We have used three textual collections (CT, CTS, CTA) and three sets of topics: original, expanded with MeSH and expanded with UMLS. Besides, we have mixed our textual results with the visual results given by the organizers in order to obtain new results. The visual results have been obtained with the FIRE software. To mix textual and visual results, we have used the same algorithm that applied in 2007 <ref type="bibr" coords="3,227.05,619.09,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. In previous years the best results reached were obtained with a weight of 0.8 for textual results and 0.2 for visual ones. This year we have only experimented with these weights.</p><p>We have submitted only 10 runs, because of the limits imposed by the organizers. The results of these runs are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,234.95,666.91,3.87,8.74">1</ref>:</p><p>The official baseline results obtain 0,2768 of MAP (Main Average Precission). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions and Further Work</head><p>This new collection has been used in the ImageCLEFmed2008. Similarly to previous years, the use of textual information improved the results of baseline visual results. In this case, the use of FIRE and MeSH expansion with the minimal collection (only caption and title) obtains the best results in the track. The use of UMLS expansion obtains worse results than the baseline. Although UMLS Metathesaurus includes MeSH ontology in the source vocabularies, MetaMap adds, in general, more terms in the queries. The MetaMap mapping is different than MeSH mapping, therefore the terms selected to expand are different.</p><p>Another conclusion is that it is better to have few textual information but more specific. Including all the section where the image appears is not good approach. Sometimes, a section contains several images, therefore the same information references different images.</p><p>Our further work was to obtain a more precise textual information by finding the phrase where a reference to the image exists, that is, by finding HTML tags that reference locally to the figure (for example: A HREF="#F1") or syntactic structures of type "in figure 1 ...". Moreover, we expanded the queries with UMLS Metathesaurus using other algorithm distinct to that used by the MetaMap tool. We investigated new methods to expand with UMLS similar to the expansion with MeSH, that is, less terms but better for information retrieval.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,104.94,112.02,129.34,8.74;3,104.94,131.95,128.49,8.74;3,104.94,151.87,118.78,8.74;3,104.94,173.79,408.06,8.74;3,90.00,185.74,423.00,8.74"><head>•</head><label></label><figDesc>diap: Diagnostic Procedure • dsyn: Disease or Syndrome • neop: Neoplastic Process MetaMap gives two types of mapped terms: Meta Candidates and Meta Mapping. The difference between both mapped terms is that the second are the Meta Candidate with best score.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,104.94,241.50,408.06,168.17"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Imaging {MSH,MTH,NCI}) [Diagnostic Procedure]</figDesc><table coords="3,104.94,261.43,408.05,20.72"><row><cell>• 734 Chest CT (Chest CT {MTH, SNOMEDCT, RCD, SNM, SNMI, ICD9CM, MTHICD9,</cell></row><row><cell>MDR}) [Diagnostic Procedure]</cell></row></table><note coords="3,104.94,293.31,408.05,8.77;3,114.91,305.30,259.54,8.74;3,104.94,325.19,408.06,8.77;3,114.91,337.18,378.83,8.74;3,104.94,357.07,408.06,8.77;3,114.91,369.06,21.86,8.74;3,104.94,388.95,408.06,8.77;3,114.91,400.94,300.79,8.74"><p>• 604 Thoracic (Dissecting aneurysm of the thoracic aorta {MTH, CCPSS, ICPC2, ICD10ENG, ICD9CM, MDR, NCI}) [Disease or Syndrome] • 577 Breast (Breast {HL7V2.5, LCH, MSH, MTH, NCI, PSY, RCD, SNM, SNOMEDCT, UWDA, CCPSS, LNC, AOD, CSP, SNMI}) [Body Part, Organ, or Organ Component] • 577 Breast (Entire breast {MTH, SNOMEDCT}) [Body Part, Organ, or Organ Component] • 560 Mammary (Mammary gland {MTH, RCD, SNM, SNOMEDCT, UWDA, MSH, NCI, AOD, CSP, PSY, SNMI}) [Body Part, Organ, or Organ Component]</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,104.94,690.82,360.20,8.74"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>shows the top ten MAP obtained in all experiments for all of participants.</figDesc><table coords="4,188.81,110.82,225.38,292.02"><row><cell>Experiment</cell><cell>MAP</cell></row><row><cell>sinai CT Base</cell><cell>0.2480</cell></row><row><cell>sinai CT Mesh</cell><cell>0.2792</cell></row><row><cell>sinai CT Umls</cell><cell>0.2275</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">sinai CT Mesh Fire20 0.2908</cell></row><row><cell>sinai CTS Base</cell><cell>0.1784</cell></row><row><cell>sinai CTS Mesh</cell><cell>0.1582</cell></row><row><cell>sinai CTS Umls</cell><cell>0.1429</cell></row><row><cell>sinai CTA Base</cell><cell>0.1982</cell></row><row><cell>sinai CTA Mesh</cell><cell>0.2057</cell></row><row><cell>sinai CTA Umls</cell><cell>0.1781</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Table 1: Performance of official SINAI runs</cell></row><row><cell>Experiment</cell><cell>MAP</cell></row><row><cell>SINAI-sinai CT Mesh Fire20</cell><cell>0.2908</cell></row><row><cell>GPLSI-IR-n2 PRF Type mesh</cell><cell>0.2881</cell></row><row><cell>EXPPRFNegativaMesh</cell><cell>0.2881</cell></row><row><cell>SINAI-sinai CT Mesh</cell><cell>0.2792</cell></row><row><cell>LIG-LIG COS0506 MPTT Emi</cell><cell>0.2791</cell></row><row><cell>LIG-LIG MPTT Emix</cell><cell>0.2781</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">TEXT-MESS-TEXMXmshTypFIREidfCT 0.2777</cell></row><row><cell>TEXTMESSmeshTypeFIREidf CT</cell><cell>0.2777</cell></row><row><cell>TEXTMESSmeshType CT</cell><cell>0.2777</cell></row><row><cell>GPLSI-IR-n2</cell><cell>0.2768</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="4,204.50,415.97,193.99,8.74"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Performance of top ten official runs</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,105.24,710.78,117.90,6.99"><p>http://www.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="1,105.24,720.28,150.65,6.99"><p>http://www.nlm.nih.gov/research/umls/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="1,105.24,729.78,230.41,6.99"><p>http://www-i6.informatik.rwth-aachen.de/˜deselaers/fire.html</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_3" coords="2,105.24,737.50,98.16,6.99"><p>http://goldminer.arrs.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5" xml:id="foot_4" coords="2,105.24,747.01,94.80,6.99"><p>http://www.nlm.nih.gov/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="6">Acknowledgements</head><p>This project has been partially supported by a grant from the <rs type="funder">Spanish Government</rs>, project <rs type="projectName">TIMOM</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">TIN2006-15265-C06-03</rs>), and the <rs type="grantNumber">RFC/PP2006/Id 514</rs> granted by the <rs type="funder">University of Jaén</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_7zv2fWq">
					<idno type="grant-number">TIN2006-15265-C06-03</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">TIMOM</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_wAqsuqW">
					<idno type="grant-number">RFC/PP2006/Id 514</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,133.84,407.51,8.74;5,105.50,145.80,407.50,8.74;5,105.50,157.75,283.49,8.74" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,419.09,133.84,93.91,8.74;5,105.50,145.80,363.67,8.74">FIRE in ImageCLEF 2005: Combining Content-based Image Retrieval with Textual Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Deselaers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Weyand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Keysers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Macherey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,476.16,145.80,36.84,8.74;5,105.50,157.75,127.69,8.74">Working Notes of the CLEF Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Vienna, Austria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-09">September 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,177.68,407.51,8.74;5,105.50,189.63,407.50,8.74;5,105.50,201.59,334.00,8.74" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,158.71,189.63,349.75,8.74">Overview of the ImageCLEFmed 2007 Medical Retrieval and Annotation Tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Deselaers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kalpathy-Cramer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Deserno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hersh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,105.50,201.59,191.09,8.74">Working Notes of the 2007 CLEF Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Budapest, Hungary</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-09">Sep, 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,221.51,407.50,8.74;5,105.50,233.47,407.50,8.74;5,105.50,245.42,149.19,8.74" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,194.25,233.47,118.31,8.74">SINAI at ImageCLEF 2007</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Díaz-Galiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Martín-Valdivia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Montejo-Raez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ureña-López</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,333.31,233.47,179.69,8.74;5,105.50,245.42,118.75,8.74">Proceedings of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2007)</title>
		<meeting>the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2007)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,265.35,407.50,8.74;5,105.50,277.30,407.50,8.74" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,176.96,265.35,336.04,8.74;5,105.50,277.30,80.66,8.74">Effective Mapping of Biomedical text to the UMLS Metathesaurus: the MetaMap Program</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,194.30,277.30,129.74,8.74">Proc.of the AMIA Symposium</title>
		<meeting>.of the AMIA Symposium<address><addrLine>Washington, DC</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-07">Nov.3-7. 2001</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,297.23,407.50,8.74;5,105.50,309.18,407.50,8.74;5,105.50,321.14,169.26,8.74" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,325.18,297.23,187.82,8.74;5,105.50,309.18,252.91,8.74">Using Ontology Dimensions and Negative Expansion to solve Precise Queries in CLEF Medical Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Chevallet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Radhouani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,366.38,309.18,146.61,8.74;5,105.50,321.14,41.16,8.74">Working Notes of the 2005 CLEF Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Vienna, Austria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-09">Sep, 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
