<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,214.80,65.96,185.70,12.91;1,208.56,83.96,198.18,12.91;1,223.44,103.83,168.58,10.76">Authorship Identification with Modality Specific Meta Features Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2011</title>
				<funder ref="#_Mkg3Gya">
					<orgName type="full">UPV</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_WUbc6kZ #_JtuYzSr">
					<orgName type="full">European Commission</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_Q7pfuHn">
					<orgName type="full">CONACYT-Mexico</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,176.04,139.76,62.94,8.97"><forename type="first">Thamar</forename><surname>Solorio</surname></persName>
							<email>solorio@cis.uab.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,247.56,139.76,55.62,8.97"><forename type="first">Sangita</forename><surname>Pillay</surname></persName>
							<email>rsangita@cis.uab.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,328.80,139.76,103.54,8.97;1,435.60,138.05,1.82,6.40"><forename type="first">Manuel</forename><surname>Montes-Y-Gómez</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">National Institute of Astrophysics, Optics and Electronics</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="MX">Mexico</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Alabama at Birmingham</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,214.80,65.96,185.70,12.91;1,208.56,83.96,198.18,12.91;1,223.44,103.83,168.58,10.76">Authorship Identification with Modality Specific Meta Features Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2011</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">D481E99A251755C1A8468A5546C03FC4</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:27+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper presents the approach used in the PAN '11 authorship identification competition. Our method extracts meta features from several independently generated clustering solutions from the training set. Each clustering solution uses a disjoint set of features that represent a specific linguistic modality. The different clustering solutions encode similarities in writing styles of authors across specific dimensions. The final classifier is trained with a combination of the meta features with first level features. Our approach has outperformed a more syntactic oriented state-of-the-art method on web forum data. We achieved moderately successful results on this PAN competition, with better results on the test set with a smaller number of authors. However, considering that our system was not fine tuned for the PAN evaluation data we found our results very encouraging.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Authorship Identification (AI) assumes the existence of individualized and identifiable writing styles. The success of previous work empirically supports this assumption, at least on the collections that have been used to test these approaches. However, when looking at writing samples from different authors it is clear that similarities exist among them. For instance, when analyzing web forum data we can see that several authors share emoticon patterns, even the absence of emoticons is in itself a pattern shared by many authors. Similarly, other authors use punctuation marks in similar ways (some like to use more than one exclamation point to highlight emotion) or tend to use similar words when writing about the same topic. Our modality specific meta feature approach was motivated by these observations. The idea is to extract these similarities across authors in a modality specific way. We refer to the different linguistic dimensions we analyze from the documents (syntactic, lexical, stylistic) as "modalities". By contrasting authors' characteristics in a modality specific way, we allow authors to share patterns with subsets of authors along a specific dimension (e.g. emoticons) while sharing writing patterns with a different subset of authors across another dimension (e.g. similar use of adverbs). These similarities are extracted by independently clustering, in an unsupervised way, the training instances using the subset of features from each modality. The combination of the meta features generated by our approach with the first level features outperformed the method presented in <ref type="bibr" coords="1,289.44,606.08,11.60,8.97" target="#b8">[9]</ref> on the task of AA on web forum data.</p><p>On the PAN competition, our system reached a micro-averaged F-measure of 14.8% on the large test set, and 44% F-measure on the small test set. Even though these results were not the best results achieved on the competition, we believe they are very positive results as our system was not tuned for the PAN task. It was applied as it was developed for the web forum data. We believe that better results can be achieved by our system using a set of features and modalities adapted for the data of the PAN task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Previous Work</head><p>Following Stamatatos' survey <ref type="bibr" coords="2,258.72,182.12,15.34,8.97" target="#b11">[12]</ref>, we can categorize AI approaches by the way the training set is processed. In a profile-based approach the training instances (text from each author) are concatenated into a single large document per author. Training under the profile-based approaches consists of extracting an author profile from the concatenated document. The final prediction in this scheme is based on measuring similarity between a test profile and the training profiles generated. Examples of recent work using a profile based approach include <ref type="bibr" coords="2,279.00,253.88,10.97,8.97" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,289.97,253.88,7.31,8.97" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,297.29,253.88,7.31,8.97" target="#b2">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,304.60,253.88,7.31,8.97" target="#b3">4]</ref>. The major advantage of these approaches over the instance based ones is scalability.</p><p>Instance-based approaches, on the other hand, follow the traditional framework of text classification, where each text sample in the training set is an instance of the problem. In this setting, the samples are typically represented individually by a feature vector, then a learning algorithm will be trained on this set of vectors. This approach has been successfully used in combination with a wide variety of learning algorithms, such as Support Vector Machines <ref type="bibr" coords="2,248.52,337.52,11.40,8.97" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,259.92,337.52,11.40,8.97" target="#b10">11]</ref>, decision trees <ref type="bibr" coords="2,334.08,337.52,15.34,8.97" target="#b14">[15]</ref>, and memory based learners <ref type="bibr" coords="2,466.44,337.52,10.69,8.97" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. The main difference with a profile-based approach is the need for a sufficiently large number of samples with known authorship.</p><p>As Stamatatos shows, both approaches have strengths and weaknesses <ref type="bibr" coords="2,432.36,373.40,16.64,8.97" target="#b11">[12]</ref> and the choice of what to use may depend on the application, the amount of available data, computer resources, and the like. In this paper we use an instance-based approach with Support Vector Machines as the underlying algorithm. Our modality specific meta features approach is different from previous machine learning approaches to AI in that it has an intermediate step where we generate meta features from clustering the training instances per modality. Solorio et al. have shown empirically that using these meta features results in higher prediction accuracy <ref type="bibr" coords="2,308.88,457.16,16.64,8.97" target="#b10">[11]</ref> than that achieved on using only first level features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Meta Features for Authorship Identification</head><p>Our approach starts with the extraction of first-level features to generate a feature vector representation for each instance. However, we generate m smaller vectors, each containing features from a specific modality describing the instances. Typical instancebased approaches extract a single feature vector for x ∈ R n . We call these subvectors modality specific because they represent different characteristics of the author's text. Each modality refers to a particular linguistic dimension, such as lexical, syntactic, or stylistic. More formally, an instance x is now represented as {x 1 , x 2 , ..., x m } where each x i is a vector with |x i | features in modality i. Note that union(x 1 , x 2 , ..., x m ) = x and intersection(x 1 , x 2 , ..., x m ) = ∅ since we are only generating sub vectors (or complementary views) from the original feature set.</p><p>Each set of the m different vectors are input to a clustering algorithm to produce m clustering solutions for the training data with k clusters each. As a result, we end up with different arrangements of the training instances into clusters, one arrangement (clustering solution) per modality. From each cluster c j in each of the m clustering solutions, we compute a centroid by averaging all the feature vectors in that cluster.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,243.96,158.65,236.72,29.25">centroid mj = 1 | c mj | xi∈cm j x i<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where j above ranges from 1 to k, the number of clusters. We generate meta features by computing the similarity of each instance to these centroids using the cosine function. We compute these similarities for training and testing instances. Each instance x is now represented by the original set of first level features x i1 , ..., x i |x i | in combination with the meta features x i1 , ..., x i k generated for each modality j.</p><p>We consider four types of first level features: stylistic (sty), lexical (lex), syntactic (syn), and perplexity (ppl) values from character 3-gram language models. That is, in these experiments m = 4. Therefore, in our problem we have x = {x sty , x lex , x ppl , x syn }.</p><p>The intuition behind our approach is to generate new meta features from clustering the data that can represent the relation, i.e. closeness, between documents from one author and documents from other authors. Thus, no class information is used during clustering, as the idea is to uncover regularities across the documents from authors on individual modalities. New in this work as well is the idea of a modality specific clustering, where each linguistic dimension is clustered separately. Our assumption is that generating clusters by looking at feature subsets separately allows to disentangle authors' characteristics that may be blurred away when clustering the entire feature vectors at once. We expect this information will be captured by the meta features, and will yield higher classification accuracy than the first level features by themselves.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">First Level Features</head><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="3,159.00,450.68,4.98,8.97" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows a list of the features we used arranged by modality. These are exactly the same features used in <ref type="bibr" coords="3,222.36,462.68,80.24,8.97" target="#b1">Solorio et al. (2011)</ref> where the task focuses web forum data <ref type="bibr" coords="3,461.52,462.68,15.34,8.97" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. In the stylistic modality we include features tuned for written interactions in social networks. We use percentages of non-alphanumeric characters that are commonly used in emoticons. We also include percentages of capitalized words, use of quotations, and use of signature, that we believe allow writers more freedom to express their unique writing style. The lexical modality contains the standard bag of words representation used in text classification that has also been commonly used in previous AI work <ref type="bibr" coords="3,428.52,534.44,11.40,8.97" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,439.92,534.44,11.40,8.97" target="#b14">15]</ref>. In the perplexity modality we use perplexity values from character 3-gram language models. We use the training data to train one language model per author and each model generates a perplexity value per instance. For training the language models and computing perplexity values we used the SRI-LM toolkit <ref type="bibr" coords="3,326.52,582.20,15.34,8.97" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. Lastly, in the syntactic modality we have unigrams, bigrams, and trigrams of POS tags, and typed dependency relations extracted using the Stanford parser <ref type="bibr" coords="3,276.00,606.08,10.60,8.97" target="#b7">[8]</ref>, that have been used before in AA. As mentioned earlier, the features described above were selected based on our belief that they would be useful in the domain of electronic web forum data. We expect that some of these features will be relevant for the PAN task, but no customization of them was done so it is also expected that many of the features in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,409.08,301.40,4.98,8.97" target="#tab_0">1</ref> will not be that useful.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Modality Features</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experimental evaluation</head><p>We are presenting results of using Support Vector Machines (SVMs) <ref type="bibr" coords="4,420.00,367.04,16.52,8.97" target="#b9">[10]</ref> as the underlying learner as implemented in WEKA <ref type="bibr" coords="4,313.08,378.92,15.24,8.97" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. Our modality specific meta features approach can be used in combination with any machine learning algorithm. However since in previous experiments SVMs have shown to yield competitive results, we chose this algorithm for the PAN competition. As described in Section 3, we cluster each of the four types of feature vectors in the training data set separately. We use a k-means clustering algorithm, implemented in CLUTO. The first step in the clustering phase is to choose the number of clusters. Since in our previous experiments we obtained better results with k =number of authors ×15, we used this value to fix the parameter k in these experiments. Therefore, for the Large test set k = 72 × 15, and for the small data set k = 26 × 15. It should be noted that since our system cannot handle the out-of-training author scenario, we did not submit results for those test sets.</p><p>In Table <ref type="table" coords="4,183.72,510.44,4.98,8.97" target="#tab_1">2</ref> we present results as reported by the PAN organizers. The baseline system we are presenting here consists of training an SVM classifier using only the first level features. On the Large data set our modality specific meta features (MSMF) approach outperforms the baseline system on the macroaveraged results, but the baseline system reaches higher microaveraged results. On the Small test set, our MSMF approach yields better results than the baseline on all measures reported. These results follow the trend we found in our previous experiments where adding the MSMF information increased prediction accuracy of the system. The overall performance reached in these test sets is much lower than what we saw on different data sets <ref type="bibr" coords="4,362.64,606.08,15.24,8.97" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. We believe this drop in prediction accuracy is due mainly to a lack of customization of our system to the domain of the competition. For instance, we did not make any changes to the features or modalities, and we also did not adapt our preprocessing step. Lastly, the smaller training set available can also be a contributing factor to the weak performance we achieved. In our previous experiments the smallest number of documents per author was 165, higher than the average number of training documents at the PAN competition. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>We have described the modality specific meta features approach we used to submit results at the PAN '11 competition. The main idea behind our approach is to explicitly exploit the fact that authors share similarities in writing patterns across different linguistic dimensions. These similarities are encoded in the meta features and are the result of several independent clustering solutions of the training instances. The results obtained at the competition are encouraging and support our claim that adding higher level features is beneficial for the AI task. Our goal is to improve these results by modifying the feature set to better represent the domain of interest.</p><p>We are also currently working on characterizing the effect of the meta features, and exploring the combination of this approach with a profile-based approach. So far, we have used only instance-based approaches to AA. We would like to evaluate the benefit of including our modality-specific meta features into a profile based approach, such as the work by <ref type="bibr" coords="5,184.80,477.08,10.60,8.97" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,196.56,75.44,222.19,155.39"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Feature breakdown by modality</figDesc><table coords="4,196.56,75.44,222.19,134.92"><row><cell cols="2">Stylistic Total number of words</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Average number of words per sentence</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Binary feature indicating use of quotations</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Binary feature indicating use of signature</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Percentage of all caps words</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Percentage of non-alphanumeric characters</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Percentage of sentence initial words with first letter capitalized</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Percentage of digits</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Number of new lines in the text</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Average number of punctuations (!?.;:,) per sentence</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Percentage of contractions (won't, can't)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Percentage of two or more consecutive non-alphanumeric characters</cell></row><row><cell>Lexical</cell><cell>Bag of words (freq. of unigrams)</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Perplexity Perplexity values from character 3-grams</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Syntactic Part-of-Speech (POS) tags</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Dependency relations</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Chunks (unigram freq.)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,134.76,161.80,345.88,95.07"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Comparison of micro and macro averaged precision, recall, and F1 values in two PAN'11 test sets. MSMF stands for our modality specific meta features approach.</figDesc><table coords="5,157.08,161.80,301.12,63.27"><row><cell cols="7">TestSet MacroAvg MacroAvg MacroAvg MicroAvg MicroAvg MicroAvg</cell></row><row><cell>System</cell><cell cols="2">Precision Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell cols="2">Precision Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell></row><row><cell>Baseline Large</cell><cell>0.119</cell><cell>0.054</cell><cell>0.041</cell><cell>0.155</cell><cell>0.155</cell><cell>0.155</cell></row><row><cell>Baseline Small</cell><cell>0.440</cell><cell>0.152</cell><cell>0.148</cell><cell>0.384</cell><cell>0.384</cell><cell>0.384</cell></row><row><cell>MSMF Large</cell><cell>0.171</cell><cell>0.084</cell><cell>0.066</cell><cell>0.148</cell><cell>0.148</cell><cell>0.148</cell></row><row><cell>MSMF Small</cell><cell>0.415</cell><cell>0.205</cell><cell>0.185</cell><cell>0.440</cell><cell>0.440</cell><cell>0.440</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>Acknowledgements. This work was partially supported by a <rs type="grantName">UAB faculty development</rs> grant and by the <rs type="funder">UPV</rs>, award 1932, under the program <rs type="grantName">Research Visits for Renowned Scientists</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">PAID-02-11</rs>) to the first author. It was also supported in part by the <rs type="funder">CONACYT-Mexico</rs> (project no. <rs type="grantNumber">134186</rs>) and by the <rs type="funder">European Commission</rs> as part of the <rs type="programName">WIQ-EI project</rs> (project no. <rs type="grantNumber">269180</rs>) within the <rs type="programName">FP7 People Programme</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_Mkg3Gya">
					<orgName type="grant-name">UAB faculty development</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_Q7pfuHn">
					<idno type="grant-number">PAID-02-11</idno>
					<orgName type="grant-name">Research Visits for Renowned Scientists</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_WUbc6kZ">
					<idno type="grant-number">134186</idno>
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">WIQ-EI project</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_JtuYzSr">
					<idno type="grant-number">269180</idno>
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">FP7 People Programme</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.54,584.92,337.86,8.07;5,150.96,595.84,329.66,8.07;5,150.96,606.76,278.96,8.07" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,262.32,584.92,218.08,8.07;5,150.96,595.84,36.15,8.07">Measuring the usefulness of function words for authorship attribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Argamon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Levitan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,208.56,595.84,272.06,8.07;5,150.96,606.76,252.33,8.07">Proceedings of the Conference of the Association for Computers and the Humanities and the Association for Literary and Linguistic Computing</title>
		<meeting>the Conference of the Association for Computers and the Humanities and the Association for Literary and Linguistic Computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.54,69.64,337.93,8.07;6,150.96,80.68,329.62,8.07;6,150.96,91.60,329.62,8.07;6,150.96,102.52,77.72,8.07" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,370.20,69.64,110.27,8.07;6,150.96,80.68,121.23,8.07">Local histograms of character n-grams for authorship attribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hugo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Thamar</forename><surname>Escalante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Manuel</forename><surname>Solorio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Montes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,289.44,80.68,191.14,8.07;6,150.96,91.60,135.09,8.07">Proceedings of the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 49th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL)</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="288" to="298" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.54,113.56,337.86,8.07;6,152.76,122.56,42.56,9.99" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,182.76,113.56,78.51,8.07">Authorship attribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Joula</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,267.00,113.56,172.86,8.07">Foundations and Trends in Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="233" to="334" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.54,135.40,337.86,8.07;6,150.96,146.44,329.53,8.07;6,150.96,157.36,55.88,8.07" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,323.40,135.40,157.00,8.07;6,150.96,146.44,36.15,8.07">N-gram based author profiles for authorship attribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Keselj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Peng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Cercone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,204.96,146.44,249.10,8.07">Proceedings of the Pacific Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the Pacific Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="264" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.54,168.28,338.02,8.07;6,150.96,179.32,319.76,8.07" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,300.36,168.28,176.91,8.07">Computational methods in authorship attribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Argamon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,150.96,179.32,259.59,8.07">Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.54,190.24,337.86,8.07;6,150.96,201.16,329.60,8.07;6,150.96,212.20,192.68,8.07" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,298.92,190.24,181.48,8.07;6,150.96,201.16,81.77,8.07">Forensic authorship attribution using compression distances to prototypes</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Maarten</forename><surname>Lambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Cor</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Veenman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,150.96,212.20,40.12,8.07">IWCF 2009</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><forename type="middle">J M H</forename><surname>Geradts</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Franke</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Veenman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5718</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="24" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.54,223.12,338.05,8.07;6,150.96,234.04,329.66,8.07;6,150.96,245.08,155.00,8.07" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,284.88,223.12,195.71,8.07;6,150.96,234.04,53.91,8.07">Shallow text analysis and machine learning for authorship attribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Kim</forename><surname>Luyckx</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Walter</forename><surname>Daelemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,213.24,234.04,267.38,8.07;6,150.96,245.08,70.32,8.07">Proceedings of the Fifteenth Meeting of Computational Linguistics in the Netherlands (CLIN)</title>
		<meeting>the Fifteenth Meeting of Computational Linguistics in the Netherlands (CLIN)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="149" to="160" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.54,256.00,337.92,8.07;6,150.96,266.92,231.20,8.07" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,392.04,256.00,88.43,8.07;6,150.96,266.92,148.13,8.07">Generating typed dependency parses from phrase structure parses</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>De Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Maccartney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,315.60,266.92,40.24,8.07">LREC 2006</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.54,277.84,337.98,8.07;6,150.96,288.88,329.63,8.07;6,150.96,299.80,329.60,8.07" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,378.60,277.84,101.92,8.07;6,150.96,288.88,126.42,8.07">Authorship attribution using probabilistic context-free grammars</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Adriana</forename><surname>Sindhu Raghavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><surname>Kovashka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Mooney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,295.08,288.88,185.51,8.07;6,150.96,299.80,13.99,8.07">Proceedings of the ACL 2010 Conference Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>the ACL 2010 Conference Short Papers<address><addrLine>Uppsala, Sweden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010-07">July 2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="38" to="42" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.17,310.72,338.29,8.07;6,150.96,321.76,243.68,8.07" xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,321.36,310.72,159.11,8.07;6,150.96,321.76,174.05,8.07">Learning with Kernels: Support Vector Machines, Regularization, Optimization and Beyond</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bernhard</forename><surname>Schölkopf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Smola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.17,332.68,338.41,8.07;6,150.96,343.60,329.49,8.07;6,150.96,354.64,262.16,8.07" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,449.28,332.68,31.31,8.07;6,150.96,343.60,228.49,8.07">Generating metafeatures for authorship attribution on web forum posts</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Thamar</forename><surname>Solorio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sangita</forename><surname>Pillay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sindhu</forename><surname>Raghavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Manuel</forename><surname>Montes Y Gómez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,398.40,343.60,82.05,8.07;6,150.96,354.64,214.34,8.07">5th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing, IJCNLP-2011</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>to appear</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.17,365.56,338.45,8.07;6,150.96,376.48,291.44,8.07" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,235.44,365.56,185.62,8.07">A survey on modern authorship attribution methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Efstathios</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,429.72,365.56,50.90,8.07;6,150.96,376.48,207.27,8.07">Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="538" to="556" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.17,387.51,335.39,8.07" xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,215.40,387.51,177.12,8.07">SRILM -an extensible language modeling toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Stolcke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="901" to="904" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.17,398.44,338.41,8.07;6,150.96,409.36,169.52,8.07" xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,265.68,398.44,214.91,8.07;6,150.96,409.36,21.88,8.07">Data Mining: Practical Machine Learning Tools and Techniques</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ian</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Witten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Eibe</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<publisher>Morgan Kauffmann</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.17,420.39,338.47,8.07;6,150.96,431.31,329.53,8.07;6,150.96,442.23,125.00,8.07" xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,231.24,420.39,234.41,8.07">Effective and scalable authorship attribution using function words</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zobel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,150.96,431.31,215.51,8.07">Proceedings of 2nd Asian Information Retrieval Symposium</title>
		<meeting>2nd Asian Information Retrieval Symposium<address><addrLine>Jeju Island, Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3689</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="174" to="189" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
