<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,142.54,116.00,330.28,12.91;1,293.18,133.93,28.97,12.91;1,223.43,154.28,168.49,10.76">Baseline Approaches for the Authorship Identification Task Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2011</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,154.07,190.77,61.90,8.97"><forename type="first">Darnes</forename><surname>Vilariño</surname></persName>
							<email>darnes@cs.buap.mx</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science B</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Autónoma de Puebla</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,222.36,190.77,63.80,8.97"><forename type="first">Esteban</forename><surname>Castillo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science B</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Autónoma de Puebla</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,292.38,190.77,46.24,8.97"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Pinto</surname></persName>
							<email>dpinto@cs.buap.mx</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science B</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Autónoma de Puebla</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,345.04,190.77,38.56,8.97"><forename type="first">Saul</forename><surname>León</surname></persName>
							<email>saul.ls@live.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science B</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Autónoma de Puebla</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,407.57,190.77,53.68,8.97"><forename type="first">Mireya</forename><surname>Tovar</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science B</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Autónoma de Puebla</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,142.54,116.00,330.28,12.91;1,293.18,133.93,28.97,12.91;1,223.43,154.28,168.49,10.76">Baseline Approaches for the Authorship Identification Task Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2011</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">02BCB5A90E1B16EA5CE857B7F676CFA0</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:27+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper we present the evaluation of three different classifiers (Rocchio, Naïve Bayes and Greedy) with the aim of obtaining a baseline in the task of authorship identification. We decided to employ as features the original words contained in each document of the test set, with a minimum of preprocessing which included elimination of stopwords, punctuation symbols and XML tags. As may be seen in this paper, the obtained results are adequate, reflecting the aim of the experiments. In average, Rocchio slightly outperformed the Naïve Bayes and the Greedy classifier. However, we recommend using both, Rocchio and Naïve Bayes in future evaluations of the PAN competition as baselines from which other teams may compare their own approach.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Authorship identification is the task of determining the real author of a given text. Nowadays, there exist many texts that have been written anonymously or under false names which lead to confusion on the identification of their authorship. The main challenge of authorship identification is to automatically assign a text to one of a set of known candidate authors. The experiments reported in this paper were carried out in the framework of the 5th International Workshop on Uncovering Plagiarism, Authorship, and Social Software Misuse (PAN'11).</p><p>Given texts of uncertain authorship and texts from a set of candidate authors, the task of "Authorship identification" of PAN'11 consists of mapping the uncertain texts onto their true authors among the candidates. For this purpose, the organizers of the aforementioned task have developed a new authorship evaluation corpus which is better described in <ref type="bibr" coords="1,185.67,571.42,10.58,8.97" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p><p>We have tackled this problem through the use of supervised learning methods. The aim of this paper is to show the performance of three different methods in order to determine whether or not they may be used as baselines in future evaluations.</p><p>The rest of this document is structured as follows. Section 2 present the pre-processing techniques applied to the given corpus and a description of the classifiers used. Section 3 presents a discussion of the obtained results. Finally, in Section 4 the conclusions are given.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Authorship features and classification</head><p>The aim of our first participation in PAN'11 was to obtain baselines for the task of authorship identification. Therefore, we decided to employ as features the original words contained in each document of the test set, with a minimum of preprocessing which included elimination of stopwords, punctuation symbols and XML tags. Future evaluations will consider appropriate features which may improve the classification task. The description of the datasets used and the classifiers evaluated follows.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Datasets</head><p>Five training collections consisting of real-world texts (i.e., often short and messy) were given to the task participants. The first one with 26 different authors, the second one with 72 different authors, and the remaining three each with a single author (for author verification). In the first two cases, there were two testing scenarios, represented by a different test set: one with only authors from the training (not necessarily all), and one with authors from the training and from outside the training. For the verification task, each test set included documents from the author to be verified and some documents from other authors as well. A complete description of the rationale on the construction of these corpora is given in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,245.04,350.59,10.58,8.97" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Classification methods</head><p>Supervised learning methods are used to calculate the most likely class given a set of features. We are given a training set D of labeled documents &lt; d, a &gt;, where d ∈ D is set of documents, and a ∈ A is the set of authors, in order to obtain the classification model.</p><p>In this paper we evaluated three supervised learning methods (Rocchio, Naïve Bayes and Greedy) which are described as follows.</p><p>Rocchio Rocchio classification is a form of Rocchio relevance feedback. The average of the relevant documents, corresponding to the most important component of the Rocchio vector in relevance feedback, is the centroid of the "class" of relevant documents (the authorship centroid in our case). We omit the query component of the Rocchio formula in Rocchio classification since there is no query in text classification. Rocchio classification can be applied to classes whereas Rocchio relevance feedback is designed to distinguish only two classes, relevant and nonrelevant.</p><p>The centroid calculation formulae is shown in Eq.( <ref type="formula" coords="2,353.80,576.53,4.19,8.97" target="#formula_0">1</ref>) and the model training is depicted in algorithm 1.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,256.35,607.11,224.24,28.28">--→ µ(a) = 1 |D a | d∈Da -→ v (d),<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where D a is the set of documents in D whose author is a : D a = {d :&lt; d, a &gt;∈ D}, and -→ v (d) is the normalized vector of d.</p><p>In this approach we have used a vectorial document representation with a TF-IDF weighting schema <ref type="bibr" coords="3,203.49,130.95,13.20,8.97" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. The classification criterion presented in algorithm 2 uses the Euclidean distance. Naïve Bayes We have used a probabilistic supervised learning method named multinomial Naïve Bayes in order to determine the authorship attribution (as described in <ref type="bibr" coords="3,463.17,427.32,10.46,8.97" target="#b0">[1]</ref>). The probability of a document d being written by author a is computed as shown in Eq.(2). P (a|d) ≈ P (a)</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,308.08,474.47,172.51,21.19">1≤k≤n d P (t k |a)<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where P (t k |a) is the conditional probability of the k-th term (t k ) occurring in a document written by author a. Actually, P (t k |a) measures the contribution of term t k so that the document d belongs to class a. n d is the number of terms in document d. P (a) is the prior probability of a document written by author a. Since we are really interested in finding the best class (author) for the document, we may calculate the maximum a posteriori (MAP) as shown in Eq.( <ref type="formula" coords="3,271.24,561.64,3.95,8.97" target="#formula_2">3</ref>).</p><p>a map = arg max a∈A P * (a|d) = arg max a∈A P * (a)</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="3,365.17,583.47,115.42,22.62">1≤k≤n d P * (t k |a)<label>(3)</label></formula><p>P * (t k |a) is estimated by using Laplace smoothing, which simply adds one to each count (See Eq. ( <ref type="formula" coords="3,199.12,624.25,3.49,8.97" target="#formula_3">4</ref>)).</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="3,246.63,643.35,233.95,25.38">P * (t k |a) = T at k + 1 t ′ ∈V (T at ′ + 1)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where T at k is the number of occurrences of t k in training documents from class a, including multiple occurrences of a term in a document and V is the corpus vocabulary.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Greedy</head><p>A greedy approach was also employed in the task of authorship attribution. We calculated a similarity matrix among all the documents in the training set. Thereafter, we selected the 100 most similar documents with respect to each document of the test set.</p><p>The final class (author) is obtained by counting the most frequent class (author) from those 100 documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Evaluation</head><p>In Tables <ref type="table" coords="4,172.76,277.09,7.47,8.97" target="#tab_0">1,</ref><ref type="table" coords="4,182.20,277.09,3.73,8.97" target="#tab_1">2</ref>, 3 and 4 we may see the obtained results for the three different Although we have used the tags Rocchio, Naïve Bayes and Greedy for these approaches, in the task description paper <ref type="bibr" coords="4,250.32,301.00,11.62,8.97" target="#b1">[2]</ref> they may be reported as authorship-vilarino-2011-05-31-1456/, authorship-vilarino-2011-05-31-1455/ and authorship-vilarino-2011-05-31-1454/, respectively. We have also included include the best run, the worst run and the arithmetic mean of all the runs submitted at the competition, so that the reader may compare the three approaches reported in this paper with respect to the rest runs.</p><p>In general, Rocchio obtained a more stable behavior than Naïve Bayes and the Greedy approach. However, it is worth noticed that Naïve Bayes outperformed the Rocchio classifier in terms of macro average precision but lousy macro average recall, which is likely because it will tend to classify most documents into the largest document classes, and so will not do well for the less frequent authors.</p><p>By comparing the arithmetic mean (obtained with all the runs submitted to the competition) with respect to the presented approaches, we may suggest that both, Rocchio and Naïve Bayes would be used as baselines in future competitions of authorship attribution. Further analysis of variance is needed in order to confirm this claim. It is important to notice that these classifiers were executed with raw data, i.e., none feature selection was performed and, therefore, we expect that any features analysis would improve significantly the performance of these classifiers. In Tables 5, 6 and 7 it is presented the results obtained when the classifiers were executed using corpora attempting to detect only one author. In other words, the task consisted on detecting whether or not a particular text were written by the given author.</p><p>All the classifiers obtained a very poor performance in this particular task. We consider that the problem is that we do not have enough term frequencies for determining the discrimination degree of each term. A similar behavior is observed in the SmallTest and SmallTest+ corpus. Besides considering the term frequency, it is important to reduce the noise in the documents as done, for instance, in <ref type="bibr" coords="5,340.63,388.18,10.58,8.97" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper we have presented the performance of three supervised learning methods for the task of authorship attribution. All these classifiers were feeded with the original training data, i.e., without considering feature selection techniques of any kind. The purpose was to determine baselines for future comparisons in this task. In general, the Rocchio classifier performed better than the other two evaluated.</p><p>A simple manner of improving the obtained results would be by lemmatizing the corpus, so that we would increase the term frequencies and, therefore, the classifiers will be able to determine the discrimination degree of each term.  Having seen that Rocchio performs well, we are in conditions of analyzing and exploring different feature selection techniques for improving the authorship identification task.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,142.24,177.00,212.24,8.97;3,149.71,190.50,171.68,8.37;3,149.71,201.76,170.85,8.07;3,149.71,212.12,69.41,8.97;3,141.25,214.08,3.49,6.28;3,165.05,223.07,101.10,8.97;3,141.25,225.03,3.49,6.28;3,165.05,230.17,9.22,8.97;3,166.88,234.03,23.07,8.97;3,199.30,233.11,3.65,5.47;3,193.70,239.32,14.86,5.98;3,211.29,234.02,9.73,8.98;3,221.01,239.41,18.64,5.30;3,242.20,230.17,9.22,8.97;3,244.40,234.03,21.45,8.96;3,141.25,237.25,3.49,6.28;3,149.71,247.84,13.95,8.07;3,141.25,249.20,3.49,6.28;3,149.71,258.80,30.43,8.07;3,180.14,254.34,9.22,8.97;3,181.97,258.20,32.02,9.22;3,215.52,254.34,9.22,8.97;3,217.35,258.50,16.11,8.64;3,141.25,260.16,3.49,6.28;3,142.24,322.14,207.82,8.97;3,149.71,332.49,39.99,12.83;3,182.31,336.36,32.01,9.22;3,215.87,332.49,9.22,8.97;3,217.69,336.36,178.31,8.97;3,149.71,347.92,198.22,8.07;3,149.71,358.87,61.12,8.07;3,210.83,354.41,9.22,8.97;3,212.66,354.41,31.77,12.83;3,237.42,358.27,21.51,8.96;3,141.25,360.23,3.49,6.28"><head>Algorithm 1 : 2 -Algorithm 2 :</head><label>122</label><figDesc>Rocchio algorithm for the training step Input: A : Set of authors; D : Set of documents Output: Centroids of each author document set foreach aj ∈ A do 1 Dj ← {d :&lt; d, aj &gt;∈ D}; -→ µ 1, • • • , -→ µ J } 5 Rocchio algorithm for the testing step Input: { -→ µ 1, • • • , -→ µ J } : Centroids; d : Document of being classifed Output: The best class (author) for the input document return arg minj| -→ µ j --→ v (d)| 1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,173.19,535.02,267.23,83.10"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>PAN authorship evaluation results with the LargeTest corpus</figDesc><table coords="4,173.19,555.26,267.23,62.86"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell cols="6">MacroAvg MacroAvg MacroAvg MicroAvg MicroAvg MicroAvg</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Prec</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>Prec</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell></row><row><cell>Best run</cell><cell>0.549</cell><cell>0.532</cell><cell>0.520</cell><cell>0.658</cell><cell>0.658</cell><cell>0.658</cell></row><row><cell>Rocchio</cell><cell>0.364</cell><cell>0.337</cell><cell>0.364</cell><cell>0.428</cell><cell>0.428</cell><cell>0.428</cell></row><row><cell>Naïve Bayes</cell><cell>0.534</cell><cell>0.095</cell><cell>0.103</cell><cell>0.238</cell><cell>0.238</cell><cell>0.238</cell></row><row><cell>Greedy</cell><cell>0.232</cell><cell>0.139</cell><cell>0.147</cell><cell>0.219</cell><cell>0.219</cell><cell>0.219</cell></row><row><cell>Worst run</cell><cell>0.021</cell><cell>0.017</cell><cell>0.013</cell><cell>0.056</cell><cell>0.055</cell><cell>0.055</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">All runs arithmetic mean 0.418</cell><cell>0.266</cell><cell>0.273</cell><cell>0.402</cell><cell>0.389</cell><cell>0.395</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,173.19,115.89,267.23,83.10"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>PAN authorship evaluation results with the LargeTest+ corpus</figDesc><table coords="5,173.19,136.13,267.23,62.86"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell cols="6">MacroAvg MacroAvg MacroAvg MicroAvg MicroAvg MicroAvg</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Prec</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>Prec</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell></row><row><cell>Best run</cell><cell>0.688</cell><cell>0.267</cell><cell>0.321</cell><cell>0.779</cell><cell>0.471</cell><cell>0.587</cell></row><row><cell>Rocchio</cell><cell>0.347</cell><cell>0.245</cell><cell>0.263</cell><cell>0.368</cell><cell>0.368</cell><cell>0.368</cell></row><row><cell>Naïve Bayes</cell><cell>0.488</cell><cell>0.084</cell><cell>0.088</cell><cell>0.222</cell><cell>0.222</cell><cell>0.222</cell></row><row><cell>Greedy</cell><cell>0.153</cell><cell>0.092</cell><cell>0.089</cell><cell>0.175</cell><cell>0.175</cell><cell>0.175</cell></row><row><cell>Worst run</cell><cell>0.001</cell><cell>0.011</cell><cell>0.000</cell><cell>0.001</cell><cell>0.001</cell><cell>0.001</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">All runs arithmetic mean 0.430</cell><cell>0.147</cell><cell>0.162</cell><cell>0.407</cell><cell>0.270</cell><cell>0.314</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,173.19,215.23,267.23,83.10"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>PAN authorship evaluation results with the SmallTest corpus</figDesc><table coords="5,173.19,235.47,267.23,62.86"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell cols="6">MacroAvg MacroAvg MacroAvg MicroAvg MicroAvg MicroAvg</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Prec</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>Prec</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell></row><row><cell>Best run</cell><cell>0.662</cell><cell>0.451</cell><cell>0.475</cell><cell>0.717</cell><cell>0.717</cell><cell>0.717</cell></row><row><cell>Rocchio</cell><cell>0.236</cell><cell>0.284</cell><cell>0.358</cell><cell>0.432</cell><cell>0.432</cell><cell>0.432</cell></row><row><cell>Naïve Bayes</cell><cell>0.359</cell><cell>0.141</cell><cell>0.157</cell><cell>0.374</cell><cell>0.374</cell><cell>0.374</cell></row><row><cell>Greedy</cell><cell>0.150</cell><cell>0.061</cell><cell>0.098</cell><cell>0.091</cell><cell>0.091</cell><cell>0.091</cell></row><row><cell>Worst run</cell><cell>0.150</cell><cell>0.061</cell><cell>0.098</cell><cell>0.091</cell><cell>0.091</cell><cell>0.091</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">All runs arithmetic mean 0.459</cell><cell>0.297</cell><cell>0.303</cell><cell>0.519</cell><cell>0.515</cell><cell>0.517</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,173.19,578.54,267.23,83.10"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>PAN authorship evaluation results with the SmallTest+ corpus</figDesc><table coords="5,173.19,598.79,267.23,62.86"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell cols="6">MacroAvg MacroAvg MacroAvg MicroAvg MicroAvg MicroAvg</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Prec</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>Prec</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell></row><row><cell>Best run</cell><cell>0.737</cell><cell>0.161</cell><cell>0.193</cell><cell>0.824</cell><cell>0.457</cell><cell>0.588</cell></row><row><cell>Rocchio</cell><cell>0.200</cell><cell>0.157</cell><cell>0.195</cell><cell>0.349</cell><cell>0.349</cell><cell>0.349</cell></row><row><cell>Naïve Bayes</cell><cell>0.371</cell><cell>0.077</cell><cell>0.084</cell><cell>0.301</cell><cell>0.301</cell><cell>0.301</cell></row><row><cell>Greedy</cell><cell>0.140</cell><cell>0.030</cell><cell>0.049</cell><cell>0.065</cell><cell>0.065</cell><cell>0.065</cell></row><row><cell>Worst run</cell><cell>0.140</cell><cell>0.030</cell><cell>0.049</cell><cell>0.065</cell><cell>0.065</cell><cell>0.065</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">All runs arithmetic mean 0.527</cell><cell>0.109</cell><cell>0.119</cell><cell>0.506</cell><cell>0.293</cell><cell>0.336</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="6,187.94,115.89,239.48,83.10"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>PAN authorship evaluation results with the Verify1 corpus</figDesc><table coords="6,221.45,136.13,170.69,62.86"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell cols="3">MacroAvg MacroAvg MacroAvg</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Prec</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell></row><row><cell>Best run</cell><cell>1.000</cell><cell>0.333</cell><cell>0.500</cell></row><row><cell>Naïve Bayes</cell><cell>0.100</cell><cell>0.333</cell><cell>0.500</cell></row><row><cell>Rocchio</cell><cell>0.043</cell><cell>0.667</cell><cell>0.900</cell></row><row><cell>Greedy</cell><cell>0.033</cell><cell>0.333</cell><cell>0.500</cell></row><row><cell>Worst run</cell><cell>0.045</cell><cell>0.333</cell><cell>0.080</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">All runs arithmetic mean 0.263</cell><cell>0.400</cell><cell>0.363</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="6,187.94,212.28,239.48,83.10"><head>Table 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>PAN authorship evaluation results with the Verify2 corpus</figDesc><table coords="6,221.45,232.51,170.69,62.87"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell cols="3">MacroAvg MacroAvg MacroAvg</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Prec</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell></row><row><cell>Best run</cell><cell>0.400</cell><cell>0.800</cell><cell>0.533</cell></row><row><cell>Naïve Bayes</cell><cell>0.071</cell><cell>0.400</cell><cell>0.571</cell></row><row><cell>Greedy</cell><cell>0.031</cell><cell>0.400</cell><cell>0.571</cell></row><row><cell>Rocchio</cell><cell>0.026</cell><cell>0.400</cell><cell>0.571</cell></row><row><cell>Worst run</cell><cell>0.035</cell><cell>0.600</cell><cell>0.067</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">All runs arithmetic mean 0.185</cell><cell>0.400</cell><cell>0.346</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" coords="6,187.94,308.67,239.48,83.10"><head>Table 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>PAN authorship evaluation results with the Verify3 corpus</figDesc><table coords="6,221.45,328.90,170.69,62.87"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell cols="3">MacroAvg MacroAvg MacroAvg</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Prec</cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell></row><row><cell>Best run</cell><cell>0.211</cell><cell>1.000</cell><cell>0.348</cell></row><row><cell>Naïve Bayes</cell><cell>0.091</cell><cell>0.333</cell><cell>0.500</cell></row><row><cell>Rocchio</cell><cell>0.037</cell><cell>0.583</cell><cell>0.833</cell></row><row><cell>Greedy</cell><cell>0.034</cell><cell>0.333</cell><cell>0.500</cell></row><row><cell>Worst run</cell><cell>0.036</cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>0.067</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">All runs arithmetic mean 0.078</cell><cell>0.437</cell><cell>0.323</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,498.26,336.72,8.07;6,146.48,509.22,164.36,8.07" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,297.24,498.26,132.05,8.07">Introduction to Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Raghavan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Schtze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,520.19,337.85,8.07" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,216.71,520.19,142.04,8.07">Authorship attribution: Task description</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,376.70,520.19,73.14,8.07">Same working notes</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,531.14,287.61,8.07;6,209.99,542.10,131.13,8.07" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,261.91,531.14,160.11,8.07">A vector space model for automatic indexing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,219.70,542.10,33.26,8.07">the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="613" to="620" />
			<date type="published" when="1975">1975</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,553.05,341.46,8.07;6,146.48,564.02,324.49,8.07;6,146.48,574.98,158.81,8.07" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,181.77,553.05,220.05,8.07">Noise reduction in a statistical approach to text categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,419.81,553.05,59.77,8.07;6,146.48,564.02,324.49,8.07;6,146.48,574.98,80.74,8.07">Proc. of the 18th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval -SIGIR-ACM</title>
		<meeting>of the 18th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval -SIGIR-ACM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="256" to="263" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
