<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,99.36,86.30,396.39,14.62;1,261.84,104.78,71.16,14.62">ImageCLEF 2006 Exper iments at the Chemnitz Technical Univer sity</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,227.28,144.93,67.70,9.16"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Wilhelm</surname></persName>
							<email>thomas.wilhelm@s2000.tuchemnitz.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chemnitz University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Media Informatics Strasse der Nationen 62</addrLine>
									<postCode>09107</postCode>
									<settlement>Chemnitz</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,302.16,144.93,65.68,9.16"><forename type="first">Maximilian</forename><surname>Eibl</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chemnitz University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Media Informatics Strasse der Nationen 62</addrLine>
									<postCode>09107</postCode>
									<settlement>Chemnitz</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,99.36,86.30,396.39,14.62;1,261.84,104.78,71.16,14.62">ImageCLEF 2006 Exper iments at the Chemnitz Technical Univer sity</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">6D4005BCB600426840F7FBD2C1F9C899</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:11+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>ACM Categor ies and Subject Descr iptor s H.3.1 Content Analysis and Indexing</term>
					<term>H.3.3 Information Search and Retrieval</term>
					<term>H.3.4 Systems and Software Keywor ds image retrieval</term>
					<term>crosslanguage information retrieval</term>
					<term>query expansion</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We present a report about our participation in the ImageCLEF photo task 2006 and a short description of our new framework for future use in further CLEF participations. We described and analysed our participation in the monolingual English task. Special Lucenealigned query expansion and histogram comparisons are helping to improve the baseline results.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.2" lry="841.68"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.2" lry="841.68"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.2" lry="841.68"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.2" lry="841.68"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Our goal was to develop a new information retrieval framework which can handle different custom retrieval mechanisms (i.e. Lucene, the GNU ImageFinding Tool and others). The framework should be so general that one can use either one of the custom retrieval mechanisms or combine different ones. Therefore our efforts were not focused on better results but to get the framework up and running.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System description</head><p>For our participation at CLEF 2006 we constructed a GUI (graphical user interface) quite easy to handle. It bases on Lucene version 1.4 and includes several userconfigurable components. For example we wrote an Analyzer in which TokenFilters can be added and rearranged.</p><p>For the participation in ImageCLEF 2006 we needed to extend this system with image retrieval capabilities. But instead of extending the old system we rewrote it and developed a general IR framework. This framework does not necessarily require Lucene and makes it possible to build an abstract layer for other search engines like GIFT (GNU ImageFinding Tool) and others.</p><p>The main component of our framework is the class Run, which includes all information required to perform and repeat searches. A Run contains • the Topics, which can be preprocessed by TopicFilters • an Index, which was created by an Indexer from a DataCollection • a search method called Searcher, which can read and search the Index To use another search engine one will have to extend the abstract classes Indexer and Searcher. To use another data collection type (e.g. GIRT4, IAPR, ...) one will have to extend the abstract class DataCollection.</p><p>In order to merge results there is a special extension of the class Searcher: the MergeSearcher. It combines several Searchers and uses an abstract class Merger to merge their results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Lucene</head><p>The text search engine used is Lucene version 1.9 with an adapted Analyzer. As described above we create a LuceneIndexer and an abstract LuceneSearcher that provides basic abilities to underlying Searchers like a selectable Lucene Analyzer. The Analyzer is based on the StandardTokenizer and LowerCaseFilter by Lucene and is enhanced by a custom Snowball filter for stemming. We also added a positional stop word filter and used the stop word list suggested on the CLEF website. The Analyzer details (stemmer and stop word list) can be configured through a GUI. The LuceneStandardSearcher works with the Lucene MultiFieldQueryParser and searches in specified fields of the index.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">GIFT (GNU ImageFinding Tool)</head><p>The GIFT was not used for a submitted run but it should be mentioned here to show the abilities of the framework. We only implemented a Searcher, which can access a GIFT server and takes images to generate queries by example. The underlying index must be created with the command line utility provided by the GIFT.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">IAPR Data Collection</head><p>To access the IAPR data collection of ImageCLEF we implemented the class IaprDataCollection that provides two special options for the DataDocuments to contain special data: </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Description of the runs submitted</head><p>We focused on the monolingual task using the English topics and annotations.</p><p>The Lucene index of the annotations contains all fields. All fields are indexed and tokenized except DATE, which is not tokenized. The DOCNO is the only field which is stored, resulting in a quite small index (only 2 MB). We used the default BooleanQuery from Lucene with no further weighting of any field pairs in order to avoid any corpus specific weighting.</p><p>The default Lucene search classes (default similarity, etc.) were used to search the topicannotation field pairs as shown in table <ref type="table" coords="2,131.76,494.85,3.78,9.16">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Topic field</head><p>Annotations searched TITLE TITLE, LOCATION, DESCRIPTION, NOTES NARR DESCRIPTION, NOTES Table <ref type="table" coords="2,96.24,569.33,3.78,9.69">1</ref>. Topicannotation field pairs Our mechanism of query expansion is adapted to the Luceneindex and is, though simple, a little bit slow. First of all a list of assumable relevant documents is identified. Then the Lucenegenerated index is checked for terms also contained in documents in this list. These terms, their frequency and the number of documents in which they are found are stored in a second list. Frequency is used to apply a threshold: only terms with a high frequency are used to expand the query. The new terms are weighted by the ratio of its frequency and the number of containing documents.</p><p>For all runs, except "tucEEANT", the query expansion was applied once, using the first 20 results of the original query.</p><p>In the run "tucEEAFT2" the query expansion is applied twice. The first time using the annotations of the example images and the second time using the first 20 results of the original query.</p><p>To speed up the colour histogram comparison, we also created an index for the histogram data. For each image the histograms for the three components hue, saturation and brightness are stored and can be retrieved by the DOCNO. Though we use a Lucene index, it is used more like a database.</p><p>For the run "tucEEAFTI" all results of the textual search are scored using the Euclidean distance of their colour histograms. The histogram distance makes 30% of the new score. The remaining 70% are taken from the original score.</p><p>4 Results As one can see, run "tucEEAFT2" is our best run which is no surprise if one takes into account that three definitely relevant documents are used for query expansion. Our second best run is "tucEEAFTI" which shows that the additional histogram comparison produces better results than without it.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fig. 1. Recallprecision graphs for our submitted runs</head><p>The good results in ImageCLEF 2006 show that our framework works and that our first implemented search methods provide good results.</p><p>The normal query expansion improves the mean average precision by more than 1%. Considering the poor overall mean average precision this seems to be a good improvement of the results. Although the histogram comparison is a very simple and presumably poor measurement to compare images, it improves our textonly retrieval slightly.</p><p>The next steps to improve the results is to implement a better image retrieval algorithm due to the weak performance of the histogram comparison.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="1,89.04,672.05,171.00,9.69"><head>•</head><label></label><figDesc>and HitSets, which contain the results.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="2,88.80,311.81,231.44,9.69;2,88.80,329.33,229.28,9.69;2,70.80,346.61,354.12,9.69"><head>• option 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>the DataDocuments contain the annotations • option 2: the DataDocuments contain the histograms In both cases the associated images can be retrieved with the help of the DataDocument.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" coords="3,141.84,453.36,311.52,247.92"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="3,141.84,453.36,311.52,247.92" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,70.80,173.97,453.76,188.68"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>shows our results at ImageCLEF 2006. To compare our results, the top four runs of the monolingual English task are included in table 2.</figDesc><table coords="3,74.40,205.73,414.00,156.92"><row><cell>Rank ENEN</cell><cell>Rank ALL</cell><cell>System</cell><cell>MOD</cell><cell>A/M</cell><cell>FB</cell><cell>QE MAP</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell cols="2">1 Cindi_Exp_RF</cell><cell cols="2">MIXED MANUAL</cell><cell>WITH</cell><cell>YES 0,3850</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell cols="2">2 Cindi_TXT_EXP</cell><cell cols="2">TEXT MANUAL</cell><cell>WITH</cell><cell>YES 0,3749</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell cols="2">3 IPALPWPFB3</cell><cell cols="3">MIXED AUTO WITHOUT</cell><cell>0,3337</cell></row><row><cell>4</cell><cell cols="4">5 NTUENENAUTOFBTXTIMG MIXED AUTO</cell><cell>WITH</cell><cell>0,2950</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell>16 tucEEAFT2</cell><cell></cell><cell>TEXT</cell><cell>AUTO</cell><cell>WITH</cell><cell>YES 0,2436</cell></row><row><cell>17</cell><cell>33 tucEEAFTI</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">MIXED AUTO</cell><cell>WITH</cell><cell>YES 0,1856</cell></row><row><cell>18</cell><cell>34 tucEEAFT</cell><cell></cell><cell>TEXT</cell><cell>AUTO</cell><cell>WITH</cell><cell>YES 0,1856</cell></row><row><cell>23</cell><cell>47 tucEEANT</cell><cell></cell><cell>TEXT</cell><cell cols="2">AUTO WITHOUT</cell><cell>0,1714</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,70.80,373.25,256.64,9.69"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Ranks of our submitted runs and the first four positions</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,92.58,233.81,430.26,9.69;4,106.80,245.73,255.48,9.16" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,342.72,233.81,175.68,9.69">Apache Lucene Overview Apache Lucene</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Husted</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Cutting</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Carlson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://lucene.apache.org/java/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-08-10">2005. August 10, 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,92.58,262.85,410.38,9.69;4,106.80,274.37,339.76,9.69;4,106.80,286.29,251.16,9.16" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,293.76,262.85,209.20,9.69;4,106.80,274.37,200.90,9.69">The IAPR Benchmark for Assessing Image Retrieval Performance in Cross Language Evaluation Tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grubinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Leung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ir.shef.ac.uk/cloughie/papers/muscleimageclef2005.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-08-10">2005. August 10, 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,92.58,303.41,411.54,9.69;4,106.80,315.33,272.76,9.16" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,178.08,303.41,321.74,9.69">The GNU ImageFinding Tool GNU Project Free Software Foundation (FSF)</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Roos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.gnu.org/software/gift/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-08-10">2005. August 10, 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
