<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,202.79,115.90,209.78,12.90;1,229.99,133.83,155.38,12.90;1,223.43,153.68,168.50,10.75">Bots and Gender Profiling Using a Deep Learning Approach Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2019</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,181.37,190.08,105.00,8.64"><forename type="first">Jose</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Prieto Fontcuberta</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Universitat Politècnica de València</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,305.75,190.08,64.46,8.64"><forename type="first">Gretel</forename><forename type="middle">Liz</forename><surname>De La</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Universitat Politècnica de València</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,372.70,190.08,56.71,8.64"><forename type="first">Peña</forename><surname>Sarracén</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Universitat Politècnica de València</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,202.79,115.90,209.78,12.90;1,229.99,133.83,155.38,12.90;1,223.43,153.68,168.50,10.75">Bots and Gender Profiling Using a Deep Learning Approach Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2019</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">1F658D5F4DFAA569DCB8CE9B93BA447E</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:59+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the system we developed for the Bots and gender profiling task, at PAN @ CLEF 2019. The task consists in, given a tweets set, automatically determine whether its author is a bot or a human. In case of human, identify her/his gender. We propose a deep learning based system, fed with the TFIDF representation from the texts instead of word embeddings representation as usual. Additionally, we use some linguistic features which improve the performance of the system according with the experimental results.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Nowadays we use a lot of social media content, being a powerful tool to communicate to the world. Some enterprises use bots accounts as a social manager to answer fast, free and automatically to their clients. However, sometimes some governments, people or powerful institutions abuse of these social networks and create bots to manipulate and distortion the information and the point of view of some users <ref type="bibr" coords="1,406.67,426.95,10.58,8.64" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" coords="1,423.77,426.95,10.58,8.64" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. A bot can be defined as a program that learns to promote some information as a normal user but automatically, and can be programmed with a software specially concerned on the manipulation on some topics. Hence identifying bots in the social networks is a relevant task, not only from a point of view of marketing, but also from a forensics and security perspective.</p><p>Among the efforts made to address this phenomenon, this year the Bots and gender profiling task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,193.06,510.64,11.62,8.64" target="#b8">[9]</ref> has been launched as part of PAN @ CLEF 2019 1 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,424.81,510.64,10.58,8.64" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. This task focuses on detecting bots against humans users given a text set from Twitter, one of the most used social networks. The tweets are in English and Spanish.</p><p>In recent related works as in <ref type="bibr" coords="1,266.21,546.50,10.58,8.64" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, deep learning techniques, used for text classification purposes, are used also for this task. More recent and new techniques are explained and used in <ref type="bibr" coords="1,181.24,570.41,10.58,8.64" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, where also Word Embeddings, dense layers and LSTM are used. In general, many works point out the flexibility in capturing nonlinear relationships of deep learning techniques.</p><p>In this paper, we propose a Feedforward Neural Network of two layers for the task. In addition, as a second step, the system should identify the author gender in case of human. For this other task we use a similar architecture but in this case with 4 layers. A point to highlight is the use of some linguistic features which can help to discriminate among types of users. The paper is organized as follows. Section 2 describes our system. Experimental results are then discussed in Section 3. Finally, we present our conclusions with a summary of our findings in Section 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Preprocessing</head><p>In the preprocessing step the text is cleaned. Firstly, the typical characteristics used in the tweets, and that possibly do not have discriminatory semantic information, have been identified. We identify urls, numbers, mentions to users and dates as that kind of features. Then, each part of the texts which represents this kind of features is replaced with a corresponding tag.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Method</head><p>We propose a model that consists in a Feedforward Neural Network (FFNN) with two layers, BatchNorm and ReLU activation. As input, the model takes a vector which is generated as TFIDF representation of the concatenation of all tweets of the user. Thus, we achieve to represent the information of a user in a unique vector. Given a text set S, a term t, and an individual text T ∈ S, we calculate:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,228.53,440.65,252.06,22.31">T F IDF (t) = tf (t, T ) * log( |S| tf (t, S) )<label>(1)</label></formula><p>Where tf (t, T ) is the number of times t appears in T , |S| is the size of the corpus, and tf (t, S) is the number of texts in which t appears in S. This representation was selected based on the idea that the words usually used by a user and no commonly by others, could be more important in the corresponding representation of the user. This is an idea that matches with the phenomenon which we try to capture. That is, this kind of representation can allow us to get typical characteristics of each user.</p><p>We also tried to encode with TFIDF every tweet separately and then concatenate all of them, creating as a result something similar to a gray scale image. For this representation we used a 2D Convolutional Neural Network with large kernels matching with the number of features extracted from the TFIDF representation (2DCNN-TFIDF). These large kernels are so expensive even when a GPU is used, due to this the train is extremely slowly. We also tried to use a Recurrent Neural Network with a few layers of LSTM (LSTM-TFIDF). On both experiments the results were not enough satisfactory.</p><p>Similarly, we tried other approaches with other kinds of representation, using the GloVe Word-Embeddings. We use all the tweets concatenated and then we look up into the Word-Embedding table. As before, for this representation we used a 2D Convolutional Neural Network with large kernels matching with the number of features extracted from the embeddings (2DCNN-WE) and a Recurrent Neural Network with a few layers of LSTM (LSTM-WE). Again, on both experiments the results were not enough satisfactory.</p><p>Finally, we tried to concatenate the tweets of a given user on depth, obtaining as result an image with the number of channels (depth) equivalent to the number of tweets of the user. Each matrix is the concatenation of words embeddings for a tweet. Therefore, the width and height are determined by the size of embeddings and number of words in the tweet, respectively. With this approach we used a 3D Convolutional Neural Network with larger kernels (3DCNN-WE). With this last approach the idea is to consider the kernels as large as the size of the embedding and in the second dimension we chose a n-gram value to consider the context.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Linguistic Features</head><p>We include some linguistic features which consider important to discriminate among users. For the implementation we used the TextBlob library<ref type="foot" coords="3,371.47,330.46,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_0">2</ref> which can be used to process texts in English. Hence, these features were employed just with the corpus in English. Two types of features were analyzed. On one side, features related with subjective information and on the other hand, features related with syntactic information:</p><p>-Subjective information (SI): Analysis of degree of subjectivity and sentiment present in the text. This can be a good discriminative feature, since bots can be less subjective and sentimental than humans. -Syntactic features (SF): Analysis of count of adjectives, adverbs and pronouns in texts. These kinds of features can discriminate between male and females as some studies suggest <ref type="bibr" coords="3,214.25,453.82,10.58,8.64" target="#b5">[6]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head><p>In this section, we report and discuss the performance of the system in the task. Training and evaluation were conducted using the PAN @ 2019 proportioned datasets which have 4120 and 3000 tweets in English and Spanish respectively. The data is balanced for each subtask and language. Results are obtained by uploaded the system to TIRA <ref type="bibr" coords="3,134.77,564.33,10.58,8.64" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p><p>The results obtained on the development set with each approach commented before are reported in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,224.10,588.93,3.74,8.64" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. As we can see the best results are achieved with the FFNN method. Hence it was the system selected for the task at PAN 2019. Other models that supposed to be superior obtained worse results. Perhaps it could be due to the large number of introduced parameters that were not well trained due the small amount of data available.</p><p>As we can see in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,248.11,119.31,3.74,8.64" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, the best results achieved have an accuracy of 0.90 and 0.93 on Spanish and English datasets, respectively. In the Spanish partition we do not use linguistic features, as we do in English dataset, where we use SI and SF features. In Table <ref type="table" coords="4,185.65,279.45,4.98,8.64">2</ref> we can see the improvement of the FFNN method adding the linguistic features (LF). As we commented before, we just used them for the English corpus. The system gains one point of accuracy adding these features, but there were no differences when adding the syntactic features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Without LF With SI With SI + SF Accuracy EN 0.92 0.93 0.93 Table <ref type="table" coords="4,230.54,380.62,3.36,8.06">2</ref>. Results in the Bot vs Humans Task with FFNN Table <ref type="table" coords="4,173.86,438.36,4.98,8.64">3</ref> shows the results of accuracy for gender profiling for those tweets predicted as a human. We achieve 0.87 accuracy on the English corpus, and the results did not vary when the linguistic features are added. Hence these features are not important for this task according to our experimental results. On the Spanish corpus, 0.86 accuracy is achieved without any linguistic feature.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Method</head><p>Without LF With SI With SI + SF Accuracy EN 0.87 0.87 0.87 Accuracy ES 0.86 --Table <ref type="table" coords="4,244.99,562.84,3.36,8.06">3</ref>. Results in the Gender Task with FFNN Table <ref type="table" coords="4,174.47,620.57,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_1">4</ref> shows the results on the test datasets for our final model and the baselines proposed by the organizers of the task. We outperform in almost all the cases the results of the baselines, except in English bot task where the LDSE method <ref type="bibr" coords="4,411.92,644.48,11.62,8.64" target="#b7">[8]</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>We propose a deep learning based system for the Bots and gender profiling task, at PAN @ CLEF 2019. The model consists of a Feedforward Neural Network which gets as input the TFIDF representation from the text. The experimental results show the suitability of the used representation for the task, achieving 0.8578 of accuracy on the Spanish corpus and 0.9045 on the English corpus, on detecting bots vs human. For gender profiling we obtain an accuracy of 0.6967 and 0.7898, respectively. Also, some linguistic features are added, allowing for a small improvement in the bots and human discrimination task, but not for gender profiling. Furthermore, we tried to use word embeddings and some different kinds of architectures with these new features but the results were not enough satisfactory. Maybe the results of CNN might be improved with more data for re-training the word-embedding for this specific task.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,136.56,186.31,349.60,41.70"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Results of different approaches on the development dataset</figDesc><table coords="4,136.56,186.31,349.60,30.84"><row><cell>Method</cell><cell cols="6">FFNN 2DCNN-TFIDF LSTM-TFIDF 2DCNN-WE LSTM-WE 3DCNN-WE</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Accuracy ES 0.90</cell><cell>0.76</cell><cell>0.73</cell><cell>0.70</cell><cell>0.69</cell><cell>0.72</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Accuracy EN 0.93</cell><cell>0.78</cell><cell>0.75</cell><cell>0.72</cell><cell>0.70</cell><cell>0.73</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,134.77,644.48,345.82,20.59"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>obtains better results. Final results in both task on the test datasets</figDesc><table coords="5,197.04,117.72,221.16,52.76"><row><cell cols="4">Method MAJORITY RANDOM LDSE Our proposal</cell></row><row><cell>EN</cell><cell>0.5000</cell><cell>0.4905 0.9054</cell><cell>0.9045</cell></row><row><cell>Bots ES</cell><cell>0.5000</cell><cell>0.4861 0.8372</cell><cell>0.8578</cell></row><row><cell>EN</cell><cell>0.5000</cell><cell>0.3716 0.7800</cell><cell>0.7898</cell></row><row><cell>Gender ES</cell><cell>0.5000</cell><cell>0.3700 0.6900</cell><cell>0.6967</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_0" coords="3,144.73,657.08,136.76,7.77"><p>https://textblob.readthedocs.io/en/dev/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,138.13,416.79,341.14,7.77;5,146.47,427.75,319.91,7.77;5,146.47,438.71,327.03,7.77;5,146.47,449.67,319.19,7.77;5,146.47,460.63,291.22,7.77;5,146.47,471.59,308.55,7.77" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,421.68,427.75,44.71,7.77;5,146.47,438.71,327.03,7.77;5,146.47,449.67,83.70,7.77">Overview of PAN 2019: Author Profiling, Celebrity Profiling, Cross-domain Authorship Attribution and Style Change Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Daelemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kestemont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Manjavancas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Specht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tschuggnall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Zangerle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,348.42,460.63,89.27,7.77;5,146.47,471.59,208.19,7.77">Proceedings of the Tenth International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Crestani</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Braschler</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Savoy</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rauber</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Losada</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Heinatz</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cappellato</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the Tenth International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019-09">2019. Sep 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,138.13,482.43,331.09,7.77;5,146.47,493.39,267.51,7.77" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,189.29,482.43,279.93,7.77;5,146.47,493.39,73.14,7.77">Disinformation and Social Bot Operations in The Run Up to The 2017 French Presidential Election</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ferrara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1707.0008622(8</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="33" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,138.13,504.23,306.74,7.77;5,146.47,515.19,277.70,7.77;5,146.47,526.15,112.61,7.77" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,364.91,504.23,79.95,7.77;5,146.47,515.19,161.46,7.77">Political Bots and The Manipulation of Public Opinion in Venezuela</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Forelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Howard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Monroy-Hernández</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Savage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>CoRR abs/1507.07109</idno>
		<ptr target="http://arxiv.org/abs/1507.07109" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,138.13,537.00,332.41,7.77;5,146.47,547.95,122.05,7.77" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,180.19,537.00,264.33,7.77">A Survey of Neural Network Techniques for Feature Extraction from Text</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>John</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1704.08531</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,138.13,558.80,335.57,7.77;5,146.47,569.76,75.46,7.77" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,245.20,558.80,146.10,7.77">Deep Neural Networks for Bot Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kudugunta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ferrara</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,397.25,558.80,76.45,7.77">Information Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">467</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="312" to="322" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,138.13,580.60,326.86,7.77;5,146.47,591.56,162.64,7.77" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,196.77,580.60,217.84,7.77">The Secret Life of Pronouns. What Our Words Say About Us</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Nerbonne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,420.92,580.60,44.07,7.77;5,146.47,591.56,78.97,7.77">Literary and Linguistic Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="142" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,138.13,602.40,335.03,7.77;5,146.47,613.36,309.15,7.77;5,146.47,624.32,209.02,7.77" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,329.38,602.40,140.16,7.77">TIRA Integrated Research Architecture</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gollub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,255.05,613.36,200.58,7.77;5,146.47,624.32,144.92,7.77">Information Retrieval Evaluation in a Changing World -Lessons Learned from 20 Years of CLEF</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,138.13,635.17,316.14,7.77;5,146.47,646.13,328.94,7.77;5,146.47,657.08,221.42,7.77" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,303.07,635.17,151.19,7.77;5,146.47,646.13,112.45,7.77">A Low Dimensionality Representation for Language Variety Identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Franco-Salvador</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,276.71,646.13,198.70,7.77;5,146.47,657.08,109.32,7.77">International Conference on Intelligent Text Processing and Computational Linguistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="156" to="169" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.13,119.96,326.02,7.77;6,146.47,130.92,316.92,7.77;6,146.47,141.88,241.55,7.77" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,224.72,119.96,239.43,7.77;6,146.47,130.92,58.90,7.77">Overview of The 7th Author Profiling Task at PAN 2019: Bots and Gender Profiling</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="-WS.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,421.29,130.92,42.10,7.77;6,146.47,141.88,72.99,7.77">CLEF 2019 Labs and Workshops</title>
		<title level="s" coord="6,225.94,141.88,85.63,7.77">Notebook Papers. CEUR</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cappellato</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Losada</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-09">Sep 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
