<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,137.51,151.14,331.59,14.30;1,153.18,168.66,288.92,14.30;1,211.27,188.66,172.70,10.67">Bots and Gender Profiling with Convolutional Hierarchical Recurrent Neural Network Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2019</title>
				<funder ref="#_g6VG2Xt #_dJmXAgE">
					<orgName type="full">Slovak Research and Development Agency</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Human Information Behavior in the Digital Space</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_ZBEGQgx">
					<orgName type="full">Scientific Grant Agency of the Slovak Republic</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,248.03,225.51,44.58,9.19"><forename type="first">Juraj</forename><surname>Petrik</surname></persName>
							<email>juraj.petrik@stuba.sk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Slovak University of Technology in</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Bratislava</settlement>
									<country key="SK">Slovakia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,298.87,225.51,59.75,9.19"><forename type="first">Daniela</forename><surname>Chuda</surname></persName>
							<email>daniela.chuda@stuba.sk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Slovak University of Technology in</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Bratislava</settlement>
									<country key="SK">Slovakia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,137.51,151.14,331.59,14.30;1,153.18,168.66,288.92,14.30;1,211.27,188.66,172.70,10.67">Bots and Gender Profiling with Convolutional Hierarchical Recurrent Neural Network Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2019</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">7806BF13113BC56C73AFB824F79E03E0</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:59+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Paper describes approach leveraging deep learning principles in bots and gender profiling task at CLEF 2019 conference. Our approach is using hierarchical network for classification of tweets sequences. We achieved 90% accuracy of type profiling for English and 86.9% for Spanish language and 77.6% and 77.2% respectively accuracy in gender profiling.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.275" lry="841.889"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.275" lry="841.889"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.275" lry="841.889"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.275" lry="841.889"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.275" lry="841.889"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.275" lry="841.889"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.275" lry="841.889"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.275" lry="841.889"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This paper describes our approach to bots and gender profiling task for PAN at CLEF 2019 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,175.19,421.83,11.69,9.19" target="#b0">[1]</ref>  <ref type="bibr" coords="1,189.87,421.83,10.64,9.19" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Our approach is based on our previous work dealing with source code authorship attribution <ref type="bibr" coords="1,239.30,433.35,10.64,9.19" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. This approach is based on newest natural language processing principles used in text classification and stylometry. Our solution was evaluated using TIRA evaluation service <ref type="bibr" coords="1,290.47,456.39,10.64,9.19" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p><p>Bots are commonly used in bank or insurance sector as chat bots. These chat bots act as first level support for customers. They are able to help people with simple problems. Another positive example are weather forecasting bots or stock exchange information bots. They are effective way for sending information to multiple users (via Twitter, Facebook and Instagram for example).</p><p>However, another type of bots is used to spread misleading information, fake news for example. And we need to filter out this kind of information, because people tend to believe in such information as this information is spread across the whole internet and looks like valid fact.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">Task Description</head><p>Aim of this task 1 is to determine if given Twitter feed is written by human or bot. In case given Twitter feed is written by human, our next task is determine if it is written by male or female. Also, this task is multilingual, it consists of two sub datasets -English and Spanish. Despite of language separation, creators of dataset do not guarantee language consistency for all tweets in feed.</p><p>Our performance is evaluated by average accuracy of each subtask (human vs bot and male vs female) of each language.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Related Work</head><p>In terms of stylometry, authorship attribution is application of linguistic style to written language, but also to music <ref type="bibr" coords="2,277.17,261.99,10.66,9.19" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, which is defining writer's style as unique property for specific author -his fingerprint. Authorship profiling is part of stylometry, which is specifically focusing on determining author traits, such as age, gender or occupation.</p><p>In context of this paper we will focus on linguistic stylometry due to natural language character of Twitter feeds.</p><p>Problem of duplicate accounts on internet discussion forums was discussed in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,456.39,331.35,10.63,9.19" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Duplicate accounts are created because of account ban, group accounts, and reputation boosting (sales). Authors of this publication trained one classifier for each account (discussion forum user) -this means that for N user accounts there were N trained classifiers. Advantage of this solution is that we can run these classifiers independently -parallelization is trivial. It is also clear from the paper, that accounts with small number of messages with short length are problematic. Another problem is intentional modification of writer's style by Anonymouth tool for example <ref type="bibr" coords="2,439.71,412.23,10.64,9.19" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, but fortunately we do not have any suspicions that such a tool was used in task datasets.</p><p>Other paper <ref type="bibr" coords="2,191.40,435.27,11.67,9.19" target="#b7">[8]</ref> was trying to find out if the writer's style was intentionally modified. They used character, numerical and special characters, words and word function properties. Samples classification was done by support vector machines (SVM) in cooperation with sequence minimal optimization (SMO). Also, other classification methods were tested, such as k-NN, naive Bayes classifier, decision trees and logistic regression. However, SVM with SMO achieved significantly better results than other methods. Next, they evaluated information gain of properties for distinguishing imitated and obfuscated documents from original ones, what is similar problem as type profiling in this task (human vs bot).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Our Method</head><p>Our method is based on our previous work, which achieved state of the art results in source code authorship attribution <ref type="bibr" coords="2,276.17,604.47,10.67,9.19" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. We made several changes to the method, to be able to leverage nature of twitter messages, most importantly to deal with natural language opposed to source code. Important improvement in our approach is hierarchical layers arrangement to take advantage of sequence character of tweets in feed.</p><p>We have done experiments also with TF-IDF based approaches in combination with different classifiers. This approach was superior to our method. However, we used it as a good baseline for experiments <ref type="bibr" coords="2,294.65,685.35,10.64,9.19" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Preprocessing</head><p>Training dataset consists of 4120 English Twitter feeds and 3000 Spanish Twitter feeds. Each feed consists of exactly 100 tweets. Maximum tweet length is 140 or 280 characters <ref type="foot" coords="3,165.25,411.33,3.00,5.47" target="#foot_1">2</ref> . Samples are provided in XML files, one sample per file.</p><p>As stated above, data for this task consists of unprocessed twitter feeds. Our brief data analysis shown that majority of tweets contain relatively large number of emojis, quiet large number of typos, double, triple chars, punctuation or mixed language.</p><p>Twitter users are standardly utilizing Unicode set of emojis <ref type="foot" coords="3,375.49,457.65,3.00,5.47" target="#foot_2">3</ref> . Working with special Unicode characters is not convenient and is easier working with their word description. In theory this should not be necessary, because we are using word embeddings. But our training corpus is relatively small, so this step is helping us to better train these embeddings -we are de facto extending tweets and got more tokens in dataset. You can see example of such a transformation in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,390.96,515.67,2.93,9.19">I</ref>.  Before @0rangelic @Roslinnovation You're doing way better than everyone here. 😉 After @0rangelic @Roslinnovation -PRON-be do way well than everyone here . : winking_face :</p><p>Next step of our preprocessing pipeline is lemmatization. Lemmatization is process of extracting word lemma (word root). We can think of this as dimensionality reduction which will potentially easier generalization of our model (Table <ref type="table" coords="4,425.82,263.19,3.62,9.19" target="#tab_1">2</ref>). Usually lemmatization is not needed when word embeddings are used, however our as stated, our corpus is small, so we are using all available method to make embeddings more stable and more domain specific.</p><p>Next step is tokenization and token encoding. We used standard Keras framework function for these two steps. Tokens were split by space characters and we filter out special characters such as braces, hash key, punctuation characters, etc. with combination of converting tokens to their lowercase representation. Tokens were encoded to integers based on their index in corpus dictionary.</p><p>Last step is zero-padding of inputs to fixed length (our model doesn't support variable length input sequence). We empirically chose sequence length of 60 tokens (words) based on histogram in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,277.45,390.39,3.76,9.19" target="#fig_0">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Classification</head><p>Our classifier is based on our previous work <ref type="bibr" coords="4,323.70,455.91,11.69,9.19" target="#b1">[2]</ref> -convolutional recurrent neural network. It consists of multiple layers -embedding, convolutional, recurrent and dense layers.</p><p>Convolutional neural networks are often used in image processing, where they achieved state of the art results in image recognition. They are gaining popularity also in natural language processing, because they act as feature extractors in texts too.</p><p>Embeddings are heavily used throughout variety of text processing problems. They are effectively encoding words into vector representation. Our embedding layer is randomly initialized (not pretrained) and trained on the fly -it should learn more specific domain specific embedding vectors this way.</p><p>Recurrent networks, especially Long-Short Term Memory units are used in state of the art models for text classification, emotions detection or speech recognition. They are good at sequence learning -and tweets are word sequences.</p><p>We were struggling with overfitting of the network, which we solve by adding dropouts. Dropout is randomly dropping connections between layers and therefore helping generalization of the model.</p><p>As stated above, tweets are word (character) sequences. We can say, that feeds are tweet sequences, therefore it could be beneficial to work with them as they are </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Hyperparameters:</head><p>Batch size: 8 Epochs: 100 Early stopping: patience 5, validation loss monitoring Loss: categorical crossentropy Adam optimizer: learning rate 0.001, beta1 0.9, beta2 0.99 </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>This chapter describes our testing results and task testing dataset results. Our testing results are average of multiple runs (10) of different dataset splits.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Our Testing Results</head><p>For our testing purposes we used 50/25/25 split for training, validation and testing fractions of data respectively. We are using accuracy metric, because classes are perfectly balanced, which means every class has exactly same number of samples.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="6,163.01,387.99,5.04,9.19" target="#tab_2">3</ref> demonstrates our results on testing split (25% of training dataset). Our results were quite encouraging, although were significantly worse than results on organizers testing dataset (Table <ref type="table" coords="6,256.86,411.03,3.62,9.19" target="#tab_3">4</ref>).</p><p>Also, our testing score (accuracy) was calculated differently than on task testing dataset. We were training exclusively on tweets posted by humans, so our gender testing accuracy is just from human samples. Gender task testing dataset was calculated from all samples (human and bot), this is main cause of big accuracy difference.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Task Testing Dataset Results</head><p>Our approach achieved roughly 90% accuracy in type recognition (human or bot) and 77.5% accuracy in gender recognition (male or female) for English Twitter feeds for task testing dataset. Spanish samples results were slightly worse -86.9% accuracy for type recognition and 72.5% for gender recognition (Table <ref type="table" coords="6,372.38,559.59,3.62,9.19" target="#tab_3">4</ref>).</p><p>It is evident that results on task testing dataset are significantly worse than results on our testing split. This is probably caused by insufficient generalization of our model, we suspect collected "vocabulary" is not large enough. Specifically speaking, vocabulary of our embedding layer is not large enough, which results in a lot out of vocabulary words and therefore next layers in our model don't have enough information to make reliable decision. Testing dataset wasn't published to the date of paper submission, so we are unable to make proper analysis in context of task testing dataset. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions and Possible Upgrades</head><p>Our final task ranking is 21 from total of 55 contestants. Unfortunately, even two baseline methods (word and character n-grams outperformed our solution). Despite of final ranking, we must say that this our first appearance in such a competition was not total disaster -we rank in better half of solutions. Unfortunately, because of time and computational constrains we were not able to realize and test all our ideas. Task results give us also some ideas, what we could done better.</p><p>First of all, tokenization step could be improved, for example there is lot of URLs in tweets, and we could get links from them and use information from sites such as topic or language of site. Additionally, we could use for example hypernyms in preprocessing to normalize texts.</p><p>Discussed above, our vocabulary was probably very limited (due to small training dataset). We could overcome this problem using pretrained English and Spanish embedding vectors or enrich dataset using Twitter real time API.</p><p>We used simple word level embedding layer, however other papers show, that using more sophisticated methods such as ELMo or character-based embedding have better results in topic modeling for example. Therefore, we can deduct usage of these methods could improve our results.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,205.51,312.07,202.24,8.32;3,165.41,138.15,259.20,166.60"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. Histogram of tweets length (number of words)</figDesc><graphic coords="3,165.41,138.15,259.20,166.60" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="5,169.42,368.95,256.46,8.32;5,144.66,162.80,317.95,198.90"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. Our convolutional hierarchical recurrent network architecture</figDesc><graphic coords="5,144.66,162.80,317.95,198.90" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,192.26,538.87,232.59,107.47"><head>Table 1 . Example transformation table of Unicode emojis Emoji Code Transformed emoji to text</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="3,199.32,565.54,200.94,80.80"><row><cell>😀</cell><cell>U+1F600</cell><cell>:grinning_face:</cell></row><row><cell>👍</cell><cell>U+1F44D</cell><cell>:thumbs_up:</cell></row><row><cell>👎</cell><cell>U+1F44E</cell><cell>:thumbs_down:</cell></row><row><cell>✊</cell><cell>U+270A</cell><cell>:raised_fist:</cell></row><row><cell>👊</cell><cell>U+1F44A</cell><cell>:oncoming_fist:</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,169.40,150.07,256.47,8.32"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Example tweet transformation of emojis to text and to lemmas</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="6,169.33,178.39,238.61,50.56"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Training dataset accuracy results (testing split)</figDesc><table coords="6,169.33,195.61,238.61,33.34"><row><cell></cell><cell>Type (acc)</cell><cell>Gender* (acc)</cell></row><row><cell>English</cell><cell>0.9831</cell><cell>0.9412</cell></row><row><cell>Spanish</cell><cell>0.9767</cell><cell>0.9221</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="7,169.33,150.07,255.26,50.56"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Testing dataset results provided by task organizers (accuracy)</figDesc><table coords="7,169.33,167.29,233.61,33.34"><row><cell></cell><cell>Type (acc)</cell><cell>Gender (acc)</cell></row><row><cell>English</cell><cell>0.9008</cell><cell>0.7758</cell></row><row><cell>Spanish</cell><cell>0.8689</cell><cell>0.7250</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,130.06,676.39,218.23,8.32"><p>https://pan.webis.de/clef19/pan19-web/author-profiling.html</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="3,130.06,676.15,250.71,8.32"><p>https://developer.twitter.com/en/docs/basics/counting-characters.html</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="3,130.06,686.95,204.25,8.32"><p>http://www.unicode.org/emoji/charts/full-emoji-list.html</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was partially supported by <rs type="funder">Human Information Behavior in the Digital Space</rs>, the <rs type="funder">Slovak Research and Development Agency</rs> under the contract No. <rs type="grantNumber">APVV-15-0508</rs>, by the <rs type="funder">Slovak Research and Development Agency</rs> under the contract No. <rs type="grantNumber">APVV-17-0267 -</rs><rs type="projectName">Automated Recognition of Antisocial Behaviour in Online Communities</rs> and by data space based on machine learning, the <rs type="funder">Scientific Grant Agency of the Slovak Republic</rs>, grant No. <rs type="grantNumber">VG 1/0725/19</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_g6VG2Xt">
					<idno type="grant-number">APVV-15-0508</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_dJmXAgE">
					<idno type="grant-number">APVV-17-0267 -</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">Automated Recognition of Antisocial Behaviour in Online Communities</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_ZBEGQgx">
					<idno type="grant-number">VG 1/0725/19</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,128.08,623.35,342.42,8.32;7,136.04,633.67,334.68,8.32;7,136.04,643.99,334.54,8.32;7,136.04,654.31,27.80,8.32" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,255.41,623.35,215.10,8.32;7,136.04,633.67,96.09,8.32">Overview of the 7th Author Profiling Task at PAN 2019: Bots and Gender Profiling</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Francisco</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="-WS.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,448.65,633.67,22.07,8.32;7,136.04,643.99,102.89,8.32">CLEF 2019 Labs and Workshops</title>
		<title level="s" coord="7,248.38,643.99,216.81,8.32">Notebook Papers. CEUR Workshop Proceedings. CEUR</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cappellato</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Losada</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,128.08,664.87,342.52,8.32;7,136.04,675.19,334.45,8.32;8,136.04,150.07,334.59,8.32;8,136.04,160.39,86.28,8.32" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,277.96,664.87,192.65,8.32;7,136.04,675.19,37.06,8.32">Source code authorship approaches natural language processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Juraj</forename><surname>Petrík</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Daniela</forename><surname>Chudá</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,190.15,675.19,280.35,8.32;8,136.04,150.07,119.60,8.32">Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Computer Systems and Technologies (CompSysTech&apos;18)</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Boris</forename><surname>Rachev</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Angel</forename><surname>Smrikarov</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the 19th International Conference on Computer Systems and Technologies (CompSysTech&apos;18)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="58" to="61" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,128.08,170.95,342.48,8.32;8,136.04,181.27,334.54,8.32;8,136.04,191.59,334.56,8.32;8,136.04,202.15,334.53,8.32;8,136.04,212.47,334.58,8.32;8,136.04,222.79,332.96,8.32" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,136.04,191.59,334.56,8.32;8,136.04,202.15,144.69,8.32">Overview of PAN 2019: Author Profiling, Celebrity Profiling, Cross-domain Authorship Attribution and Style Change Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Daelemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kestemont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Manjavancas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Specht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tschuggnall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Zangerle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,402.25,212.47,68.38,8.32;8,136.04,222.79,232.25,8.32">Proceedings of the Tenth International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Crestani</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Braschler</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Savoy</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rauber</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Müller</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Losada</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Heinatz</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cappellato</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the Tenth International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019-09">2019. Sep 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,128.08,233.35,342.44,8.32;8,136.04,243.67,334.54,8.32;8,136.04,253.99,210.74,8.32" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,324.19,233.35,142.70,8.32">TIRA Integrated Research Architecture</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gollub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,255.56,243.67,215.02,8.32;8,136.04,253.99,146.38,8.32">Information Retrieval Evaluation in a Changing World -Lessons Learned from 20 Years of CLEF</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,128.08,264.55,342.51,8.32;8,136.04,274.87,334.69,8.32;8,136.04,285.19,334.57,8.32;8,136.04,295.51,94.54,8.32" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,270.39,264.55,200.21,8.32;8,136.04,274.87,77.89,8.32">A Low Dimensionality Representation for Language Variety Identification</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Franco</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,234.27,274.87,236.47,8.32;8,136.04,285.19,236.35,8.32">Proceedings of the 17th International Conference on Intelligent Text Processing and Computational Linguistics (CICLing&apos;16)</title>
		<meeting>the 17th International Conference on Intelligent Text Processing and Computational Linguistics (CICLing&apos;16)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>LNCS</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">9624. 2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="156" to="169" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,128.08,306.07,342.50,8.32;8,136.04,316.39,334.56,8.32;8,136.04,326.71,45.03,8.32" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,419.80,306.07,50.78,8.32;8,136.04,316.39,165.74,8.32">Doppelganger finder: Taking stylometry to the underground</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Afroz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Caliskan-Islam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Stolerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Greenstadt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mccoy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,312.86,316.39,119.01,8.32">Proc. -IEEE Symp. Secur. Priv</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="212" to="226" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,128.08,337.27,342.49,8.32;8,136.04,347.59,209.76,8.32" xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,380.33,337.27,90.24,8.32;8,136.04,347.59,147.19,8.32">Anonymouth Revamped: Getting Closer to Stylometric Anonymity</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">W E</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ulman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Barrowclift</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Greenstadt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="4" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,128.08,357.91,342.59,8.32;8,136.04,368.47,268.49,8.32" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,306.55,357.91,164.12,8.32;8,136.04,368.47,69.13,8.32">Detecting hoaxes, frauds, and deception in writing style online</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Afroz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brennan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Greenstadt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,214.53,368.47,114.76,8.32">Proc. -IEEE Symp. Secur. Priv</title>
		<meeting>-IEEE Symp. Secur. Priv</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="461" to="475" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,128.08,378.79,342.48,8.32;8,136.04,389.11,207.75,8.32" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,268.69,378.79,194.02,8.32">On musical stylometry-a pattern recognition approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Backer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Van Kranenburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,136.04,389.11,80.59,8.32">Pattern Recognit. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="309" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
