<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,173.64,148.86,255.73,15.15;1,118.44,170.78,366.11,15.15">TextMESS at GeoCLEF 2008: Result Merging with Fuzzy Borda Ranking</title>
				<funder ref="#_hGG5f4Y #_qNUXC9C">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,190.98,204.67,94.48,8.74"><forename type="first">José</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Perea Ortega</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">de Informática</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,308.16,204.67,45.02,8.74"><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Alfonso</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">de Informática</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,356.50,204.67,55.52,8.74"><forename type="first">Ureña</forename><surname>López</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">de Informática</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,228.50,266.32,70.63,8.74"><forename type="first">Davide</forename><surname>Buscaldi</surname></persName>
							<email>dbuscaldi@dsic.upv.es</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">de Informática</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Jaén</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,321.81,266.32,52.70,8.74"><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
							<email>prosso@dsic.upv.es</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Dpto. de Sistemas Informáticos</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Natural Language Engineering Lab y Computación (DSIC)</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Politécnica de Valencia</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="ES">Spain</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,173.64,148.86,255.73,15.15;1,118.44,170.78,366.11,15.15">TextMESS at GeoCLEF 2008: Result Merging with Fuzzy Borda Ranking</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">0B6D5B20AD5E42E8E7E1D857027FB720</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:17+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.3 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: H.3.1 Content Analysis and Indexing</term>
					<term>H.3.3 Information Search and Retrieval</term>
					<term>H.3.4 Systems and Software</term>
					<term>I.2 [Artificial Intelligence]: I.2.3 Uncertainty, &quot;fuzzy,&quot; and probabilistic reasoning</term>
					<term>I.2.7 Natural Language Processing Measurement, Performance, Experimentation Geographical Information Retrieval, Merging techniques, Fuzzy Borda</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describe the joint participation by the Universidad Politécnica de Valencia and the Universidad of Jaén to the GeoCLEF task. This activity has been carried out within the framework of the Spanish TextMESS project (Intelligent, Interactive and Multilingual Text Mining based on Human Language Technologies). The method employed for the participation is a result merging algorithm based on the fuzzy Borda voting scheme. This method takes as input the two document lists returned by the two systems developed by the participating groups and creates a document list where the documents are ranked according to the fuzzy Borda voting scheme. The results obtained are better than the individual systems, and also ones of the best ones of the task (second as group). However, the best result was obtained with a run which combined the baseline systems. The analysis of the results showed that the best runs were those in which only title and description were used, and unfortunately we chose to submit only a run of this type, with the base systems. The results confirm the effectiveness of the fuzzy Borda scheme for the combination of different systems.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In this paper we describe the joint participation of the groups of the Universidad Politécnica de Valencia and Universidad de Jaén to GeoCLEF 2008. This participation has been carried out within the framework of the Spanish project TextMESS (Spanish acronym for Intelligent, Interactive and Multilingual Text Mining based on Human Language Technologies).</p><p>We previously investigated various possibilities for the integration of our systems, focusing on two possible choices:</p><p>• Identify some features in the topics that allow to determine which system is going to obtain the best result over a determined topic (system selection);</p><p>• Combine the output of the different systems in a unique output (output merging).</p><p>We carried out some preliminary experiments with the GeoCLEF topics from 2005 to 2007 and the systems presented by the two groups in GeoCLEF 2007, in order to check whether the first option was feasible or not. These results proved that it was possible to use bag-of-words features to select the best system for a given topic. However, the experiments carried out with the new systems (those developed for GeoCLEF 2008) did not provide us with the same conclusion. Therefore, we chose to participate with an output merging algorithm based on the fuzzy Borda voting scheme <ref type="bibr" coords="2,90.00,337.08,10.52,8.74" target="#b8">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,103.50,337.08,7.01,8.74" target="#b5">6]</ref>. This method was previously used in the Word Sense Disambiguation task at Semeval<ref type="foot" coords="2,486.18,335.50,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref> with good results <ref type="bibr" coords="2,147.49,349.03,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Preliminary experiments with the data from 2005 to 2007 showed that it was possible to achieve an improvement of ∼ 2% in Mean Average Precision (MAP) over the best system.</p><p>In Sections 2 and 3 we describe briefly the systems of each group (a more complete description can be found in the corresponding report of the CLEF Working Notes). In Section 4 we describe the fuzzy Borda ranking method, and finally we present the results and a brief discussion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">SINAI-GIR System Description</head><p>The SINAI-GIR system is made up of five main subsystems: Translator, Collection Preprocessing subsystem, Query Analyzer, Information Retrieval subsystem and Validator. Each translated query is preprocessed and analyzed by the Query Analyzer, identifying their geo-entities and spatial relations and making use of Geonames gazetteer<ref type="foot" coords="2,280.25,497.87,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_1">2</ref> . This module also applies query reformulation based on the query parsing subtask <ref type="bibr" coords="2,223.98,511.40,9.96,8.74" target="#b7">[8]</ref>, generating several independent queries which will be indexed and searched by means of the IR subsystem. On the other hand, the collection is preprocessed by the Collection Preprocessing module and finally the documents recovered by the IR subsystem are filtered and re-ranked by means of the Validator subsystem. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,408.37,547.26,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows the SINAI-GIR system architecture.</p><p>The main features of each subsystem are:</p><p>• Translator. We have used SINTRAM (SINai TRAnslation Module), our Machine Translation system which works with different online machine translators and implements several heuristics to combine different translations <ref type="bibr" coords="2,304.22,617.00,9.96,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref>.</p><p>• Collection Preprocessing Subsystem. During the collection preprocessing, two indexes are generated (locations and keywords indexes). We apply the Porter stemmer [10], the Brill POS tagger <ref type="bibr" coords="2,191.41,660.84,10.52,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref> and a specific Named Entity Recognizer (NER) as LingPipe<ref type="foot" coords="2,467.42,659.26,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_2">3</ref> . We also discard the English stop-words.</p><p>• Query Analyzer. It is responsible for preprocessing of English queries as well as the generation of different query reformulations. 3 The UPV GeoWorSE System</p><p>The system is built around the Lucene<ref type="foot" coords="3,264.81,528.55,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_4">5</ref> open source search engine, version 2.1. The Stanford NER system based on Conditional Random Fields <ref type="bibr" coords="3,314.13,542.08,10.52,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref> is used for Named Entity Recognition and classification. The access to WordNet is provided by the MIT Java WordNet Interface <ref type="foot" coords="3,481.71,552.46,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_5">6</ref> . The toponym disambiguator is based on the method presented in <ref type="bibr" coords="3,358.16,565.99,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Indexing</head><p>During the indexing phase, the documents are examined in order to find location names (toponym) by means of the Stanford NER system. When a toponym is found, the disambiguator determines the correct reference for the toponym. Then, a modified lucene indexer adds to the geo index the toponym coordinates (retrieved from GeoWordNet); finally, it stores in the wn index the toponym together with its holonyms and synonyms. All document terms are stored in the text index. The indices are then used in the search phase, although the geo index is not used for search: it is used only to retrieve the coordinates of the toponyms in the document.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Searching</head><p>The architecture of the search module is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,342.81,130.41,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. The topic text is searched by Lucene in the text index. The toponyms extracted by the Stanford NER are searched for in the wn index with a weight 0.25 with respect to the content terms. The result of the search is a list of documents ranked using the Lucene's weighting scheme. At the same time, the toponyms are passed to a module named GeoAnalyzer that creates a geographical constraint that is used to re-rank the document list. The GeoAnalyzer may return two types of geographical constraints:</p><p>• a distance constraint, corresponding to a point in the map: the documents that contain locations closer to this point will be ranked higher;</p><p>• an area constraint, correspoinding to a polygon in the map: the documents that contain locations included in the polygon will be ranked higher. The polygon is obtained by calculating the convex hull of the points associated to the toponyms using the Graham algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="4,114.91,591.45,9.96,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p><p>WordNet is used by the GeoAnalyzer module in order to extract the meronyms of the toponyms in the topic. These meronyms allow to improve the precision of the area constraint. The objective of the GeoFilter module is to re-rank the documents retrieved by Lucene, according to geographical information. If the constraint extracted from the topic is a distance constraint, the weights of the documents are modified according to the following formula:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="4,196.09,683.11,316.91,14.58">w(doc) = w Lucene (doc) * (1 + exp(-min p∈P d(q, p)))<label>(1)</label></formula><p>Where w Lucene is the weight returned by Lucene for the document doc, P is the set of points in the document, and q is the point extracted from the topic.</p><p>If the constraint extracted from the topic is an area constraint, the weights of the documents are modified according to formula 2:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="5,222.18,120.72,290.82,22.31">w(doc) = w Lucene (doc) * 1 + |P q | |P |<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where P q is the set of points in the document that are contained in the area extracted from the topic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Fuzzy Borda Merging 4.1 Fuzzy Borda count</head><p>In the classical (discrete) Borda count each expert gives a mark to each alternative, according to the number of alternatives worse than it. The fuzzy variant <ref type="bibr" coords="5,370.50,246.61,10.52,8.74" target="#b8">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="5,384.71,246.61,7.75,8.74" target="#b5">6]</ref> allows the experts to show numerically how much some alternatives are preferred to the others, evaluating their preference intensities from 0 to 1.</p><p>Let R 1 , R 2 , . . . , R m be the fuzzy preference relations of m experts over n alternatives x 1 , x 2 , . . . , x n . Each expert k expresses its preferences by means of a matrix of preference intensities:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="5,90.00,309.97,423.00,80.54">    r k 11 r k 12 . . . r k 1n r k 21 r k 22 . . . r k 2n . . . . . . . . . . . . r k n1 r k n2 . . . r k nn     where each r k ij = µ R k (x i , x j ), with µ R k : X × X → [0, 1] is the membership function of R k . The number r k ij ∈ [0, 1]</formula><p>is considered as the degree of confidence with which the expert k prefers x i to x j . The final value assigned by the expert k to each alternative x i is the sum by row of the entries greater than 0.5 in the preference matrix, or, formally:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="5,253.81,418.37,259.19,33.70">r k (x i ) = n j=1,r k ij &gt;0.5 r k ij<label>(3)</label></formula><p>The threshold 0.5 ensure the relation R k to be an ordinary preference relation <ref type="bibr" coords="5,431.37,461.44,9.96,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref>.</p><p>The fuzzy Borda count for an alternative x i is obtained as the sum of the values assigned by each expert:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="5,262.97,494.32,250.04,30.55">r(x i ) = m k=1 r k (x i )<label>(4)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Application of Fuzzy Borda count to Result Merging</head><p>In our approach each system is an expert: therefore, there are two preference matrices. The size of these matrices is variable: the reason is that the document list is not the same for the two systems. Therefore, the size of a preference matrix is N t × N t , where N t is the number of unique documents retrieved by the two systems (i.e. the number of documents that appear at least in one of the lists returned by the systems) for topic t.</p><p>The systems ranks the document with weights that are not in the same range. Therefore, the output weights w 1 , w 2 , . . . , w n of each expert k are transformed to fuzzy confidence values by means of the following transformation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="5,270.93,655.25,242.07,23.22">r k ij = w i w i + w j<label>(5)</label></formula><p>This transformation ensure that the preference values are in the range [0, 1]. In order to adapt the fuzzy Borda count to the merging of the results of IR systems, we had to determine the preference values in all the cases where one of the systems does not retrieve a document that has been retrieved by the other one. We decided to set the preference values of these documents to 0.5. This corresponds to the idea that the expert is presented an option on which it cannot express a preference.</p><p>We submitted a total of 9 runs. In Table <ref type="table" coords="6,278.23,133.84,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref> we show the detail of each run in terms of the two systems combined and the topic fields used. base system, all fields EXP3 "fusion" system (query reformulations) EXP5</p><p>filtering system (rule-based)</p><p>In Table <ref type="table" coords="6,145.03,551.65,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_2">3</ref> we show the Mean Average Precision (MAP) obtained for each run, together with the MAP obtained by its composing runs.</p><p>The obtained results show that the use of the fuzzy Borda merging method always allows to improve the results of the best system. The improvement is greater if the two systems have a similar performance (see TMESS06) and the UPV system does not use map filtering. This behaviour is not observed when the UPV system uses map filtering. We suppose that a key feature for obtaining greater improvements by means of fuzzy Borda is that the systems share as few as characteristics as possible.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions and Further Work</head><p>We combined two different systems by means of the fuzzy Borda voting scheme. The implemented method allowed to improve the results of the combined systems, although the improvement was limited. We suppose that the best results with the fuzzy Borda merging can be obtained if the two systems share the same level of accuracy. Further work will be aimed to verify this hypothesis and to the integration of more than two systems. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,210.74,377.78,181.53,8.74;3,132.30,108.86,338.40,253.80"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: SINAI-GIR system architecture</figDesc><graphic coords="3,132.30,108.86,338.40,253.80" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,213.18,410.13,176.64,8.74;4,132.30,151.10,338.42,243.92"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Diagram of the Search module</figDesc><graphic coords="4,132.30,151.10,338.42,243.92" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="6,187.11,176.57,228.78,138.40"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Details of the setup of the TextMESS runs.</figDesc><table coords="6,192.91,198.23,217.19,116.73"><row><cell>run ID</cell><cell cols="3">fields UPV run ID Jaen run ID</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS01</cell><cell>TDN</cell><cell>NLEL0802</cell><cell>EXP3</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS02</cell><cell>TDN</cell><cell>NLEL0802</cell><cell>EXP2</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS03</cell><cell>TDN</cell><cell>NLEL0802</cell><cell>EXP5</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS04</cell><cell>TDN</cell><cell>NLEL0803</cell><cell>EXP3</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS05</cell><cell>TDN</cell><cell>NLEL0803</cell><cell>EXP2</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS06</cell><cell>TDN</cell><cell>NLEL0803</cell><cell>EXP5</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS07A</cell><cell>TD</cell><cell>NLEL0804</cell><cell>EXP1</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS08</cell><cell>TDN</cell><cell>NLEL0505</cell><cell>EXP5</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS09</cell><cell>TDN</cell><cell>NLEL0807</cell><cell>EXP5</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="6,142.17,360.97,318.67,139.59"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Description of the runs of each system.</figDesc><table coords="6,142.17,382.63,29.50,8.74"><row><cell>run ID</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="7,115.02,118.94,372.97,136.46"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Results obtained for the submitted runs.</figDesc><table coords="7,115.02,138.66,372.97,116.73"><row><cell>run ID</cell><cell cols="5">MAP UPV run MAP Jaen run MAP system diff. improvement</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS01</cell><cell>0.226</cell><cell>0.201</cell><cell>0.225</cell><cell>0.024</cell><cell>0.1%</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS02</cell><cell>0.227</cell><cell>0.201</cell><cell>0.226</cell><cell>0.025</cell><cell>0.1%</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS03</cell><cell>0.219</cell><cell>0.201</cell><cell>0.212</cell><cell>0.011</cell><cell>0.8%</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS04</cell><cell>0.234</cell><cell>0.216</cell><cell>0.225</cell><cell>0.009</cell><cell>0.9%</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS05</cell><cell>0.235</cell><cell>0.216</cell><cell>0.226</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>0.9%</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS06</cell><cell>0.226</cell><cell>0.216</cell><cell>0.212</cell><cell>0.004</cell><cell>1.4%</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">TMESS07A 0.286</cell><cell>0.224</cell><cell>0.284</cell><cell>0.06</cell><cell>0.2%</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS08</cell><cell>0.216</cell><cell>0.203</cell><cell>0.212</cell><cell>0.009</cell><cell>0.4%</cell></row><row><cell>TMESS09</cell><cell>0.213</cell><cell>0.202</cell><cell>0.212</cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell>0.1%</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,105.24,723.60,141.53,6.99"><p>http://nlp.cs.swarthmore.edu/semeval</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,105.24,733.11,96.73,6.99"><p>http://www.geonames.org</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="2,105.24,742.61,99.31,6.99"><p>http://alias-i.com/lingpipe</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_3" coords="3,105.24,702.92,108.46,6.99"><p>http://www.lemurproject.org</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5" xml:id="foot_4" coords="3,105.24,712.43,95.51,6.99"><p>http://lucene.apache.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6" xml:id="foot_5" coords="3,105.24,721.93,183.78,6.99"><p>http://www.mit.edu/∼markaf/projects/wordnet/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We would like to thank the <rs type="institution">TIMOM</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">TIN2006-15265-C06-03</rs>) and <rs type="grantNumber">TIN2006-15265-C06-04</rs> research projects for partially supporting this work.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_hGG5f4Y">
					<idno type="grant-number">TIN2006-15265-C06-03</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_qNUXC9C">
					<idno type="grant-number">TIN2006-15265-C06-04</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.48,378.25,402.52,8.74;7,110.48,390.21,385.80,8.74" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,158.31,378.25,179.92,8.74">A simple rule-based part-of-speech tagger</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Brill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,359.55,378.25,153.45,8.74;7,110.48,390.21,225.82,8.74">Proceedings of the third Conference on Applied Natural Language Processing (ANLP&apos;92)</title>
		<meeting>the third Conference on Applied Natural Language Processing (ANLP&apos;92)<address><addrLine>Trento, Italy</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="152" to="155" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.48,409.81,402.52,8.74;7,110.48,421.76,402.53,8.74;7,110.48,433.72,148.06,8.74" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,262.96,409.81,250.03,8.74;7,110.48,421.76,81.00,8.74">Upv-wsd : Combining different wsd methods by means of fuzzy borda voting</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Davide</forename><surname>Buscaldi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,214.27,421.76,298.73,8.74;7,110.48,433.72,22.67,8.74">Fourth International Workshop on Semantic Evaluations (SemEval-2007)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="434" to="437" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.48,453.32,402.52,8.74;7,110.48,465.28,402.52,8.74;7,110.48,477.23,22.69,8.74" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,263.15,453.32,249.84,8.74;7,110.48,465.28,70.76,8.74">A conceptual density-based approach for the disambiguation of toponyms</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Davide</forename><surname>Buscaldi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,189.69,465.28,252.71,8.74">International Journal of Geographical Information Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="301" to="313" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.48,496.83,402.53,8.74;7,110.48,508.79,402.52,8.74;7,110.48,520.74,402.52,8.74;7,110.48,532.70,219.10,8.74" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,409.20,496.83,103.81,8.74;7,110.48,508.79,296.87,8.74">Incorporating non-local information into information extraction systems by gibbs sampling</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><forename type="middle">Rose</forename><surname>Finkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Trond</forename><surname>Grenager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,433.11,508.79,79.89,8.74;7,110.48,520.74,369.94,8.74">Proceedings of the 43nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2005)</title>
		<meeting>the 43nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2005)<address><addrLine>U. of Michigan -Ann Arbor</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="363" to="370" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.48,552.30,402.52,8.74;7,110.48,564.26,402.52,8.74;7,110.48,576.21,402.52,8.74;7,110.48,588.17,137.34,8.74" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,222.22,564.26,290.78,8.74;7,110.48,576.21,49.68,8.74">BRUJA System. The University of Jaén at the Spanish task of QA@CLEF</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Miguel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><forename type="middle">Martínez</forename><surname>Alfonso Ureña López</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">José</forename><forename type="middle">M Perea</forename><surname>Santiago</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Ortega</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="s" coord="7,202.08,576.21,151.13,8.74;7,428.79,576.21,53.28,8.74">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4730</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="328" to="338" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006. 2007</date>
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>LNCS Series</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.48,607.77,402.52,8.74;7,110.48,619.72,256.66,8.74" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,350.93,607.77,162.07,8.74;7,110.48,619.72,79.31,8.74">Borda Count Versus Approval Voting: A Fuzzy Approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">José</forename><surname>Luis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">García</forename><surname>Lapresta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><surname>Martínez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Panero</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,199.19,619.72,57.69,8.74">Public Choice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="167" to="184" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.48,639.33,402.52,8.74;7,110.48,651.28,243.73,8.74" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,203.04,639.33,309.96,8.74;7,110.48,651.28,11.25,8.74">An efficient algorith for determining the convex hull of a finite planar set</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ronald</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,129.90,651.28,132.79,8.74">Information Processing Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="132" to="133" />
			<date type="published" when="1972">1972</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.48,670.88,402.52,8.74;7,110.48,682.84,396.13,8.74" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,364.11,670.88,148.89,8.74;7,110.48,682.84,51.61,8.74">Query Parsing Task for GeoCLEF 2007 Report</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Zhisheng</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Chong</forename><surname>Wanga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Xing</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wei-Ying</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,183.69,682.84,292.37,8.74">Proceedings of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2007)</title>
		<meeting>the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2007)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.48,702.44,402.52,8.74;7,110.48,714.40,235.33,8.74" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,178.28,702.44,329.97,8.74">Resolving Group Choice Paradoxes Using Probabilistic and Fuzzy Concepts</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hannu</forename><surname>Nurmi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,110.48,714.40,138.53,8.74">Group Decision and Negotiation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="199" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.48,734.00,368.27,8.74" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,169.75,734.00,140.77,8.74">An algorithm for suffix stripping</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,331.55,734.00,36.55,8.74">Program</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="130" to="137" />
			<date type="published" when="1980">1980</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
