<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.03,75.53,410.74,17.00;1,72.03,96.28,128.38,17.00;1,72.03,116.27,148.65,9.90">Profiling Hate Speech Spreaders by Classifying Micro Texts Using BERT Model Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2021</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,74.03,141.85,76.61,10.80"><forename type="first">Alzahrani</forename><surname>Esam</surname></persName>
							<email>esam@uab.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Alabama at Birmingham</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1720 University Blvd</addrLine>
									<postCode>35294</postCode>
									<settlement>Birmingham</settlement>
									<region>AL</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Al-Baha University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>65799</postCode>
									<settlement>Alaqiq</settlement>
									<country key="SA">Saudi Arabia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">CLEF</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,166.33,141.85,65.24,10.80"><forename type="first">Jololian</forename><surname>Leon</surname></persName>
							<email>leon@uab.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Alabama at Birmingham</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1720 University Blvd</addrLine>
									<postCode>35294</postCode>
									<settlement>Birmingham</settlement>
									<region>AL</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">CLEF</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.03,75.53,410.74,17.00;1,72.03,96.28,128.38,17.00;1,72.03,116.27,148.65,9.90">Profiling Hate Speech Spreaders by Classifying Micro Texts Using BERT Model Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2021</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">477CF7DC0914A56C70AE25CF7F94E6DC</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T16:15+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Author profiling</term>
					<term>hate speech</term>
					<term>transfer learning</term>
					<term>digital forensics</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Hate speech detection has lately gained considerable attention from researchers. To profile authors effectively, we consider classifying all tweets for a specific author independently. We used BERT, the pretrained model, to classify all individual tweets for each user. Then, we added an extra layer, called a confidence layer, by which we calculate the percentage of classified hateful tweets by the model and decide whether this author is spreading hate speech or not. We found this approach simple, yet effective in determining those considered haters. Our approach achieved 77% accuracy for the Spanish test dataset and 63% accuracy for the English test dataset.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>The field of data mining and text analysis has recently received considerable attention. The enormous amount of text on the internet makes analyzing such content a necessity. The purposes of textual content analysis vary, e.g., sentiment analysis, cyberbullying detection, and hate speech detection. One of the major topics to be investigated in this field is hate speech spreaders profiling, which is the focus of the author's profiling task of PAN at CLEF 2021. Hate speech is sometimes mistaken as freedom of speech. However, any speech that might elicit tension between different groups of society and spread hate among them is considered hate speech. Generally, text analysis is intertwined with the field of Natural Language Processing (NLP). NLP is a broad field where humans' language choices are investigated and analyzed using AI techniques, such as machine learning and deep learning. The latter has received more attention recently, especially, after the emergence of transformers.</p><p>The goal of this task is to profile authors who are seen as hate speech spreaders on Twitter. The datasets of the PAN committee were collected from Twitter within two different languages, English and Spanish. Each dataset consists of 100 authors with 200 tweets for each author. The rest of the paper covers related previous work, dataset handling, method, results and discussion, and conclusion <ref type="bibr" coords="1,489.45,572.41,12.57,9.90" target="#b0">[1]</ref>- <ref type="bibr" coords="1,506.21,572.41,12.57,9.90" target="#b2">[3]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Related work</head><p>Efforts in hate speech studies vary as some researchers present annotated datasets for other researchers to work with. Corpora are provided in different languages such as Arabic, English, German, and others. English is the most frequent language used in hate speech tasks. As a result, some papers offer ready datasets along with detection techniques for different hate speech tasks <ref type="bibr" coords="1,438.17,667.94,12.57,9.90" target="#b3">[4]</ref>- <ref type="bibr" coords="1,454.94,667.94,12.57,9.90" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. The source of corpora could be Facebook, Twitter, and other textual platform resources. The categorization of hate speech varies because hate speech could be directed to a certain group of people who share the same quality or characteristic. Hate speech against a religion would be, for example, Islamophobia. Another example is Cyberbullying, where some users bully others and leave a pronounced negative impact on them. Therefore, determining the type of hate speech will affect the strategy of collection, annotation, feature selection, and classification techniques.</p><p>Shared tasks are an important source of hate speech research. Usually, a dataset and an objective are shared by an organizer to encourage researchers to work on a demanding area of research. The results and approaches offered by participants provide a versatile package that represents a rich source of different methods and techniques. There are hate specific tasks that offer the above-mentioned benefits, such as HaSpeeDe <ref type="bibr" coords="2,156.58,201.29,11.44,9.90" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, AMI <ref type="bibr" coords="2,198.58,201.29,16.82,9.90" target="#b9">[10]</ref>, HatEval <ref type="bibr" coords="2,261.35,201.29,16.62,9.90" target="#b10">[11]</ref>, OffensEval organized by SemEval, TRAC-2 <ref type="bibr" coords="2,483.70,201.29,16.60,9.90" target="#b11">[12]</ref>, and MEX-A3T <ref type="bibr" coords="2,123.30,213.82,18.16,9.90" target="#b12">[13]</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Method</head><p>As the first step in most text analysis tasks, preprocessing is an important step that can significantly affect model performance. In our method of handling the datasets, we have tried different techniques with controlling the method of classification to ensure the best use of the given datasets. We have found that the English dataset gives a better performance when hashtags, URLs, mentions, RT tags, and punctuation are removed. However, the Spanish dataset gave better accuracy when we kept the text unchanged.</p><p>Because we used the transfer learning method for our classification, we have conducted experiments about the tokenization of different transfer learning models such as BERT, ROBERTA, and Longformer. BERT uses WordPiece tokenizer1; one of the downsides of WordPiece is the lack of emojis support. Emojis are heavily used in social media contexts and they can reveal useful information that can boost model performance. On the other hand, ROBERTA and Longformer use the same tokenizer, Byte-Pair Encoding (BPE)1. BPE can handle emojis and assign a token to them. Conversely, WordPiece assigns an unknown token [UNK] to all emojis as shown in Figure1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1: How different tokenizers handle emojis</head><p>As mentioned before, we considered using transfer learning techniques for this task. Transfer learning has been proven to be state-of-the-art for many tasks <ref type="bibr" coords="2,340.90,607.91,16.80,9.90" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. There are different choices we could have considered, but in the interest of time and simplicity, we have considered using BERT, ROBERTA, and Longformer Huggingface implementations. With the use of Huggingface, we conducted experiments with different parameters for better accuracy. After conducting multiple experiments, we found that BERT gave us the best accuracy for the target task. For the English dataset task, we used bert-base-cased version with the following hyperparameters.</p><p>• Batch_size = 32</p><p>• Epochs= 50</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,90.05,711.58,103.53,23.28">• Learning rate = 2-5 • Max_length = 50</formula><p>For the Spanish dataset task, we used bert-multilingual-cased with the following hyperparameters.</p><p>• Batch_size = 16</p><p>• Epochs= 50</p><p>• Learning rate = 2-5</p><p>• Max_length = 60 The hyperparameters are within the range of suggested values by BERT authors <ref type="bibr" coords="3,427.18,128.54,16.60,9.90" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. After visualizing and understanding the target datasets, we decided to handle the data differently and observe the outcome. We built three scenarios: 1) using the preprocessed dataset as is; 2) combining all tweets for each user; and 3) considering all tweets for each user to be in the same group after splitting the dataset into training, validation, and testing datasets (Fig2 shows the steps). The first scenario gave the best accuracy among all three scenarios. However, we could not test the accuracy for each user because the tweets were randomly selected and not all users have the same number of tweets. The second choice was the worst among all the scenarios as the dataset became small, which limited the ability of the model convergence and representation.</p><p>The results are based on the first scenario for both the Spanish language and the English language. The third scenario gave us the ability to test the model within 10 balanced authors, including all the tweets for all selected authors. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,238.85,267.57,5.50,9.90" target="#fig_0">2</ref> illustrates the third scenario steps where all tweets for the same user are included in the assigned dataset (Training, testing, validation) with a random shuffle. This scenario allows us to add an extra layer for confidence, which calculates the number of tweets that are classified as hateful for each user. In our initial testing, we achieved 80% accuracy when we determined the threshold for the number of hateful tweets for each use at 95. If more than 95 tweets of any user were classified hateful, the user will be classified as a hate speech spreader. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Results and discussion</head><p>Our best results for the Spanish and English datasets were 77% and 63%, respectively. Table1 shows the results and the setup we used to achieve those results. We found that using BERT multilingual cased model with the determined hyperparameters in table 1 for the Spanish language achieved the best results among all the three models, BERT, ROBERTA, and Longformer. The experiments on the English dataset showed that using the BERT base cased model with the determined hyperparameters in table1 achieved the best results among all different conducted experiments which differ in the type of models and the values of hyperparameters. In our experiments, we tried using all three models with different hyperparameters and different preprocessing techniques. Nevertheless, the best results were achieved when we did not apply any preprocessing technique with the determined hyperparameters. In both languages, the use of cased models always yielded better accuracies. ROBERTA and Longformer tokenizers can handle emojis that exist in most tweets nowadays. The problem we faced in using both models was when they converged and became stuck at the same starting loss and accuracy. Therefore, Construct dataframes with tweets, texts using randomly selected ids, e.g., testing dataframe contains 5 users type 0 and 5 users type 1</p><p>Select randomly from zeros and ones, users ids to build training (180), validation <ref type="bibr" coords="3,256.94,478.95,14.82,10.00" target="#b9">(10)</ref>, and testing <ref type="bibr" coords="3,325.66,478.95,16.02,10.00" target="#b9">(10)</ref> datasets Split dataframes into two dataframes based on users' types (hateful &amp; nonhateful)</p><p>Preprocessed Dataframe our choice fell on BERT because it started to converge in the early epochs. However, as mentioned earlier, the BERT tokenizer cannot handle emojis which creates a failure of using an important part of the data. The shortness of tweets is another factor that contributes to the low accuracy. In this task specifically, not all hate speech spreaders' tweets are considered hateful. If a user is considered a hateful speech spreader, there might be only a few number of hateful tweets. As a result, this creates confusion for the model as the author is classified as a hate speech spreader, but not all of his/her tweets are classified as hateful. We also found that some users repeat the same tweets more than once.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table 1</head><p>Models settings for the achieved results</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusion</head><p>In this task, we considered studying the problem closely to understand the nature of the dataset and the purpose of the task. We considered using the transfer learning technique because it has been proven to perform well in NLP tasks. Even though it has been tested in the context of language modeling, recently, researchers started to apply transfer learning for classification tasks. Even though our results are near the average of all participated teams <ref type="bibr" coords="4,270.13,440.36,11.44,9.90" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, we were always aiming for a better result. We believe the result did not match the sophistication of the approach we used but using transfer learning leaves you with many choices for future optimization. Due to time constraints, we provided what we have achieved to comply with the timeline provided by the organizers. However, we consider this as an ongoing learning experience which we will keep investigating. We faced some challenges with the dataset such as the limited size, the repetitive tweets or words, and the amount of noise compared to the short tweets. In some cases, the markers are unclear as some words can have different meanings depending on the context or the user's intended meaning. Tokenizers play an important role in language analysis tasks. Therefore, for future work, we would love to spend more time customizing the tokenizer we want to use to better represent the dataset. Moreover, we would consider spending more time exploring the tweets and eliminating any undesired noise. We would also consider using other pretrained models for the task. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Language</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,72.03,559.17,66.60,11.00;3,138.55,558.67,6.18,7.00;3,147.30,559.17,111.88,11.00"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The 3 rd scenario dataset splitting</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" coords="2,90.00,445.97,427.60,120.49"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="2,90.00,445.97,427.60,120.49" type="bitmap" /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,104.05,649.83,419.14,10.00;4,104.05,662.58,419.10,10.01;4,104.05,675.19,61.50,9.90" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,426.40,649.83,96.79,10.00;4,104.05,662.58,186.59,10.00">Profiling Hate Speech Spreaders on Twitter Task at PAN 2021</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L D L P</forename><surname>Sarracén</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bert</forename><surname>Chulvi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fersini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,318.88,662.69,152.23,9.90">CLEF 2021 Labs and Workshops</title>
		<title level="s" coord="4,481.02,662.69,42.13,9.90;4,104.05,675.19,29.14,9.90">Notebook Papers</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,104.05,687.83,418.97,10.01;4,104.05,700.58,419.17,10.01;4,104.05,713.19,173.05,9.90" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,202.67,687.83,320.35,10.00;4,104.05,700.58,224.61,10.00">Overview of PAN 2021: Authorship Verification,Profiling Hate Speech Spreaders on Twitter,and Style Change Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bevendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,355.40,700.69,167.82,9.90;4,104.05,713.19,140.78,9.90">12th International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF 2021)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,104.05,725.85,419.15,10.00;4,104.05,738.46,418.92,9.90;4,104.05,751.21,171.88,9.90" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,343.12,725.85,171.17,10.00">TIRA Integrated Research Architecture</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gollub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,115.80,738.46,243.02,9.90">Information Retrieval Evaluation in a Changing World</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.05,74.66,419.26,10.01;5,104.05,87.16,373.40,10.01" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,265.46,74.66,257.85,10.01;5,104.05,87.16,122.30,10.01">A New Measure of Polarization in the Annotation of Hate Speech BT -AI*IA 2019</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Akhtar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Basile</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Patti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,229.10,87.16,151.58,10.00">Advances in Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="588" to="603" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.05,99.91,418.86,10.00;5,104.05,112.41,419.21,10.01;5,104.05,125.29,419.18,9.90;5,104.05,138.04,175.22,9.90" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,287.19,99.91,235.72,10.00;5,104.05,112.41,245.05,10.00">Are they Our Brothers? Analysis and Detection of Religious Hate Speech in the Arabic Twittersphere</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Albadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kurdi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mishra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/ASONAM.2018.8508247</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,408.39,112.52,114.87,9.90;5,104.05,125.29,336.91,9.90">IEEE/ACM International Conference on Advances in Social Networks Analysis and Mining (ASONAM)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="76" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.05,150.43,419.34,10.01;5,104.05,163.18,419.27,10.01;5,104.05,175.79,418.93,9.90;5,104.05,188.54,103.28,9.90" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,397.85,150.43,125.54,10.01;5,104.05,163.18,385.79,10.01">ConaN -Counter narratives through nichesourcing: A multilingual dataset of responses to fight online hate speech</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Chung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kuzmenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Tekiroglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Guerini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/p19-1271</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,503.20,163.29,20.12,9.90;5,104.05,175.79,288.37,9.90">ACL 2019 -57th Annu. Meet. Assoc. Comput. Linguist. Proc. Conf</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2819" to="2829" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.05,201.18,419.27,10.01;5,104.05,213.71,419.38,10.01;5,104.05,226.57,57.75,9.90" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,417.19,201.18,106.13,10.01;5,104.05,213.71,153.60,10.00">Peer to peer hate: Hate speech instigators and their targets</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Elsherief</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Nilizadeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Vigna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Belding</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,269.38,213.82,232.06,9.90">12th Int. AAAI Conf. Web Soc. Media, ICWSM 2018</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="52" to="61" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.05,238.96,419.07,10.00;5,104.05,251.82,263.10,9.90" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,206.75,238.96,262.87,10.00">Detecting Online Hate Speech Using Context Aware Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.26615/978-954-452-049-6_036</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015. 2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="266" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.05,264.46,418.78,10.00;5,104.05,276.95,338.63,10.01" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,446.92,264.46,75.91,10.00;5,104.05,276.95,198.11,10.00">Overview of the EVALITA 2018 Hate Speech Detection Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bosco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Dell'orletta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Poletto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sanguinetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tesconi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,326.13,277.06,83.48,9.90">EVALITA@CLiC-it</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.05,289.70,418.77,10.00;5,104.05,302.23,385.87,10.01" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,306.54,289.70,216.28,10.00;5,104.05,302.23,132.54,10.01">Overview of the task on automatic misogyny identification at IberEval 2018</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fersini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Anzovino</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,249.35,302.34,101.33,9.90">CEUR Workshop Proc</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2150</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="214" to="228" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.05,314.98,419.01,10.00;5,104.05,327.73,419.20,10.01;5,104.05,340.34,134.05,9.90" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,372.81,314.98,150.25,10.00;5,104.05,327.73,237.82,10.00">Resources and benchmark corpora for hate speech detection: a systematic review</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Poletto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Basile</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sanguinetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bosco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Patti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10579-020-09502-8</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,360.40,327.84,98.78,9.90">Lang. Resour. Eval</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.05,352.98,418.73,10.00;5,104.05,365.48,419.39,10.01;5,104.05,378.36,309.13,9.90" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,348.58,352.98,174.20,10.00;5,104.05,365.48,56.16,10.00">Evaluating Aggression Identification in Social Media</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ojha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Malmasi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zampieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.aclweb.org/anthology/2020.trac-1.1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,173.58,365.59,235.63,9.90">Proc. Second Work. Trolling, Aggress. Cyberbullying</title>
		<meeting>Second Work. Trolling, Aggress. Cyberbullying</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-05">May. 2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="5" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.05,390.86,419.33,9.90;5,104.05,403.50,418.98,10.01;5,104.05,416.36,418.88,9.90;5,104.05,428.86,68.75,9.90" xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,246.57,403.50,276.46,10.01;5,104.05,416.36,230.21,9.90">Overview of MEX-A3T at IberLEF 2019: Authorship and aggressiveness analysis in Mexican Spanish tweets</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Aragón</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Álvarez-Carmona</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Montes-Y-Gómez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Escalante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Villaseñor-Pineda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Moctezuma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,347.40,416.36,103.78,9.90">CEUR Workshop Proc</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2421</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="478" to="494" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.05,441.50,419.38,10.01;5,104.05,454.00,419.08,10.01;5,104.05,466.89,418.90,9.90;5,104.05,479.64,24.75,9.90" xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,342.90,441.50,180.53,10.01;5,104.05,454.00,177.71,10.00">BERT: Pre-training of deep bidirectional transformers for language understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Devlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Toutanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,294.38,454.11,228.75,9.90;5,104.05,466.89,267.39,9.90">NAACL HLT 2019 -2019 Conf. North Am. Chapter Assoc. Comput. Linguist. Hum. Lang. Technol. -Proc. Conf</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4171" to="4186" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
