<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,106.92,75.23,392.87,12.58;1,139.08,92.69,317.13,12.58">Hybrid Approach of Query and Document Translation with Pivot Language for Cross-Language Information Retrieval</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,234.00,131.28,66.95,9.02"><forename type="first">Kazuaki</forename><surname>Kishida</surname></persName>
							<email>kishida@surugadai.ac.jp</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Surugadai University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>698 Azu</addrLine>
									<postCode>357-8555</postCode>
									<settlement>Hanno</settlement>
									<region>Saitama</region>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,311.94,131.28,57.49,9.02"><forename type="first">Noriko</forename><surname>Kando</surname></persName>
							<email>kando@nii.ac.jp</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute of Informatics (NII)</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>101-8430</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,106.92,75.23,392.87,12.58;1,139.08,92.69,317.13,12.58">Hybrid Approach of Query and Document Translation with Pivot Language for Cross-Language Information Retrieval</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">81359FE12049DC2854649B74DD5C60AE</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:08+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.3.3 [Information Search and Retrieval]: Query formulation</term>
					<term>Relevance feedback Cross-language information retrieval</term>
					<term>Query translation</term>
					<term>Document translation</term>
					<term>Hybrid approach</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper reports experimental results of cross-language information retrieval (CLIR) from German to French, in which a hybrid approach of query and document translation was attempted, i.e, combining results of query translation (German to French) and of document translation (French to German). In order to avoid too high complexity of computation for translating a large amount of texts in documents, we executed pseudo-translation, i.e., a simple replacement of terms by a bilingual dictionary (for query translation, a machine translation system was used). In particular, since English was used as an intermediary language for both translation directions of German and French, English translations at the middle stage were employed as document representations in order to reduce the number of translation steps. By omitting a translation step (English to German), the performance was improved. Unfortunately, our hybrid approach could not show better performance than a simple query translation. This may be due to the low performance of document translation, which was carried out by a simple replacement of terms using a bilingual dictionary with no term disambiguation.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This paper describes our experiment of cross-language IR (CLIR) from German to French languages in the CLEF 2005 campaign. Our focus in this experiment is on examining search performance of a hybrid approach combining query translation and document translation, in which English is employed as an intermediary language for translation.</p><p>Some researchers have already attempted to merge two results from query and document translation for enhancing effectiveness of CLIR. An intention of combining them is to enlarge possibility of matching successfully subject representations of the query with those of each document. One problem for implementing this approach is that the document translation is usually a cost-intensive task, but we can alleviate it by using simpler translation techniques, e.g., "pseudo translation" <ref type="bibr" coords="1,310.50,627.42,11.69,9.02" target="#b0">[1]</ref> in which each term is simply replaced with its corresponding translations by a bilingual dictionary. It is worth while investigating the performance of the hybrid approach in the case of employing such a simpler document translation technique that is more practical for use in real situation.</p><p>This paper is organized as follows. In section 2, the hybrid approach combining two results from query and document translation is discussed. Section 3 describes our system used in the experiment of CLEF 2005. In section 4, the results are reported.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Hybrid Approach of Query and Document Translation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Combination of query and document translation</head><p>In order to execute CLIR, we have to match subject representations between a query and each document by translating either the query or documents. In general, queries tend to be translated <ref type="bibr" coords="2,413.08,145.98,10.64,9.02" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. This may be due to its easiness for implementation, i.e., no special device is needed for executing CLIR rather than a tool for translating the query text. In contrast, document translation has not often been adopted as the strategy for CLIR partly because a very large amount of processing is needed for translating all documents in the whole database.</p><p>However, some researchers have reported that a hybrid approach of query and document translation bring us better search performance in CLIR. For example, McCarley <ref type="bibr" coords="2,313.15,203.46,11.72,9.02" target="#b2">[3]</ref> has attempted to use an average of two document scores which are computed from query translation and document translation respectively in order to rank documents for output. Fujii and Ishikawa <ref type="bibr" coords="2,251.56,226.44,11.71,9.02" target="#b3">[4]</ref> have translated documents that are searched based on query translation, and tried to re-rank them according to results of the document translation. In NTCIR-4, Kang et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,70.92,249.42,11.70,9.02" target="#b0">[1]</ref> tried to execute Korean to Chinese and Korean to Japanese bilingual retrieval using the hybrid approach.</p><p>An advantage of the hybrid approach is to increase possibility for identifying correctly documents having the same subject content with the query. Suppose that a term A is included in a given search query and its corresponding term in the language of documents is B. If a tool for translation from the query language to the document language can not translate A into B correctly, the system would fail to find documents containing the term B by this query translation. However, if another tool for translation in reverse direction, i.e., the document language into the query language, can identify the term A from the term B, matching between the query and documents including the term B becomes successful.</p><p>For implementing the hybrid approach, it is important to solve a problem that document translation is a costintensive task. For example, it may take too long time for translating all documents by commercial software for machine translation (MT). McCarley <ref type="bibr" coords="2,221.51,364.32,11.70,9.02" target="#b2">[3]</ref> applied a statistical translation technique for alleviating this problem. In contrast, Kang et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,157.42,375.78,10.70,9.02" target="#b0">[1]</ref> have employed "pseudo" translation technique, in which each term in documents is simply replaced with its translations by using a bilingual dictionary. Although the replacement is not exactly equal to MT, it is so fast and enables us to have translations of a large amount of document texts within a reasonable time. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Hybrid approach with a pivot language</head><p>In our hybrid approach, queries in German are translated by a commercial MT system, and each French term included in documents is replaced with its corresponding German words using bilingual dictionaries. After the translation, two scores are computed for each document from the results of query and document translation respectively. Finally, we calculate a final score for ranking the document by using a simple linear formula such that where x is a score computed from a results of query translation, y is a score from document translation, and w is a weight (in this paper, we always set that 7 . 0 = w</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,179.70,729.34,235.00,14.71">y w wx z ) 1 ( - + = ,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>). The procedure is graphically shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,474.20,87.66,3.74,9.02" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. Both the translation methods employed in this experiment, i.e., MT and dictionary-based method, make use of a pivot language. The MT software translates German sentences into English ones, and translates the results into French sentences. Similarly, each term included in French documents are replaced with corresponding English translations by a French to English dictionary, and these English translations are replaced with German terms by an English to German dictionary. An appropriate translation resource is not always available for a pair of languages that actual users require. But, in this case, it is possible that we find translation tools between English and these languages since English is an international language. Therefore, the pivot language approach via English is considered to be useful in real situations, although two steps of translation in this approach often yield erroneously more irrelevant translations, particularly in the case of dictionary-based transitive translation, because all final translations obtained from an irrelevant English term in the middle stage are usually irrelevant <ref type="bibr" coords="3,70.92,214.80,10.65,9.02" target="#b4">[5]</ref>.</p><p>One method for alleviating this problem may be to limit the dictionary-based translation to only conversion of French terms into English ones. In order to compute document scores from documents translated into English, German queries have to be translated into English. In the case of pivot language approach, an English version of the query is automatically obtained in the middle stage of translation from German to French (see Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,513.48,260.76,3.63,9.02" target="#fig_2">2</ref>). Therefore, the number of translation operations is just three as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,389.81,272.22,3.77,9.02" target="#fig_2">2</ref>. In contrast, the standard hybrid approach in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,150.27,283.74,5.01,9.02" target="#fig_0">1</ref> using a pivot language needs four translation operations, i.e., (1) German query to English query, (2) English query to French query, (3) French documents to English documents and (4) English documents to German documents. Removing an operation of dictionary-based translation may contribute to reduction of erroneous translations, and the search performance is expected to be improved. headwords included in the German to English dictionary in machine-readable form. For example, a German word, "Briefbombe," is broken down into two headwords listed in the German to English dictionary, "Brief" and "Bombe," according to a rule that only the longest headwords included in the original compound word are extracted from it. If a substring of "Brief" or "Bombe" is also listed in the dictionary, the substring is not used as a separated word.</p><p>We downloaded free dictionaries (German to English and English to French) from the Internet<ref type="foot" coords="4,475.26,130.42,3.00,5.40" target="#foot_0">1</ref> . Stemmers and stopword lists for German and French were also available through the Snowball project<ref type="foot" coords="4,457.98,141.94,3.00,5.40" target="#foot_1">2</ref> . Stemming for English was conducted by the original Porter's algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="4,302.01,153.66,10.63,9.02" target="#b5">[6]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Translation Procedure</head><p>We used a commercial MT system produced by a Japanese company <ref type="foot" coords="4,366.48,209.38,3.00,5.40" target="#foot_2">3</ref> for query translation, and French or English sentences that it output were processed according to the procedures described above. In the case of document translation, each German sentence was processed, and its words and decomposed elements of compound words were simply replaced with corresponding English terms using a German to English dictionary with no term disambiguation. If no corresponding headword was included in the dictionary for a German term, it was entered into the set of English terms with no change as an unknown term. In order to moreover obtain French translations, a set of the English translations is converted using an English to French dictionary by the same procedure with that for obtaining English translations. It should be noted that all terms included in these dictionaries were normalized through stemming and lemmatization processes with the same procedure applied to texts of documents and queries. Therefore, by the dictionary-based translation, a set of normalized English or French terms was obtained.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Search Algorithm</head><p>The standard Okapi BM25 <ref type="bibr" coords="4,182.47,380.52,11.68,9.02" target="#b6">[7]</ref> was used for all search runs, and for pseudo-relevance feedback, we employed a term weighting formula,</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="4,132.48,406.52,278.32,30.45">) 5 . 0 )( 5 . 0 ( ) 5 . 0 )( 5 . 0 ( log + - + - + + - - + × = t t t t t t t r R n N r n R N r r w , (<label>2</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="4,410.80,409.50,3.89,9.02">)</formula><p>where N is the total number of documents, R is the number of top-ranked documents that is assumed to be relevant, t n is the number of documents including term t , and t r is the number of documents including term t in the top-ranked R documents. In this experiment, we always set that 30 = R and ten terms were selected based on their weights in Eq. ( <ref type="formula" coords="4,171.49,487.20,3.54,9.02" target="#formula_1">2</ref>). Let t y be the frequency of a given term in the query. If a newly selected term was already included in the set of search terms, the term frequency in the query t y was changed into ). The PRF procedure was carried out for all search runs in this experiment.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Merge of Document Lists</head><p>For merging two document lists generated by different strategies (i.e., query and document translation), we used the formula in Eq.( <ref type="formula" coords="4,145.96,601.02,3.97,9.02" target="#formula_0">1</ref>). More precisely, the procedure is as follows.</p><p>(a) Using a result of query translation, document scores are computed, and documents up to 10,000th position in the ranked list are selected in maximum. (b) Similarly, using a result of document translation, document scores are computed again, and documents up to 10,000th position in the ranked list are selected in maximum. (c) Final scores for documents selected in (a) and (b) are computed based on Eq.( <ref type="formula" coords="4,410.84,658.50,4.21,9.02" target="#formula_0">1</ref>) and all documents are reranked (If a document was not included in either of lists in (a) or (b), its score is set to zero in the list).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Type of Search Runs</head><p>We executed five runs in which &lt;TITLE&gt; and &lt;DESCRIPTION&gt; fields in each search topic were used, and submitted the results to the organizers of CLEF 2005. All runs were executed on the information retrieval system, ADOMAS (Advanced Document Management System) developed at Surugadai University in Japan. The five runs are as follows.</p><p>-Hybrid-1: merging two results of French translations for query and of German translation for documents.</p><p>-Hybrid-2: merging two results of French translations for query and of English translation for documents as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,158.40,164.64,3.77,9.02" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. -Query translation: using only query translation from German to Italian with no document translation as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,158.40,187.62,3.77,9.02" target="#fig_2">2</ref>. -Document translation: using only document translation from French to German with no query translation -Monolingual: searching the French document collection for the French topics (not translation). In order to comparatively evaluate the performance of our hybrid approach, search runs using only query translation and only document translation were attempted. In addition, for checking effectiveness of these CLIR runs, monolingual search was also executed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experimental Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Basic Statistics</head><p>The target French collection includes 177,452 documents in total. The average document length is 232.65 words. In the case that the document collection was translated into English, the average document length in the English collection amounts to 663.49 and that in the German collection translated from the original French one is 1799.74. Since we did not incorporate any translation disambiguation into our process as mentioned above, each translated document became so long. Fig. <ref type="figure" coords="5,260.71,730.44,3.77,9.02">3</ref>. Recall-precision curves</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Results</head><p>Scores of average precision and R-precision are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,334.35,95.70,3.75,9.02" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, and recall-precision curves of these runs are presented in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="6,150.85,107.22,3.76,9.02">3</ref>. Note that each value in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,281.26,107.22,5.01,9.02" target="#tab_0">1</ref> and Figure <ref type="figure" coords="6,334.32,107.22,5.01,9.02">3</ref> is calculated for all 50 topics that be prepared for evaluating search runs.</p><p>As shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,164.70,130.20,3.77,9.02" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, the hybrid approach using English documents translated from the original collection (hybrid-2, SrgMgE03) outperforms another hybrid approach using German documents (hybrid-1, SrgdMgG02), i.e., the scores of mean average precision (MAP) are 0.2605 for hybrid-2 and 0.2492 for hybrid-1. Although the degree of difference is not large, dominance of the hyper-2 approach is consistent with our logical expectation. Unfortunately, the hyper approach could not show better performance than a simple query translation approach (SrgdQT04), i.e., its score of MAP is 0.2658, which is slightly greater than that of SrgdMgE03. This may be due to the low performance in document translation approach, e.g., the MAP score of document translation from French to German (SrgdDT05) is only 0.1494. That is, by combining results from document translation with that from query translation, ranking of relevant documents in the list generated by query translation approach became lower in some topics. Of course, in other topics, the performance was improved as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="6,143.24,557.52,3.77,9.02">3</ref>, which is a topic-by-topic plot of two scores of average precision for hyper-2 and query translation approach. However, we should consider that our hybrid approach did not show better effectiveness due to the low performance in document translation approach. The reason of the low performance may be (1) quality of free dictionaries downloaded from the Internet and (2) omission of translation disambiguation. We have to solve these problems for improving the performance of our hybrid approach.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Concluding remarks</head><p>This paper reports the results of our experiment on German to French bilingual retrieval, for which a hybrid approach combining results of query translation and document translation was used. For avoiding too high complexity of computation for translating a large amount of documents in the database, we applied pseudotranslation, i.e., a simple replacement of terms by using a bilingual dictionary. In contrast, machine translation software was used for translation of queries which are usually short.</p><p>Since a pivot language approach was applied in the translation process by both MT system and bilingual dictionaries, we attempted to reduce the number of translation steps by employing English translations from the original French collection as a result of document translation. Actually, it is empirically shown that this approach outperforms slightly the standard hybrid approach using German translations as representations of documents. Unfortunately, our hybrid approach could not show better effectiveness than a simple query translation approach partly because the performance of document translation is poor. We have to develop techniques for enhancing effectiveness of document translation approach.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,224.64,602.19,146.06,8.10"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Procedure of hybrid approach (1)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="3,224.64,611.49,146.06,8.10"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. Procedure of hybrid approach (2)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="6,195.66,465.93,204.12,8.10"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4. Topic-by-topic analysis (average precision score)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,104.70,425.13,376.08,286.35"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Average precision and R-precision (average over all 50 topics)</figDesc><table coords="5,104.70,443.28,376.08,268.20"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell></cell><cell>ID</cell><cell>Average</cell><cell>R-Precision</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Precision</cell></row><row><cell>French Monolingual</cell><cell></cell><cell>SrgdMono01</cell><cell>.3910</cell><cell>.3998</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Hybrid-1: German doc translation</cell><cell>SrgdMgG02</cell><cell>.2492</cell><cell>.2579</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Hybrid-2: English doc translation</cell><cell>SrgdMgE03</cell><cell>.2605</cell><cell>.2669</cell></row><row><cell>Query translation</cell><cell></cell><cell>SrgdQT04</cell><cell>.2658</cell><cell>.2642</cell></row><row><cell>Document translation</cell><cell></cell><cell>SrgdDT05</cell><cell>.1494</cell><cell>.1605</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.8</cell><cell></cell><cell>SrgdMono01</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.7</cell><cell></cell><cell>SrgdMgG02 SrgdMgE03</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.6</cell><cell></cell><cell>SrgdQT04</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>SrgdDT05</cell></row><row><cell>Precision</cell><cell>0.3 0.4 0.5</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.0</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">0.0 0.1 0.2 0.3 0.4 0.5 0.6 0.7 0.8 0.9 1.0</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Recall</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="4,76.20,727.53,88.51,8.10"><p>http://www.freelang.net/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="4,76.20,738.03,100.05,8.10"><p>http://snowball.tartarus.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="4,76.20,748.59,145.29,8.10"><p>http://www.crosslanguage.co.jp/english/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,74.30,184.17,450.13,8.10;7,82.26,194.49,313.06,8.10" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,225.52,184.17,298.91,8.10;7,82.26,194.49,79.00,8.10">POSTECH at NTCIR-4: CJKE Monolingual and Korean-related Cross-Language Retrieval Experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Na</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Na</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,177.30,194.49,161.61,8.10">NTCIR Workshop 4 Meeting Working Notes</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="95" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,74.30,204.81,450.26,8.10;7,82.26,215.19,58.58,8.10" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,126.02,204.81,236.10,8.10">Technical issues of cross-language information retrieval: a review</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kishida</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,368.21,204.81,140.57,8.10">Information Processing &amp; Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="433" to="455" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,74.29,225.51,450.27,8.10;7,82.26,235.83,352.33,8.10" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,161.65,225.51,347.20,8.10">Should we translate the documents or the queries in cross-language information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Scott Mccarley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,82.26,235.83,293.75,8.10">Proceedings of the 37th conference on Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 37th conference on Association for Computational Linguistics</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="208" to="214" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,74.29,246.21,450.20,8.10;7,82.26,256.53,442.25,8.10;7,82.26,266.85,81.48,8.10" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,164.05,246.21,360.43,8.10;7,82.26,256.53,28.67,8.10">Japanese-English cross-language information retrieval integrating query and document translation methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fujii</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Ishikawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,118.45,256.53,359.26,8.10">The Transactions of the Institute of Electronics, Information and Communication Engineers. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="362" to="369" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In Japanese</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,74.29,277.23,450.24,8.10;7,82.26,287.55,442.18,8.10;7,82.26,297.87,408.11,8.10" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,179.94,277.23,344.60,8.10;7,82.26,287.55,196.68,8.10">Two-Stage refinement of query translation in a pivot language approach to cross-lingual information retrieval: an experiment at CLEF 2003</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kishida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kando</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,82.26,297.87,248.27,8.10">Comparative Evaluation of Multilingual Information Access Systems</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gonzalo</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Braschler</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kluck</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3237</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="262" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,74.30,308.25,280.51,8.10" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,128.64,308.25,117.43,8.10">An algorithm for suffix stripping</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,251.77,308.25,33.27,8.10">Program</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="130" to="137" />
			<date type="published" when="1980">1980</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,74.29,318.57,450.24,8.10;7,82.26,328.95,350.05,8.10" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,364.59,318.57,61.13,8.10">Okapi at TREC-3</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hancock-Beaulieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gatford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://trec.nist.gov/pubs/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,442.50,318.57,82.03,8.10;7,82.26,328.95,3.38,8.10">Proceedings of TREC-3</title>
		<meeting>TREC-3<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>National Institute of Standards and Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
