<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,149.89,116.95,315.58,12.62;1,228.23,134.89,158.90,12.62">Convolutional Expectation Maximization for Population Estimation</title>
				<funder ref="#_BkKQeBV">
					<orgName type="full">European Unions</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,212.55,172.79,72.95,8.74"><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Pomente</surname></persName>
							<email>pomente.andrea@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Rome Tor Vergata</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Rome</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,322.20,172.79,66.59,8.74"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Aleandri</surname></persName>
							<email>davidaleandri@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Rome Tor Vergata</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Rome</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,149.89,116.95,315.58,12.62;1,228.23,134.89,158.90,12.62">Convolutional Expectation Maximization for Population Estimation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">BCB21C0DD01B82E788C3AA93EA938B38</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:49+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Convolutional Neural Networks</term>
					<term>Information Retrieval</term>
					<term>Image Retrieval</term>
					<term>Copernicus data</term>
					<term>Automatic Population Estimation</term>
					<term>Fab-Space 2.0</term>
					<term>CLEF</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>There is a fundamental spatial mismatch in the data available for estimate population from satellite imagery. Spectral reflectances are available for each pixel of an image, but ground reference population data are available only for larger zones, therefore satellite imagery has bigger resolution than ground reference images. The general response has been to build models for the average population density of the zones, utilizing spatially aggregated spectral data. This article reports a new approach to solve this problem where per pixel spectral data are used. The already used expectation maximization algorithm (EM) [1] is paired with a convolutional neural network to improve the resolution of a preexistent population ground truth provided by the GHS POPULATION GRID (LDS) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,218.97,368.55,9.22,7.86" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. We start with the satellite imagery by Sentinel-2 mission and, the regression model we have built, upscales the LDS dataset to 10 meters resolution, the same as Sentinel-2 images. As you can see in Table <ref type="table" coords="1,198.43,401.43,3.58,7.86">1</ref>, we obtained an AvgRelDelta of 50.05 for Uganda's rural area and 96.31 for the city of Lusaka in Zambia, while our method scored 87.57 in Overall. This results are computed from a test dataset provided for ImageCLEF 2017 Population Estimation Task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,367.12,434.31,9.22,7.86" target="#b7">[8]</ref>.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>There is a substantial literature on the application of orbital remote sensing to the estimation of human population and population growth. The levels of accuracy achieved in these studies has been limited by several factors <ref type="bibr" coords="1,414.38,561.47,7.75,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,422.13,561.47,3.87,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,426.00,561.47,7.75,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. First, the relationship between human habitation and the spectral characteristics of land surface and land cover is inherently indirect and inexact. Second, the problem of estimating a quantitative variable like population density across the spatial dimensions of an image is intrinsically more difficult than the more usual qualitative objectives of remote sensing analysis, such as segmentation or classification. And third, while the resolution of remotely sensed imagery is quite adequate for most demographic purposes, ground reference population data for model development and training is generally only available at a much lower resolution, either for census-related areal units. To date, the response to this problem of spatial incompatibility of data has been to aggregate the finer resolution spectral data up to the geographical level of the available ground reference populations, and then to build regression models for estimating the population density of these larger spatial aggregate units <ref type="bibr" coords="2,264.03,167.81,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. Aggregated remote sensing predictor variables have included mean reflectances of individual spectral bands, numbers of pixels in various land-use categories, measures of variability and image texture and various band-to-band ratios and other mathematical transformations of the multispectral data. The availability of demographic data defined the spatial level at which modeling took place (either the elements of a regular grid or some form of census district), and the remote sensing data were spatially aggregated. The aggregation took various forms: averages of individual spectral bands or band ratios, measures of variability and texture, counts or proportions of pixels in different land use classes, and so on. By contrast, this paper examines several potential advantages to be gained by modeling at the level of single pixels rather than larger spatial aggregates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Studied areas and data</head><p>This work was based on two areas centered on the Lusaka city in Zambia and on a rural area in Uganda. The satellite imagery is provided by Sentinel-2 mission, in particular the 10 meters resolution RGB and Near-infrared bands are used. This choice was made because of the highest resolution respect to other bands. The LDS was recently produced from Landsat imagery (30 meters resolution) collections through automatic analysis of satellite imagery to produce unprecedented fine scale maps quantifying built-up structures in terms of their location and density. The image processing technology exploits structure (texture, morphology, and pattern) as key information. Population estimates were produced and made available for processing by the Center for International Earth Science Information Network (CIESIN) <ref type="foot" coords="2,269.80,474.77,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref> . These estimates consist of country based layers (one for each of 241 countries) of census and administrative polygons containing estimated residential population. The LDS resolution is 250 meters and in order to use in this work the following steps are done:</p><p>-The LDS images are re-projected to the same geo-referentiation (UTM 35-South) of Sentinel-2 imagery -The image is stretched to fit the same dimensions of Sentinel-2 imagery through nearest neighbor interpolation algorithm -Each pixel has 10x10 meters of resolution, but the value is still related to an area of 250x250 meters. To correct this problem, an initial redistribution operation is applied following this equation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,196.11,624.65,284.49,23.89">p 10x10 i,j = p 250x250 n ; i = 1, . . . 25; j = 1, . . . 25; n = 25 • 25<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where p 10x10 i,j</p><p>is the pixel value in the new resampled image, obtained in the second step, n is the number of 10x10 resolution pixels inside each 250x250 resolution pixel and p 250x250 is the pixel value in original LDS imagery, with:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,264.31,163.52,216.28,30.32">25 i=1 25 j=1 p 10x10 i,j = p 250x250<label>(2)</label></formula><p>The equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="3,217.11,210.15,4.24,8.74" target="#formula_0">1</ref>) is performed for each pixel in original LDS imagery.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Convolutional EM</head><p>The method described in this paper assumes that the relation between pixel reflectance and the number of population is non-linear. To make this relation a convolutional neural network (CNN) <ref type="bibr" coords="3,300.85,288.55,10.52,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref> is defined, it takes as input the pixel values (RGB and near infrared) and returns the population estimate. The CNN is composed of two convolutional layers with kernel size of 2 and 64 feature maps with strides equal to 1 and a ReLU activation function. Each convolutional layer is followed by a batch normalization layer. The final layers are fully connected; the first one has 128 ReLU neurons and the last one has only a neuron with linear activation function.</p><p>We can now refine our initial assigned pixel population estimates, by redistributing population within each pixel away from underestimated pixels and towards overestimated pixels while maintaining the known image total. Intuition suggests <ref type="bibr" coords="3,159.76,408.11,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, that the optimal redistribution, which minimizes the sum of squared residues on the regression line and simultaneously holds the sum of the constant p values, is obtained by making all residuals equal, by adjusting the estimated population as follows: p i,j,adj = p i,j,pred + r</p><p>where p i,j,pred is the previous iteration population prediction make by CNN described above and r is defined by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="3,238.13,502.46,242.46,26.77">r = m i=1 m j=1 (p i,j -p i,j,pred ) m • m<label>(4)</label></formula><p>where m • m is the total number of pixels in the input image. This procedure is iterated many times to obtain a redistribution of pixel's population to minimize a RMS loss function. To train the CNN at each iteration, Adam <ref type="bibr" coords="3,164.33,573.43,10.52,8.74" target="#b8">[9]</ref> is used as optimizer algorithm with default parameters. The iteration process is stopped analyzing the values of R 2 coefficient. The whole process is written in Python using the Keras library <ref type="bibr" coords="3,418.60,597.34,15.50,8.74" target="#b9">[10]</ref> with Tensorflow backend. The output of this process is a new image, with the same size of input, representing the new population for each pixel, also the geodata from the geotiff input is reused for the output. Each area of interest is represented by a shape file. To extract the population of each area we used QGIS importing the shape file and the output image from the CNN.</p><p>The model was tested using the ImageCLEF 2017 Remote Task <ref type="bibr" coords="4,421.69,142.18,10.52,8.74" target="#b7">[8]</ref> evaluation system. This pilot task is part of the imageCLEF 2017 Labs <ref type="bibr" coords="4,403.42,154.14,10.51,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref> and was introduced this year. It aims at investigating the use of non commercial satellite data as a free and quicker process to estimate the population of an area of interest.</p><p>The following result were obtained: Looking at the AvgRelDelta metric in the table above, our model performs better for rural area (UGD) than for Lusaka city(ZMB). A possible reason why we have obtained this different can be found in the better initial estimation in LDS ground truth for UGD respect the ZMB area. Considering the short period of development we forced due dead line, we trust the method proposed in this article is promising. It can be surely improved by using better resolution imagery and making more tests on CNN having a test dataset.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,134.77,222.11,351.26,62.61"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Population estimation. UGD stands for Uganda while ZMB is for Zambia region. Overall is when considering both regions all together</figDesc><table coords="4,136.16,222.11,349.86,41.14"><row><cell cols="6">Team Name Team Country Geographic Zone Sum Delta RMSE Pearson AvgRelDelta</cell></row><row><cell>AndreaDavid</cell><cell>Italy</cell><cell>UGD</cell><cell>18,485 1,816</cell><cell>0.76</cell><cell>50.05</cell></row><row><cell>AndreaDavid</cell><cell>Italy</cell><cell>ZMB</cell><cell>1,465,603 30,480</cell><cell>0.08</cell><cell>96.31</cell></row><row><cell>AndreaDavid</cell><cell>Italy</cell><cell>Overall</cell><cell>1,484,088 2,7462</cell><cell>0.21</cell><cell>87.57</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,144.73,657.79,93.51,7.86"><p>http://www.ciesin.org/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>Acknowledgments This work is part of <rs type="projectName">FabSpace</rs> project that received funding from the <rs type="funder">European Unions</rs> <rs type="programName">Horizon 2020 Research and Innovation programme</rs> under the Grant Agreement <rs type="grantNumber">n693210</rs>. https://www.fabspace.eu/</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_BkKQeBV">
					<idno type="grant-number">n693210</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">FabSpace</orgName>
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">Horizon 2020 Research and Innovation programme</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.35,495.13,342.24,7.86;4,146.91,506.09,333.68,7.86;4,146.91,517.05,84.48,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,218.03,495.13,258.77,7.86">Population Estimation Models Based on Individual TM Pixels</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jack</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Harvey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,146.91,506.09,196.74,7.86">Photogrammetric Engineering &amp; Remote Sensing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1181" to="1192" />
			<date type="published" when="2002-11">November 2002. 2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.35,527.58,342.24,7.86;4,146.91,538.54,172.74,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,259.27,527.58,182.33,7.86">Population estimation from Landsat imagery</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Iisaka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hegedus</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,449.74,527.58,30.85,7.86;4,146.91,538.54,93.95,7.86">Remote Sensing of Environment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="272" />
			<date type="published" when="1982">1982</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.35,549.06,342.24,7.86;4,146.91,560.02,333.67,7.86;4,146.91,570.98,333.68,7.86;4,146.91,581.94,254.42,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,344.36,549.06,136.23,7.86;4,146.91,560.02,333.67,7.86;4,146.91,570.98,259.50,7.86">The areal interpolation problem: Estimating population using remote sensing within a GIs framework. Handling Geographical Information: Methodology and Potential Applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Langford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Maguire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Unwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>I. Masser and M. Blakemore</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1991">1991</date>
			<publisher>Longman</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="77" />
			<pubPlace>London, U.K.</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.35,592.47,342.24,7.86;4,146.91,603.43,156.66,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,210.01,592.47,210.29,7.86">Population and dwelling unit estimates from space</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Webster</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,428.63,592.47,51.96,7.86;4,146.91,603.43,66.14,7.86">Third World Planning Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="176" />
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.35,613.96,342.24,7.86;4,146.91,624.92,333.68,7.86;4,146.91,635.88,333.68,7.86;4,146.91,646.84,333.68,8.12;4,146.91,658.44,194.00,7.47" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://data.europa.eu/89h/jrc-ghsl-ghs_pop_gpw4_globe_r2015a" />
		<title level="m" coord="4,434.92,624.92,45.67,7.86;4,146.91,635.88,190.33,7.86">GHS population grid, derived from GPW4, multitemporal</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Joint Research Centre (JRC</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1975">2015. 1975. 1990, 2000, 2015</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>European Commission ; Joint Research Centre (JRC) ; Columbia University ; Center for International Earth Science Information Network -CIESIN</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>European Commission</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,138.35,120.67,342.24,7.86;5,146.91,131.63,333.67,7.86;5,146.91,142.59,333.68,7.86;5,146.91,153.55,270.82,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,162.04,142.59,279.68,7.86">Handwritten character recognition using neural network architectures</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Matan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Kiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Stenard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Boser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Denker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Henderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Howard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hubbard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Jackel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lecun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,448.68,142.59,31.92,7.86;5,146.91,153.55,242.15,7.86">Proc. of the 4th US Postal Service Advanced Technology Conference</title>
		<meeting>of the 4th US Postal Service Advanced Technology Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990">1990</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,138.35,164.51,342.24,7.86;5,146.91,175.46,333.68,7.86;5,146.91,186.42,333.67,7.86;5,146.91,197.38,333.68,7.86;5,146.91,208.34,333.68,7.86;5,146.91,219.30,85.03,7.86" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,431.32,186.42,49.26,7.86;5,146.91,197.38,216.26,7.86">Overview of ImageCLEF 2017: Information extraction from images</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Ionescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Villegas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Arenas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Boato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D.-T</forename><surname>Dang-Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Dicente Cid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Eickhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Garcia Seco De Herrera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gurrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Islam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kovalev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Liauchuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mothe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Piras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Riegler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Schwall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,381.35,197.38,95.02,7.86">CLEF 2017 Proceedings</title>
		<title level="s" coord="5,217.41,208.34,144.27,7.86">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">September 11-14 2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10456</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,138.35,230.26,342.24,7.86;5,146.91,241.22,333.68,7.86;5,146.91,252.18,320.71,7.86" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,384.94,230.26,95.65,7.86;5,146.91,241.22,161.50,7.86">Overview of the Image-CLEF 2017 Population Estimation Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Helbert</forename><surname>Arenas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bayzidul</forename><surname>Islam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Josiane</forename><surname>Mothe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,315.99,241.22,164.61,7.86;5,146.91,252.18,154.08,7.86">CLEF 2017 Labs Working Notes, CEUR Workshop Proceedings, CEUR-WS.org</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">September 11-14 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,138.35,263.14,342.24,7.86;5,146.91,274.09,240.07,7.86" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,296.08,263.14,180.22,7.86">Adam: a Method for Stochastic Optimization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Kingma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Ba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,146.91,274.09,216.46,7.86">International Conference on Learning Representations</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">113</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.62,285.05,337.98,8.12" xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Chollet</forename><surname>François</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Keras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/fchollet/keras" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
