<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,81.92,58.32,448.11,17.10">CBNU at TREC 2015 Clinical Decision Support Track</title>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">MSIP(Ministry of Science, ICT and Future Planning)</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_MNPs7Mf">
					<orgName type="full">ITRC</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Korea</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,93.54,97.00,88.96,11.36"><forename type="first">Seung-Hyeon</forename><surname>Jo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Division of Computer Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">CAIIT Chonbuk National University Jeonju</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="KR">Republic of Korea</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,265.50,97.00,80.99,11.36"><forename type="first">Jae-Wook</forename><surname>Seol</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Science and Technology Information Daejeon</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>Korea, Republic of Korea</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,429.47,97.00,89.11,11.36"><forename type="first">Kyung-Soon</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Division of Computer Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">CAIIT Chonbuk National University Jeonju</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="KR">Republic of Korea</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,81.92,58.32,448.11,17.10">CBNU at TREC 2015 Clinical Decision Support Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">C226221072DC564FBC93D496AB7EEE97</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:08+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>clinical decision support</term>
					<term>clinical semantic knowledge</term>
					<term>query expansion</term>
					<term>UMLS</term>
					<term>Wikipedia</term>
					<term>topic model</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the participation of the CBNU team at the TREC Clinical Decision Support track 2015. We propose a query expansion method based on a clinical semantic knowledge and a topic model. The clinical semantic knowledge is constructed by using medical terms extracted from Unified Medical Language System (UMLS) and Wikipedia articles. The word and document topics are generated by using a topic model for a document collection. The proposed methods achieved 0.2327 and 0.3033 in the inferred NDCG on Task A and Task B, respectively.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">INTRODUCTION</head><p>The goal of the Clinical Decision Support (CDS) Track is to retrieve biomedical articles relevant for answering generic clinical questions about medical records <ref type="bibr" coords="1,171.97,409.80,9.54,7.80">[1]</ref>.</p><p>Basically, we assume that disease terms are helpful for query expansion for all kind of query types. Besides, the different kinds of expansion terms would be effective according to the query types such as diagnosis, treatment, and test.</p><p>In our participation to TREC 2015 CDS, we propose a query expansion method based on a clinical semantic knowledge and a topic model. The first step is to establish a clinical semantic knowledge by using medical terms extracted from Unified Medical Language System (UMLS) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,190.85,511.32,10.45,7.80" target="#b1">[3]</ref> concepts and Wikipedia articles. The second step is to generate document topics and word topics for the CDS document collection using Latent Dirichlet Allocation(LDA). Then the query expansion step is to select expansion terms from clinical semantic knowledge, and word topics associated with the document topics of an initial retrieval set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">ESTABLISHING A CLINICAL SEMANTIC KNOWLEDGE BASED ON UMLS AND WIKIPEDIA 2.1 Defining clinical categories for UMLS semantic types</head><p>The UMLS semantic types represent intensional knowledge, while the UMLS concepts that are assigned to those types represent extensional knowledge.</p><p>We have defined four clinical categories for 27 semantic types which are related to medical terms among a total of 133 semantic types. The clinical categories defined are Disease, Symptom, Test, and Treatment. Table <ref type="table" coords="1,407.45,210.12,4.44,7.80" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows the clinical categories and the associated UMLS semantic types. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head># of concepts (terms)</head><p>Disease "Anatomical Abnormality", "Congenital Abnormality", "Acquired Abnormality", "Pathologic Function", "Disease or Syndrome", "Mental or Behavior Dysfunction", "Neoplastic Process" 610,356 Symptom "Signs and Symptoms", "Pathologic Function", "Disease or Syndrome", "Mental or Behavior Dysfunction", "Neoplastic Process", "Finding" 1,224,254 Test "Medical Device", "Drug Delivery Device", "Research Device", "Indicator, Reagent, or Diagnostic Acid", "Laboratory Procedure", "Diagnostic Procedure"</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>296,161</head><p>Treatment "Biomedical or Dental Material", "Therapeutic or Preventive Procedure", "Clinical Drug", "Pharmacologic Substance", "Antibiotic", "Biologically Active Substance", "Neuroreactive Substance or Biogenic Amine", "Hormone", "Enzyme", "Vitamin", "Immunologic Factor", "Receptor", "Amino Acid, Peptide, or Protein" 609,675</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Establishing a clinical semantic knowledge from Wikipedia and UMLS</head><p>Wikipedia articles are used for enriching a Clinical semantic knowledge. The articles are extracted by using UMLS terms belong to the Disease and Symptom clinical category. The number of Wikipedia articles extracted is 60,982.</p><p>The Wikipedia article [2] consists of title, abstract, and contents. Here, disease terms are extracted from the "title" part. The seven fields of the "contents" part are used for extraction of medical information: "Signs and symptoms", "Diagnosis", "Characteristics", "Complications", "Screening", "Treatment", Table <ref type="table" coords="2,86.71,214.20,4.44,7.80" target="#tab_1">2</ref> shows that the fields of contents corresponding to the clinical categories. Treatment "Treatment", "Management" field 57,625</p><p>The terms for Symptom, Test, and Treatment are extracted from the corresponding fields of contents in a Wikipedia page, as shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,119.94,404.52,3.37,7.80" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. The terms are extracted from "Signs and symptoms", "Diagnosis", "Characteristics", and "Complications" fields for the Symptom category, the terms are extracted from "Diagnosis", and "Screening" fields for the Test category, and the terms are extracted from "Treatment", "Management" fields for the Treatment category.</p><p>When the Wikipedia page does not have such fields in the contents, the terms for Symptom, Test, and Treatment category are extracted from the abstract part. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Generating documents and words topics</head><p>On the other hand, we have used documents topics and words topi cs for a query expansion. The topics are generated for the docume nt collection using LDA.</p><p>Latent Dirichlet allocation (LDA) is a generative probabilistic model. The basic idea is that documents are represented as random mixtures over latent topics, where each topic is characterized by a distribution over words <ref type="bibr" coords="2,475.26,87.48,9.54,7.80" target="#b2">[4]</ref>. Our system runs a query expansion using the words topics corresponding to the documents topics for the initial retrieval set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">SELECTING EXPANSION TERMS FROM THE CLINICAL SEMANTIC KNOWLEDGE AND TOPICS 3.1 Expansion terms from the clinical semantic knowledge</head><p>For a query expansion, the medical terms are selected based on our clinical semantic knowledge.</p><p>The expansion terms are selected as follows:</p><p>1) Extracting symptom terms from a query.</p><p>2) Selecting disease terms based on the symptom terms in th e query and SYMPTOM-DISEASE relations.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Expansion terms from documents and words topics</head><p>For the initial retrieval set, document topics are selected when the document topic contains the top-retrieved documents (R) in the highest rank (M). Then the corresponding word topics are selected when the word topic contains query terms (S ) in the highest rank (N).</p><p>If the document topic and the word topic selected are the same topic, then expansion terms are selected from the word topics. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Expansion terms from synonym of disease terms</head><p>The synonyms of disease terms are used for a query expansion.</p><p>In the UMLS Metathesaurus, each unique medical concept is associated with a "concept unique identifier" or CUI such that all entries in the Metathesaurus which refer to the same concept share the same CUI.</p><p>Wikipedia also contains pages called redirects which do not contain content themselves, but rather redirect a user to another article (or section of an article). Redirects typically embody alternate names, spellings, forms, closely related words, alternately punctuated or encoded forms, less specific forms in which the redirected name is the primary topic, or more specific forms of some other page.</p><p>The synonyms of disease terms are selected by UMLS CUI and Wikipedia redirects.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Expansion terms according to the query types (Task B)</head><p>The different kinds of expansion terms would be effective according to the query types such as diagnosis, treatment, and test.</p><p>In our experiments, the expansion terms are selected according to the query types. The query types and expansion term categories are as follow. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Query expansion methods</head><p>Expansion terms are gained through section 3.1 to 3.4. In our experiment, the Indri search engine <ref type="bibr" coords="3,195.71,568.68,10.46,7.80" target="#b3">[5]</ref> is used for the query likelihood (QL) model with Dirichlet prior smoothing as our baseline.</p><p>The final score is a combination of scores received from the original query and expanded query. The expanded query consists of disease, symptom, test, and treatment terms. The weight of disease terms is assigned as 1.</p><p>The parameters are learned by using TREC 2014 CDS collection:</p><p>the weight of the original query (λ): {0.1, 0.2, 0. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">EXPERIMENTS 4.1 Run description</head><p>In our experiments for Task A, the query type information is not used for a query expansion. For Task B, the different kinds of expansion terms are selected according to the query types. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Experimental Results</head><p>The experimental results for Task A are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,521.20,512.28,3.48,7.80" target="#tab_4">4</ref>: </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">CONCLUSIONS</head><p>Combining the clinical semantic knowledge extracted from UMLS and Wikipedia with a topic model is effective for TREC Clinical Decision Support Track. In our experiments for Task A, the query type information is not used for a query expansion. For Task B, the different kinds of expansion terms are selected according to the query types. The proposed methods achieved 0.2327 and 0.3033 in the inferred NDCG on Task A and Task B, respectively.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,87.19,150.36,173.62,7.80;2,63.05,54.00,231.00,90.00"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. The example of a Wikipedia article</figDesc><graphic coords="2,63.05,54.00,231.00,90.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="2,63.00,505.56,231.05,7.80;2,54.00,515.64,109.44,7.80;2,63.00,530.04,193.17,7.80;2,83.00,544.68,211.05,8.62;2,83.00,555.00,34.74,8.62;2,83.00,565.32,211.04,8.62;2,83.00,575.64,47.01,8.62;2,83.00,586.20,200.29,8.62;2,83.00,596.52,189.07,8.62;2,83.00,606.84,211.07,8.62;2,85.25,617.16,45.25,8.62;2,83.00,627.48,208.82,8.62;2,83.00,637.80,55.49,8.62"><head>A</head><label></label><figDesc>clinical semantic knowledge is established from these terms extracted by matching UMLS. The clinical semantic knowledge forms are as follow: SYMPTOM-DISEASE relation: &lt; symptom: disease 1 , dis ease 2 ... &gt; DISEASE-SYMPTOM relation: &lt; disease: symptom 1 , sy mptom 2 … &gt; TEST-DISEASE relation: &lt; test: disease 1 , disease 2 ... &gt; DISEASE-TEST relation: &lt; disease: test 1 , test 2 … &gt; TREATMENT-DISEASE relation: &lt; treatment: disease 1 , disease 2 ... &gt; DISEASE-TREATMENT relation: &lt; disease: treatment 1 , treatment 2 … &gt;</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="2,326.76,284.28,231.06,8.27;2,346.76,294.84,211.03,7.80;2,346.76,305.16,84.45,7.80;2,326.76,315.72,231.05,8.27;2,346.76,326.04,15.21,7.80"><head>3 )</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Selecting symptom, test, and treatment terms based on DI SEASE-SYMPTOM, DISEASE-TEST, and "DISEASE-T REATMENT relations. 4) Selecting expansion terms according to the highest freque ncy.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="2,329.69,472.44,216.11,7.80;2,399.18,482.52,77.17,7.80;2,323.15,344.30,230.21,125.65"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. Selecting expansion terms based on the clinical semantic knowledge</figDesc><graphic coords="2,323.15,344.30,230.21,125.65" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="2,326.76,623.64,231.01,7.80;2,317.76,633.72,37.71,7.80;2,346.11,648.36,165.06,7.80;2,346.11,658.68,211.69,7.80;2,346.11,669.00,58.24,7.80;2,346.11,679.32,209.46,7.80;2,346.11,689.64,22.27,7.80;2,346.11,699.96,211.65,7.80;2,346.11,710.28,115.28,7.80;3,82.35,56.52,188.78,7.80;3,82.35,66.84,211.76,7.80;3,82.35,77.16,84.35,7.80;3,54.00,87.24,206.74,7.80"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The parameters are learned by using the TREC 2014 CDS collection.# of topics (D): {50, 100, 150, 200, 250, 500} # of words in the highest rank in a word topic (N): {10, 13 , 15, 17, 20, 25} # of query terms belong to a word topic (S): {4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10} # of documents in the highest rank in a document topic (M ): {50, 100, 150, 200, 250, 500} # of retrieved documents (R): {100, 200, 500, 1000} # of the retrieved documents belong to a document topic ( T): {10, 15, 20, 25, 50} Note that the bold character indicates the final parameter.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5" coords="3,326.76,261.72,176.53,7.80;3,346.11,276.36,122.21,7.80;3,346.11,286.68,211.68,7.80;3,346.11,297.00,77.69,7.80;3,346.11,307.56,211.68,7.80;3,346.11,317.88,142.44,7.80;3,326.76,338.28,175.96,7.80;3,346.11,352.92,211.71,7.80;3,346.11,363.24,45.70,7.80;3,346.11,373.56,211.69,7.80;3,346.11,383.88,211.72,7.80;3,346.11,394.20,54.23,7.80;3,346.11,404.52,211.76,7.80;3,346.11,414.84,209.43,7.80;3,346.11,425.40,193.69,7.80;3,346.11,435.72,211.75,7.80;3,346.11,446.04,209.43,7.80;3,346.11,456.36,211.67,7.80;3,346.11,466.68,20.96,7.80"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Our methods for task A are described as follows: cbnu0: Baseline Language model cbnu1: query expansion based on the clinical semantic kn owledge (section 3.1) cbnu2: query expansion based on the clinical semantic kn owledge and LDA (section 3.1 and 3.2) Our methods for task B are described as follows: cbnu0': Baseline Language model with terms in TREC Di agnosis field cbnu3: query expansion based on the clinical semantic kn owledge and LDA according to the query types (section 3. 1, 3.2, and 3.4) cbnu4: query expansion using medical terms and synony m disease terms based on the clinical semantic knowledge according to the query types(section 3.1, 3.3, and 3.4) cbnu5: query expansion using medical terms and synony m disease terms based on the clinical semantic knowledge and LDA according to query types(section 3.1, 3.2, 3.3 an d 3.4)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="1,323.29,249.00,212.90,35.88"><head>Table 1 . Four clinical categories for a query expansion Clinical categories UMLS semantic types</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="2,59.28,238.92,228.46,108.36"><head>Table 2 . Fields in a Wikipedia article for the clinical categories Clinical categories Fields of Contents # of UMLS concepts</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="2,59.28,289.08,219.59,7.80"><row><cell>Disease</cell><cell>title</cell><cell>18,442</cell></row></table><note coords="2,59.28,314.28,34.92,7.80;2,108.72,304.20,84.72,7.80;2,108.72,314.52,112.18,7.80;2,108.72,324.60,79.19,7.80;2,254.18,314.28,24.70,7.80;2,59.28,339.48,15.46,7.80;2,108.72,339.48,111.17,7.80;2,254.18,339.48,24.70,7.80"><p><p>Symptom</p>"Signs and symptoms", "Diagnosis", "Characteristics", "Complications" field 70,312 Test "Diagnosis", "Screening" field 36,048</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="3,66.48,410.28,223.09,108.60"><head>Table 3 . Expansion terms according to the query types</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="3,66.48,425.40,223.09,93.48"><row><cell>TREC CDS Query Types</cell><cell>Expansion terms</cell></row><row><cell>Diagnosis</cell><cell>Disease and Symptom terms from Disease and Symptom categories</cell></row><row><cell>Test</cell><cell>Disease and Test terms from Disease and Test categories</cell></row><row><cell>Treatment</cell><cell>Disease and Treatment terms from Disease and Treatment categories</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="3,323.28,526.68,213.39,96.36"><head>Table 4 . Experimental results for task A</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="3,323.28,541.56,213.39,81.48"><row><cell>RunID</cell><cell>infNDCG</cell><cell>R-prec</cell><cell>P@10</cell></row><row><cell>cbnu0</cell><cell>0.2179</cell><cell>0.1863</cell><cell>0.3733</cell></row><row><cell>cbnu1</cell><cell>0.2317</cell><cell>0.1954</cell><cell>0.3833</cell></row><row><cell>cbnu2</cell><cell>0.2327</cell><cell>0.1913</cell><cell>0.3967</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">The experimental results for Task B are shown in Table 5:</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="3,323.28,629.64,206.85,71.64"><head>Table 5 . Experimental results for task B</head><label>5</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="3,323.28,646.20,206.85,55.08"><row><cell>RunID</cell><cell>infNDCG</cell><cell>R-prec</cell><cell>P@10</cell></row><row><cell>cbnu0'</cell><cell>0.2779</cell><cell>0.2265</cell><cell>0.4600</cell></row><row><cell>cbnu3</cell><cell>0.2260</cell><cell>0.1836</cell><cell>0.4000</cell></row><row><cell>cbnu4</cell><cell>0.2917</cell><cell>0.2456</cell><cell>0.4900</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="6.">ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</head><p>This research was supported by the <rs type="funder">MSIP(Ministry of Science, ICT and Future Planning)</rs>, <rs type="funder">Korea</rs>, under the <rs type="funder">ITRC</rs>(<rs type="programName">Information Technology Research Center) support program</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">IITP-2015-R0992-15-1023</rs>) supervised by the <rs type="institution">IITP(Institute for Information &amp; communications Technology Promotion</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_MNPs7Mf">
					<idno type="grant-number">IITP-2015-R0992-15-1023</idno>
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">Information Technology Research Center) support program</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,58.50,293.50,97.43,10.54" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>References</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,75.25,339.24,218.74,7.80;4,75.25,349.56,218.83,7.80;4,75.25,359.64,150.20,7.80" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Bodenreider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,166.42,339.24,127.56,7.80;4,75.25,349.56,211.10,7.80">The Unified Medical Language System(UMLS): intergrating biomedical terminology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="D270" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,77.50,374.28,216.61,7.80;4,75.25,384.60,218.80,7.80;4,75.25,394.92,174.19,7.80" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,271.28,374.28,22.83,7.80;4,75.25,384.60,70.40,7.80">Latent dirichlet allocation</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Blei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,158.49,384.60,135.55,7.80;4,75.25,394.92,31.29,7.80">The Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="993" to="1022" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,77.50,409.32,216.53,7.80;4,75.25,419.64,218.81,7.80;4,75.25,430.20,218.87,7.80;4,75.25,440.28,183.80,7.80" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,78.67,419.64,215.39,7.80;4,75.25,430.20,25.05,7.80">Indri: A language model-based search engine for complex queries</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Strohman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Metzler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Turtle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.lemurproject.org/indri" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,122.15,430.20,171.97,7.80;4,75.25,440.28,29.99,7.80">Proc. International Conference on Intelligence Analysis</title>
		<meeting>International Conference on Intelligence Analysis</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,75.25,454.68,218.79,7.80;4,75.25,465.24,218.80,7.80;4,75.25,475.56,218.76,7.80;4,75.25,485.88,83.59,7.80;4,158.91,483.71,6.00,5.27;4,167.47,485.88,126.60,7.80;4,75.25,496.20,218.83,7.80;4,75.25,506.28,55.47,7.80" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,168.66,465.24,125.40,7.80;4,75.25,475.56,170.97,7.80">Mining diabetes complication and treatment patterns for clinical decision support</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lu</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jie</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ankit</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wei-Keng</forename><surname>Liao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alok</forename><surname>Choudhary</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,256.75,475.56,37.25,7.80;4,75.25,485.88,83.59,7.80;4,158.91,483.71,6.00,5.27;4,167.47,485.88,126.60,7.80;4,75.25,496.20,214.45,7.80">CIKM &apos;13 Proceedings of the 22 nd ACM international conference on Conference on information &amp; knowledge management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="279" to="288" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,75.25,520.92,218.86,7.80;4,75.25,531.24,165.28,7.80;4,240.64,529.07,4.67,5.27;4,248.62,531.24,45.44,7.80;4,75.25,541.56,218.83,7.80;4,75.25,551.64,143.69,7.80" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,199.64,520.92,94.47,7.80;4,75.25,531.24,24.01,7.80">A topic model of clinical reports</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Corey</forename><surname>Arnold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Speier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,110.97,531.24,129.57,7.80;4,240.64,529.07,4.67,5.27;4,248.62,531.24,45.44,7.80;4,75.25,541.56,218.83,7.80;4,75.25,551.64,73.71,7.80">SIGIR &apos;12 Proceedings of the 35 th international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1031" to="1032" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,75.25,566.28,218.83,7.80;4,75.25,576.60,218.80,7.80;4,75.25,586.92,98.77,7.80;4,174.09,584.75,4.67,5.27;4,186.37,586.92,107.63,7.80;4,75.25,597.24,218.81,7.80;4,75.25,607.32,89.94,7.80" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,79.26,576.60,166.89,7.80">Circumlocution in diagnostic medical queries</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Isabelle</forename><surname>Stanton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Samuel</forename><surname>Ieong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nina</forename><surname>Mishra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,256.63,576.60,37.43,7.80;4,75.25,586.92,98.77,7.80;4,174.09,584.75,4.67,5.27;4,186.37,586.92,107.63,7.80;4,75.25,597.24,218.81,7.80;4,75.25,607.32,28.97,7.80">SIGIR &apos;14 Proceedings of the 37 th international ACM SIGIR conference on Research &amp; development in information retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="133" to="142" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,75.25,621.96,218.79,7.80;4,75.25,632.28,218.82,7.80;4,75.25,642.84,98.03,7.80;4,173.34,640.67,4.67,5.27;4,186.87,642.84,107.13,7.80;4,75.25,653.16,218.83,7.80;4,75.25,663.24,89.94,7.80" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,199.69,621.96,94.35,7.80;4,75.25,632.28,171.29,7.80">Studies of the onset and persistence of medical concerns in search logs</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ryen</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Horvitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,256.77,632.28,37.30,7.80;4,75.25,642.84,98.03,7.80;4,173.34,640.67,4.67,5.27;4,186.87,642.84,107.13,7.80;4,75.25,653.16,218.83,7.80;4,75.25,663.24,28.97,7.80">SIGIR &apos;12 Proceedings of the 35 th international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="265" to="274" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
