<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,143.52,80.93,324.97,14.85;1,210.15,98.86,191.71,14.85">Using Neural Embeddings for Diagnostic Inferencing in Clinical Question Answering</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,156.83,142.99,76.46,12.37"><forename type="first">Sadid</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hasan</surname></persName>
							<email>sadid.hasan@philips.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Artificial Intelligence Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Philips Research North America</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,242.20,142.99,51.32,12.37"><forename type="first">Yuan</forename><surname>Ling</surname></persName>
							<email>yuan.ling@philips.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Artificial Intelligence Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Philips Research North America</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,301.89,142.99,41.75,12.37"><forename type="first">Joey</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<email>joey.liu@philips.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Artificial Intelligence Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Philips Research North America</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,374.12,142.99,81.06,12.37"><forename type="first">Oladimeji</forename><surname>Farri</surname></persName>
							<email>dimeji.farri@philips.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Artificial Intelligence Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Philips Research North America</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,143.52,80.93,324.97,14.85;1,210.15,98.86,191.71,14.85">Using Neural Embeddings for Diagnostic Inferencing in Clinical Question Answering</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">09B87CD4B320C26595356D7D3FAC3E72</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:08+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper, we describe our clinical question answering system implemented for the Text Retrieval Conference (TREC 2015) Clinical Decision Support (CDS) track. We submitted six runs for two related tasks using a multi-step approach that leverages Natural Language Processing (NLP) and neural embeddings to retrieve relevant biomedical articles for answering generic clinical questions. Evaluation results demonstrated that our system achieved higher scores for most clinical questions requiring answers that pertain to treatment and test/investigations, topics in which the ground-truth diagnoses were provided by the track organizers. However, our system was less accurate with questions requiring answers pertaining to diagnosis. We conclude that diagnostic inferencing may be the most important determinant of the accuracy of the clinical question answering systems, and that the use of neural embeddings and advanced deep learning techniques could help improve the quality of such systems in order to effectively support decision-making in patient care.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Similar to 2014, the main objective of the 2015 CDS track 1 was to retrieve a ranked list of the top 1000 biomedical articles that can answer questions related to multiple categories (diagnosis, test, and treatment) of clinical information needs. There were two tasks in the 2015 edition of the CDS track:</p><p>Task A was identical to the 2014 task. In addition, based on the feedback from our participation in the 1 http://www.trec-cds.org/ 2014 edition where we demonstrated that clinical knowledge-based inferencing is a critical factor for more focused retrieval of biomedical articles <ref type="bibr" coords="1,509.11,264.67,30.89,10.45;1,313.20,278.22,51.60,10.45" target="#b3">(Hasan et al., 2014)</ref>, the organizers defined a new task this year, Task B, where the ground truth diagnoses were provided for the test and treatment topics in order to verify if such important information can actually improve the accuracy of the relevant biomedical article retrieval. We submitted six runs for the two tasks using a variety of NLP-based techniques to address the clinical questions provided.</p><p>Motivated by the recent surge of Deep Learning (DL) techniques in demonstrating superior performance over the traditional supervised and unsupervised Machine Learning (ML) techniques for various NLP tasks, we exploited the strength of neural word and phrase embeddings in extending the context of the underlying topics (clinical case narratives) towards improved diagnostic inferencing for our clinical question answering system. Current applications of deep learning in NLP tasks largely rely on learning high-dimensional vector representations of words and their relationships (called word embeddings) using neural network architectures. Once a language model is trained in this manner, semantically related words would be transformed into similar vector representations <ref type="bibr" coords="1,499.06,590.67,40.94,10.45;1,313.20,604.22,50.22,10.45" target="#b5">(Mikolov et al., 2013)</ref>. Following the success of word embeddings in modeling high-level abstractions in textual data, researchers have progressed beyond the wordlevel to propose deep learning algorithms for learning phrase-level, sentence-level, and document-level representations <ref type="bibr" coords="1,382.77,671.97,104.47,10.45" target="#b4">(Le and Mikolov, 2014)</ref>. The main advantage of this architecture over the traditional bag-of-words model is its ability to capture the embedded ordering and semantics of the words while learning a fixed-length vector representation for variable-length text structures. Our experiments showed that deep neural embeddings can provide performance improvements for a number of topics and the evaluation results further emphasized the significance of accurate diagnostic inferencing for effective retrieval of relevant biomedical articles for the automated clinical question answering task. In the subsequent sections, we describe the overall architecture of our system, and present the evaluation results with analyses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System Description</head><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,103.65,590.67,5.45,10.45" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows the generic architecture of our clinical question answering system. Our hybrid NLPdriven method presents a combination of syntactic, semantic and filtering processes towards extracting relevant biomedical articles corresponding to clinical concepts (diagnoses, treatment and/or test) relevant to each given topic. Similar to last year <ref type="bibr" coords="2,267.91,671.97,30.89,10.45;2,72.00,685.52,52.13,10.45" target="#b3">(Hasan et al., 2014)</ref>, our overall approach centers on three steps: (i) Topical Analysis: identifying the most relevant topical keywords from the given topic de-scriptions or summaries; (ii) Clinical Inferencing: reasoning through the topical keywords to determine the appropriate diagnoses, tests, and treatments based on underlying clinical context by using neural embeddings and/or an external clinical knowledge base; and, (iii) Relevant Article Retrieval: retrieving and ranking pertinent biomedical articles based on the topical keywords and clinical inferences from steps (i) and (ii). Our submitted runs are varied based on the use of topical descriptions or summaries in association with different clinical inferencing methodologies.</p><p>In the first step, we extracted term frequencyinverse document frequency (TF-IDF) weighted topical keywords from the given descriptions/summaries and mapped them to categories represented in controlled clinical vocabularies/ontologies. We also identified relevant demographic information, interpreted vital patient parameters based on standard normal range values, and filtered out negated clinical concepts in order to give more weight to positive clinical manifestations in a given patient scenario. The use of clinical domain ontologies is effective in this step as they have been implemented to promote standard clinical vocabulary, and are widely used to semantically categorize clinical concepts, and facilitate information exchange and interoperability <ref type="bibr" coords="3,238.95,129.77,59.85,10.45;3,72.00,143.32,24.85,10.45" target="#b0">(Bodenreider, 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,101.76,143.32,103.20,10.45" target="#b7">Stenzhorn et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,209.86,143.32,84.25,10.45" target="#b2">Garde et al., 2007)</ref>.</p><p>In our system, we used the following clinical domain ontologies: SNOMED CT<ref type="foot" coords="3,224.74,168.45,3.99,7.64" target="#foot_0">2</ref>  <ref type="bibr" coords="3,232.62,170.42,66.17,10.45;3,72.00,183.97,59.96,10.45" target="#b1">(Cornet and de Keizer, 2008)</ref> for diagnoses, LOINC<ref type="foot" coords="3,233.74,182.00,3.99,7.64" target="#foot_1">3</ref> for tests, and RxNorm<ref type="foot" coords="3,110.18,195.55,3.99,7.64" target="#foot_2">4</ref> for treatments.</p><p>In the next step, we implemented a word-and phrase-to-vector neural embedding model trained on over 4 million clinically relevant sentences garnered from multiple clinical data sources: PubMed Central<ref type="foot" coords="3,86.54,264.60,3.99,7.64" target="#foot_3">5</ref> articles, Wikipedia (Clinical Medicine<ref type="foot" coords="3,268.03,264.60,3.99,7.64" target="#foot_4">6</ref> ) articles, and MIMICII discharge summaries <ref type="bibr" coords="3,257.33,280.12,41.47,10.45;3,72.00,293.67,42.18,10.45" target="#b6">(Saeed et al., 2011)</ref>. The generated model is used to capture the overall context of a given topic description or summary towards inferring the differential diagnoses based on the commonest clinical diagnoses represented in the clusters of topical keywords from the first step. We used the skip-gram model architecture to learn the vector representations of words and phrases as it has been reported to provide better results in comparison to the continuous bag-of-words (CBOW) model <ref type="bibr" coords="3,148.56,415.61,100.67,10.45" target="#b5">(Mikolov et al., 2013)</ref>. The list of possible diagnoses was further validated, filtered, and ranked by referencing a clinical knowledge base (derived from Wikipedia articles and indexed using Elasticsearch<ref type="foot" coords="3,129.56,467.84,3.99,7.64" target="#foot_5">7</ref> ) to extract a list of candidate articles with relevant diagnoses corresponding to each topical keyword. Our main goal was to find relationships between topical keywords and associated clinical concepts (diagnoses/disorders, treatment and test) within a comprehensive knowledge base for the purpose of biomedical evidence retrieval. Candidate Wikipedia articles were filtered using various criteria e.g., location, gender, match with topical keywords, etc., and the resulting list of Wikipedia articles with relevant clinical concepts were mined to retrieve specific diagnoses (from the title of the Wikipedia article), and tests and treatments ( from sections and subsections of the Wikipedia article). It is important to note that for Task B, we skipped inferring the differential diagnoses for the topic descriptions/summaries under the "treatment" and "test" categories, given that the organizers included the diagnoses (ground truth) in the test data.</p><p>In the final step, topical keywords and the corresponding disorders/diagnoses, tests, and treatments obtained from the clinical inferencing step were used to retrieve candidate biomedical articles by searching through the TREC-CDS database of PubMed Central articles. Candidate articles were ranked using multiple weighting algorithms specific to the three types of clinical questions (diagnosis, test, and treatment). The retrieved biomedical articles were further filtered by location (e.g. USA/Canada), demographic information and other contextual information from the topic description/summary towards improving the relevance of the results. The final list of top 1000 biomedical articles was ordered by article publication date to provide chronological biomedical evidence for the answers to each topic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experimental Setup</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Test Data</head><p>The test dataset comprises 30 topics divided into three question types: topic 1-10 (diagnosis), topic 11-20 (test), and topic 21-30 (treatment). The given topic descriptions (or topics) are essentially medical case narratives that describe scenarios related to patient's medical history, signs/symptoms, diagnoses, tests, and treatments. The topics are provided in two versions depending on the depth of information. Topic "descriptions" include comprehensive descriptions of the patient's situation whereas topic "summaries" contain an abridged version of the most important information. In addition, for Task B, ground truth diagnoses were provided for the test and treatment topics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Corpus</head><p>Similar to 2014, a snapshot of the open access portion of PubMed Central (PMC), a freely available online database of full-text biomedical articles comprising 733, 138 biomedical publications was made available by the TREC CDS track organizers.    </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Run Description</head><p>For Task A, we submitted three runs as follows: 1) prna1-A: considers topic descriptions with clinical knowledge base inferencing, 2) prna2-A: considers topic summaries with clinical knowledge base inferencing, and 3) prna3-A: considers topic descriptions with clinical inferencing using neural word/phrase embeddings and the clinical knowledge base. Our three runs for Task B were designed in the same fashion with the exception that we skipped inferring the differential diagnoses for the topic descriptions/summaries under the "treatment" and "test" categories as we simply used the ground truth diagnoses provided in the test data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Evaluation and Analysis</head><p>The evaluation of the CDS track was conducted using the standard TREC evaluation procedures for adhoc information retrieval tasks <ref type="bibr" coords="8,208.69,324.73,90.11,10.45" target="#b10">(Yilmaz et al., 2008;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="8,72.00,338.28,69.34,10.45" target="#b8">Voorhees, 2014)</ref>. The highest ranked biomedical articles were sampled and judged by medical domain experts on a three-point scale of 0: not relevant, 1: possibly relevant, and 2: definitely relevant depending on the relevance of the answer to the associated question type about a given case report.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="8,113.63,419.86,5.45,10.45" target="#fig_1">2</ref> to Figure <ref type="figure" coords="8,162.79,419.86,5.45,10.45">5</ref> and Figure <ref type="figure" coords="8,219.20,419.86,5.45,10.45" target="#fig_3">6</ref> to Figure <ref type="figure" coords="8,268.35,419.86,5.45,10.45">9</ref> show the overall scores of our runs for Task A and Task B respectively across all the topics as compared to the median and best scores for the submitted automatic runs for the following evaluation measures: inferred average precision 8 (infAP), inferred normalized discounted cumulative gain 9 (infNDCG), precision at R where R is the number of known relevant documents (R-prec), and precision at 10 documents (Prec (10)). The two inferred measures are used to provide more accurate estimates of a system's performance when relevance judgments are incomplete due to dynamic and/or larger document collections <ref type="bibr" coords="8,263.65,582.45,35.15,10.45;8,84.65,602.34,2.99,5.73">(Yilmaz 8</ref> Average Precision (AP) is a measure that combines precision and recall for evaluating systems that retrieve a ranked list of articles. In particular, AP is the mean of the precision scores after each relevant article is retrieved. 9 Discounted Cumulative Gain (DCG) measures the quality of ranking for a system when it retrieves a ranked list of results and the results are graded with relevance judgment. In particular, DCG computes the usefulness of an article based on its rank in the retrieved list. Normalized DCG (NDCG) is computed by using the maximum possible DCG (calculated by sorting the result list by relevance) as the normalization factor. <ref type="bibr" coords="8,313.20,75.57,77.33,10.45" target="#b9">and Aslam, 2006;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="8,393.31,75.57,84.49,10.45" target="#b10">Yilmaz et al., 2008)</ref>. All the evaluation measures used for the CDS track contribute towards providing a comprehensive assessment of the quality of a system.</p><p>The reported results show that our clinical question answering system performs close to or better than the median scores for 43% of the topics in Task A and 50% of the topics in Task B across all evaluation measures. Analysis of these results also demonstrates that our clinical question answering system can achieve better results for 53% of the topics when topic summaries are used whereas neural word/phrase embeddings could improve upon the scores for 13% of the topics. Moreover, we find that the results for Task B improves drastically over those for Task A for most of the test and treatment topics across all runs by often outperforming the median scores -thus, emphasizing that accurate differential diagnoses can have a significant impact on the accuracy of the relevant biomedical article retrieval.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion and Future Work</head><p>In this paper, we described our participation in the TREC 2015 CDS Track. Evaluation results showed additional gains with the implementation of neural word and phrase embeddings in extending relevant context for our clinical question answering system. Results also demonstrated the importance of accurate inferencing of diagnosis in retrieving relevant biomedical articles corresponding to underlying clinical narratives. In future, we plan to improve our clinical inferencing algorithms towards extracting the most accurate differential diagnoses by employing advanced deep learning architectures (e.g. Recurrent Neural Networks (RNNs)) for training models from large collections of clinical knowledge sources.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,190.87,372.24,230.27,9.54;2,72.00,72.00,468.00,283.47"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Clinical question answering system architecture</figDesc><graphic coords="2,72.00,72.00,468.00,283.47" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,213.41,377.68,185.17,9.54;4,72.00,77.44,467.99,283.47"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: infAP scores for each topic (Task A)</figDesc><graphic coords="4,72.00,77.44,467.99,283.47" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="5,211.76,377.68,188.48,9.54;5,72.00,77.44,468.00,283.47"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: R-prec scores for each topic (Task A)</figDesc><graphic coords="5,72.00,77.44,468.00,283.47" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="6,213.69,377.67,184.63,9.54;6,72.00,77.44,468.00,283.47"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: infAP scores for each topic (Task B)</figDesc><graphic coords="6,72.00,77.44,468.00,283.47" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="7,212.03,377.67,187.93,9.54;7,72.00,77.44,467.99,283.47"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8: R-prec scores for each topic (Task B)</figDesc><graphic coords="7,72.00,77.44,467.99,283.47" type="bitmap" /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_0" coords="3,88.14,658.15,120.80,8.59"><p>http://www.ihtsdo.org/snomed-ct/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_1" coords="3,88.14,669.32,55.89,8.59"><p>http://loinc.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_2" coords="3,88.14,680.49,169.39,8.59"><p>http://www.nlm.nih.gov/research/umls/rxnorm/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5" xml:id="foot_3" coords="3,88.14,691.67,123.83,8.59"><p>http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6" xml:id="foot_4" coords="3,88.14,702.84,205.67,8.59"><p>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:Clinical medicine</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7" xml:id="foot_5" coords="3,88.14,713.93,104.84,8.59"><p>http://www.elasticsearch.org/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="8,313.20,618.01,226.80,9.54;8,324.11,629.96,215.89,9.54;8,324.11,641.92,73.01,9.54;8,404.08,648.64,135.92,2.71;8,324.11,660.60,28.50,2.71;8,355.10,653.87,51.75,9.54" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,405.98,618.01,134.02,9.54;8,324.11,629.96,215.89,9.54;8,324.11,641.92,68.75,9.54">Biomedical Ontologies in Action: Role in Knowledge Management, Data Integration and Decision Support</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Bodenreider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,404.08,648.64,135.92,2.71;8,324.11,660.60,24.43,2.71">IMIA Yearbook of Medical Informatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,313.20,665.63,226.80,9.54;8,324.11,677.59,134.75,9.54;8,466.93,684.31,73.08,2.71;8,324.11,696.27,128.40,2.71;8,455.00,689.54,25.19,9.54" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,478.59,665.63,61.41,9.54;8,324.11,677.59,130.21,9.54">Forty Years of SNOMED: A Literature Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Cornet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>De Keizer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,466.93,684.31,73.08,2.71;8,324.11,696.27,123.69,2.71">BMC Medical Informatics and Decision Making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,313.20,701.30,226.80,9.54;8,324.11,713.26,215.89,9.54;9,82.91,76.21,35.14,9.54;9,135.07,82.94,163.73,2.71;9,82.91,88.17,61.71,9.54" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,526.41,701.30,13.59,9.54;8,324.11,713.26,215.89,9.54;9,82.91,76.21,30.75,9.54">Towards Semantic Interoperability for Electronic Health Records</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Garde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Knaup</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hovenga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Heard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,135.07,82.94,159.33,2.71">Methods of Information in Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="332" to="343" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,72.00,100.87,226.80,9.54;9,82.91,112.83,215.89,9.54;9,82.91,124.78,46.30,9.54;9,131.81,131.51,166.99,2.71;9,82.91,143.46,215.89,2.71;9,82.91,155.42,139.91,2.71" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,112.21,112.83,186.59,9.54;9,82.91,124.78,29.78,9.54">A Hybrid Approach to Clinical Question Answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Farri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,131.81,131.51,166.99,2.71;9,82.91,143.46,72.38,2.71">Proceedings of the Twenty-Third Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>the Twenty-Third Text REtrieval Conference<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-11-19">2014. 2014. November 19-21, 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,72.00,161.40,226.80,9.54;9,82.91,173.35,152.49,9.54;9,238.55,180.08,60.25,2.71;9,82.91,192.03,215.89,2.71;9,82.91,203.99,215.89,2.71;9,82.91,209.22,72.50,9.54" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,206.88,161.40,91.91,9.54;9,82.91,173.35,133.92,9.54">Distributed representations of sentences and documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Le</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,238.55,180.08,60.25,2.71;9,82.91,192.03,215.89,2.71;9,82.91,203.99,66.05,2.71">Proceedings of the 31th International Conference on Machine Learning, ICML 2014</title>
		<meeting>the 31th International Conference on Machine Learning, ICML 2014<address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-06">2014. June 2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1188" to="1196" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,72.00,221.92,226.80,9.54;9,82.91,233.87,215.89,9.54;9,82.91,245.83,176.15,9.54;9,262.74,252.55,36.06,2.71;9,82.91,264.51,215.89,2.71;9,82.91,276.46,160.85,2.71;9,247.62,269.74,51.18,9.54;9,82.91,281.69,22.42,9.54" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,151.25,233.87,147.55,9.54;9,82.91,245.83,156.41,9.54">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,262.74,252.55,36.06,2.71;9,82.91,264.51,215.89,2.71;9,82.91,276.46,156.36,2.71">Proceedings of the 27th Annual Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems NIPS 2013</title>
		<meeting>the 27th Annual Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems NIPS 2013</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3111" to="3119" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,72.00,294.40,226.80,9.54;9,82.91,306.35,215.89,9.54;9,82.91,318.31,215.89,9.54;9,82.91,330.26,215.89,9.54;9,82.91,342.22,179.92,9.54;9,267.80,348.94,31.00,2.71;9,82.91,360.90,61.61,2.71;9,147.01,354.17,50.09,9.54" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Saeed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Villarroel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Reisner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Clifford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Lehman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Moody</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Heldt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kyaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Moody</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,236.82,318.31,61.98,9.54;9,82.91,330.26,215.89,9.54;9,82.91,342.22,175.84,9.54">Multiparameter intelligent monitoring in intensive care ii MIMIC-II: A public-access intensive care unit database</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="952" to="960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,72.00,366.87,226.80,9.54;9,82.91,378.83,215.89,9.54;9,82.91,390.78,57.99,9.54;9,149.52,397.51,149.28,2.71;9,82.91,409.47,20.74,2.71;9,106.14,402.74,76.65,9.54" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,114.95,378.83,183.85,9.54;9,82.91,390.78,53.53,9.54">Adapting Clinical Ontologies in Real-World Environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Stenzhorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Boeker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,149.52,397.51,149.28,2.71;9,82.91,409.47,16.59,2.71">Journal of Universal Computer Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3767" to="3780" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,72.00,415.44,226.80,9.54;9,82.91,427.40,117.91,9.54;9,203.56,434.12,95.24,2.71;9,82.91,446.08,215.89,2.71;9,82.91,458.03,169.87,2.71;9,254.95,451.31,43.86,9.54;9,82.91,463.26,72.50,9.54" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,175.87,415.44,122.93,9.54;9,82.91,427.40,100.68,9.54">The Effect of Sampling Strategy on Inferred Measures</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,203.56,434.12,95.24,2.71;9,82.91,446.08,215.89,2.71;9,82.91,458.03,169.87,2.71;9,254.95,451.31,39.91,9.54">Proceedings of the 37th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval, SIGIR &apos;14</title>
		<meeting>the 37th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval, SIGIR &apos;14</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1119" to="1122" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,72.00,475.97,226.80,9.54;9,82.91,487.92,215.89,9.54;9,82.91,499.88,8.30,9.54;9,95.12,506.60,203.69,2.71;9,82.91,518.56,215.89,2.71;9,82.91,523.79,109.30,9.54" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,219.48,475.97,79.32,9.54;9,82.91,487.92,211.38,9.54">Estimating Average Precision with Incomplete and Imperfect Judgments</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Yilmaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Aslam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,95.12,506.60,203.69,2.71;9,82.91,518.56,215.89,2.71;9,82.91,523.79,40.33,9.54">Proceedings of the 15th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM &apos;06</title>
		<meeting>the 15th ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management, CIKM &apos;06</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="102" to="111" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,72.00,536.49,226.80,9.54;9,82.91,548.44,215.89,9.54;9,82.91,560.40,61.25,9.54;9,147.08,567.12,151.72,2.71;9,82.91,579.08,215.89,2.71;9,82.91,591.03,143.24,2.71;9,228.89,584.31,69.91,9.54;9,82.91,596.26,37.36,9.54" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,269.52,536.49,29.28,9.54;9,82.91,548.44,215.89,9.54;9,82.91,560.40,41.87,9.54">A Simple and Efficient Sampling Method for Estimating AP and NDCG</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Yilmaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kanoulas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Aslam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,147.08,567.12,151.72,2.71;9,82.91,579.08,215.89,2.71;9,82.91,591.03,143.24,2.71;9,228.89,584.31,40.54,9.54">Proceedings of the 31st Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval, SIGIR &apos;08</title>
		<meeting>the 31st Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval, SIGIR &apos;08</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="603" to="610" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
