<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,79.29,70.21,428.87,13.98">RealSakaiLab at the TREC 2020 Health Misinformation Track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,210.09,99.95,50.73,10.48;1,260.81,98.34,1.88,7.44"><forename type="first">Sijie</forename><surname>Tao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Waseda University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>3-4-1 Okubo, Shinjuku-ku</addrLine>
									<postCode>169-8555</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,291.73,99.95,81.33,10.48;1,373.08,98.34,1.88,7.44"><forename type="first">Tetsuya</forename><surname>Sakai</surname></persName>
							<email>†tetsuyasakai@acm.org</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Waseda University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>3-4-1 Okubo, Shinjuku-ku</addrLine>
									<postCode>169-8555</postCode>
									<settlement>Tokyo</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,79.29,70.21,428.87,13.98">RealSakaiLab at the TREC 2020 Health Misinformation Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">7DE0135B7AA8B8D156F39AA00F203E94</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:11+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper, we describe our experiments conducted for the AdHoc Retrieval task of the TREC 2020 Health Misinformation Track. This task offers a challenges to participants to design a ranking model that promotes retrieval of both credible and correct health information. To address both relevance and credibility, we combined several techniques to re-rank a BM25 baseline ranking. The results from a language identification model, a news category classifier and a majority score calculation were used to modify the BM25 scores of the baseline ranking.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.28" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.28" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Incorrect information in a search engine results page (SERP) can be detrimental. Previous research has shown that a bias towards misinformation in SERP can increase the possibility of the users making incorrect choices in a decisionmaking task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,94.38,364.16,9.22,7.86" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p><p>The AdHoc Retrieval task of the TREC 2020 Health Misinformation Track aims to provide a venue for participants to design ranking models to retrieve information that is both credible and correct. Participants are required to develop approaches to rank not only relevant but also credible and correct documents over those with incorrect information. This year, the track focuses on the pandemic, and hence, the topics are all related to COVID-19.</p><p>We submitted four runs to the track. One is a BM25 ranking as the baseline, and the other three runs are re-ranked based on the BM25 ranking scores. Several techniques are combined in the re-ranking runs. First, as non-English documents are considered irrelevant in this track, we utilized a language identification model to filter out documents that are not in English. Further, to boost the rankings of the documents that may contain health information, we trained a news category classifier to detect documents that have relevant contents. Next, the credibility of a document is modeled by calculating a majority score, which is based on its similarities with other documents. The results from the language identification model, the news category classifier, and the majority score calculation are used to modify the BM25 scores of the baseline ranking.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Submitted Runs</head><p>In this section, details of the submitted runs are discussed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Language Identification</head><p>Although the corpus used in this task contains documents in different languages, non-English documents are considered irrelevant in this track. Therefore, it is necessary to detect the language in which a document is prepared and filter the non-English documents from the ranking. A pre-trained language identification model using fastText <ref type="bibr" coords="1,475.61,364.16,9.73,7.86" target="#b2">[3]</ref> [4]<ref type="foot" coords="1,496.60,363.08,3.39,4.37" target="#foot_0">1</ref> is used to identify the languages in which a document is prepared.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">News Category Classification</head><p>To rank more documents that contain health information, we trained a classifier to detect the categories of the documents' content. As all documents are news articles, a news category classifier was trained on an external dataset named News Category Dataset 2 . This dataset contains 200,000 news headlines and each headline is assigned to a corresponding category. There are 41 categories, and we chose four categories, politics, science &amp; tech, wellness, and world news as "relevant categories", that could contain health-related information about COVID-19. If a document is classified under one of the relevant categories, then the result from the classifier will be used to boost the ranking of the document.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Majority Score</head><p>As the task requires participants to retrieve credible information, we address the credibility of a document by calculating a "Majority Score". This idea is based on a hypothesis that "the more similar a document is to others, the more likely the document is credible". For each topic, the baseline BM25 ranking returns 1,000 documents. The Majority Score of a retrieved document is calculated as the average of the similarity values with the other 999 documents. For calculating document similarity, the documents are first represented as tf-idf vectors, and the similarity value of two documents is defined as the cosine similarity of the document representations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Runs</head><p>We submitted four runs to the track. The first, RSL BM25 is a baseline BM25 ranking, automatically generated by Anserini <ref type="bibr" coords="2,78.80,251.14,9.73,7.86" target="#b5">[6]</ref> 3 with default parameter settings.</p><p>The second run is named RSL BM25LC, where L stands for Language Identification and C stands for Category Classification. The BM25 scores are set to 0 if the detected language is not English. For English documents, the BM25 scores are modified as the following equation if they are classified under a relevant category:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,52.28,360.66,224.30,8.37">RSL BM 25LC(d) = BM 25(d) * (1 + P (d))<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where P (d) is the output of the news category classifier for a given document d, which is the probability of the document being classified under a relevant category (See Section 2.2).</p><p>The third run RSL BM25LM (Language Identification and Majority Score) re-ranks documents by boosting the BM25 scores using the majority scores:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,52.28,477.99,237.90,7.86">RSL BM 25LM (d) = BM 25(d) * (1+M ajorityScore(d))(2)</formula><p>The last run RSL BM25LMC is a run combining RSL BM25LC and RSL BM25LM, where the scores of the documents are calculated as the sum of the scores from the two runs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Result and Discussion</head><p>The results were assessed to judge whether the retrieved documents are useful, credible, and correct. Table <ref type="table" coords="2,253.50,602.02,4.61,7.86">1</ref> shows the evaluation results of our runs and the medians of the scores from all the participant teams. The evaluation measure cam map three is an extended version of the convex aggregating measure (CAM) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,151.52,660.14,9.22,7.86" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. The organizers designed this measure based on the original one considering all the three aspects (usefulness, credibility, and correctness). Other measures such as nDCG and compatibility <ref type="bibr" coords="2,202.15,703.73,9.73,7.86" target="#b0">[1]</ref> were also used to evaluate the runs.</p><p>From the evaluation results, it is difficult to say that our 3 ：https://github.com/castorini/anserini method can retrieve more credible and correct documents.</p><p>Although the combined run RSL BM25LMC slightly outperforms the other runs, the run RSL BM25LM does not produce better results than the BM25 baseline run or the RSL BM25LC in terms of cam map three and nDCG. Therefore, from the evaluation results, it is not clear whether reranking using majority score can promote retrieval of more credible and correct documents. Re-ranking using majority score does not work as expected because using tf-idf may not be effective in capturing document similarity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions</head><p>In this paper, we described our participation in the TREC 2020 Health Misinformation Track. We used several techniques to build our runs: a language identification model, a news category classifier, and a majority score calculation to modify the BM25 baseline ranking. The evaluation results show that our method cannot significantly impact the retrieval of correct and credible documents. In future work, we hope to find alternative ways for better identification of correct and credible documents to help users avoid making erroneous decisions.</p></div>			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,302.96,745.71,246.01,6.71"><p>：https://dl.fbaipublicfiles.com/fasttext/supervised-models/lid.176.bin</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="2,325.35,515.56,218.43,6.99;2,325.35,526.20,176.82,6.99" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="2,486.71,515.56,57.07,6.99;2,325.35,526.20,39.52,6.99">Assessing top-k preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vtyurina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Smucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>abs/2007.11682</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="2,371.28,526.20,20.83,6.99">ArXiv</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="2,325.35,536.83,218.43,6.99;2,325.35,547.46,218.42,6.99;2,325.35,558.09,218.43,6.99;2,325.35,568.72,162.29,6.99" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="2,506.51,536.83,37.26,6.99;2,325.35,547.46,218.42,6.99;2,325.35,558.09,22.79,6.99">A Think-Aloud Study to Understand Factors Affecting Online Health Search</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ghenai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Smucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="2,354.87,558.09,188.91,6.99;2,325.35,568.72,133.60,6.99">Proceedings of the 2020 Conference on Human Information Interaction and Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 2020 Conference on Human Information Interaction and Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="2,325.35,579.36,218.42,6.99;2,325.35,589.99,218.42,6.99;2,325.35,600.62,199.20,6.99" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Joulin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Grave</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bojanowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Douze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Jégou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1612.03651</idno>
		<title level="m" coord="2,390.19,589.99,153.58,6.99;2,325.35,600.62,41.43,6.99">FastText.zip: Compressing text classification models</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="2,325.35,611.25,218.42,6.99;2,325.35,621.88,218.43,6.99;2,325.35,632.51,94.19,6.99" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Joulin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Grave</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bojanowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1607.01759</idno>
		<title level="m" coord="2,529.31,611.25,14.46,6.99;2,325.35,621.88,155.55,6.99">Bag of Tricks for Efficient Text Classification</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="2,325.35,643.15,218.43,6.99;2,325.35,653.78,218.43,6.99;2,325.35,664.41,218.43,6.99;2,325.35,675.04,148.96,6.99" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="2,482.02,643.15,61.76,6.99;2,325.35,653.78,194.92,6.99">Evaluation Measures for Relevance and Credibility in Ranked Lists</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lioma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Simonsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Larsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="2,527.38,653.78,16.41,6.99;2,325.35,664.41,218.43,6.99;2,325.35,675.04,120.26,6.99">Proceedings of the ACM SIGIR International Conference on Theory of Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the ACM SIGIR International Conference on Theory of Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="2,325.35,685.67,218.42,6.99;2,325.35,696.30,218.43,6.99;2,325.35,706.94,112.90,6.99" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="2,455.33,685.67,88.44,6.99;2,325.35,696.30,118.39,6.99">Anserini: Reproducible Ranking Baselines Using Lucene</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="2,450.59,696.30,89.41,6.99">ACM J. Data Inf. Qual</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
