<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,149.33,166.48,294.65,18.14;1,261.15,199.92,71.01,8.74">Radboud University at TREC 2020 Notebook Paper</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,158.09,227.45,65.42,10.48"><forename type="first">Pepijn</forename><surname>Boers</surname></persName>
							<email>p.boers@cs.ru.nl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Arjen de Vries</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,259.27,227.45,83.04,10.48"><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Kamphuis</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Arjen de Vries</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,149.33,166.48,294.65,18.14;1,261.15,199.92,71.01,8.74">Radboud University at TREC 2020 Notebook Paper</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">316B86985C59859229590014D413BEF0</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:11+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The IR research group from the Radboud University (RUIR) has an interest in creating graph-based solutions for domain specific challenges. We aim to increase effectiveness by incorporating domain knowledge into graph development. This work was developed as part of a Master's thesis project about graph representations for news articles of TREC's background linking task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,431.69,352.52,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. The introduced work explores the use of named entities, novelty scores and diversification of background documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">News Track</head><p>During the revision of background linking methods in prior editions of the News track, we noticed that many participants approached the problem similarly. They extract keywords from the focus article and issue them as search request in a classic ad-hoc information retrieval system. Even though such an approach has yielded good results, we saw some caveats and were interested in exploring an alternative background linking model.</p><p>The first apparent weakness we observed was the lack of connectivity between search terms; a bag-of-words query does not give much insight into coherence of a news story and might form a too simplistic representation of a news article for the task of background linking. A second potential weakness might lie in the undue focus on content overlap. Most models use retrieval algorithms like BM25 that rank most overlapping documents highest. Considering the objective to expand a reader's understanding, the presence of new information inside news articles should be somehow rewarded.</p><p>ru graph For our first run we attempted to create a richer representation of news articles by connecting individual query terms in a weighted graph. Article terms were extracted based on their tf • idf score; the 100 highest scoring terms were selected as these have proven to be successful in earlier work <ref type="bibr" coords="1,422.46,658.34,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. Nodes were weighted based on an alternative form of the tf • idf score as found in the work by Zhang et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,220.03,128.96,9.96,8.74" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, see equations 1-3.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,216.93,149.38,251.59,117.17">tf td =                    1 + log(f td -1) n i=1 f id if f td &gt; 1 1 n i=1 f id if f td = 1 (1) idf tc = log( |c| -f tc + 0.5 f tc + 0.5 + 1)<label>(2)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,260.37,279.96,208.14,9.65">W td = tf td • idf tc<label>(3)</label></formula><p>Term frequency scores (tf td ) was obtained by taking the logarithm of the term's original frequency in the article and subsequently dividing that by the sum of all term frequencies in the document. The frequency of term t in document d is denoted by f td and the sum of other terms is denoted as v i=1 f id . The inverse document frequency (idf ) was based on the number of articles in corpus c (|c|) and the frequency of a term in the corpus f tc . Furthermore, work on the entity ranking task from last year <ref type="bibr" coords="2,397.64,369.62,12.35,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref> showed that the importance of an entity in an article correlated strongly with their position in a text; the earlier an entity is mentioned the more relevant it tends to be. Evaluation on 2019 topics showed that our graph method effectiveness increased when appending a text position score to our node weights. The position score was based on the index of a paragraph a node occurred in, see (4) for the full equation.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,230.14,472.68,238.37,22.31">W td = tf td • idf tc + 1 index(t, d)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>Nodes were connected using semantic features found in word embeddings. The connections were based on the distance between their vector representations as obtained from a large corpus. We used the Wikipedia word embeddings from Gerritse et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,193.01,538.50,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. The cosine similarity between two vectors determined the connection strength between nodes (Eq. 5).</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,256.16,586.32,208.11,9.65">W t1,t2 = cos( t 1 , t 2 ) (<label>5</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="2,464.27,586.32,4.24,8.74">)</formula><p>This run kept the widely used overlap criterion as a measure for article relevance, here translated into a variation of the Greatest Maximum Common Sub-graph <ref type="bibr" coords="2,124.80,628.16,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. A similarity score S gave an indication of the overlap between topic articles Q and candidate articles C by means of a common sub-graph G CS . The similarity score was calculated by summing the node and edge weights in the common sub-graph and dividing those with the maximum sum of node and edge weights respectively, see equation 6. Subsequently, the scores for node and edge similarity were scaled using hyper parameter λ (λ = 0.5 in our work).</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="3,124.80,171.30,354.37,57.24">sim(G Q , G C ) = λ ni∈G CS w ni max ni∈G Q w ni , ni∈G C w ni +(1-λ) ei∈G CS w ei max ei∈G Q w ei , ei∈G C w ei<label>(6)</label></formula><p>ru g ne In our second run we attempted to create an even richer representation of a news article by including named entities as additional graph nodes. These entities were retrieved using the Radboud Entity Linker (REL) <ref type="bibr" coords="3,413.46,279.58,10.52,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref> and were integrated in the existing graph.</p><p>ru g novelty Instead of recommending news articles that have the highest overlap with the focus article, we were interested to see how the rewarding of new information affected the background linking effectiveness. This run tested a method for the retrieval of articles with novel content, where we define novel content as the aggregation of nodes that possess an above average connection to the main story (common sub-graph). We presume that novel nodes contain concepts that are closely related to the main story, yet were not included in the focus article. We computed a novelty score per article by dividing the sum of novel weight by the sum of total weight. Since it remains important that articles cover the same subject matter, we used the harmonic mean of the similarity and novelty score to determine the rank of a candidate article.</p><p>ru g textrank Our fourth run experimented with a modified version of the TextRank algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="3,212.04,470.86,13.15,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref> that recalculated the graph's weights. We presumed that by obtaining new node weights based on the internal connections, we could obtain a more accurate representation of a news story. Node weights were updated following an iterative process in which the sum of all incoming nodes contributed to a node's new weight. The weights of the incoming nodes were normalized using the number of their outgoing connections. The process was stopped whenever the difference between old a new weight became too small (10 -5 ) or when the maximum number of iterations (1000) was reached. We used a damping coefficient of 0.85.</p><p>ru g diversity Our last submission focused on the diversification of recommended background articles. Since there are no clear guidelines on what is meant with diversity in the context of background linking, we came up with a basic definition using entity types. Many entity extraction models allow for the collection of entity types; these types show the category to which you can assign a specific entity. Examples are: Lionel Messi (Person), F.C. Barcelona (Organization), The Nou Camp (Location). We extracted the following entity types: Person, Organization, Location and Miscellaneous. Articles with a focus on Locations generally contain more location-type entities and could bring a different perspective to a story than person-focused articles. Therefore, we restructured our background recommendations by creating a top 4 with unique entity type majorities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ans bm25</head><p>In order to compare our graph methods with the earlier described bag-of-words approach, we collaborated with the Anserini team and used the Anserini software <ref type="bibr" coords="4,197.33,176.78,12.63,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref> to replicate three traditional runs. These runs were inspired by their work in 2018 and were similar to our work in 2019 <ref type="bibr" coords="4,390.32,188.73,10.52,8.74" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="4,404.50,188.73,7.01,8.74" target="#b3">4]</ref>. These runs used the BM25 framework to create an initial ranking using an article's top 100 tf • idf terms.</p><p>ans bm25 rm3 The previous run with RM3 reranking.</p><p>ans bm25 rm3 df Same as the previous run but documents that were published later than the focus article are filtered out. The assumption here is that articles that are published later than the focus article can not background knowledge. This does not necessarily have to be true following this track's guidelines.</p><p>fuse ru g ne ans bm25 rm3 We noticed that although ru graph and ru ans bm25 scored similarly on 2019 data, the top 5 documents often consisted of different documents. We found that when we interleaved the rankings of these 2 methods that the resulting ranked was significantly better on the 2019 data. This run was not submitted to TREC.</p><p>Note As a means to lower the high computation time that comes with the creation and comparison of graph methods, we assumed that the ans bm25 rm3 model (very effective in 2019) would retrieve all possibly relevant documents in its top 100. Therefore, our graph models only performed a re-ranking of those documents to create their top 5. The introduced graph models show similar effectiveness as the bag-of-words models, scoring slightly lower on the mean metric, but slightly better on the median. The only exception is the model with the appended named entities, which scored higher than two bag-of-words models. An overview is shown in table <ref type="table" coords="5,149.70,140.91,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. Again the fusion method seems to help, but the results are not significantly better on this year's data alone.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,178.59,534.53,232.81,137.73"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="4,178.59,534.53,232.81,137.73"><row><cell cols="3">: 2020 Results Background Linking Task</cell></row><row><cell>Model</cell><cell cols="2">NDCG@5 NDCG@10</cell></row><row><cell>ru graph</cell><cell>0.5194</cell><cell>0.5304</cell></row><row><cell>ru g ne</cell><cell>0.5380</cell><cell>0.5338</cell></row><row><cell>ru g novelty</cell><cell>0.5106</cell><cell>0.5301</cell></row><row><cell>ru g textrank</cell><cell>0.4874</cell><cell>0.5010</cell></row><row><cell>ru g diversity</cell><cell>0.4599</cell><cell>0.4391</cell></row><row><cell>ans bm25</cell><cell>0.5231</cell><cell>0.5105</cell></row><row><cell>ans bm25 rm3</cell><cell>0.5673</cell><cell>0.5596</cell></row><row><cell>ans bm25 rm3 df</cell><cell>0.5279</cell><cell>0.5053</cell></row><row><cell>fuse ru g ne ans bm25 rm3</cell><cell>0.5913</cell><cell>0.5776</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,140.30,207.63,328.21,9.30;5,140.30,219.59,262.08,8.74" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,190.18,207.63,273.85,8.74">Graph Representations of News Articles for Background Linking</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Boers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Radboud University, the Netherlands</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Master&apos;s thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,140.30,241.20,146.41,7.61;5,307.73,239.51,160.78,8.74;5,140.30,251.47,328.22,8.74;5,140.30,263.42,26.01,8.74" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,307.73,239.51,160.78,8.74;5,140.30,251.47,119.23,8.74">graph distance metric based on the maximal common subgraph</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Bunke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Shearer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,269.79,251.47,120.24,8.74">Pattern Recognition Letters</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="259" />
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,140.30,283.35,328.21,9.30;5,140.30,295.30,328.22,8.74;5,140.30,307.26,120.16,8.74" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,369.68,283.35,98.83,8.74;5,140.30,295.30,102.49,8.74">Graph-embedding empowered entity retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Gerritse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Hasibi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>De Vries</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,264.04,295.30,204.47,8.74;5,140.30,307.26,73.62,8.74">European Conference on Information Retrieval (2020), ECIR &apos;20</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,140.30,327.19,328.21,9.30;5,140.30,339.14,328.21,8.74;5,140.30,351.10,328.21,8.74;5,140.30,363.05,328.21,8.74;5,140.30,375.01,245.89,8.74" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,447.34,327.19,21.17,8.74;5,140.30,339.14,137.13,8.74">Radboud University at TREC 2019</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kamphuis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Hasibi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>De Vries</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Crijns</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,300.65,339.14,167.86,8.74;5,140.30,351.10,92.07,8.74">Proceedings of The Twenty-Eigth Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ellis</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>The Twenty-Eigth Text REtrieval Conference<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1250</biblScope>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>TREC</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,140.30,394.93,328.21,9.30;5,140.30,406.89,328.21,8.74;5,140.30,418.84,328.21,8.74;5,140.30,430.80,135.85,8.74" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,292.86,394.93,156.37,8.74">TextRank: Bringing order into text</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mihalcea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Tarau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,140.30,406.89,328.21,8.74;5,140.30,418.84,73.21,8.74">Proceedings of the 2004 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2004 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing<address><addrLine>Barcelona, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004-07">July 2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="404" to="411" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,140.30,452.41,328.21,7.61;5,140.30,462.68,328.21,9.30;5,140.30,474.63,328.21,8.74;5,140.30,486.59,328.22,8.74" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,218.13,462.68,246.30,8.74">REL: An entity linker standing on the shoulders of giants</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Van Hulst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Hasibi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Dercksen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Balog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Vries</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,154.04,474.63,314.47,8.74;5,140.30,486.59,214.46,8.74;5,392.53,486.59,42.64,8.74">Proceedings of the 43rd International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 43rd International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SIGIR &apos;20</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,140.30,506.51,328.21,9.30;5,140.30,518.47,328.22,8.74;5,140.30,530.42,328.22,8.74;5,140.30,542.38,328.22,8.74;5,140.30,554.33,110.17,8.74" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,350.75,506.51,117.76,8.74;5,140.30,518.47,143.37,8.74">Enabling the use of lucene for information retrieval research</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Anserini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,306.42,518.47,162.10,8.74;5,140.30,530.42,328.22,8.74;5,140.30,542.38,27.37,8.74;5,301.85,542.38,42.67,8.74">Proceedings of the 40th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 40th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1253" to="1256" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SIGIR &apos;17</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,140.30,574.26,328.21,9.30;5,140.30,586.21,328.22,8.74;5,140.30,598.17,328.21,8.74;5,140.30,610.12,328.22,8.74;5,140.30,622.08,185.50,8.74" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,255.88,574.26,212.63,8.74;5,140.30,586.21,67.70,8.74">Anserini at TREC 2018: Centre, common core, and news tracks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,227.93,586.21,240.59,8.74;5,140.30,598.17,29.07,8.74">Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ellis</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the Twenty-Seventh Text REtrieval Conference<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="500" to="331" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>NIST Special Publication, National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,140.30,642.00,328.22,9.30;5,140.30,653.96,328.22,8.74;5,140.30,665.92,328.21,8.74;5,140.30,677.87,71.40,8.74" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,352.83,642.00,115.69,8.74;5,140.30,653.96,74.33,8.74">A Graph Based Document Retrieval Method</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,225.80,653.96,242.72,8.74;5,140.30,665.92,259.35,8.74">Proceedings of the 2018 IEEE 22nd International Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work in Design</title>
		<meeting>the 2018 IEEE 22nd International Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work in Design</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2018</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="660" to="665" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
