<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,139.21,116.95,336.94,12.62;1,170.87,134.89,273.61,12.62;1,246.44,152.82,122.48,12.62">SBS 2016 : Combining Query Expansion Result and Books Information Score for Book Recommendation</title>
				<funder ref="#_aQSchpS">
					<orgName type="full">French program Investissements dAvenir Equipex &quot;A</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,196.43,190.86,48.29,8.74"><forename type="first">Amal</forename><surname>Htait</surname></persName>
							<email>amal.htait@univ-amu.fr</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,252.33,190.86,79.44,8.74"><forename type="first">Sébastien</forename><surname>Fournier</surname></persName>
							<email>sebatien.fournier@univ-amu.fr</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,358.85,190.86,60.08,8.74"><forename type="first">Patrice</forename><surname>Bellot</surname></persName>
							<email>patrice.bellot@univ-amu.fr</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">LSIS UMR 7296</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Aix Marseille Université</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">ENSAM</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">Toulon Université</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>13397</postCode>
									<settlement>Marseille</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Aix-Marseille Université</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">CLEO OpenEdition UMS</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>3287</addrLine>
									<postCode>13451</postCode>
									<settlement>Marseille</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,139.21,116.95,336.94,12.62;1,170.87,134.89,273.61,12.62;1,246.44,152.82,122.48,12.62">SBS 2016 : Combining Query Expansion Result and Books Information Score for Book Recommendation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">84BA4B785FCCCCFAD0DD46AAB594C38A</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:46+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Social Information Retrieval</term>
					<term>Recommendation</term>
					<term>Sequential Dependence Model</term>
					<term>Expand Query</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper, we present our contribution in Suggestion Track at the Social Book Search Lab. This track aims to develop test collections for evaluating ranking effectiveness of book retrieval and recommender systems. In our experiments, we combine the results of Sequential Dependence Model (SDM) and the books information that includes the price, the number Of P ages and the publication Date. We also expand topics' queries by the similar books information to improve the recommendation performance.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The Social Book Search (SBS) Tracks <ref type="bibr" coords="1,300.40,470.33,10.52,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref> were introduced by INEX in 2010 with evaluation purposes for supporting users in searching collections of books based on book metadata and associated user-generated content.</p><p>Social Book Search Lab includes the following tracks: Suggestion Track, Interactive Track and Mining Track. Our work is on Suggestion Track, which suggests a list of the most relevant books according to the request provided by the user. Since 2011, for the social books search task, the document provided is a collection of 2.8 million records containing professional metadata (Amazon 1 ) extended with user-generated content and social metadata (LibraryThing 2 ). In addition, a set of 113,490 anonymous users profiles is provided from LibraryThing (LT). Therefore, Information Retrieval (IR) Systems must search through editorial data, user reviews and ratings for each book, instead of searching through the whole content of the book. The topics provided each year are extracted from the LibraryThing forums and by represent real requests from real users.</p><p>Our participation in 2011 and 2012 was based on re-ranking books using social component such as popularity and ratings <ref type="bibr" coords="2,351.15,131.95,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" coords="2,364.43,131.95,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. On 2014, we were able to achieve the second best run using InL2 model implemented in Terrier<ref type="foot" coords="2,462.84,142.33,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">3</ref>  <ref type="bibr" coords="2,467.31,143.90,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. And for 2015 participation, we combined results of InL2 and Sequential Dependence Model (SDM). Also, we integrated tools from natural language processing (NLP) and approaches based on graph analysis to improve the recommendation performance <ref type="bibr" coords="2,183.92,191.72,13.41,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. This year's participation is through an IR system based on 3 main steps:</p><p>-We expand the topic queries using the similar books information, since the topics contain books titles mentioned by the user as similar or example books to those he seeks. -We apply a re-ranking method using a score calculated of books information including the price, the number Of P ages and the publication Date. -We apply these methods on Amazon book collection and on the users profiles collection.</p><p>For our participation in SBS 2016, we submitted 4 runs in which we applied the previously mentioned steps. The rest of this paper is organized as follows.</p><p>The following section describes the data processing and indexing. In section 3, we have the description of our retrieval framework. In section 4, we describe the submitted runs. Finally, we present the obtained results in section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Data processing and indexing</head><p>We use, in addition to the Amazon book Collection, the users profiles Collection provided by SBS Lab track which contains the cataloguing transactions of 113,490 users. The cataloguing transactions of a user is a list of information concerning the books read by the user. Each transaction is represented by a row, where each row contains eight columns; user, book, author, book title, publication year, month in which the user added that book, rating and a set of tags assigned by this user to this book. From the users profiles, we create for each book an XML file with all its information. An example is illustrated in the following XML code of Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,268.73,558.70,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_0">1</ref>.</p><p>For indexing the Amazon book collection, we take all the tags of the XML files identified by the ISBNs. And for indexing users profiles collection, we take all the tags of the created XML files identified by the LibraryThingID. Also, we use the following Indri<ref type="foot" coords="2,230.70,607.15,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_1">4</ref> indexing parameters: P orter Stemmer and Stop W ords Removal. 3 Retrieval Model</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Query Expansion by example books information</head><p>To build our queries we use mainly the title of the query and the information of similar example books mentioned by the user in the topic. Also, we use the tags of these similar books extracted from the users profiles collection for query expansion. The XML code in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,298.20,404.08,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_1">2</ref> illustrates an example of adding similar book tags for query expansion. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Sequential Dependence Model</head><p>SDM relies on the idea of integrating multi word phrases by considering a combination of query terms with proximity constraints such as: single term features (standard unigram language model features, f T ), exact phrase features (words appearing in sequence, f O ) and unordered window features (require words to be close together, but not necessarily in an exact sequence order, f U ) <ref type="bibr" coords="4,418.65,195.91,9.96,8.74" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. In Table <ref type="table" coords="4,472.84,195.91,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, more details about the term weighting functions are shown, where tf e,D is the number of times term e matches in document D, cf e,D is the number of times term e matches in the entire collection, |D| is the length of document D, and |C| is the size of the collection. Finally, µ is a weighting function hyperparameter that is set in our work to 2500 <ref type="bibr" coords="4,271.09,255.68,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. </p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="4,142.99,347.36,327.02,67.42">in document D. fO(qi, qi+1, D) = log tf #1(q i ,q i+1 ),D +µ cf #1(q i ,q i+1 ) |C| |D|+µ Weight of exact phrase 'qi qi+1' in document D. fU (qi, qi+1, D) = log tf #uw8(q i ,q i+1 ),D +µ cf #uw8(q i ,q i+1 ) |C| |D|+µ</formula><p>Weight of unordered window 'qi qi+1' (span=8) in document D.</p><p>And the documents are ranked according to the below scoring equation, Equation <ref type="formula" coords="4,177.80,491.94,3.87,8.74" target="#formula_1">1</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="4,216.35,519.80,264.25,63.47">SDM (Q, D) = λ T q∈Q f T (q, D) +λ O |Q|-1 i=1 f O (q i , q i + 1, D) +λ U |Q|-1 i=1 f U (q i , q i + 1, D)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>We used the Equation 1 with feature weights set to λ T = 0.85, λ O = 0.1 and λ U = 0.05, like previous participation years. We applied this model to the queries using Indri 5.4 4 Query Language<ref type="foot" coords="4,284.80,618.47,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_2">5</ref> . An example of Indri Query Language is in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,166.20,632.00,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_2">3</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Combination of Retrieval System output and books' information</head><p>We combine the results of SDM model with a sum of normalized scores, which we calculate from the book's price, publication Date and number Of P ages. And since the combined values are of different weighting, we use the maximum and minimum scores according to Lees formula <ref type="bibr" coords="5,343.54,284.70,10.52,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref> as followed in Equation <ref type="formula" coords="5,462.73,284.70,3.87,8.74" target="#formula_2">2</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="5,211.42,308.50,269.17,22.31">normalizedScore = oldScore -minScore maxScore -minScore<label>(2)</label></formula><p>The scores of SDM model and books information have different levels of retrieval effectiveness, thus it is necessary to weigh scores depending on their overall performance. We used an interpolation parameter (α) that varies in testing for the goal of achieving the best interpolation that provides better retrieval effectiveness, as shown in the Equation <ref type="formula" coords="5,308.08,388.55,3.87,8.74" target="#formula_3">3</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="5,174.04,416.39,306.55,8.74">SDM bookInf o = α.(SDM (Q, D)) + (1 -α).(bookInf o(D))<label>(3)</label></formula><p>After several testings on 2015 SBS topics<ref type="foot" coords="5,337.69,436.68,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_3">6</ref> , α is set to 0.55 with the best result. bookInf o(D) is calculated by a normalized score of the values of price only, since the price alone obtains the best result on 2015 SBS topics compared to the values of price, publication Date and number Of P ages combined. In Table <ref type="table" coords="5,162.59,486.08,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref>, an example of our tests showing a modest but still an increase in the results when combining books prices to the equation with α = 0.55. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Runs</head><p>We submit 4 runs for the SBS Suggestion Track: Run1 ExeOrNarrativeNSW Collection: We concatenate the title of the topic and the similar books fields (title, author and tags), then perform a retrieval using the SDM model. But since not all topics have example books, in this case we concatenate the title and the narrative fields of the topic after removing the Stop W ords from the narrative field. This run is applied on Amazon book collection.</p><p>Run2 ExeOrNarrativeNSW UserProfile : This run is same as Run1 but it is applied on users profiles collection.</p><p>Run3 ExeOrNarrativeNSW Collection AddData : In this run, we combine the books price normalized score to the results of Run1. Run4 ExeOrNarrativeNSW UserProfile AddData : Also in this run, we combine the books price normalized score to the results of Run2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Results</head><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="6,163.11,382.69,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_2">3</ref> shows 2016 official SBS Suggestion Track results for our 4 runs. Our models presented this year show differences in results. The use of retrieval SDM model alone gave the best results between our runs. The use of users profiles file and the combination of books information with the SDM scores decreases the results.</p><p>We should mention that we tested our methods with the topics of SBS 2015, which had a field named mediated query containing the key words of the user's request. Since this field is not in the topics of SBS 2016, we used the field narrative and that caused a massive amount of noise in the query. This can also explain the bad results of using users profiles collection, since it's difficult to find similarity between the query with noise and the limited information in the users profiles collection. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we present our contribution for the Suggestion Track of Social Book Search Lab. In the 4 submit runs, we use SDM retrieval model and we extend the query by the similar books information (title, author and tags). We apply the retrieval on Amazon book collection, and on users profiles collection. We combine the results of the retrieval system (SDM) with the normalized score of the books prices. The best result is achieved by using SDM retrieval model with the extended query on Amazon book Collection. We should note that the topics of SBS 2015 had a field named mediated query, which contained the key words of the user's request (from field narrative). The mediated q uery field is used in our testing on SBS 2015 topics and helped to increase the results. But since this field is not in the topics of SBS 2016, we had to use the narrative field which contains many useless information that effect negatively the information research. Thus, to increase the results for future participation, we must work on extracting only the key words from the narrative field to be used in the query, and eliminate any noise information.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,170.02,287.51,275.32,7.89;3,134.77,116.83,346.36,155.91"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. An example of book XML files from users profiles collection.</figDesc><graphic coords="3,134.77,116.83,346.36,155.91" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,134.77,632.82,345.83,7.89;3,134.77,447.97,376.92,170.08"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. An example of adding similar book tags for query expansion from Topics 2015.</figDesc><graphic coords="3,134.77,447.97,376.92,170.08" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="5,236.63,188.30,142.11,7.89;5,134.77,116.83,382.46,56.69"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3. An example of Indri Query.</figDesc><graphic coords="5,134.77,116.83,382.46,56.69" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,139.92,291.50,326.25,50.00"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Language modeling-based unigram and term weighting functions<ref type="bibr" coords="4,453.88,291.53,9.22,7.86" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</figDesc><table coords="4,139.92,312.80,278.20,26.24"><row><cell>Weighting</cell><cell></cell><cell>Description</cell></row><row><cell>fT (qi, D) = log</cell><cell>tf qi,D +µ</cell><cell>cf qi |C|</cell></row></table><note coords="4,223.12,336.26,20.77,5.24;4,372.10,331.18,85.13,7.86"><p><p>|D|+µ</p>Weight of unigram qi</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,191.98,531.50,231.40,86.25"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results of testing applied on SBS 2015 Topics.</figDesc><table coords="5,191.98,552.27,231.40,65.47"><row><cell>Method</cell><cell cols="3">nDCG10 Recip Rank MAP</cell></row><row><cell>SDM(Q, D)</cell><cell>0.1278</cell><cell>0.1231</cell><cell>0.0431</cell></row><row><cell>SDM bookInfo all</cell><cell>0.1251</cell><cell>0.1229</cell><cell>0.0407</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">SDM bookInfo price 0.4 0.1275</cell><cell>0.1237</cell><cell>0.0427</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">SDM bookInfo price 0.6 0.1267</cell><cell>0.1207</cell><cell>0.0433</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">SDM bookInfo price 0.55 0.129</cell><cell>0.1266</cell><cell>0.0428</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="6,137.13,551.21,341.09,86.25"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Official results at SBS 2016. The runs are ranked according to nDCG@10.</figDesc><table coords="6,137.34,571.98,340.68,65.47"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell cols="3">nDCG10 Recip Rank MAP R1000</cell></row><row><cell>Best Run 2016</cell><cell>0.2157</cell><cell>0.5247</cell><cell>0.1253 0.3474</cell></row><row><cell>Run1 ExeOrNarrNSW Collection</cell><cell>0.0450</cell><cell>0.1166</cell><cell>0.0251 0.2050</cell></row><row><cell>Run2 ExeOrNarrNSW UserProfile</cell><cell>0.0239</cell><cell>0.1018</cell><cell>0.0144 0.1742</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Run3 ExeOrNarrNSW Collection AddData 0.0177</cell><cell>0.0533</cell><cell>0.0101 0.2050</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Run4 ExeOrNarrNSW UserProfile AddData 0.0152</cell><cell>0.0566</cell><cell>0.0079 0.1742</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,144.73,646.84,71.00,7.86"><p>hhtp://terrier.org</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,144.73,657.79,146.26,7.86"><p>http://www.lemurproject.org/indri/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5" xml:id="foot_2" coords="4,144.73,657.79,251.13,7.86"><p>http://www.lemurproject.org/lemur/IndriQueryLanguage.php</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6" xml:id="foot_3" coords="5,144.73,657.79,256.27,7.86"><p>http://social-book-search.humanities.uva.nl/#/data/suggestion</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>Acknowledgments. This work was supported by the <rs type="funder">French program Investissements dAvenir Equipex "A</rs> <rs type="programName">digital library for open humanities</rs>" of OpenEdition.org.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_aQSchpS">
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">digital library for open humanities</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,409.60,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,420.56,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,431.52,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,442.48,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,453.44,20.99,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,146.91,420.56,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,431.52,11.14,7.86">Overview of the inex 2010 book track: Scaling up the evaluation using crowdsourcing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gabriella</forename><surname>Kazai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Marijn</forename><surname>Koolen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jaap</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Antoine</forename><surname>Doucet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Monica</forename><surname>Landoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="s" coord="7,240.52,442.48,142.22,7.86">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shlomo</forename><surname>Geva</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jaap</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ralf</forename><surname>Schenkel</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Trotman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6932</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">98117</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,463.75,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,474.71,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,485.67,45.05,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,316.30,463.75,164.29,7.86;7,146.91,474.71,94.89,7.86">Social recommendation and external resources for book search</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Deveaud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sanjuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bellot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,249.67,474.71,173.36,7.86">Working Notes for CLEF 2011 Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">7424. 2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">6879</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,495.99,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,506.94,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,517.90,219.82,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,374.84,495.99,105.75,7.86;7,146.91,506.94,48.68,7.86">Do social information help book search?</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ludovic</forename><surname>Bonnefoy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Romain</forename><surname>Deveaud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Patrice</forename><surname>Bellot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,146.91,517.90,191.12,7.86">CLEF (Online Working Notes/Labs/Workshop)</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pamela</forename><surname>Forner</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jussi</forename><surname>Karlgren</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christa</forename><surname>Womser-Hacker</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,528.22,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,539.18,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,550.14,61.43,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,426.56,528.22,54.04,7.86;7,146.91,539.18,146.37,7.86">Collaborative Filtering for Book Recommendation</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Benkoussas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Hamdan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Albitar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ollagnier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bellot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,302.20,539.18,174.14,7.86">Working Notes for CLEF 2014 Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">501507</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,560.45,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,571.41,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,582.37,54.55,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,323.39,560.45,157.20,7.86;7,146.91,571.41,177.73,7.86">Book Recommendation Using Information Retrieval Methods and Graph Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Benkoussas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ollagnier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bellot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,332.26,571.41,103.32,7.86">Working Notes for CLEF</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015. 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Conference</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,592.68,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,603.64,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,614.60,266.15,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,303.27,592.68,177.32,7.86;7,146.91,603.64,41.71,7.86">A markov random field model for term dependencies</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Donald</forename><surname>Metzler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">Bruce</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,274.85,614.60,23.62,7.86">SIGIR</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ricardo</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Baeza-Yates</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nivio</forename><surname>Ziviani</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gary</forename><surname>Marchionini</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alistair</forename><surname>Moffat</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Tait</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">472479</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,138.35,624.92,342.24,7.86;7,146.91,635.88,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,646.84,333.68,7.86;7,146.91,657.79,137.98,7.86" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,205.47,624.92,275.12,7.86;7,146.91,635.88,30.33,7.86">Combining multiple evidence from different properties of weighting schemes</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Joon</forename><surname>Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lee</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,196.24,635.88,284.36,7.86;7,146.91,646.84,270.08,7.86">Proceedings of the 18th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval, SIGIR 95</title>
		<meeting>the 18th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval, SIGIR 95<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">180188</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,120.67,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,131.63,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,142.59,246.29,7.86" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,323.39,120.67,157.20,7.86;8,146.91,131.63,178.49,7.86">Book Recommendation Using Information Retrieval Methods and Graph Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Benkoussas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ollagnier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bellot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,333.17,131.63,147.42,7.86;8,146.91,142.59,86.35,7.86">CLEF 2015 Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Toulouse (France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-09">sep 2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">8</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
