<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,146.25,116.95,322.85,12.62;1,170.82,134.89,273.71,12.62">USTB at Social Book Search 2016 Suggestion Task: Active Books Set and Reranking</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,140.53,173.13,62.16,8.74"><forename type="first">Shao-Hui</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
							<email>shaohui_feng@xs.ustb.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Science and Technology Beijing (USTB)</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100083</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,210.68,173.13,62.96,8.74"><forename type="first">Bo-Wen</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<email>bowenzhang@xs.ustb.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Science and Technology Beijing (USTB)</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100083</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,286.92,173.13,50.62,8.74"><forename type="first">Zan-Xia</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Science and Technology Beijing (USTB)</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100083</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,344.90,173.13,61.43,8.74"><forename type="first">Xu-Cheng</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
							<email>xuchengyin@ustb.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Science and Technology Beijing (USTB)</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100083</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,419.07,173.13,51.71,8.74"><forename type="first">Jian-Lin</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Science and Technology Beijing (USTB)</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100083</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,159.62,185.08,53.46,8.74"><forename type="first">Jian-Wei</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Science and Technology Beijing (USTB)</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100083</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,222.30,185.08,52.85,8.74"><forename type="first">Le-Le</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Science and Technology Beijing (USTB)</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100083</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,283.47,185.08,51.23,8.74"><forename type="first">Hao-Jie</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Science and Technology Beijing (USTB)</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100083</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,342.96,185.08,38.66,8.74"><forename type="first">Fan</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Science and Technology Beijing (USTB)</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100083</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,409.11,185.08,46.63,8.74"><forename type="first">Fang</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Science and Technology Beijing (USTB)</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100083</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,146.25,116.95,322.85,12.62;1,170.82,134.89,273.71,12.62">USTB at Social Book Search 2016 Suggestion Task: Active Books Set and Reranking</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">984D6F440207423F77F83D68967807C5</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:46+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>XML retrieval</term>
					<term>key query</term>
					<term>re-ranking</term>
					<term>active books set</term>
					<term>popularity</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper, we describe our participation in the Social Book Search(SBS) Suggestion Task. We developed some new re-ranking models, based on what we applied in last year. We used Galago search from the index which was built with active books. The queries input to search engine were composed by key words from topics, and then we performed re-ranking models(popularity related) on Galago searching results on enriched XML index by 14 different fields. Experiments on these approaches shown that an enriched index and key query model improves the effectiveness. As our approaches in INEX2014 [1],SBS2015 [2] and combined those re-ranking models according to a specific order shown the best performance.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In this paper, we describe our participation in the Social Book Search 2016 suggestion task. Our goals for this task were <ref type="bibr" coords="1,324.99,513.08,12.73,8.74" target="#b0">(1)</ref> to investigate the contribution of key words from topics in searching; <ref type="bibr" coords="1,287.58,525.03,12.73,8.74" target="#b1">(2)</ref> to testify the active books set functioning in searching <ref type="bibr" coords="1,190.50,536.99,12.95,8.74" target="#b2">(3)</ref>to testify the effect of popularity related re-ranking approaches <ref type="bibr" coords="1,134.77,548.94,12.73,8.74" target="#b3">(4)</ref> to find an effective approach to combine the results of different re-ranking models.</p><p>The structure of this paper is as follows. We start Section 2 by describing our methodology: pre-processing on the XML formatted documents, indexing, searching by Galago, introduction of key query and active books set. In the section 3,we describe the re-ranking models and the re-ranking models experiments. In section 4, we describe the results of our enriched index, key query model, active books set and re-ranking models. Section 5 describes about the runs which we submitted,with the results of those runs presented. We discuss our results and conclude in Section 6.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Methodology</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Data Pre-Processing</head><p>We perform a process similar to <ref type="bibr" coords="2,279.60,165.36,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, such as expand and enrich the documents XML with replacing the numeric information with textual information. For instance:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,238.05,209.81,139.27,8.74">&lt;tag count="3"&gt;fiction&lt;/tag&gt;</formula><p>We change it to &lt;tag&gt;fiction fiction fiction&lt;/tag&gt;.</p><p>In addition, this time we expand to 14 fields when we clean the XML documents, it is different from last year. They are title, isbn, tags, review -content, review -summary, dewey, f irstwords, lastwords, chracters,places, subjects, browsenodes, abstract, addcontent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Indexing</head><p>Galago<ref type="foot" coords="2,169.74,357.06,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref> is an open-source search engine. In order to improve the search effectiveness, we study two strategies to build the index. One indexing strategy is the normal indexing approach described as follows. Experimentally, we find that the fields (etc. the title, tag, content and summary) are more relevant and meaningful than others in the XML formatted documents. So we build our basic index by removing the other fields which were not useful. Another strategy is to enrich the basic index. Observing the book information from the Library Thing, we find out that a large proportion of books lack the content and summary fields. Therefore, documents expansion technology is expected to utilized to enrich the basic index. Firstly, we select two web sites which contain a large amount of more useful metadata of books. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Generate Keywords from queries</head><p>We collect all the topics from 2011 to 2015. Our purpose is to get the best evaluation results after a great quantity of attempts. So that we can get the best queries for these topics, then we summed up a word list for topic queries. In Social Book Search 2016, we used the word list to filter the request field, then combine it with the title field compose the queries for Galago.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Active subset in book collections</head><p>Through the analysis of the profile, we select a subset of high frequent books which is called active book set. In this set, all the books are considered much more should be recommended to the topic author. We filter out all the books which are not in the active set. The operation is similar to filter the catalog and example books of the topic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Re-ranking Models</head><p>Some of the re-ranking approaches were proposed and used by USTB at INEX2014 <ref type="bibr" coords="3,184.34,464.09,10.52,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref> and proposed by Toine Bogers in 2012 <ref type="bibr" coords="3,376.66,464.09,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, which proved to be effective. This year our re-rank approach can be roughly divided into two categories 1) Tag-Rerank (T), similar product re-rank (S), Read by one re-rank (R) 2) popularity re-rank (P ), example recommended re-rank (E), Reader number re-rank (R), Browsnodes re-ranking(B). The first category was based on computing the similarity of two books that from the original result from Galago. The second category was based on attributes (number of readers, popularity) of the books or the example books of the topics.</p><p>We use these models to re-rank by the following stages: 1)Similarity Calculation. Models like T , N focus on the field &lt;tag&gt; and &lt;BrowseNode&gt;. We can build a feature matrix for features for each field. Equation (1) is used to calculate the T , N , T N similarities of two documents.</p><p>Features like I focus on the field &lt;similar-product&gt;, the similarities of two documents based on the feature I is calculated by the Equation <ref type="bibr" coords="3,416.45,619.50,11.62,8.74" target="#b1">(2)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,229.56,636.11,251.03,32.79">sim ij (f ) = cos &lt; - → f i , - → f j &gt;= - → f i • - → f j | - → f i || - → f j |<label>(1)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="4,172.16,128.14,58.91,69.14">sim ij (I) =               </formula><p>1, i is j's similar product or j is i's similar product 0.5, i is j's similar product's similar product or j is i's similar product's similar product 0, else</p><p>2)Re-ranking</p><p>First category rerank We re-rank the top 1000 list of initial ranking for the above-mentioned features by Equation (3). For feature R, we use Equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="4,472.10,252.01,4.24,8.74">4</ref>) <ref type="bibr" coords="4,134.77,263.97,10.52,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref> and for B, we use Equation <ref type="bibr" coords="4,272.28,263.97,11.62,8.74" target="#b4">(5)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="4,177.14,285.72,303.45,30.32">score (i) = α • score(i) + (1 -α) • N j=1 sim ij • score(j)(j = i)<label>(3)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="4,139.75,340.88,340.85,23.44">score (i) = α•score(i)+(1-α)×log(|reviews(i)|)× r∈Ri r |reviews(i)| ×score(i) (4)</formula><p>where R i is the set of all ratings given by users for the document i, and |reviews(i)| is the number of reviews.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="4,181.57,407.90,299.02,23.22">score (i) = α • score(i) + (1 -α) × 1 + BA(i) 1 + BA max × score(i)<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where BA(i) is the Bayesian average rating of document i, which can be referred to <ref type="bibr" coords="4,142.14,453.85,11.07,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p><p>In addition, Tag re-rank and read by one re-rank (we hold the opinion that if two books are read by same reader, they are related) are very similar to similar product re-rank.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Second category reranking</head><p>Popularity re-rank approach We got a data set from Library Thing like this: W ork id i , popularity i When we input initial search result to this model, we will change the works score by equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="4,218.51,634.70,4.24,8.74" target="#formula_7">6</ref>)</p><formula xml:id="formula_7" coords="4,167.05,657.11,313.54,10.62">score i = α * score i + (1 -α) * score i * (1 -popularity/30, 0000)<label>(6)</label></formula><p>As shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,229.25,119.99,3.87,8.74">1</ref>, the best performance is obtained from Initial+keywords+ allReRank + f iltercatalogandexampl ,and active, readernumber make greater contributions to the improvements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Submitted Runs</head><p>We selected six automatic runs for submission to SBS2016 based on our Key Query and re-ranking Models. They are:</p><p>run1. This run was made by a searching-re-ranking process where the initial retrieval result was based on the selection of query keywords and a small index of active books, the re-ranking results based on a combination of several strategies (number of people who read the book from profile, similar-product from amazon.com, popularity from LT forum, etc.).</p><p>run2. This run was made by a searching-reranking process where the initial retrieval result was based on the selection of query keywords and a small index of active books, the re-ranking results based on number of people who read the book from profile.</p><p>run3. This run was made by a searching-reranking process where the initial retrieval result was based on the selection of query keywords and a small index of active books, the re-ranking results based on the books in a same user's profile.</p><p>Run4. This run was made by a searching-reranking process where the initial retrieval result was based on the selection of query keywords and a small index of active books, the re-ranking results based on similar products provided by amazon.</p><p>run5. This run was made by a searching-reranking process where the initial retrieval result was based on the selection of query keywords and the full index filtered by active books, the re-ranking results based on the books in a same user's profile.</p><p>run6. This run was made by a searching-reranking process where the initial retrieval result was based on the selection of query keywords and the full index filtered by active books, the re-ranking results based on a combination of several strategies (number of people who read the book from profile, similar-product from amazon.com, popularity from LT forum, etc.).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Result</head><p>The runs submitted to the Social Book Search 2016 were evaluated using graded relevance judgments. The relevance value were labeled manually according to the behaviors of topic creators, for example, if creator adds book to catalogue after it's suggested, the book is treated as highly relevant. A decision tree was built to help the labeling 3. All runs were evaluated using NDCG@10, MRR, MAP, R@1000 with NDCG@10 as the main metric. Table <ref type="table" coords="6,396.48,633.20,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref> shows the official evaluation results. Results of the six submitted runs on Social Book Search 2016, evaluated using all 120 topics with relevance value calculated from the decision tree. The best run scores are printed in bold, we got the first place in the competition. In addition, all the results we submitted are in the top six.</p><p>So we got the first place in the Social Book Search suggestion task 2016. It necessary to state that run 7, run 8 and run 9 are our additional experiments, obvious we can find that key query and active books set have a great increase in results .Key query improve Initial+stopwords run by about 25 percent, then active books set improves the Initial+keyQuery run by about 24 percent.We see that the best-performing run on all 120 topics was run1 with an NDCG@10 of 0.2157. Run 1 used Key Query, small index built by active books and all re-ranking models combine. Also we see that re-ranking model does improve over the initial results by Galago searching engine.</p><p>All the runs from 1 to 6 were filtered by the topics catalog books set and example books set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Discussion &amp; Conclusion</head><p>All of the re-ranking approaches can improve the evaluation results, the best results are from combined all re-ranking approaches. Of course, the use of key queries and active book set make the greatest contributions to the effectiveness of our systems.</p><p>This year, we used much information from profile, and we got a better performance, but we failed to make use of the random forest to combine the re-ranking to improve the result. We keep the opinion that machine learning can get a better results. So, it is worth discussing how to combining the re-ranking results with machine learning algorithms.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="7,134.77,180.19,347.74,167.68"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results of the five submitted runs on Social Book Search 2016, evaluate using all 120 topics with relevance value calculated from the decision tree.</figDesc><table coords="7,444.33,191.18,36.27,7.86"><row><cell>The best</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,144.73,647.48,131.81,7.47"><p>http://www.galagosearch.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,144.73,658.44,108.27,7.47"><p>http://book.douban.com/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Just as what we see, popularity is the number from the set, score is from Galago search result, score is the final output score from this re-rank modes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Example recommended reranking approaches</head><p>Through summarizing the information from the profile, we got a example recommended list for some topics like this format:</p><p>T opic id i recommended 1 , recommended 2 , recommended 3 , etc.</p><p>When using the re-ranking approach, if a work of the result is contained in the topics list. We would change it rate by the equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="5,385.72,234.83,4.24,8.74">7</ref>)</p><p>if the work in the result was not contained in the topic id 's list, α = 0.</p><p>Reader number re-ranking approach We extracted information from the profile, then we got a set which showing the workss reader number.Like this:</p><p>reader number i Through this approach, we optimize the search result by the below equation( <ref type="formula" coords="5,471.39,362.34,4.55,8.74">8</ref>)</p><p>3) Combining. We applied these approaches on the key query search result according to a specific order, then got the final result.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Re-Ranking Models Experiments</head><p>In order to choose the most effective feature and select the optimized parameter, in the first round, we trained our re-ranking models on SBS2015. The results were shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,258.69,497.28,3.87,8.74">1</ref>. </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,143.58,342.25,7.86;8,146.91,154.54,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,165.50,211.66,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,268.74,154.54,195.01,7.86">USTB at INEX2014: Social Book Search Track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bo-Wen</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Xu-Cheng</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Xiao-Ping</forename><surname>Cui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bin</forename><surname>Geng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jiao</forename><surname>Qu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Fang</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hong-Wei</forename><surname>Hao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,146.91,165.50,143.97,7.86">INEX&apos;13 Workshop Pre-proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,176.46,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,187.42,184.29,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,146.91,176.46,329.28,7.86">Working Notes of CLEF 2015 -Conference and Labs of the Evaluation forum</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Toulouse, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">September 8-11, 2015. 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,198.38,342.25,7.86;8,146.91,209.34,173.39,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,252.23,198.38,174.61,7.86">Rslis at inex 2013: Social book search track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Larsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,445.40,198.38,35.19,7.86;8,146.91,209.34,105.70,7.86">INEX&apos;13 Workshop Pre-proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,220.30,342.25,7.86;8,146.91,231.26,230.27,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,252.23,220.30,174.61,7.86">Rslis at inex 2012: Social book search track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Larsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,445.40,220.30,35.19,7.86;8,146.91,231.26,105.70,7.86">INEX&apos;12 Workshop Pre-proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="108" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,242.21,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,253.17,333.68,7.86;8,146.91,264.13,107.33,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,250.84,253.17,229.75,7.86;8,146.91,264.13,60.61,7.86">Social Book Search Reranking with Generalized Content-Based Filtering</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bo-Wen</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Xu-Cheng</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Xiao-Ping</forename><surname>Cui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bin</forename><surname>Geng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jiao</forename><surname>Qu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Fang</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hong-Wei</forename><surname>Hao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,214.31,264.13,34.94,7.86">CIKM&apos;14</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,275.09,342.24,7.86;8,146.91,286.05,273.15,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,306.61,275.09,162.40,7.86">Do social information help book search?</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Bonnefoy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bellot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,146.91,286.05,143.97,7.86">INEX&apos;12 Workshop Pre-proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="113" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,138.35,297.01,342.25,7.86;8,146.91,307.97,253.71,7.86" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,278.79,297.01,201.81,7.86;8,146.91,307.97,23.54,7.86">Comparing topic representations for social book search</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Marijn</forename><surname>Koolen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,188.97,307.97,143.96,7.86">INEX&apos;13 Workshop Pre-proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
