<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,145.02,152.87,305.16,12.58;1,220.02,170.87,155.13,12.58">Verbose Query Reduction by Learning to Rank for Social Book Search Track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,183.48,210.24,71.46,9.02"><forename type="first">Messaoud</forename><surname>Chaa</surname></persName>
							<email>mchaa@cerist.dz</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Research Center on Scientific and Technical Information</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>05 rue des 03 frères Aissou, Ben Aknoun</addrLine>
									<postCode>16030</postCode>
									<settlement>Alger</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Université Abderrahmane Mira Béjaia Rue Targa Ouzemour</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>6000</postCode>
									<settlement>Béjaïa</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,268.03,210.24,63.56,9.02"><forename type="first">Omar</forename><surname>Nouali</surname></persName>
							<email>onouali@cerist.dz</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Research Center on Scientific and Technical Information</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>05 rue des 03 frères Aissou, Ben Aknoun</addrLine>
									<postCode>16030</postCode>
									<settlement>Alger</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,339.88,210.24,68.63,9.02"><forename type="first">Patrice</forename><surname>Bellot</surname></persName>
							<email>patrice.bellot@lsis.org</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">LSIS UMR 7296</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Aix-Marseille Université</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CNRS</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>13397</postCode>
									<settlement>Marseille</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,145.02,152.87,305.16,12.58;1,220.02,170.87,155.13,12.58">Verbose Query Reduction by Learning to Rank for Social Book Search Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">A12F2966D033F099376E0AA908AC5BB1</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:46+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Learning to rank</term>
					<term>verbose query reduction</term>
					<term>Social Book Search</term>
					<term>query term weighting</term>
					<term>BM15</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper, we describe our participation in the INEX 2016 Social  Book Search Suggestion Track (SBS). We have exploited machine learning techniques to rank query terms and assign an appropriate weight to each one before applying a probabilistic information retrieval model (BM15). Thereafter, only the top-k terms are used in the matching model. Several features are used to describe each term, such as statistical features, syntactic features and others features like whether the term is present in similar books and in the profile of the topic starter. The model was learned using the 2014 and 2015 topics and tested with the 2016 topics. Our experiments show that our approach improves the search results.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The goal of the Social Book Search Track is to adapt the traditional models of information retrieval (IR) and develop new models to support users in searching for books in LibraryThing (LT). The collection of this task consists of 2.8 million records containing both professional metadata from Amazon, extended with user-generated content, reviews form Amazon and tags from LT <ref type="bibr" coords="1,314.70,561.72,10.64,9.02" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. To evaluate systems submitted by participants at the SBS task, a set of topics have been made available which combine a natural language description of the user needs, as well as similar books of his/her topic.</p><p>The verbose natural language description of the topic in SBS made the understanding of the users' information need a very difficult task and can cause a topic drift as well as search engine performs poorly.</p><p>In this paper, we focus on query reduction and query term weighting <ref type="bibr" coords="1,409.62,654.24,10.84,9.02" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,423.60,654.24,7.53,9.02" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,434.27,654.24,8.36,9.02" target="#b6">7]</ref> to improve the performance of search engine by rewriting the original verbose query into a short query that the search engines perform better with. Explicitly, instead of search-ing with the original verbose query, it is closest to keyword queries which contain only the important terms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Proposed approach</head><p>In this section we present our approach to tackle the described problems of verbose queries. We begin by presenting the idea of our approach. Then we discuss adapting Learning to rank algorithm to weight and rank the terms of the topics. Finally, we explain the employed methodology.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Query Reduction and term weighting</head><p>The key idea of our approach is to reduce the long verbose queries by assigning a weight to query terms. This weight should reflect their importance in the query. We then filtering the less important terms and select the top terms with highest weight to replace the original query. In order to do so we must find a function f to weight the original terms that satisfies the following assumption:</p><p>Given an arbitrary query Q ={q1,q2,…;qn}, let P(qi,qj) denotes all possible pairs of the terms of the query. For each existing pair, if qi is more important than qj then f(qi) must be superior to f(qj).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Learning to rank terms</head><p>In our approach, we consider the problem of weighting terms and reducing the verbose queries as a Learning to rank problem <ref type="bibr" coords="2,300.18,449.22,10.65,9.02" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. Instead of ranking documents for each topic, as we usually do, we rank the terms of the topic. This can be formally described as follows:</p><p>Given n training queries qi (i = 1. . . n), their associated terms represented by features vectors, and the corresponding labels (degree of importance of the terms). Then a learning to rank algorithm is used to learn the ranking function. The function learned is applied to rank terms for the test topics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Methodology</head><p>In order to learn the ranking function, we have to prepare a training data first. There are several important things to be considered:</p><p>Training phase.</p><p>• Select queries and their associated terms to be used in the training phase;</p><p>• Assign to each term a ground truth label (degree of importance)</p><p>• Extract a list of features which represent each term: such features have to be as decisive as possible for term weighting;</p><p>• Choose and apply a learning to rank algorithm.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Testing phase.</head><p>• Apply the ranking function learned in the training phase, to rank terms associated to each unseen query;</p><p>• Select the top terms of each query from the ranked list to form the new query;</p><p>• Apply an information retrieval model to machining books with this new query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experimental setup</head><p>We used the topics of 2014 and 2015 for training. As to the terms associated to each query, we selected all the terms present in the three topic fields title, group, and narrative, as well as the terms of similar books. The natural language processing toolkit MontyLingua<ref type="foot" coords="3,178.56,293.29,3.24,5.83" target="#foot_0">1</ref> is used to analyze the text of queries and keep only the nouns and adjectives while eliminating prepositions, verbs and articles.</p><p>Regarding the ground truth label for learning and since we have for each topic the relevant books, from Qrels2014 file, but of course not the most relevant terms, we have decided to rank, for each topic, the terms of the relevant books by using the tf-idf function. The label of each previously selected term will be assigned the inverse rank if the term is present in the ranked list, otherwise 0.</p><p>For the features, several different categories have been used, including Statistical, Linguistic, Field, Profile, and similar book features. Table <ref type="table" coords="3,373.50,403.32,5.01,9.02" target="#tab_0">1</ref> describes the features of the five categories we used.</p><p>After preparing the training data set as described previously, the learning to rank algorithm Coordinate Ascent from RankLib<ref type="foot" coords="3,292.86,443.71,3.24,5.83" target="#foot_1">2</ref> have been used to learn the function of weighting and ranking terms, this efficient linear algorithm have been chosen due to the unbalanced data we have and in order to avoid the overfitting in the training phase.</p><p>Finally, the ranking function learned by the learning algorithm in the training phase have been used to weight and rank the terms of the 2016 topics. The top-10 ranked terms of each topic have been selected to calculate the score of books for each query. The BM15 model <ref type="bibr" coords="3,200.00,534.24,11.71,9.02" target="#b4">[5]</ref> was used to matching queries and books as well as the indexation is the same used in our participation to INEX SBS 2015. Please consult <ref type="bibr" coords="3,444.76,545.76,11.69,9.02" target="#b2">[3]</ref> for more details on this matching model and indexation process. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Linguistic Features</head><p>Is_Proper_Noun "1" if the term is a proper noun and "0" otherwise Is_Noun "1" if the term is a noun and to "0" otherwise In_Noun_Phrase "1" if the term appears in the list of noun-phrases extracted from the query and "0" otherwise</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Nb_Noun_Phrases</head><p>The number of noun phrases in which the term appears</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Field Features</head><p>In_Title_Topic "1" if the term appears in the title of the topic and "0" otherwise In_Narrative_Topic "1" if the term appears in the narrative of the topic and "0" otherwise In_Group_Topic "1" if the term appears in the group field of the topic and "0" otherwise</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Profile Features</head><p>In_profile "1" if the term appears in the list of tags extracted from the profile of the user and "0" otherwise nTF(t,u)</p><p>The ratio of the use of term t to tag resources to amount of resources tagged by the user u</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Example Feautres</head><p>In_Example_Book "1" if the term appears in the example books and "0" otherwise Tf_Idf(t,d,D) (in example book)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Product of Term Frequency and Inverse Document Frequency</head><p>In order to improve the performance of our system, several combinations of features are experimented to determine the optimal set. Table <ref type="table" coords="4,360.80,548.64,5.01,9.02" target="#tab_1">2</ref> summarizes the different combinations. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>According to the number of combinations described in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,374.65,177.30,3.77,9.02" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, six models have been learned using 2014 and 2015 3 topics and tested using 2016 topics. Table <ref type="table" coords="5,422.26,189.30,5.01,9.02" target="#tab_2">3</ref> and Table <ref type="table" coords="5,124.68,201.30,5.01,9.02" target="#tab_3">4</ref> report the evaluation results of the combinations on the training phase, based on Qrels2014_v1 and Qrels2014_v2 respectively.  <ref type="table" coords="5,465.54,509.82,5.01,9.02" target="#tab_4">5</ref> shows the official evaluation results of our submissions. From the table, we note that combining linguistic features with statistical features improves the results more than using the statistical features only. In term of NDCG@10 measure, the result increases from 0.1082 to 0.1290. However, when we add the field features and profile features we obtain significantly lower NDCG@10 (0.1084 and 0.1077). We can also clearly mention that combining all features gives the best results in term of NDCG@10, MRR and MAP compared to all other combinations of features. It has 91.09% improvement on NDCG@10, 88.36% on MRR and 63.03% on MAP compared with the baseline. Finally, we can say that our approach has advantage because all the combinations of features perform better than the baseline in term of NDCG@10. For all combinations NDCG@10 is superior than 0.1077 while NDCG@10 of the baseline is 0.0820.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>We proposed a simple and effective framework to reduce queries in SBS. Several categories of features have been proposed and used, namely, statistical, Linguistic, Fields, Profile and example features. A learning to rank algorithm has been used to weight and rank terms of the query and then select only the top important to matching books. Our experiments show the effectiveness of the approach.</p><p>For perspectives, We would like to use other features in order to better understand the users' information needs and improve the performance of the system like whether the term is a name of author or is part of the title of similar book, etc. we can also use terms with n-grams instead of unigrams. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="5,124.68,684.22,3.00,5.40;5,136.02,686.19,324.48,8.10"><head>3</head><label></label><figDesc>2015 topics are used to extract example books mentioned by a LT user for the 208 topics.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,124.14,150.09,347.11,126.70"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>List of features categorized in five categories.</figDesc><table coords="4,124.14,168.90,347.11,107.90"><row><cell>Features categories</cell><cell>Feature</cell><cell>Feature description</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>In_Query</cell><cell>"1" if the term appears in the query and "0" oth-erwise</cell></row><row><cell>Statistical Features</cell><cell>Tf_Iqf (t,q,Q) Tf(t,q)</cell><cell>Product of Term Frequency and Inverse Query Frequency Term Frequency of t in the topic</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Iqf(t,Q)</cell><cell>Inverse Query Frequency of the term among all topics</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,126.54,583.95,334.08,99.22"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>List of different combinations</figDesc><table coords="4,126.54,601.68,334.08,81.50"><row><cell>Features Combinations</cell><cell>Description</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_features</cell><cell>Statistical features only</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_ling_features</cell><cell>Statistical and linguistic features</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_ling_field_features</cell><cell>Statistical, linguistic and Field features</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_lin_field_profile_feat</cell><cell>Statistical, linguistic, Field and profile features</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_ling_profil_expl_feat</cell><cell>Statistical, linguistic, profile and example features</cell></row><row><cell>All_features</cell><cell>All categories of features</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,140.04,237.09,312.99,113.20"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Evaluation results of the 2014 topics using Qrels2014_v1</figDesc><table coords="5,140.04,255.72,312.99,94.58"><row><cell>Features Combinations</cell><cell>NDCG@10</cell><cell>MRR</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>R@1000</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_feautres</cell><cell>0.1078</cell><cell>0.2124</cell><cell>0.0805</cell><cell>0.5169</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_ling_features</cell><cell>0.1240</cell><cell>0.2546</cell><cell>0.0897</cell><cell>0.5366</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_ling_field_features</cell><cell>0.1103</cell><cell>0.2424</cell><cell>0.0801</cell><cell>0.5401</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_lin_field_profile_feat</cell><cell>0.1156</cell><cell>0.2368</cell><cell>0.0843</cell><cell>0.5249</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_ling_profil_expl_feat</cell><cell>0.1301</cell><cell>0.2673</cell><cell>0.0945</cell><cell>0.5063</cell></row><row><cell>All_features</cell><cell>0.1277</cell><cell>0.2626</cell><cell>0.0924</cell><cell>0.5133</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,136.02,380.19,325.37,138.64"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Evaluation results of the 2014 topics using Qrels2014_v2</figDesc><table coords="5,136.02,398.82,325.37,120.02"><row><cell>Features Combinations</cell><cell>NDCG@10</cell><cell>MRR</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>R@1000</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_feautres</cell><cell>0.0961</cell><cell>0.1823</cell><cell>0.0719</cell><cell>0.4919</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_ling_features</cell><cell>0.1088</cell><cell>0.2100</cell><cell>0.0801</cell><cell>0.5042</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_ling_field_features</cell><cell>0.0973</cell><cell>0.1906</cell><cell>0.0712</cell><cell>0.5105</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_ling_field_profile_feat</cell><cell>0.0975</cell><cell>0.1898</cell><cell>0.0724</cell><cell>0.4940</cell></row><row><cell>Stat_ling_profil_expl_feat</cell><cell>0.1098</cell><cell>0.2101</cell><cell>0.0787</cell><cell>0.4791</cell></row><row><cell>All_features</cell><cell>0.1088</cell><cell>0.2090</cell><cell>0.0776</cell><cell>0.4827</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">For our participation to INEX SBS 2016 track, we submitted six runs. Table</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="6,215.16,150.09,165.03,8.10"><head>Table 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Evaluation results of the 2016 topics</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="3,129.96,675.15,176.09,8.10"><p>http://alumni.media.mit.edu/~hugo/montylingua/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="3,129.96,686.19,166.35,8.10"><p>https://sourceforge.net/p/lemur/wiki/RankLib/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,132.69,584.79,337.83,8.10;6,141.72,595.83,328.84,8.10;6,141.72,606.81,300.84,8.10" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,301.34,584.79,169.18,8.10;6,141.72,595.83,35.20,8.10">Reducing Long Queries using Query Quality Predictors</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Giridhar</forename><surname>Kumaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Vitor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Carvalho</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,193.39,595.83,277.17,8.10;6,141.72,606.81,108.29,8.10">Proc. of the 32nd Intl. ACM SIGIR Conf. on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR)</title>
		<meeting>of the 32nd Intl. ACM SIGIR Conf. on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="564" to="571" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,132.68,617.79,337.96,8.10;6,141.72,628.83,172.70,8.10" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,279.41,617.79,191.22,8.10;6,141.72,628.83,5.83,8.10">Linear feature-based models for information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Donald</forename><surname>Metzler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">Bruce</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,152.75,628.83,76.87,8.10">Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="274" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,132.68,639.81,338.06,8.10;6,141.72,650.79,314.13,8.10" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,275.59,639.81,181.43,8.10">CERIST at INEX 2015: Social Book Search Track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Chaa</forename><surname>Messaoud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Omar</forename><surname>Nouali</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,141.72,650.79,154.50,8.10">Working Notes for CLEF 2015 Conference</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Toulouse, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">September 08-11, 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,132.68,150.09,337.94,8.10;7,141.72,161.07,328.86,8.10;7,141.72,172.05,328.87,8.10;7,141.72,183.09,328.84,8.10;7,141.72,194.07,26.76,8.10" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,242.48,172.05,91.85,8.10">Overview of INEX 2014</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bellot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Bogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Geva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Huurdeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kazai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koolen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Moriceau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mothe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Preminger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sanjuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Schenkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Skov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Tannier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Walsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,353.38,172.05,117.21,8.10;7,141.72,183.09,171.27,8.10">Information Access Evaluation. Multilinguality, Multimodality, and Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="212" to="228" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,132.68,205.05,337.95,8.10;7,141.72,216.09,238.03,8.10" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,141.72,216.09,61.02,8.10">Okapi at TREC-3</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hancock-Beaulieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gatford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,209.69,216.09,131.45,8.10">NIST SPECIAL PUBLICATION SP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="109" />
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,132.68,227.07,338.01,8.10;7,141.72,238.05,328.92,8.10;7,141.72,249.09,233.98,8.10" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,315.78,227.07,154.91,8.10;7,141.72,238.05,12.21,8.10">Discovering key concepts in verbose queries</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Bendersky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bruce</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,170.13,238.05,300.51,8.10;7,141.72,249.09,146.99,8.10">Proceedings of the 31st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 31st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="491" to="498" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,132.68,260.07,337.89,8.10;7,141.72,271.05,329.02,8.10;7,141.72,282.09,294.89,8.10" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,263.07,260.07,207.50,8.10;7,141.72,271.05,44.32,8.10">Query term ranking based on dependency parsing of verbose queries</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jae</forename><surname>Hyun Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">Bruce</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,192.70,271.05,278.03,8.10;7,141.72,282.09,147.02,8.10">Proceedings of the 33rd international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 33rd international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval<address><addrLine>Geneva, Switzerland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">July 19-23, 2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,132.68,293.07,338.02,8.10;7,141.72,304.05,324.41,8.10" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,221.43,293.07,157.34,8.10">Learning to Rank for Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Tie-Yan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,386.36,293.07,84.34,8.10;7,141.72,304.05,268.67,8.10">Foundations and Trends in Information Retrieval, Foundations and Trends in Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="331" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
