<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,450.12,70.04,26.39,11.84">2005</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,248.64,108.94,54.16,8.48"><forename type="first">Mirna</forename><surname>Adriani</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">IMAGE-CLEF</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Indonesia Participation</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Indonesia Depok</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>16424</postCode>
									<country key="ID">Indonesia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,450.12,70.04,26.39,11.84">2005</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">546780A19B4856E5B6D97295B457B98A</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:08+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>image retrieval</term>
					<term>cross-language information retrieval</term>
					<term>machine translation</term>
					<term>query expansion</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We present a report on our participation in the English-Indonesian image adhoc task of the 2005 Cross-Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF). We chose to translate the Indonesian query set into English using a commercial machine translation tool called Transtool. We show that some improvement in retrieval effectiveness can be obtained using a query expansion technique. We used an approach that combines the retrieval results of the query on text and on image.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This year we, the University of Indonesia IR-group, participate in the bilingual ad-hoc Image -Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF) 2005 task, i.e., the Indonesian-English CLIR. We used commercial machine translation software called Transtool<ref type="foot" coords="1,234.54,349.36,3.05,5.49" target="#foot_0">1</ref> to translate an Indonesian query set into English. We learned from our previous work [1, 2] that freely-available dictionaries on the Internet failed to provide correct translations for many query terms, as their vocabulary was very limited. We hoped that we could improve the result using machine translation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The Query Translation Process</head><p>As a first step, we translated the original query set from CLEF into Indonesian. Then this Indonesian version of the query set was translated back into English using Transtool. After deleting stopwords from the translated English queries, the words were then stemmed using a Porter stemmer. The resulting queries were then used to find relevant documents in the collections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Query Expansion Technique</head><p>Expanding translation queries by adding relevant terms has been shown to improve CLIR effectiveness. Among the query expansion techniques is the pseudo relevance feedback [3, 5]. This technique is based on an assumption that the top few documents initially retrieved are indeed relevant to the query, and so they must contain other terms that are also relevant to the query. The query expansion technique adds such terms into the translated queries. We applied this technique to this work. To choose the good terms from the top ranked documents, we used the tf*idf term weighting formula [3, 5]. We added a certain number of noun terms that have the highest weight values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Combining the Scores of the Text and the Image</head><p>The short caption that attached to each image in the collections was indexed using Lucene <ref type="bibr" coords="2,450.96,92.92,3.05,5.49" target="#b1">2</ref> , an open source indexing and retrieval engine, and the image collection was indexed using GIFT <ref type="bibr" coords="2,395.04,103.72,3.05,5.49" target="#b2">3</ref> . We combined the scores of the text and the image retrieval in order to get a better result. The text was given more weight because the image retrieval effectiveness that we obtained from using the GIFT was poor. We used the two examples given by CLEF and ran them as query by example through GIFT to search through the collection. We combined the color histogram, texture histogram, the color block, and the texture block in order to get the images that are most similar to the two examples. The text score was given a weight of 0.8 and the image score was given 0.2. These weights were chosen after comparing a number of different weight configurations in our initial experiments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiment</head><p>The image collection contains 28,133 images from St. Andrews image collection that have short captions in English. We participated in the bilingual task using Indonesian query topics. We opted to use the query title and the narrative for all of the available 28 topics. The query translation process was performed fully automatic using the Transtool machine translation software.</p><p>We then applied the pseudo relevance-feedback query-expansion technique to the translated queries. We used the top 20 documents from the Glasgow Herald collection to extract the expansion terms.</p><p>In these experiments, we used the Lucene information retrieval system to index and retrieve image captions (text).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>Our work was focused on the bilingual task using Indonesian queries to retrieve images from the image collections. The machine translation tool failed to translate 3 words in the titles and 8 words in the narratives. In particular, the machine translation failed to translate Indonesian names of places or locations such as Skotlandia (Scotland), Swis (Swiss), and Irlandia (Ireland) into English. The average number of words in the queries was largely the same as the resulting English version.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="2,116.77,445.36,4.71,8.48" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows the result of our experiments. The retrieval performance of the translation queries obtained using the machine translation-based technique falls 34.55% below that of the equivalent monolingual query. The retrieval precision of the translated queries was below that of the monolingual retrieval, i.e. by 40.02%. The retrieval effectiveness of translated narrative was 48.5% below that of the monolingual retrieval. The retrieval effectiveness of combined translated title and narrative was 46.28% below that of the monolingual retrieval.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task</head><p>The retrieval performance of the translated queries using machine translation was best for title only (see Table <ref type="table" coords="2,92.58,658.12,3.41,8.48">2</ref>). The effectiveness of narrative-only retrieval was 16.06% worse than that of the title only. By taking the</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,206.88,493.54,199.09,86.48"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Average retrieval precision of the monolingual runs using English queries.</figDesc><table coords="2,213.66,493.54,165.97,51.77"><row><cell>: Monolingual</cell><cell>P/R</cell></row><row><cell>Title</cell><cell>0.3538</cell></row><row><cell>Narrative</cell><cell>0.3463</cell></row><row><cell>Title + Narrative</cell><cell>0.3878</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,97.92,703.24,173.60,8.48"><p>See http://www.geocities.com/cdpenerjemah/.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,97.92,692.44,111.40,8.48"><p>See http://lucene.apache.org/.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="2,97.92,703.24,157.87,8.48"><p>See http://savannah.gnu.org/projects/gift/.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>image score into account, in additional to text, the results showed some improvement. For the title-based retrieval, the image score increased the average retrieval precision by 7.9%; for the narrative-based retrieval, the image score increased the average retrieval precision by 11.22%. However, the query expansion technique did not improve the retrieval performance. It decreased the retrieval performance of the title-only retrieval by 30.01% and narrative-only retrieval by 10.94%. Average retrieval precision of the bilingual runs using Indonesian queries that were translated into English using machine translation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Task</head><p>The retrieval effectiveness of combining title and narrative was 1.88% worse than that of the title only retrieval, but was 14.45% better than the narrative only retrieval. The query expansion also decreased the retrieval performance by 7.25% compared to the combined title and narrative queries. Adding the weight of the image to the combined title and narrative scores helped increase the retrieval performance by 7.34%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Summary</head><p>Our results demonstrate that combining the image with the text in the image collections result in better retrieval performance compared to using only the text [4]. However query expansions using general newspaper collections hurt the retrieval performance of the queries. We hope to find a better approach to improve the retrieval effectiveness of the combined text and image-based retrieval.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="3,96.13,538.54,423.37,8.48;3,109.50,549.34,409.98,8.48;3,109.50,560.14,330.44,8.48" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,268.32,538.54,251.18,8.48;3,109.50,549.34,81.54,8.48">Term Similarity Based Query Expansion for Cross Language Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Adriani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Rijsbergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,209.16,549.34,310.32,8.48;3,109.50,560.14,125.37,8.48">Proceedings of Research and Advanced Technology for Digital Libraries, Third European Conference (ECDL&apos;99)</title>
		<meeting>Research and Advanced Technology for Digital Libraries, Third European Conference (ECDL&apos;99)<address><addrLine>Paris</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999-09">September 1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="322" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,96.13,571.00,423.27,8.48;3,109.50,581.80,143.29,8.48" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,161.25,571.00,229.96,8.48">Ambiguity Problem in Multilingual Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Adriani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,412.56,571.00,106.84,8.48;3,109.50,581.80,36.07,8.48">CLEF 2000 Working Note Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Portugal</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000-09">September 2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,96.13,592.60,423.30,8.48;3,109.50,603.46,54.17,8.48" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="3,312.90,592.60,115.97,8.48">Modern Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Richardo</forename><surname>Baeza-Yates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Berthier</forename><surname>Ribeiro-Neto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,96.13,614.26,423.23,8.48;3,109.50,625.06,317.87,8.48" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,320.62,614.26,198.75,8.48;3,109.50,625.06,72.17,8.48">The CLEF Cross Language Image Retrieval Track (ImageCLEF) 2004</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Sanderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,198.29,625.06,139.99,8.48">CLEF 2004 Working Note Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004-09">September 2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,96.13,635.92,423.23,8.48;3,109.50,646.72,40.56,8.48" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="3,259.56,635.92,172.37,8.48">Introduction to Modern Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gerard</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Mcgill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983">1983</date>
			<publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
