<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,111.24,82.36,372.80,14.42">Experiments in Trec 2007 Blog Opinion Task at CAS-ICT</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,95.52,107.55,65.03,9.45"><forename type="first">Xiangwen</forename><surname>Liao</surname></persName>
							<email>liaoxiangwen@software.ict.ac.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computing Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate school</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,174.61,107.55,53.91,9.45"><forename type="first">Donglin</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computing Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate school</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,242.17,107.55,38.30,9.45"><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computing Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate school</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,294.31,107.55,33.79,9.45"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computing Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate school</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,342.13,107.55,50.06,9.45"><forename type="first">Songbo</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computing Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,400.99,107.55,49.23,9.45"><forename type="first">Hongbo</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computing Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,474.19,107.55,25.67,9.45;1,282.18,123.15,27.46,9.45"><forename type="first">Xueqi</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computing Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,111.24,82.36,372.80,14.42">Experiments in Trec 2007 Blog Opinion Task at CAS-ICT</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">A34776034B586FC8B0C15D5C1F73F0B4</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes our participation in TREC 2007 Blog Track Tasks: Opinion retrieval and Polarity classification. As for Opinion retrieval task, a two-step approach is used to retrieve opinion relevant blog unit (that is blog post and its comments) given a query after filtering Spam blog and extracting blog unit. With Polarity Classification, Drag-push [1] based classifier is employed to get polarity of blog unit. Finally, we introduce all the runs submitted.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.22" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Given a query, the aim of Blog Opinion Retrieval task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,324.18,325.95,12.26,9.45" target="#b2">[2]</ref> is to retrieve opinion relevant blog unit using blog data collection as an important test bed. Compared with traditional retrieval task, opinion retrieval is more challenged since it is very difficult to combine opinion (i.e. Positive, negative and natural) with some topic and then rank the blog unit according to the strength of opinion of the query topic. To complete such task, we present a framework that filters spam data, extracts blog unit, retrieves relavant blog unit and finally re-ranks related blog according the strength of blog unit. A machine learning approach is employed to filter different kind of Spam blogs. The resulted permalink is used as input for our string uniqueness based algorithm to extract blog unit. And then topic related result list is retrieved by BM25 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,366.41,450.77,12.28,9.45" target="#b3">[3]</ref> and Language Model given a query. In the end, Drag-push <ref type="bibr" coords="1,218.25,466.38,12.28,9.45" target="#b1">[1]</ref> based algorithm is adopted to re-rank the result list by opinion strength.</p><p>As for polarity classification, there are two strategies used to get polarity according to different representation of each relevant blog unit after filtering Spam Blog and extracting blog unit. First, the blog unit is represented by traditional multidimensional vector of various words. Second, sentiment lexicon constructed by Inquirer <ref type="bibr" coords="1,282.11,544.39,12.28,9.45" target="#b4">[4]</ref> is used to compute blog unit vector. Finally, Drag-push based classifier is employed to classify polarity of each blog unit.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Filtering Spam Blog</head><p>Spam blogs or Splogs are faked blogs, containing gibberish or plagiarized content from other blogs and news sources with the sole purpose of hosting profitable content based ads, promoting affiliate sites unjustifiably <ref type="bibr" coords="1,203.12,637.95,11.18,9.45">[5]</ref>. So Splogs can be roughly classified into faked blogs and link spam blogs. The former is more prevalent in the blogosphere and the latter is quite common in other web pages.</p><p>For the link spam, we counted the links density which is very simple but effective. A blog is classified as link spam if the number of links in it exceeds the predefined thresholds. The thresholds are trained from a heuristic approach and tuned to get a better accuracy. For the faked blogs detection, we adopt a machine learning approach, and we treat the task to be a two-category classification problem. Our model is based on SVM <ref type="bibr" coords="1,377.05,747.18,11.12,9.45" target="#b6">[6]</ref>, which is widely used and performs well in text classification. We introduce several powerful local features, as follows:</p><p>1) We choose the traditional feature such as "bag-of-words", and "bag-of-word-N-Grams"based on blogs' textual content, where the occurrence of words in text or content of some specific tags on a page like "title" is used as a feature.</p><p>2) We use two new features which are called bag-of-anchors and bag-of-urls. In bag-of-anchors, features are extracted from the anchor text on a page. Similarly, in bag-of-urls, URLs are tokenized on punctuation (\,/,.,?,=,etc.) and each token is used as a feature. For the bag-of-urls, we adopt additional segmentation of the URLs to combat the case that words are glued together as one token with the attempt to avoid being detected (e.g.,businesscardforfree) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,238.60,216.78,12.24,9.45" target="#b7">[7]</ref> . 3) Normalized term frequency (TF) and binary forms are employed to represent the features, and we used Mutual Information together with term frequency as our feature selection mechanism <ref type="bibr" coords="2,219.28,263.58,11.18,9.45" target="#b3">[3]</ref>, which is simple but performs well in practice for SVM. Finally, we train the libsvm <ref type="bibr" coords="2,215.79,279.19,13.59,9.45" target="#b8">[8]</ref> classifier by manually labeling some examples, and detect splog using above features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Extracting Blog Unit (Post and its Comments)</head><p>Blog extraction is a kind of difficult job because each blog site has a lot of different blog templates which can be chosen by bloggers. Each template has different styles which greatly enhance the difficulty of extraction.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,273.17,741.57,5.25,9.45">1</ref> A blog page While many algorithms for content extraction <ref type="bibr" coords="3,309.02,76.35,12.15,9.45" target="#b9">[9]</ref>[10], template detection <ref type="bibr" coords="3,426.12,76.35,17.19,9.45" target="#b11">[11]</ref>[12] and page segmentation <ref type="bibr" coords="3,145.12,91.95,18.37,9.45" target="#b13">[13]</ref> already exist, they don't fit well in Blogsphere. According to blog opinion retrieval task, two requirements for the content extraction algorithm are raised. First, this algorithm should run fast enough to meet the updating speed of the whole blogsphere. Second, the extraction result should be precise. Not only the page template but also some dynamic parts of pages should be excluded from the extraction result. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,343.73,154.36,5.25,9.45">1</ref> shows a blog page. On the right part of this page, there are "Recent Comments", "Calendar", and "Blogroll", all of them should be excluded. Considering these two requirements, most existing algorithms can not satisfy both requires at the same time. A new content extraction algorithm is created to fit with both requires. Our algorithm relies on such an assumption: given a bunch of pages from a site, main content sections contain more unique strings than other sections. It seems reasonable since main content sections are more likely to provide new information to people. With this assumption, we propose an effective algorithm, as follows:</p><p>1) For every page of the blog, divide it into text segments. Every text in a web page that can be seen by users after rendering is called a text segment. In web pages, text segments are separated by html tags, process instructions, comments, etc. 2) Build a hash map from all pages of the blog, keys of the map are text segments, values of the map are occurrence times of keys. 3) Erase all text segments whose occurrence times are bigger than a given threshold.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Opinion Retrieval</head><p>The aim of blog opinion retrieval task is to retrieve opinion relevant blog unit using blog data collection as an important test bed given a query. In our system, a two-step approach is used to retrieve opinion relevant blog unit.</p><p>First, the Firtex platform <ref type="bibr" coords="3,205.36,450.76,17.86,9.45" target="#b14">[14]</ref> is used to index the blog unit collection constructed after filtering spam blog and extracting procession. Since BM25 algorithm always effectively retrieves related document in ad hoc retrieval task, it is also employed to retrieve relevant blog unit as input for re-ranking according to strength of opinion in our system. In this Model, we have:</p><p>Where .</p><p>The parameters in this formula are K 1 , b, r and R. Since we have no relevance information in advance, we set r = R =0. Experiments in former TREC suggest a value of b around 0.75 is good. So we also set b=0.75. We tune K 1 by experiments using 2006 TREC data and set it 2.75. Language Model is used in our Firtex system besides the BM25 algorithm.In order to improve the performance of Language Model, we used Dirichlet smoothing method. Our ranking function is as follows: Comparing BM25 Model with Language Model, our experiments show that Language Model is a little better than BM25 Model. Finally, the related topic result is obtained in Language Model. After retrieving the related topic result lists, our system re-ranks the blog unit and constructs 6 submitted runs: 2 simple statistics runs, 3 Drag-push classifier based runs, and 1 relevance run. Simple statistics runs are constructed by just computing the sum score of sentiment words (specified by Inquirer) in blog unit, normalizing the sum score, and then re-ranking the result lists. The difference of the two submitted runs is: SmpStm gets sum score after stemming blog unit and lexicon words while BaseSmp not. Drag-push classifier is employed to get 3 Drag-push classifier based runs:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,213.30,688.07,174.82,24.56">( ; ) ( | ) ( | ) ( ; )</formula><p>1) For all the six runs, Relevent run gets best MAP, R-precision and p@10. The reason leading to such result is that after retrieving relevant blog units we re-rank the relevant result lists according to strength of opinion. So it is possible that some less relevant but more strength opinion units get higher rank than more relevant and less strength opinion units. But the test evaluation seems to prefer more relevant and less strength opinion units. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Run</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Polarity Task</head><p>There are three runs we submitted this year. In our system, we employ Drag-push classifier to get the polarity of each blog unit. The Drag-push classifier takes advantage of training errors to successively refine the classification model of the Centroid Classifier. We train the Drag-push classifier using TREC 2006 Blog Task result lists, use the resulting classifier to classify each related blog unit and then construct the submitted runs. The difference of the three runs is the representation of blog unit: DrapComSub uses bags of word; DrapOpiSub bases lexicon words; DrapStm adopts stemmed lexicon words. The result illustrates that using blog unit as a process unit is no enough to classify polarity. It is necessary to extract opinion relevant fragment and use such finer granular fragment to classify blog unit.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,291.84,716.07,4.30,5.81;3,269.94,688.07,33.96,9.50;3,340.38,688.07,39.80,9.50;3,205.02,694.79,38.46,9.50;3,304.38,703.13,33.96,9.50;3,328.62,684.07,6.08,13.65;3,363.00,699.13,6.08,13.65;3,316.44,684.67,5.79,12.92;3,256.68,691.40,5.79,12.92;3,350.82,699.73,5.79,12.92;3,286.80,697.30,10.87,18.66;3,89.99,731.51,415.35,9.50;3,89.99,747.11,415.35,9.50;4,90.00,76.91,126.42,9.50;4,223.62,70.61,5.15,11.56;4,236.94,76.91,268.45,9.50;4,90.00,92.51,400.19,9.50;4,497.28,86.21,5.15,11.56;4,89.99,107.51,33.31,9.50"><head>∑</head><label></label><figDesc>Where d denotes a document, w denotes the word, C denotes the document collection. c(w;d) denotes the number of word w in document d. p(w|C) denotes the probability of the word w in the whole document collection C. μ is the only parameter which can be adjusted in language model. Our experiments in TREC 2006 corpus show that the best result is achieved when the value of μ is 2500.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" coords="2,90.00,400.92,415.26,324.90"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="2,90.00,400.92,415.26,324.90" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,90.00,263.51,415.50,247.52"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Train a Drag-push classifier using TREC 2006 Blog Task result lists; 2) Score each 2007 Blog Unit by the sum of similarity to positive core and negative core; 3) Re-rank each result lists to form submitted run. While all the 3 Drag-push classifier based runs use the above method to get result lists, there is difference among them: DrapCom just uses relevant blog unit to train and gets result lists; DrapOpi represents training and tests blog unit by lexicon words; DrapStem represents training and tests blog unit by stemmed lexicon words. Result of submitted opinion search runs</figDesc><table coords="4,173.70,388.79,241.69,106.10"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>Map</cell><cell>R-precision</cell><cell>p@10</cell></row><row><cell>Relevent</cell><cell>0.3041</cell><cell>0.3600</cell><cell>0.4460</cell></row><row><cell>BaseSmp</cell><cell>0.1433</cell><cell>0.1843</cell><cell>0.2300</cell></row><row><cell>DrapCom</cell><cell>0.1564</cell><cell>0.1999</cell><cell>0.2460</cell></row><row><cell>DrapOpi</cell><cell>0.1659</cell><cell>0.2176</cell><cell>0.2920</cell></row><row><cell>DrapStm</cell><cell>0.1537</cell><cell>0.2047</cell><cell>0.2640</cell></row><row><cell>SmpStm</cell><cell>0.1409</cell><cell>0.1788</cell><cell>0.2320</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,94.32,216.59,60.86,10.37" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>References</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.80,232.31,400.52,9.50;5,90.00,247.91,333.57,9.50" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,287.29,232.31,218.03,9.50;5,90.00,247.91,67.45,9.50">A Novel Refinement Approach for Text Categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Songbo</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Xueqi</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,162.27,247.91,38.54,9.50">CIKM2005</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Bremen, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-11-05">October 31-November 5, 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,103.25,263.51,402.05,9.50;5,90.00,279.11,274.79,9.50" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Iadh</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Maarten</forename><surname>De Rijke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://trec.nist.gov/pubs/trec15/papers/BLOG06.OVERVIEW.pdf" />
		<title level="m" coord="5,293.81,263.51,207.03,9.50">Overview of the TREC-2006 Blog Track</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,107.79,294.71,397.60,9.50;5,90.00,310.31,415.40,9.50;5,90.00,325.91,81.71,9.50" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="5,292.70,294.71,212.69,9.50;5,90.00,310.31,410.18,9.50">A Probabilistic Model of Information Retrieval: Development and Comparative Experiments Part 2.Information Processing and Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="779" to="808" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,107.38,341.51,397.94,9.50;5,90.00,357.11,168.92,9.50" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,289.88,341.51,215.45,9.50;5,90.00,357.11,70.38,9.50">The General Inquirer: A Computer Approach to Content Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Philip</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Dexter</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Dunphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1966">1966</date>
			<publisher>The MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.83,372.71,400.43,9.50;5,90.00,388.35,117.71,9.45" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,292.09,372.71,185.89,9.50">Characterizing the Splogosphere.WWW</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Pranam</forename><surname>Kolari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Akshay</forename><surname>Java</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Finin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-05-22">2006. May 22-26, 2006</date>
			<pubPlace>Edinburgh,UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,106.20,403.91,399.12,9.50;5,90.00,419.51,415.39,9.50;5,90.00,435.11,170.38,9.50" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,330.09,403.91,175.23,9.50;5,90.00,419.51,40.90,9.50">A training algorithm for optimal margin classifiers</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Boser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Guyon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Vapnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,151.62,419.55,353.77,9.45;5,90.00,435.15,25.31,9.45">COLT &apos;92: Proceedings of the fifth annual workshop on Computational learning theory</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACMPress</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="144" to="152" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.83,450.71,400.60,9.50;5,90.00,466.31,311.94,9.50" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,303.78,450.71,201.66,9.50;5,90.00,466.31,87.17,9.50">SVMs for the Blogosphere:Blog Identification and Splog Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Pranam</forename><surname>Kolari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Finin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Anupam</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<publisher>American Association forArtificial Intelligence</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,104.87,481.91,249.91,9.50" xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://www.csie.ntu.edu.tw/~cjlin/libsvmtools/#3" />
		<title level="m" coord="5,104.87,481.91,26.67,9.50">libsvm</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.22,497.51,400.01,9.50;5,90.00,513.11,234.10,9.50" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,234.67,497.51,265.52,9.50">Discovering Informative Content Blocks from Web Documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Shian-Hua</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jan-Ming</forename><surname>Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,101.42,513.11,127.95,9.50">Proc. of the SIGKDD&apos;02 Conf</title>
		<meeting>of the SIGKDD&apos;02 Conf</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="588" to="593" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.15,528.71,395.22,9.50;5,90.00,544.31,220.15,9.50" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,230.76,528.71,258.40,9.50">Eliminating Noisy Information in Web Pages for Data Mining</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lan</forename><surname>Yi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Xiaoli</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,90.00,544.31,125.29,9.50">Proc.of the SIGKDD&apos;03 Conf</title>
		<meeting>.of the SIGKDD&apos;03 Conf</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="296" to="305" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,114.44,559.91,390.94,9.50;5,90.00,575.51,282.93,9.50" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,293.43,559.91,211.95,9.50;5,90.00,575.51,51.98,9.50">Template Detection via Data Mining and its Applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ziv</forename><surname>Bar-Yossef</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sridhar</forename><surname>Rajagopalan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,160.31,575.51,117.86,9.50">Proc. of the WWW&apos;02 Conf</title>
		<meeting>of the WWW&apos;02 Conf</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="580" to="591" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,111.89,591.11,393.47,9.50;5,90.00,606.71,338.03,9.50" xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,312.57,591.11,192.78,9.50;5,90.00,606.71,108.36,9.50">Extracting unstructured Data from Template Generated Web Document</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ling</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nali</forename><surname>Goharian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Abdur</forename><surname>Chowdhury</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,217.56,606.71,115.72,9.50">Proc. of the CIKM&apos;03 Conf</title>
		<meeting>of the CIKM&apos;03 Conf</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="516" to="519" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.53,622.31,394.79,9.50;5,90.00,637.91,415.33,9.50;5,90.00,653.50,87.85,9.50" xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,346.95,622.31,158.37,9.50;5,90.00,637.91,161.24,9.50">Extracting Content Structure for Web Pages based on Visual Representation</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Deng</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Shipeng</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ji-Rong</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wei-Ying</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,271.46,637.91,227.97,9.50">Proc. of the APWeb&apos;03 Conf., number 2642 in LNCS</title>
		<meeting>of the APWeb&apos;03 Conf., number 2642 in LNCS</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="406" to="417" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,113.59,669.09,391.73,9.51;5,90.00,684.69,415.37,9.51;5,90.00,700.31,386.55,9.50" xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,252.81,669.09,252.51,9.51;5,90.00,684.69,198.57,9.50">Efficient On-line Index Maintenance for Dynamic Text Collections by Using Dynamic Balancing Tree</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ruijie</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Xueqi</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,312.66,684.75,192.71,9.45;5,90.00,700.35,233.39,9.45">Proceedings of the 16th ACM Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM 2007)</title>
		<meeting>the 16th ACM Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM 2007)<address><addrLine>Lisbon, Portugal</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-11">November 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
