<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,77.76,75.59,456.45,12.58;1,197.10,91.91,217.78,12.58">IIT TREC-2007 Genomics Track: Using Concept-based Semantics in Context for Genomics Literature Passage Retrieval</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,114.60,125.35,46.82,9.27"><forename type="first">Jay</forename><surname>Urbain</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Information Retrieval Laboratory Computer Science Department Illinois Institute of Technology Chicago</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>IL</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,273.66,125.35,64.77,9.27"><forename type="first">Nazli</forename><surname>Goharian</surname></persName>
							<email>goharian@iit.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Information Retrieval Laboratory Computer Science Department Illinois Institute of Technology Chicago</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>IL</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,445.20,125.35,57.66,9.27"><forename type="first">Ophir</forename><surname>Frieder</surname></persName>
							<email>frieder@iit.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Information Retrieval Laboratory Computer Science Department Illinois Institute of Technology Chicago</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>IL</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,77.76,75.59,456.45,12.58;1,197.10,91.91,217.78,12.58">IIT TREC-2007 Genomics Track: Using Concept-based Semantics in Context for Genomics Literature Passage Retrieval</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">E71275BE8CF19389048AFB3093D02C88</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:04+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>For the TREC-2007 Genomics Track [1], we explore unsupervised techniques for extracting semantic information about biomedical concepts with a retrieval model for using these semantics in context to improve passage retrieval precision. Dependency grammar analysis is evaluated for boosting the rank of passages where complementary subject/object concept pairs can be identified between queries and sentences from candidate passages.</p><p>In our model, a concept is represented as a set of synonymous terms and a concept-word distribution. Concept terms are identified using an information extraction technique relying on shallow sentence parsing, external knowledge sources, and document context.</p><p>The system combines a dimensional data model for indexing scientific literature at multiple levels of document context, with a rule-based query processing algorithm. The data model consists of two hierarchical indices: one for individual words and a second for extracted concepts. The word index provides retrieval of single or multi-word terms. The concept index provides efficient retrieval of single or multiple independent concepts.</p><p>A retrieval function combines concepts with term statistics at multiple levels of context to identify relevant passages. Finally, we boost the relevance score of sentences identified within a passage where we can identify term dependencies that complement subject/object pairs between query and passage sentences via dependency grammar analysis.</p><p>Our objective for this year's forum was to improve passage retrieval precision. We submitted three automatically generated results for three variations of our retrieval model to the TREC forum. The three results exceeded the track median for character based passage retrieval by 75 to 93%. The mean average precision (MAP) for our top passage retrieval model was 0.0940 which compares favorably to the top result of 0.0976.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Information retrieval in the genomics literature domain is challenging due to the wide variation of synonymous terms, acronyms, and morphological variants used for identifying the same biological concepts. In addition, acronyms frequently have multiple meanings (polysemy) and require contextual clues for accurate disambiguation. For example, the terms "bovine spongiform encephalopathy", "BSE", and "Mad Cow Disease" are all different terms representing the same named entity or concept. Search terms also have much higher relevance when matched against document terms when occurring within the local context of a phrase, sentence, or passage of text. An acronym like "IP" could represent "immunoprecipitant" or "ischemic precondition." In this case, context captured at the paragraph or document level where an acronym is defined can help disambiguate its meaning <ref type="bibr" coords="1,354.86,445.02,10.67,9.02" target="#b2">[2]</ref>.</p><p>Databases from the National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,402.02,472.44,11.72,9.02">[3]</ref> and other sources can be helpful in providing semantic evidence supporting identification and extraction of named biological entities. However, it is important to recognize that no knowledge source can fully capture the complexities of human language let alone be fully up-to-date with the dynamic vocabulary of an evolving science. In most cases, there are varying levels of semantic evidence which can make accurate identification of biological concepts difficult. In these cases, optimal retrieval solutions need to integrate additional sources of evidence including identification of key phrases and terms within context.</p><p>We propose that effective search requires a systematic approach for combining semantic and contextual evidence. Our approach relies on an indexing model that supports search of single and multi-word terms to support identification of concept term variants, search at different levels of document structure for identifying terms and concepts within context, and integration of external knowledge sources to aid in the identification and resolution of named biological entities and related synonymous terms.</p><p>We first describe our indexing model, followed by the indexing process, query processing, our methods, results, and a discussion of related work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Dimensional Data Model</head><p>Paragraphs, sentences, and terms, representing complete topics, thoughts, and units of meaning respectively, provide a logical breakdown of document lexical structure into finer levels of meaning and context. We capture these hierarchical relationships within a search index based on a dimensional data model. As shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,267.66,209.34,3.77,9.02" target="#fig_0">1</ref>, the dimensional index has a dimension table for each level of document structure (document, paragraph, sentence, term) and one central fact table or postinglist. The postinglist represents a single mapping table, containing foreign key fields that map the relations between all dimensions. The "grain", i.e., the smallest non-divisible element of the database, is the individual word. Sentences aggregate words in sequence by position, paragraphs aggregate sentences, and documents aggregate paragraphs. In the data warehousing literature, this model is refered to as a star schema <ref type="bibr" coords="2,86.64,338.04,10.88,9.02" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,97.52,338.04,7.25,9.02" target="#b4">5]</ref>. The postinglist includes a term's position within a sentence, textual representation, as well as term and morphological variants. The dimensional indexing model can be extended to include additional dimensions, and allows for efficient formulation of SQL search queries. By indexing each individual word, queries can be developed for searching single-and multi-word terms, and term statistics can be aggregated over different levels of document structure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">System Description</head><p>Indexing, retrieval, and analysis applications were developed in Java and the system utilizes the Oracle 10g Personal Edition database. The system is platform and database independent. TREC retrieval runs were performed on a 3.1GHz Pentium 4 PC with 2 GB of main memory.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Indexing Process</head><p>The indexing process includes the following:</p><p>1. Lexical Partitioning: Documents are parsed into paragraphs. Paragraphs are parsed into sentences. 2. Acronym identification: Acronyms and their longforms are identified during indexing using the Schwartz and Hearst algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="2,462.93,248.10,10.64,9.02" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. A long-short form would include "vasoactive intestinal peptide (VIP)", and a short-long form would include "VIP (vasoactive intestinal peptide)". The algorithm works backwards through the long form text and attempts to identify corresponding letters in the acronym. Acronyms and their long-forms are added to an acronym table to help with disambiguation. Long-form variants are added to the same indexing location as acronyms during indexing (and vice versa). This technique helps disambiguate acronyms, and allows identification of passages using either the short-or long-form of an entity. 3. Tokenization: Sentence terms are tokenized, stop words removed, and lexical variants of gene and protein names are generated <ref type="bibr" coords="2,451.23,425.58,10.64,9.02">[7]</ref>. Porter stemming <ref type="bibr" coords="2,539.38,425.58,11.72,9.02" target="#b7">[8]</ref> is used on each token with the following exceptions: gene names (as defined by the Entrez Gene database); all upper case, mixed case, alpha-numeric terms; and non-gene terms that would become a gene name after being stemmed. Small "s" is also stripped from all upper-case terms. 4. Indexing: Each term along with its long-form expansion and lexical variants are stored in the index with the same positional information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Query Processing</head><p>Structured query generation is illustrated with the following query: "Provide information about the role of the gene PRNP (prion protein) in the disease Mad Cow Disease". Prior to including synonyms as a concept term variant, its level of ambiguity is determined. If the synonym is considered ambiguous it is not included. We consider a term ambiguous if either of the following tests is met:</p><p>1. The synonym's normalized inverse document frequency (NIDF) is &lt; 0.1. Where NIDF is the IDF=log (N/df) normalized to between 0 and 1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">The synonym correlates with the correct long-form in less than 50% of all instances within the acronym table</head><p>Resolved concepts and corresponding synonyms are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,96.72,368.82,3.77,9.02" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. Resolved concept instances are added to a concept index with the same structure and fact tables as the dimensional term index described in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,240.60,392.40,3.77,9.02" target="#fig_0">1</ref>, except the postinglist table is replaced with a conceptlist. Search can be performed within the context of an individual term/phrase, sentence, paragraph, or document.</p><p>For TREC, we first perform paragraph-level searches using the probabilistic BM25 retrieval function <ref type="bibr" coords="3,237.09,600.06,11.70,9.02" target="#b8">[9]</ref> shown in equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="3,94.99,611.76,3.91,9.02">1</ref>) implemented in standard SQL <ref type="bibr" coords="3,228.34,611.76,10.89,9.02">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,241.77,611.76,11.89,9.02" target="#b9">10]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>BM25:</head><p>(1)</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,68.58,642.27,230.54,45.32">( ) ∑ ⎟ ⎟ ⎠ ⎞ ⎜ ⎜ ⎝ ⎛ + + ⎟ ⎟ ⎟ ⎟ ⎠ ⎞ ⎜ ⎜ ⎜ ⎜ ⎝ ⎛ + + - + ⎟ ⎟ ⎠ ⎞ ⎜ ⎜ ⎝ ⎛ + + - wq q d tf k tfq k tfd avgDocLen docLen b b k tf k df df N 3 3 1 * ) 1 ( ) ( * ) 1 ( * 1 * 1 5 . 0 5 .</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="0">ln</head><p>Note: We used k1=1.4, k2=0, k3=7, and b=0.75 <ref type="bibr" coords="3,244.50,706.77,9.53,8.10">[7]</ref>.</p><p>Next, using the top 1000 paragraphs we perform a concept search as follows:</p><p>1. The position of all term variants of each concept is retrieved from the dimensional index by paragraph. 2. A concept graph is constructed by creating an adjacency list using each concept term as a vertex. 3. A minimum-spanning tree is constructed from the adjacency list by determining the maximum number of distinct concepts within the shortest lexical distance. Distance measurements are weighted such that terms within a lexical unit, e.g., a sentence, are always closer than terms in separate units. 4. Finally, the passage boundary based on the first and last occurrences of distinct concepts is expanded out to include sentence boundaries. Passage level concept search is further illustrated with the following query: "Exact reactions that take place when you do glutathione S-transferase (GST) cleavage during affinity chromatography".</p><p>First, the following concepts and term variants (shown in stemmed form) are identified:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,331.56,342.56,208.02,29.69">• Cleavage: [[cleavag], [merogenesi], [cytokinesi]] • Affinity purification: [affin, purif], [affin, chromatographi]] • Glutathione S-transferase: [[glutathion, s, transferase], [gst]]</formula><p>Second, the index is searched for all term variants of each concept. The following query searches for the concept term variant "affinity, chromatography": select i1.term as term1, i2.term as term2, p1.docid, p1.parid, p1.sentid, p1.startpos, p1.endpos from invertedindex i1, invertedindex i2, postinglist p1, postinglist p2 where i1.term='affin' and i2.term='chromatographi' and i1.termid=p1.termid and i2.termid=p2.termid and p1.docid=p2.docid and p1.parid=p2.parid and p1.sentid=p2.sentid and abs(p2.seq-p1.seq)&lt;=2; Third, passages are identified: "affinity chromatography, and purified <ref type="figure" coords="3,370.61,525.24,28.41,9.02" target="#fig_1">Mce1A</ref> and<ref type="figure" coords="3,419.90,525.24,25.77,9.02" target="#fig_1">Mce1E</ref>, free of the fusion partner, were recovered following specific proteolytic cleavage of the GST" Finally, passages are expanded to sentence boundaries: "The fusion proteins were purified to near homogeneity by affinity chromatography, and purified <ref type="figure" coords="3,477.74,587.94,28.42,9.02" target="#fig_1">Mce1A</ref> and<ref type="figure" coords="3,527.11,587.94,25.78,9.02" target="#fig_1">Mce1E</ref>, free of the fusion partner, were recovered following specific proteolytic cleavage of the GST portion by thrombin protease."</p><p>The following similarity coefficients (SC) are identified for each candidate passage: • Number of distinct concepts for the entire passage weighted by the likelihood of the words in the sentence containing the concept.</p><p>• The normalized sum of the normalized IDF's of each concept within the passage. • Number of distinct concepts for the top sentence within the passage weighted by the likelihood of the words in the sentence containing the concept. • The normalized sum of the normalized IDF's of each concept within the top sentence within the passage.</p><p>A linear weighted sum ( <ref type="formula" coords="4,163.00,166.44,3.91,9.02">2</ref>) is used to generate various retrieval models by weighting and combining similarity coefficients (SC) for each passage.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="4,69.78,205.23,205.72,8.95">SC composite = w 1 SC 1 + w 2 SC 2 + …+ w n SC n (2)</formula><p>Passages with the same SC composite are ranked by the passage's lexical distance, i.e., the width of the MST of distinct concept instances.</p><p>Finally, we apply Stanford's dependency grammar parser to identify subject/object complements between queries and passage sentences <ref type="bibr" coords="4,134.61,282.66,15.35,9.02" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. Dependencies are motivated by grammatical function, i.e., syntactically and semantically.</p><p>A word depends on another if it is either a complement or a modifier of the latter. If we can identify the modifier of the object of the original query, we increase the likelihood of answering the query. For example, for query 201: What [mutations] in the Raf gene are associated with cancer?</p><p>We retrieved the following passage MST: …melanoma cell lines with B-RAF and N-RAS mutations… for which we can identify dependencies between the modifiers B-RAF and N-RAS and the object of the sentence mutations which was the subject of the original query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Results</head><p>Retrieval model weighting and similarity coefficients for each submitted run are summarized in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,259.02,460.20,3.77,9.02" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. IITx1 emphasizes passage level weighting, while IITx2 emphasizes weighting the top scoring sentence for each passage. IITx2 also used dependency grammar rank boosting. IITx3 used the IITx1 retrieval model with dependency grammar boosting.</p><p>The results for are three automatically generated runs are summarized in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,153.30,546.30,3.77,9.02" target="#tab_2">3</ref>. All three results significantly outperformed the median results for the track, including the character-based passage retrieval measurement we sought to optimize. We believe the heavy emphasize of our retrieval functions on identifying distinct biological concepts helped precision for passage retrieval, but otherwise reduced recall for document, aspect, and the passage2 measurement. Integrating the query term density measurement we utilized with last year's track <ref type="bibr" coords="4,253.31,639.90,11.71,9.02" target="#b2">[2]</ref> would most likely improve these scores.</p><p>We also discovered an error in our database software where frequently occurring terms were not stored in our index. Such terms included gene and protein. The corrected results for IITx3 are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,241.98,702.60,3.77,9.02" target="#tab_3">4</ref>. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,54.00,355.39,176.60,7.18;2,92.58,368.58,176.46,221.76"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. Search index based on dimensional model.</figDesc><graphic coords="2,92.58,368.58,176.46,221.76" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="2,335.88,622.62,222.19,9.02;2,335.88,634.32,179.98,9.02;2,335.88,648.00,215.67,9.02;2,551.52,645.91,6.48,5.83;2,335.88,659.70,222.11,9.02;2,335.88,671.40,222.17,9.02;2,335.88,683.10,222.16,9.02;2,335.88,694.80,131.13,9.02;3,72.00,74.58,222.11,9.02;3,72.00,86.28,45.46,9.02;3,72.00,99.96,222.19,9.02;3,72.00,111.66,222.11,9.02;3,72.00,123.36,222.12,9.02;3,72.00,135.06,56.73,9.02;3,72.00,148.74,222.12,9.02;3,72.00,160.44,215.80,9.02;3,287.76,158.35,6.35,5.83;3,72.00,172.14,222.14,9.02;3,72.00,183.84,222.13,9.02;3,72.00,195.54,222.17,9.02;3,72.00,207.24,202.35,9.02"><head>1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Sentences are extracted, acronyms and their long forms are identified: PRNP (PRioN Protein). 2. Part-of-speed tagging is performed using our 2 nd order statistical Hidden Markov Model tagger: … role_NN of_II the_DD gene_NN PRNP_NN (_( prion_NN protein_NN )_) in_II the_DD disease_NN Mad_NN Cow_NN Disease_NN. 3. Stop and function words are removed from further processing. 4. Candidate entities are identified by locating nonrecursive noun phrases ("noun chunks"): [gene PRNP], [prion protein], [Mad_NN Cow_NN Disease_NN]. 5. Candidate entities are verified in the index, and resolved using the UMLS Metathesaurus®, OMIM ™ (Online Mendelian Interface to Man), MeSH (Medical Subject Headings), and Entrez Gene databases. If an entity is successfully resolved, all synonyms and one level of hyponyms, i.e., child terms, are identified.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,54.00,421.45,220.54,128.24"><head>Table 1 -Retrieval function weighting and similarity coefficients</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="3,66.96,438.75,202.45,110.94"><row><cell>Resolved concepts</cell><cell>Synonyms</cell></row><row><cell>[Encephalopathy, Bovine</cell><cell>[Mad Cow Disease]</cell></row><row><cell>Spongiform]</cell><cell>[MCD]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[BSE]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[CJD]</cell></row><row><cell>[PRNP gene]</cell><cell>[prion protein]</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>[prnp]</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,317.88,74.23,212.91,174.94"><head>Table 2 -Retrieval model weighting and similarity coefficients</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="4,350.82,95.35,171.01,153.82"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>Retrieval Function</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.45*distinct number of passage concepts +</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.05*distinct number of sentence concepts +</cell></row><row><cell>iitx1</cell><cell>0.45*passage norm IDF sum +</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.05*sentence norm IDF sum</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>no dependency grammar passage rank boost</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.05*distinct number of passage concepts +</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.45*distinct number of sentence concepts +</cell></row><row><cell>iitx2</cell><cell>0.05*passage norm IDF sum +</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.45*sentence norm IDF sum</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>dependency grammar passage rank boost</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.45*distinct number of passage concepts +</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.05*distinct number of sentence concepts +</cell></row><row><cell>iitx3</cell><cell>0.45*passage norm IDF sum +</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.05*sentence norm IDF sum</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>dependency grammar passage rank boost</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="4,317.88,264.07,239.92,94.18"><head>Table 3 -Results for runs submitted to TREC (% above track median)</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="4,322.80,282.49,228.65,75.76"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>Document MAP</cell><cell>Aspect MAP</cell><cell>Passage MAP</cell><cell>Passage2 MAP</cell></row><row><cell>iitx1</cell><cell>0.2454 (31.15%)</cell><cell>0.1272 (18.06%)</cell><cell>0.0852 (75.27%)</cell><cell>0.0388 (39.82%)</cell></row><row><cell>iitx2</cell><cell>0.2462 (31.60%)</cell><cell>0.1166 (8.16%)</cell><cell>0.0926 (90.38%)</cell><cell>0.0335 (20.56%)</cell></row><row><cell>iitx3</cell><cell>0.2414 (28.99%)</cell><cell>0.1253 (16.25%)</cell><cell>0.0940 (93.22%)</cell><cell>0.0443 (59.30%)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="4,317.88,373.15,260.57,44.62"><head>Table 4 -Corrected run Corrected Run</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="4,322.80,390.25,255.65,27.52"><row><cell></cell><cell>Document</cell><cell></cell><cell>Passage</cell><cell>Passage2</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>Aspect MAP</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>MAP</cell></row><row><cell>iitx3</cell><cell>0.2670</cell><cell>0.1662</cell><cell>0.1060</cell><cell>0.0616</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,322.38,430.58,67.74,10.80" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>References</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,320.88,450.61,232.60,7.18;4,317.88,460.03,228.35,7.18" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,384.67,450.61,119.79,7.18">TREC 2007 Genomics track overview</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hersh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,513.51,450.61,39.96,7.18;4,317.88,460.03,141.32,7.18">Proceedings of the Fourteenth Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>the Fourteenth Text REtrieval Conference<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,320.88,469.63,237.11,7.18;4,317.88,479.05,225.09,7.18" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,465.29,469.63,92.70,7.18;4,317.88,479.05,17.92,7.18">IIT TREC-2006: Genomics Track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Urbain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Goharian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Frieder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,344.95,479.05,176.52,7.18">Proceedings of the Fifteenth Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>the Fifteenth Text REtrieval Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,320.88,507.67,237.08,7.18;4,317.88,517.09,240.11,7.18;4,317.88,526.51,240.17,7.18;4,317.88,535.93,156.75,7.18" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,395.92,517.09,162.07,7.18;4,317.88,526.51,240.17,7.18;4,317.88,535.93,69.02,7.18">Data Cube: A Relational Aggregation Operator Generalizing Group-By, Cross-Tab, and Sub-Totals. Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chaudhuri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bosworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Layman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Reichart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Venckatrao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Pells</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,320.88,545.53,237.16,7.18;4,317.88,554.95,218.89,7.18" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,372.68,545.53,185.35,7.18;4,317.88,554.95,128.49,7.18">The Data Warehouse Toolkit: Practical Techniques for Building Dimensional Data Warehouses</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kimball ; Ralph</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Wiley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,320.88,564.55,237.09,7.18;4,317.88,573.97,240.14,7.18;4,317.88,583.39,67.00,7.18" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,431.60,564.55,126.36,7.18;4,317.88,573.97,150.65,7.18">A simple algorithm for identifying abbreviation definitions in biomedical text</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hearst</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,480.00,573.97,78.02,7.18;4,317.88,583.39,43.38,7.18">Pacific Symposium on Biocomputing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,320.88,592.99,237.12,7.18;4,317.88,602.41,79.30,7.18" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,420.33,592.99,130.41,7.18">A Relational Genomics Search Engine</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Urbain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Goharian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,317.88,602.41,35.97,7.18">BIOCOMP</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,320.88,612.01,237.07,7.18;4,317.88,621.43,34.10,7.18" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,377.17,612.01,109.91,7.18">An algorithm for suffix stripping</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,496.94,612.01,27.04,7.18">Program</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="130" to="137" />
			<date type="published" when="1980">1980</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,320.88,631.03,237.13,7.18;4,317.88,640.45,88.20,7.18" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,415.15,631.03,88.70,7.18">Okapi/Keenbow at TREC-8</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,515.00,631.03,43.01,7.18;4,317.88,640.45,37.45,7.18">NIST Special Publication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="500" to="246" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,324.55,650.05,233.44,7.18;4,317.88,659.47,240.11,7.18;4,317.88,668.89,70.16,7.18" xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,427.77,650.05,130.22,7.18;4,317.88,659.47,32.82,7.18">Information Retrieval: Algorithms and Heuristics</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Grossman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Frieder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<publisher>Springer Publishers</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="4020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Second Edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,324.55,678.49,233.43,7.18;4,317.88,687.91,240.09,7.18;4,317.88,697.33,105.74,7.18" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,377.14,687.91,180.84,7.18;4,317.88,697.33,52.22,7.18">Generating Typed Dependency Parses from Phrase Structure Parses</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Marie-Catherine</forename><surname>De Marneffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Maccartney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,384.11,697.33,19.50,7.18">LREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006. 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
