<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,99.24,58.51,413.50,16.20">The Open University at TREC 2007 Enterprise Track</title>
				<funder ref="#_tT9HpFp">
					<orgName type="full">IBM</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_BHpdqUp">
					<orgName type="full">JISC (Joint Information Systems Committee)</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,203.28,86.96,62.49,10.80"><forename type="first">Jianhan</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
							<email>j.zhu@open.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Knowledge Media Institute and Centre for Research in Computing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">The Open University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,274.82,86.96,57.59,10.80"><forename type="first">Dawei</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
							<email>d.song@open.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Knowledge Media Institute and Centre for Research in Computing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">The Open University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,341.08,86.96,67.64,10.80"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Rüger</surname></persName>
							<email>s.rueger@open.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Knowledge Media Institute and Centre for Research in Computing</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">The Open University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,99.24,58.51,413.50,16.20">The Open University at TREC 2007 Enterprise Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">8D147E1EE961EF0914A7DA32D9C679DB</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:04+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The Multimedia and Information Systems group at the Knowledge Media Institute of the Open University participated in the Expert Search and Document Search tasks of the Enterprise Track in TREC 2007. In both the document and expert search tasks, we have studied the effect of anchor texts in addition to document contents, document authority, url length, query expansion, and relevance feedback in improving search effectiveness. In the expert search task, we have continued using a two-stage language model consisting of a document relevance and co-occurrence models. The document relevance model is equivalent to our approach in the document search task. We have used our innovative multiple-window-based cooccurrence approach. The assumption is that there are multiple levels of associations between an expert and his/her expertise. Our experimental results show that the introduction of additional features in addition to document contents has improved the retrieval effectiveness.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">INTRODUCTION</head><p>In this year's enterprise track, the domain is the website of the CSIRO (Australian Commonwealth Scientific and Research Organization). The task is to find a number of key pages on a topic and a few key experts on the topic in order for a science communicator to create an overview page for the topic. For example, find key experts and key pages on "genetic modification".</p><p>Unlike last year's expert search task on the W3C (World Wide Web Consortium) website dataset, expert search on the CSIRO dataset aims to find only a few key contacts on a topic, while expert search on the W3C dataset can find a larger number of experts. Expert search on the CSIRO dataset is judged based on the ground truth provided by science communicators, while expert search results on the W3C dataset were pooled and manually judged by participating groups. Therefore, expert search task this year tends to be more challenging than last year, since the retrieval system needs to not only identify experts on a topic but also rank key contacts among these experts higher than the other non-key contacts.</p><p>Another challenge in expert search is that there is not a given list of candidates like in previous two years. This is more like a real world expert search scenario, where there is not a centralized database for maintaining all employees working at an organization. The named entity recognition task gets easier given that all CSIRO staff's email addresses follow the pattern "firstname.lastname@csiro.au". However, one person may have several emails. A mechanism for grouping different emails and name variants under a same person needs to be studied.</p><p>A new task in this year's enterprise track is key document search. The task is to identify a few key pages on a topic that a science communicator can put on an overview page about the topic. A key page needs to be not only relevant but also highly authoritative on a topic. This task is similar to the topic distillation task in TREC Web Track. The challenge in document search is how to identify key pages from a large number of documents which are all relevant to the topic on different degrees.</p><p>Based on our success in last year's expert search task, we will further investigate the effect of integrating multiple document features in this year's expert and document search.</p><p>In both the document and expert search tasks, we have studied the effect of anchor texts in addition to document contents, document authority, url length, query expansion, and relevance feedback in improving search effectiveness and the weighting of the above components in the final document relevance to a topic.</p><p>In the expert search task, we have continued using a two-stage model consisting of a document relevance model and a co-occurrence model. The document relevance model is equivalent to our approach in the document search task. We have used our innovative multiple window based cooccurrence approach <ref type="bibr" coords="1,425.54,609.02,11.58,9.88" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. The assumption is that there are multiple levels of associations between an expert and his/her expertise. We give higher weights to co-occurrences in smaller windows and lower weights to co-occurrences in larger windows. We have studied different weighting scheme in the multiple-window approach.</p><p>In expert name recognition, we have use a clustering algorithm to group email addresses that belong to the same person. We have developed an automatic method for generating variants of an experts' name.</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows. We present our document search approach integrating multiple document features in Section 2. A two stage approach consisting of a document relevance model and a co-occurrence model is presented in Section 3. We report our experimental results in Section 4, and conclude in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">DOCUMENT SEARCH</head><p>Anchor texts in addition to document contents, document authority, url length, query expansion, and relevance feedback are considered in document search.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Anchor texts and document content</head><p>Anchor texts describe how the others think about a document in a pithy way. We have studied whether anchor texts will improve retrieval results and use different weightings of the contribution of anchor texts and document content in document relevance respectively.</p><p>All anchor texts of a document are aggregated together to form an overall anchor text field of the document. A document's relevance to a query is a weighted sum of the relevance of the document's overall anchor text field to the query and the relevance of the document's content to the query. We give higher weight to the anchor text based relevance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Inlinks and Outlinks</head><p>We study the effect of inlinks and outlinks in document retrieval. Typically, the number of inlinks of a document is an indicator of the document's authority. Previous work shows that there is a strong correlation between the number of inlinks and PageRank <ref type="bibr" coords="2,54.00,567.67,11.55,9.88" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. We have combined the number of in-links of a document with the document's content-based relevance. Based on previous work of integrating Pag-eRank in document relevance <ref type="bibr" coords="2,188.84,605.83,11.55,9.88" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, we have taken the logarithm of the number of inlinks in the combination.</p><p>As overview pages on a topic are good candidates and they typically have a relatively large number of outlinks, we have studied whether taking into account outlinks can help improve retrieval effec-tiveness. Our initial results show that outlinks are not very helpful.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">URL length</head><p>The length of the URL of a document shows the depth of the document in the URL hierarchy of a website. Our observation is that authoritative and overview pages on a topic tend to be higher up in the hierarchy. This can be due to various reasons such as that shorter URLs are easy to remember and that document authors tend to assign shorter URLs to key pages which link to a number of pages covering more detailed information on the topic.</p><p>We have combined the URL length of a document with the document content-based relevance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Query expansion</head><p>Narrative part of a topic has been used to enhance document search.</p><p>In our automatic runs, a document's relevance to a topic is a weighted sum of the document's relevance to the query part of the topic and the document relevance to the narrative part of the topic.</p><p>In our manual runs, the narrative part of a topic was manually modified. A document's relevance to a topic is a weighted sum of the document's relevance to the query part of the topic and the document relevance to the modified narrative part of the topic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Relevance feedback</head><p>Relevance feedback in terms of using the given key pages to improve the retrieval effectiveness is considered.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">EXPERT SEARCH</head><p>We continue to adopt a two-stage approach in expert retrieval. The two-stage model consists of a document relevance model and a co-occurrence model. The document relevance model is equivalent to the model used in the document search task.</p><p>Since the document relevance model has taken into account anchor texts, document authority, url length, query expansion, and relevance feedback, we hypothesize that people appearing in more relevance document are more likely than the other people who do not.</p><p>We have continued to use our innovative multiple window based co-occurrence model. A number of windows of different sizes are applied in the cooccurrence model consecutively. The assumption is that there are multiple levels of associations between an expert and a topic, e.g., sentence, paragraph, sec-tion, …, up to a whole document level. Given a text window, if a person and query terms co-occur, the probability that the person and the topic are associated is higher when the window size is small than the case when the window size is large.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">NAMED ENTITY RECOGNITION</head><p>In expert name recognition from the documents, we use a pattern to find all email addresses ending with ".csiro.au". We will get a large number of email addresses to which we apply a clustering algorithm for grouping email addresses belong to the same person together. The clustering algorithm is based on a similarity measure between each pair of email addresses. The similarity measure is defined based on whether two email addresses share the same last name, the same initials, the same last and first name but one have the middle name but the other does not have the middle name etc.</p><p>For each expert, we generate his/her first, last, and possibly middle names based on his/her email addresses. Given the person's name, we generate variants of his/her names. All identifies of a person is matched against the whole corpus for finding out occurrences of the person in the whole corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">EXPERIMENTAL RESULTS</head><p>We have applied our approach to the CSIRO dataset to get four document search runs and four expert search runs for submission. Based our training on the W3C dataset, we have used give incremental text windows for all four runs, i.e., size 5, 20, 80, 200, and 400. Anchor texts, inlinks, and URL length are all considered in the four runs. Descriptions of the four submitted document search runs in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,265.40,489.19,5.49,9.88" target="#tab_0">1</ref> are as follows.</p><p>ouTopicOnly: Only query part of each topic is used in this automatic run. ouNarrAuto: Narrative part of each topic is used directly in this automatic run. Document relevance to the query part and document relevance to the narrative part are combined for the overall relevance score.</p><p>ouNarr: Narrative part of each topic is manually modified in this manual run. Document relevance to the query part and document relevance to the modified narrative part are combined for the overall relevance score. ouNarrRF: Narrative part of each topic is manually modified in this manual run. Document relevance to the query part and document relevance to the modi-fied narrative part are combined in addition to relevance feedback for the overall relevance score. After TREC 2007, we found that there is a mistake in our expert name extraction component for recognizing anti-spam enabled email addresses which results in 73 experts not been recognized in the corpus.</p><p>After correcting the mistake, we re-ran our experiments with the exact same settings as our four submitted runs, respectively, and got the results shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,95.97,253.57,4.12,9.88" target="#tab_2">3</ref>. We can see that the performance of all four runs is largely improved. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,324.00,86.47,234.05,385.65"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Document Search Results (The best results for each measure is in bold and underlined)</figDesc><table coords="3,324.00,116.40,234.05,355.73"><row><cell>Runs</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>R-Prec Bpref P@10</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">ouTopicOnly 0.3326 0.3734 0.3503 0.5333</cell></row><row><cell>ouNarrAuto</cell><cell cols="2">0.3137 0.3391 0.3416 0.5238</cell></row><row><cell>ouNarr</cell><cell cols="2">0.3591 0.3962 0.3682 0.5643</cell></row><row><cell>ouNarrRF</cell><cell cols="2">0.3703 0.4017 0.3793 0.5762</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Descriptions of the four submitted expert search runs</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">in Table 2 are as follows.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">ouExTitle: Only query part of each topic is used in</cell></row><row><cell>this automatic run.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">ouExNarrAu: Narrative part of each topic is used</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">directly in this automatic run. Document relevance</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">to the query part and document relevance to the nar-</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">rative part are combined for the overall relevance</cell></row><row><cell>score.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">ouExNarr: Narrative part of each topic is manually</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">modified in this manual run. Document relevance to</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">the query part and document relevance to the modi-</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">fied narrative part are combined for the overall rele-</cell></row><row><cell>vance score.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">ouExNarrRF: Narrative part of each topic is manu-</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">ally modified in this manual run. Document rele-</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">vance to the query part and document relevance to</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">the modified narrative part are combined in addition</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">to relevance feedback for the overall relevance</cell></row><row><cell>score.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,325.32,479.23,230.11,97.95"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Expert Search Results (The best results for each measure is in bold and underlined)From both Table1and 2, we can see that the direct introduction of narrative part in retrieval has negative effective showing that direct use of narrative will introduce more noise than informative keywords. Modified narrative part has help improve both search tasks showing that narrative part contains additional useful information for determining key pages on a topic.</figDesc><table coords="3,325.32,508.83,223.26,68.34"><row><cell>Runs</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell cols="2">R-Prec Bpref</cell><cell>P@10</cell></row><row><cell>ouExTitle</cell><cell>0.4337</cell><cell>0.3704</cell><cell>0.8224</cell><cell>0.1560</cell></row><row><cell>ouExNarrAu</cell><cell>0.4164</cell><cell>0.3514</cell><cell>0.7851</cell><cell>0.1560</cell></row><row><cell>ouExNarr</cell><cell>0.4675</cell><cell>0.4104</cell><cell>0.8391</cell><cell>0.1640</cell></row><row><cell>ouExNarrRF</cell><cell>0.4787</cell><cell>0.4147</cell><cell>0.8457</cell><cell>0.1640</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="4,54.00,279.25,234.08,210.34"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Re-run expert search results after TREC 2007 (The best results for each measure is in bold and underlined) We have participated in both document search and expert search tasks of TREC 2007 Enterprise Track. Our two stage modeling approach has integrated multiple document features in addition to our innovative multiple window based co-occurrence model for effective document and expert search.</figDesc><table coords="4,54.00,321.57,224.59,91.75"><row><cell>Runs</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell cols="2">R-Prec Bpref</cell><cell>P@10</cell></row><row><cell>ouExTitle-Re</cell><cell>0.4807</cell><cell>0.3914</cell><cell>0.9118</cell><cell>0.1642</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ouExNarrAu-Re 0.4657</cell><cell>0.3742</cell><cell>0.4756</cell><cell>0.1643</cell></row><row><cell>ouExNarr-Re</cell><cell>0.5256</cell><cell>0.4480</cell><cell>0.9384</cell><cell>0.1798</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ouExNarrRF-Re 0.5331</cell><cell>0.4580</cell><cell>0.9391</cell><cell>0.1780</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">6. CONCLUSIONS</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</head><p>The work reported in this paper is funded in part by an <rs type="funder">IBM</rs> <rs type="grantName">UIMA innovation award</rs> and the <rs type="funder">JISC (Joint Information Systems Committee)</rs> funded <rs type="projectName">DYNIQX (Metadata-based DYNamIc Query Interface for Cross</rs>(X)-searching content resources) project.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_tT9HpFp">
					<orgName type="grant-name">UIMA innovation award</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_BHpdqUp">
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">DYNIQX (Metadata-based DYNamIc Query Interface for Cross</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,72.00,601.68,216.00,9.02;4,71.88,613.38,216.19,9.02;4,71.88,625.08,216.08,9.02;4,71.88,636.78,216.11,9.02;4,71.88,648.48,84.41,9.02" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,244.55,613.38,43.51,9.02;4,71.88,625.08,200.83,9.02">PageRank: HITS and a Unified Framework for Link Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">Q</forename><surname>Chris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Xiaofeng</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Parry</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hongyuan</forename><surname>Husbands</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Horst</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Zha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,71.88,636.78,216.11,9.02;4,71.88,648.48,79.25,9.02">Proc. of Third SIAM International Conference on Data Mining (SDM)</title>
		<meeting>of Third SIAM International Conference on Data Mining (SDM)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,72.00,663.18,215.98,9.02;4,71.88,674.88,216.08,9.02;4,71.88,686.58,216.21,9.02;4,71.88,698.28,216.24,9.02;4,71.88,709.98,22.65,9.02" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,207.61,674.88,80.36,9.02;4,71.88,686.58,216.21,9.02;4,71.88,698.28,18.10,9.02">Microsoft Research Asia at Web Track and Terabyte Track of TREC 2004</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ruihua</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ji-Rong</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Shuming</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Guomao</forename><surname>Xin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Tie-Yan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,107.95,698.28,180.17,9.02">Proc. of Text REtrieval Conference (TREC)</title>
		<meeting>of Text REtrieval Conference (TREC)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004. 2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,342.00,56.58,216.00,9.02;4,341.88,68.28,216.12,9.02;4,341.88,79.98,216.10,9.02;4,341.88,91.68,206.67,9.02" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,411.86,68.28,146.14,9.02;4,341.88,79.98,147.35,9.02">The Open University at TREC 2006 Enterprise Track Expert Search Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Rüger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Eisenstadt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Motta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,507.55,79.98,50.44,9.02;4,341.88,91.68,146.75,9.02">Proc. of The Fifteenth Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>of The Fifteenth Text REtrieval Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>TREC</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006. 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
