<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,137.25,116.00,340.87,12.91;1,206.72,133.93,201.92,12.91">The Robert Gordon University at the Opinion Retrieval Task of the 2007 Trec Blog Track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,199.58,171.94,63.91,8.97"><forename type="first">Rahman</forename><surname>Mukras</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing The</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Robert Gordon University St Andrew Street Aberdeen UK</addrLine>
									<postCode>AB25 1HG</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,270.68,171.94,77.58,8.97"><forename type="first">Nirmalie</forename><surname>Wiratunga</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing The</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Robert Gordon University St Andrew Street Aberdeen UK</addrLine>
									<postCode>AB25 1HG</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,355.18,171.94,60.59,8.97"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Lothian</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing The</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Robert Gordon University St Andrew Street Aberdeen UK</addrLine>
									<postCode>AB25 1HG</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,137.25,116.00,340.87,12.91;1,206.72,133.93,201.92,12.91">The Robert Gordon University at the Opinion Retrieval Task of the 2007 Trec Blog Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">45ABAFC376BCBD97811B21D0E8105F16</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:04+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The Robert Gordon University (RGU) participated in the Opinion Retrieval Task of the Trec 2007 Blog Track. At the core of the system we developed is a set of training documents labeled with respect to opinion. These documents are used to train a classifier in order to classify the documents that are relevant to the given Trec topics. However, a major limitation with these training documents is that they are not always generic enough to serve as good training examples for all the 50 Trec topics. We therefore propose a solution that generalizes their content by exploiting the context of opinion related language constructs such as adjectives, verbs, and adverbs. Our system significantly improves over RGU's previous Blog Track systems.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The simplicity of Internet publishing has resulted in individuals postings up their thoughts in a variety of different forms in an almost uncontrollable manner. Furthermore, many of these postings remain largely unmonitored. One particular publishing form of interest is Blogs (short for Web-log). Blogs have been claimed to be the latest form of self expression and it has been noted that they are rapidly changing the face of the Web.</p><p>The key aspect of Blogs that makes them attractive is that they are mainly authored by independent individuals, with the sole purpose of making their opinions known to the world. Consequently, Blogs are highly rich in opinion and are often in sync with current affairs. This factor makes them quite useful to industries such as marketing or the media where direct feedback is an invaluable resource.</p><p>The collection used in both the 2006 and 2007 Blog Tracks <ref type="bibr" coords="1,394.88,560.47,11.62,8.97" target="#b3">[4]</ref> consists of over a three million blog posts collected over 77 days. It was meant to be a realistic snapshot of the blogosphere and hence offers an excellent test-bed for Blog analysis research. This study addresses the opinion retrieval task of the 2007 Blog Track <ref type="bibr" coords="1,392.96,596.34,10.58,8.97" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. This task was first introduced in Trec 2006. It basically involves retrieving opinionated documents that are relevant to each of the 50 predefined Trec topics regardless of their opinion orientation. Each retrieved document should, however, be assigned to a real-valued opinion score in the range of [0 . . . 1], where 0 signifies a neutral opinion, whereas 1 signifies an extreme opinion that could be either positive or negative. The idea we present to address this task is composed of two phases that draw from both Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Information Retrieval (IR). Our technique basically exploits the context of opinion related language constructs, such as adjectives verbs and adverbs, to identify and rank opinionated texts within the collection. These language constructs were chosen primarily because they are commonly associated with opinion rich contexts. For instance, an adjective such as "great" would typically occur within contexts such as "great player," or "great disaster."</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Retain Relevant</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Contexts</head><p>In the first phase of the procedure, Part-of-Speech (PoS) tags are assigned to the words (features) contained in a set of training documents that are labeled with respect to opinion. These documents are then pruned such that only a set of selected words, along with their respective contexts, are retained. Proper nouns are also omitted as they tend to be domain specific <ref type="bibr" coords="2,241.75,471.76,10.58,8.97" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. This results in a corpus with a high precision of opinion rich phrases that are relatively domain independent. The documents of the resultant corpus are then mapped onto a vector space <ref type="bibr" coords="2,311.61,495.67,11.62,8.97" target="#b7">[8]</ref> after which a regression based Support Vector Machine (SVM) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,231.32,507.63,11.62,8.97" target="#b2">[3]</ref> is trained on the resultant document vectors.</p><p>In the second and last phase, a Lucene search engine is used to retrieve all documents, from the Trec Blog collection, that are relevant to the current topic of interest. The regression based SVM is then used to assign each of these documents to an opinion score, and this completes a single Trec run.</p><p>The remainder of this paper is organized as follows. Section 2 describes the two phase procedure in more detail. The Implementation specifications are then presented in Section 3. Finally, the Conclusions and Future Work appear in Section 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The Opinion Retrieval System</head><p>A complete overview of our opinion retrieval system has been illustrated in Fig. <ref type="figure" coords="2,462.85,644.17,3.73,8.97" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. A crucial resource for this system is the background set of training documents that are labeled with respect to opinion. Each of these labels assumes a value in the ordered set {c 1 , . . . , c n }, where c 1 &lt; c n and c 1 , c n respectively represent an extreme negative and positive opinion.</p><p>These training documents offer a good estimate of the structure and content of opinion rich texts. However, one limitation with them is that they may not be general enough to suffice as good document examples for each of the 50 Trec topics. To tackle this problem, we applied a procedure that retains the relevant contexts of language constructs such as adjectives verbs and adverbs. The hypothesis behind this is based on the fact that these constructs act as the transmitters, rather than the objects, of an opinion. Consequently, they would be used in much the same way across various domains. This type of pruning would therefore generalize the opinions expressed within the training documents.</p><p>To retain the relevant contexts, we first applied PoS tags to the text within the training documents by using the RASP PoS tagger <ref type="bibr" coords="3,328.04,276.23,10.58,8.97" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. We then retained a context of 10 words on either side of each word that was tagged as an adjective, verb, or adverb i.e: JJT, JJ, JJR, VV0, RR, RG, RGA, RGR<ref type="foot" coords="3,301.91,298.56,3.49,6.28" target="#foot_0">1</ref> . We, however, did not retain any singular or plural proper nouns (NP, NP1, NP2) as these tend to be domain specific <ref type="bibr" coords="3,442.31,312.09,10.58,8.97" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. Once the training documents were pruned, we then mapped them onto a vector space whose dimensions, or features, were determined by the Information Gain measure <ref type="bibr" coords="3,437.95,336.01,15.27,8.97" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. A regression based SVM was then trained on the resultant document vectors.</p><p>Finally, given a list of documents from the Trec Blog Corpus that are relevant to a Trec topic, the regression based SVM was used to assign the i th document in this list to a score q i that assumes a real-value in the range [c 1 . . . c n ]. Note, however, that the Trec rules require that the score q i be mapped onto the range of [0 . . . 1], where 0 signifies a neutral opinion, whereas 1 signifies an extreme opinion that could be either positive or negative. In order to accomplish this, we mapped the score of the i th document to the value 2 qi-c1 cn-c1 -1 which satisfies the Trec requirement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Implementation</head><p>In order to prepare the Trec Blog collection, we first extracted the text from the initial HTML format discarding all tokens that contained non-printable characters. We then preprocessed it using the sequence of tokenization, conversion to lowercase, stemming and stopword removal (The 50 Trec topics also went through the same preprocessing steps). We finally indexed the resultant collection, containing 2,466,650 documents, using the Lucene<ref type="foot" coords="3,204.30,560.04,3.49,6.28" target="#foot_1">2</ref> search engine. This entire procedure lasted 46 continuous days on standard hardware running on a Ubuntu Linux platform.</p><p>The second task was to prepare the opinionated training datasets. These were four in number namely: The Edmunds dataset <ref type="bibr" coords="3,308.91,598.39,11.62,8.97" target="#b5">[6]</ref> with classes {1, . . . , 26}, the Rateitall dataset <ref type="bibr" coords="3,165.70,610.34,11.62,8.97" target="#b1">[2]</ref> with classes {1, . . . , 5}, the Scale dataset <ref type="bibr" coords="3,351.57,610.34,11.62,8.97" target="#b6">[7]</ref> with classes {1, . . . , 8}, and the documents that constituted the results of the Trec 2006 polarity task which had classes {0, . . . , 4}. Note, however, that we only used classes 2, 3, and 4 which respectively correspond to a negative, a neutral, and a positive opinion. All four datasets were preprocessed in the similar fashion using the sequence of tokenization, PoS tagging, conversion to lower case, stemming, and stopword removal.</p><p>Once the four training datasets were ready, their contexts were pruned as discussed in the previous section. They were then used, in succession, to train a regression based SVM in order to classify the documents that were relevant to the 50 Trec topics. The outcome of the four train-classify sessions formed the basis of four of the runs that we submitted to Trec. The fifth run was based on plain relevance retrieval. The following list is a summary of all the five runs that we submitted: Although our official Trec results were far from being the best, our highest Mean Average Precision (MAP) of 0.2798 improved significantly from our previous years result of 0.0001. Hopefully this trend will continue for successive Trec competitions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>In the Trec 2007 Block Track, our best run achieved a MAP of 0.2798. It also took seventeenth position among all the runs that were submitted by the 20 participants in terms of MAP, R-precision, b-Bref, and P@10. Although this performance leaves a great deal to be desired, our approach of exploiting the context of adjectives, verbs, and adverbs to identify opinionated text was quite innovative. For future work, we intend to build upon this approach by investigating the effect of variable sized contexts. We also intend to employ deeper NLP techniques to determine the focal point of a context, rather than simply assuming that it would always be an adjective, a verb, or an adverb.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,211.02,307.82,193.31,8.07"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. An Overview of the Opinion Retrieval System.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,139.25,248.36,290.45,8.97;4,139.25,260.30,239.71,8.97;4,139.25,272.23,235.83,8.97;4,139.25,284.16,223.65,8.97;4,139.25,296.09,254.01,8.97"><head>1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>rgu0: All opinion finding features turned off. Simply a Relevance run. 2. rgu1: Edmunds dataset used as background training data. 3. rgu2: Rateitall dataset used as background training data. 4. rgu3: Scale dataset used as background training data. 5. rgu4: Trec Polarity dataset used as background training data.</figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="3,144.73,645.63,278.88,8.07"><p>See the CLAWS2 Tagset: http://www.comp.lancs.ac.uk/ucrel/claws2tags.html</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="3,144.73,656.80,85.97,8.07"><p>http://lucene.apache.org</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,142.61,536.34,337.98,8.07;4,150.96,547.30,266.93,8.07" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,264.89,536.34,199.86,8.07">Robust Accurate Statistical Annotation of General Text</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ted</forename><surname>Briscoe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Carroll</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,150.96,547.30,50.07,8.07">Proc. of LREC</title>
		<meeting>of LREC<address><addrLine>Las Palmas, Canary Islands</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002-05">May 2002</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1499" to="1504" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,142.61,558.24,337.97,8.07;4,150.96,569.20,329.63,8.07;4,150.96,580.15,161.61,8.07" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,205.07,569.20,230.10,8.07">Supervised Latent Semantic Indexing using Adaptive Sprinkling</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sutanu</forename><surname>Chakraborti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Rahman</forename><surname>Mukras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Lothian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nirmalie</forename><surname>Wiratunga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Stuart</forename><surname>Watt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Harper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,452.04,569.20,28.55,8.07;4,150.96,580.15,19.72,8.07">Proc. of IJCAI</title>
		<meeting>of IJCAI</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>AAAI Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1582" to="1587" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,142.61,591.09,337.98,8.07;4,150.96,602.05,328.41,8.07" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,222.84,591.09,257.75,8.07;4,150.96,602.05,62.66,8.07">Text Categorization with Support Vector Machines: Learning with Many Relevant Features</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Thorsten</forename><surname>Joachims</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,230.18,602.05,51.66,8.07">Proc. of ECML</title>
		<meeting>of ECML<address><addrLine>London, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="142" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,142.61,612.99,337.97,8.07;4,150.96,623.95,329.63,8.07;4,150.96,634.90,108.70,8.07" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,276.79,612.99,203.80,8.07;4,150.96,623.95,79.98,8.07">The TREC Blogs06 Collection : Creating and Analysing a Blog Test Collection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Craig</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Iadh</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<pubPlace>Glasgow, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Department of Computing Science, University of Glasgow</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,142.61,645.84,337.98,8.07;4,150.96,656.80,100.21,8.07" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,330.50,645.84,146.29,8.07">Overview of the TREC-2007 Blog Track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Craig</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Iadh</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Soboroff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,160.67,656.80,63.26,8.07">Proc. of the TREC</title>
		<meeting>of the TREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.61,119.68,337.97,8.07;5,150.96,130.63,329.63,8.07;5,150.96,141.59,213.99,8.07" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,180.32,130.63,300.26,8.07;5,150.96,141.59,52.84,8.07">Information Gain Feature Selection for Ordinal Text Classification using Probability Re-distribution</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Rahman</forename><surname>Mukras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nirmalie</forename><surname>Wiratunga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Lothian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sutanu</forename><surname>Chakraborti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Harper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,220.26,141.59,118.08,8.07">Proc. of IJCAI Textlink Workshop</title>
		<meeting>of IJCAI Textlink Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.61,152.55,337.97,8.07;5,150.96,163.51,274.49,8.07" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,246.45,152.55,234.13,8.07;5,150.96,163.51,128.10,8.07">Seeing stars: Exploiting class relationships for sentiment categorization with respect to rating scales</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bo</forename><surname>Pang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lillian</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,295.37,163.51,44.54,8.07">Proc. of ACL</title>
		<meeting>of ACL</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="115" to="124" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.61,174.47,337.98,8.07;5,150.96,185.43,125.50,8.07" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,286.08,174.47,167.25,8.07">A Vector Space Model for Automatic Indexing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,460.67,174.47,19.92,8.07;5,150.96,185.43,35.60,8.07">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="613" to="620" />
			<date type="published" when="1975">1975</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.61,196.38,337.98,8.07;5,150.96,207.35,329.63,8.07;5,150.96,218.30,42.23,8.07" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,213.35,196.38,267.23,8.07;5,150.96,207.35,112.84,8.07">Thumbs Up or Thumbs Down? Semantic Orientation Applied to Unsupervised Classification of Reviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Turney</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,284.07,207.35,46.08,8.07">Proc. of ACL</title>
		<meeting>of ACL<address><addrLine>Morristown, NJ, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACL</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="417" to="424" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.24,229.26,338.35,8.07;5,150.96,240.22,259.61,8.07" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,278.55,229.26,202.04,8.07;5,150.96,240.22,35.08,8.07">A Comparative Study on Feature Selection in Text Categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Yiming</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jan</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Pedersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,202.49,240.22,49.66,8.07">Proc. of ICML</title>
		<meeting>of ICML</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="412" to="420" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
