<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,186.48,76.93,238.93,15.70">TREC Genomics Track at UIC</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,246.66,109.79,47.89,10.46"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<email>wzhou8@uic.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Illinois at Chicago</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,303.64,109.79,61.67,10.46"><forename type="first">Clement</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
							<email>yu@cs.uic.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Illinois at Chicago</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,186.48,76.93,238.93,15.70">TREC Genomics Track at UIC</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">1CF2F65E5B08D1F2D11972E4EA7756A8</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:04+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>We considered that a query of this year's Genomics track consists of two parts, target and qualification. A target refers to any instance of a certain entity type and the qualification refers to the condition that the target needs to satisfy in order to be qualified as an answer to the query. For example, the target and qualification of the query "What <ref type="bibr" coords="1,214.75,300.84,73.25,9.57">[ANTIBODIES]</ref> have been used to detect protein TLR4?" are "an instance of ANTIBODIES" and "have been used to detect protein TLR4", respectively. The relevance of a document to a query was measured by to what degree the document contains a target and satisfies the qualification.</p><p>We observed that for some entity types (Type I), such as "SIGNS OR SYMPTOMS", we were able to retrieve some candidate targets from some resources, such as UMLS. For example, "headache" and "cough" are found to be candidate targets of "SIGNS or SYMPTOMS" in the UMLS. For other entity types (Type II), such as "ANTIBODIES" and "PATHWAYS", we were unable to find resources to retrieve the candidate targets so far. We employed different strategies for these two types of queries.</p><p>For queries involving Type I entity types, we ask whether a document contains any candidate target and in addition, does the document match the qualification. An interesting issue is that whether different candidate targets should be differentiated according to their frequencies. Two experiments, one differentiates candidate targets and the other does not, have been carried out to investigate this issue.</p><p>For queries involving Type II entity types, we have compiled a set of representative words for each entity type. These representative words co-occur with the entity type much more often than being independent in the same sentences of PubMed abstracts. Then the raw query was expanded with the set of representative words. The intuition is that, the representative words are expected to capture the context or surrounding neighborhood within which a target of that entity type occurs and a document having that context is much likely to contain a target also. This year's task is still a passage retrieval task, where a passage could be a part of a sentence, a sentence, a set of consecutive sentences or a paragraph (i.e., the whole span of text that are inside of &lt;P&gt; and &lt;/P&gt; HTML tags). We approached the task by having two steps. The first step, document (or paragraph) retrieval, retrieves the top 2,000 paragraphs. The second step, passage retrieval, extracts passages from each paragraph and then ranks those passages according to their relevance with respect to the query. This notebook paper is organized as follows: the paragraph retrieval is introduced in section 2; the passage extraction and retrieval is presented in section 3; in section 4, we present the experiment results; and the summary is given in section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Document (or Paragraph) Retrieval</head><p>The document collection contains 162,259 Highwire full-text documents in HTML format. We partitioned each document into paragraphs by using the HTML paragraph tag &lt;p&gt; and &lt;/p&gt;. The paragraph retrieval step retrieves the top 2,000 relevant paragraphs, assuming that the top 1,000 most relevant passages can be extracted from the top 2,000 paragraphs. We employed a conceptual retrieval model <ref type="bibr" coords="1,324.00,615.00,12.84,9.57" target="#b0">[1]</ref> for the paragraph retrieval step.</p><p>We divided the 14 entity types into two groups. The first group G 1 consisting of 9 types that either correspond to some UMLS semantic types (e.g., the entity type "SIGNS OR SYMPTOMS" corresponds to the UMLS semantic type "Sign or Symptom") or can be  <ref type="table" coords="2,220.24,356.40,4.12,9.57" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Identifying Query Concepts and Retrieving Domain-specific Knowledge</head><p>To apply this conceptual retrieval model, we need to identify the query concepts (MeSH terms or gene symbols in the Entrez Gene). We use the query translation functionality of PubMed to extract MeSH terms in a query. This is done by submitting the whole query to PubMed, which will then return a file in which the MeSH terms in the query are labeled. Query terms in the Entrez Gene database were identified.</p><p>For each query concept, we retrieved its domainspecific knowledge, which refers to information about concepts and their relationships in a certain domain. We used five types of domain-specific knowledge in the domain of genomics: Type 1. Synonyms (terms listed in the thesauruses that refer to the same meaning) Type 2. Hypernyms (more generic terms, one level only) Type 3. Hyponyms (more specific terms, one level only) Type 4. Lexical variants (different forms of the same concept, such as abbreviations.</p><p>They are commonly used in the literature, but might not be listed in the thesauruses) Type 5. Implicitly related concepts (terms that are semantically related and also cooccur more frequently than being independent in the biomedical texts)</p><p>Knowledge of type 1-3 is retrieved from the following two thesauruses: </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Retrieval Models for G 1 Type of Queries</head><p>A query q involving an entity type of G 1 , the query can be written as:</p><p>{ } </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model 1</head><p>The similarity between query q and document d is measured on two levels: the concept level and word level. The concept-level similarity is obtained by matching targets and query concepts, while the word-level similarity is obtained by matching words In Model 1, each target g g i ∈ is assigned a weight wt(g i ) using the IDF of g i . Two values were computed by matching targets and query concepts. The concept-level similarity is a linear combination of these two values: whereα is a tuning parameter. In the experiments, α = 0.25.</p><p>The similarity between q and d on the word level is computed using Okapi <ref type="bibr" coords="3,156.44,546.64,11.83,9.59" target="#b2">[2]</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,70.68,564.64,200.24,33.41">1 0.5 ( 1) log ( , ) 0.5 word w q N n k tf sim q d n K t f ∈ ⎛ ⎞ -+ + ⎛ ⎞ = ⎜ ⎟ ⎜ ⎟ + + ⎝ ⎠ ⎝ ⎠ ∑</formula><p>where N is the size of the document collection; n is the number of documents containing w. The other parameters are defined in <ref type="bibr" coords="3,168.27,634.06,11.60,9.59" target="#b2">[2]</ref>.</p><p>Given two documents d 1 and d 2 , we say 1 2</p><p>( , ) ( , ) sim q d sim q d &gt; or d 1 will be ranked higher than d 2 , with respect to the same query q, if either ( , ) ( , )</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,324.00,71.88,140.87,62.69">concept concept sim q d sim q d &gt; OR 2) 1 2 1 2 AND ( , )<label>( , ) ( , ) ( , )</label></formula><p>concept concept word word sim q d sim q d sim q d sim q d = &gt;</p><p>In this model, two similarity values are computed between and a document d and a query q. The concept-level similarity is obtained by matching concepts, while the word-level similarity is obtained by matching words. This conceptual IR model emphasizes the similarity on the concept level. More precisely, documents are ranked in descending order of the concept-level similarity. Only when documents have the same similarity in concepts, then the similarities in words are used to break ties. A similar model but applied to non-biomedical domain has been given in <ref type="bibr" coords="3,390.01,297.70,11.60,9.59" target="#b4">[3]</ref>. Okapi relevance scoring formula is known to embody a good model of relevance based upon term occurrences within text documents and the length of the documents. However, Okapi, in general, does not work well if the query contains multiple concepts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Model 2</head><p>This model does not differentiate what targets a document has. In another words, all the documents having at least one g g i ∈ receive the same similarity value with respect to the targets. The similarity between query q and document d is measured on three levels: the target concept-level, qualification concept-level and word level. The value of the target concept-level similarity is either 0 or 1 to indicate whether d has any target in g. The qualification concept-level similarity is obtained by matching query concepts, while the word-level similarity is obtained by matching words.</p><p>Given two documents d 1 and d 2 , we say 1 2</p><p>( , ) ( , ) sim q d sim q d &gt; or d 1 will be ranked higher than d 2 , with respect to the same query q, if any of the following three conditions satisfies: sim q d sim q d sim q d sim q d = ( , ) ( ( , ),( ( , ))</p><p>concept word sim q d sim q d sim q d = (1) sim q d sim q d sim q d sim q d sim q d sim q d = =</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>&gt;</head><p>In this model, documents having at least one target will be ranked higher than documents having no targets at all. For those documents having at least one target, the qualification concept-level similarity will be used next to break the tie. If two documents continue to have a tie on the qualification concept-level similarity, then the word-level similarity will be used to break the tie. In the TREC 2007 Genomics Track protocol <ref type="bibr" coords="4,121.90,300.74,11.61,9.62" target="#b5">[4]</ref>, a retrieved document is said to be relevant as along as it contains some entity of the specified entity type in the query. Thus Model 2 is more consistent with the protocol than Model 1, which has been demonstrated by the experiment results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Retrieval Models for G 2 Type of Queries</head><p>Unfortunately, we were unable to find resources to retrieve targets for all the entity types. When this happens, we compile a set of representative words for that entity type. These representative words cooccur with the entity type much more often than being independent in the same sentences of PubMed abstracts. The top 15 representative words were added into the query. Two levels of similarities were computed: concept level and word level. The concept-level similarity is obtained by matching the query concepts and the word-level similarity is obtained by matching the original query words and the added representative words. Then the model given in (1) was used for ranking. The intuition is that, the representative words are expected to capture the context or surrounding neighborhood within which a target of that entity type occurs and a document having that context is much likely to contain a target also.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Passage Extraction</head><p>The goal of passage extraction is to highlight the most relevant fragments of text in paragraphs. A passage is defined as any span of text that does not include the HTML paragraph tag (i.e., &lt;P&gt; or &lt;/P&gt;). A passage could be a part of a sentence, a sentence, a set of consecutive sentences or a paragraph (i.e., the whole span of text that are inside of &lt;P&gt; and &lt;/P&gt; HTML tags). It is also possible to have more than one relevant passage in a single paragraph. Our strategy for passage extraction assumes that the optimal passage(s) in a paragraph should have all the query concepts that the whole paragraph has. Also they should have higher density of query concepts than other fragments of text in the paragraph.</p><p>Suppose we have a query q and a paragraph p represented by a sequence of sentences 1 2 ... . n p s s s = Let C be the set of concepts in q that occur in p and S = Φ.</p><p>Step 1. For each sequence of consecutive sentences 1 ... ,    if (j -i + 1) &gt; L. This step is to remove those sequences of sentences in S that have lower density of query concepts.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="4,324.00,345.79,233.98,25.53">i i j s s s + 1 ≤ i ≤ j ≤ n, let S = S 1 { ... } i i j s s s + ∪ if 1 ...</formula><p>Step 3. For every two sequences of consecutive sentences:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="4,329.52,608.43,228.48,26.84">If (2)</formula><p>then do  Repeat this step until for every two sequences of consecutive sentences in S, condition (2) does not apply. This step is to merge those sequences of sentences in S that are adjacent or overlapped.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Experiment Results</head><p>We submitted two official runs. For G 2 type of queries, both runs used the same retrieval model. But for G 1 type of queries, different strategies have been used: UICGen1.</p><p>We employed Model 1, in which different targets of the same entity type were weighted according to their global frequencies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>UICGen2.</head><p>Model 2 was employed. Documents having at least one target receive the same weight with respect to the target. These documents were ranked higher than documents having no targets at all.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="5,353.56,535.41,5.51,9.62" target="#tab_6">2</ref> shows the performance of the two official runs. As you can see, the performance of UICGen2 is better than UICGen1 over all 4 different measures, which indicates that a document should be determined as a relevant document as long as it has a target of the specified entity type of the query and also satisfies the qualification no matter which target, more important or less, or how many targets it has. To further look into the performance of UICGen1 and UICGen2 with respect to each query, Figure <ref type="figure" coords="6,282.64,87.57,5.51,9.62" target="#fig_2">1</ref> shows the document MAP of the two runs for each G 1 type of query. As you can see, for 26 out of 29 queries of G 1 type, the document MAP of UICGen2 is at least as good as that of UICGen1. This result again confirmed the result indicated in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,254.14,150.81,4.13,9.62" target="#tab_6">2</ref>.</p><p>To evaluate whether using existing resources is helpful for retrieving targets, we compared the document MAP of UICGen2 with the median document MAP of all 49 automatic official runs in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,243.44,214.05,4.13,9.62" target="#tab_7">3</ref>. As you can see that, for those queries using existing resources to retrieve targets, the improving of document MAP over the median is a little higher than of those queries without using resources. It is possible that representative words of an entity type, to some sense, have captured the context in which a target of that entity type appears. It is good to have another baseline only using the original query. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Summary</head><p>In summary, in this year's Genomics Track, we explored two different types of strategies to answer information needs like "What [ANTIBODIES] have been used to detect protein TLR4?", which is asking for a list of biological objects of a certain type. This task is more challenging than last year's task where the biological objects or processes are explicitly given in the queries. Two conclusions have been made based on the experimental results. The first conclusion is that a document should be determined as a relevant document as long as it has some target of the specified entity type and satisfies the qualification no matter which targets or how many targets it has. The second conclusion is that using existing resources, such as UMLS or Entrez Gene, to retrieve targets of the entity type is a little more useful than using the representative words of the entity type.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="4,419.82,364.81,11.39,5.81;4,460.68,364.81,1.85,5.81;4,414.24,360.60,14.02,10.05;4,453.30,360.60,4.48,10.05;4,432.72,362.49,3.65,8.15;4,466.74,361.71,57.79,9.62;4,338.40,375.75,155.79,9.62;4,338.40,389.73,8.58,9.62;4,368.88,391.90,3.68,6.41;4,372.96,387.24,9.48,11.09"><head>1 )</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Every query concept in C occurs in 1 ...</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="4,354.18,391.90,10.03,6.41;4,388.44,391.90,2.04,6.41;4,349.50,387.24,12.93,11.09;4,382.20,387.24,4.95,11.09;4,364.98,389.33,4.03,9.00;4,393.48,389.73,15.92,9.62;4,338.40,403.71,209.12,9.62;4,338.40,417.75,153.42,9.62;4,361.32,434.26,3.76,6.56;4,365.70,429.52,9.79,11.35"><head>2 )</head><label>2</label><figDesc>There does not exist k, such that i &lt; k &lt; j and every query concept in C occurs in 1 ...</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="4,345.96,434.26,2.09,6.56"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>i</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5" coords="5,54.00,453.61,225.07,9.31;5,279.12,457.65,3.60,6.02;5,285.48,453.61,265.75,9.31;5,54.00,465.07,226.22,9.31"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1.Performance of two runs for queries of G 1 type (i.e., queries involving entity types that their targets can be automatically retrieved from existing resources.)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,54.00,76.56,504.04,289.41"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>14 entity types are classified into two groups, G 1 and G 2 . Entity types in G 1 are those that we are able to retrieve their instances from some resources; Entity types in G 2 are those that we are unable to find any resources to automatically retrieve their instances.</figDesc><table coords="2,54.00,76.56,460.13,289.41"><row><cell></cell><cell>G1</cell><cell></cell><cell>G2</cell></row><row><cell>Entity Type</cell><cell>Resource</cell><cell>Mapping</cell><cell>Entity Type</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">BIOLOGICAL SUBSTANCES UMLS</cell><cell cols="2">Biologically Active Substance ANTIBODIES</cell></row><row><cell>CELL OR TISSUE TYPES</cell><cell>UMLS</cell><cell>Cell</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Tissue</cell><cell>MUTATIONS</cell></row><row><cell>DISEASES</cell><cell>UMLS</cell><cell>Disease or Syndrome</cell><cell>PATHWAYS</cell></row><row><cell>DRUGS</cell><cell>UMLS</cell><cell>Pharmacologic Substance</cell><cell>STRAINS</cell></row><row><cell>GENES</cell><cell cols="2">Entrez Gene Gene symbols</cell><cell>TOXICITIES</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">MOLECULAR FUNCTIONS UMLS</cell><cell>Molecular Function</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>PROTEINS</cell><cell>UMLS</cell><cell>Amino Acid, Peptide, or Protein</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>SIGNS OR SYMPTOMS</cell><cell>UMLS</cell><cell>Sign or Symptom</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>TUMOR TYPES</cell><cell>UMLS</cell><cell>Neoplastic Process</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">found in the Entrez Gene database. The second</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">group G 2 consisting of the remaining 5 types that we</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">are not sure they correspond to any UMLS semantic</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">type, such as "ANTIBODIES". The classification of</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>the 14 entity types are given in Table</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6" coords="5,334.08,648.19,213.84,68.95"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Performance of the two official runs.</figDesc><table coords="5,334.08,648.19,213.84,50.95"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>Doc MAP</cell><cell>Asp MAP</cell><cell>Psg MAP</cell><cell>Psg2 MAP</cell></row><row><cell>UICGen1</cell><cell>0.209</cell><cell>0.145</cell><cell>0.083</cell><cell>0.044</cell></row><row><cell>UICGen2</cell><cell>0.239</cell><cell>0.181</cell><cell>0.098</cell><cell>0.051</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7" coords="6,54.00,340.75,230.10,111.67"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Performance of UICGen2 comparing to the median of all 49 automatic official runs.</figDesc><table coords="6,78.36,340.75,185.42,76.21"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Doc MAP</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Using</cell><cell>Without using</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>resources</cell><cell>resources</cell></row><row><cell>Median</cell><cell>0.1659</cell><cell>0.2704</cell></row><row><cell>UICGen2</cell><cell>0.2147</cell><cell>0.3410</cell></row><row><cell>Diff.</cell><cell>+29.42%</cell><cell>+26.11%</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="6.">Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank <rs type="person">Wen Tian</rs> for helping analyzing the results.</p></div>
			</div>			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,342.66,182.19,215.42,9.62" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Smalheiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Torvik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,324.00,194.85,234.01,9.62;6,324.00,207.51,234.13,9.62;6,324.00,220.17,234.04,9.62;6,324.00,232.77,234.16,9.62;6,324.00,245.43,19.31,9.62" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,324.00,194.85,234.01,9.62;6,324.00,207.51,186.11,9.62">Knowledge-intensive Conceptual Retrieval and Passage Extraction of Biomedical Literature</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,519.03,207.51,39.10,9.62;6,324.00,220.17,234.04,9.62;6,324.00,232.77,48.18,9.62">Proceedings of the 30th Annual International ACM SIGIR2007</title>
		<meeting>the 30th Annual International ACM SIGIR2007<address><addrLine>Amsterdam, Netherlands</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="655" to="662" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,350.82,270.74,207.27,9.62" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,324.00,283.40,233.90,9.62;6,324.00,296.06,234.03,9.62;6,324.00,308.66,46.46,9.62" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,412.17,283.40,145.72,9.62;6,324.00,296.06,234.03,9.62">TREC-8. NIST Special Publication. 500-246:The Eighth Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,339.72,333.98,218.27,9.62;6,324.00,346.64,234.06,9.62;6,324.00,359.30,228.02,9.62" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,501.24,333.98,56.74,9.62;6,324.00,346.64,234.06,9.62;6,324.00,359.30,152.53,9.62">An Effective Approach to Document Retrieval via Utilizing WordNet and Recognizing Phrases</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Meng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,495.75,359.30,28.75,9.62">SIGIR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,341.22,384.56,216.78,9.62;6,324.00,397.22,22.03,9.62;6,379.86,397.22,44.62,9.62;6,458.37,397.22,25.68,9.62;6,518.02,397.22,40.01,9.62;6,324.00,409.88,212.46,9.62" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hersh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Trec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ir.ohsu.edu/genomics/2007protocol.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,379.86,397.22,44.62,9.62;6,458.37,397.22,25.68,9.62;6,518.02,397.22,35.57,9.62">Genomics Track Protocol</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
