<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,90.06,87.44,432.08,14.82;1,230.94,105.86,150.28,14.82">Persuasive, authorative and topical answers for complex question answering</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,191.88,139.14,70.56,9.88"><forename type="first">Leif</forename><surname>Azzopardi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Glasgow</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,271.49,139.14,59.57,9.88"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Baillie</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Strathclyde Glasgow</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>G12 8QQ G1 1XH</postCode>
									<settlement>Glasgow</settlement>
									<country>UK, UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,357.81,139.14,58.93,9.88"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Ruthven</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Strathclyde Glasgow</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>G12 8QQ G1 1XH</postCode>
									<settlement>Glasgow</settlement>
									<country>UK, UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,90.06,87.44,432.08,14.82;1,230.94,105.86,150.28,14.82">Persuasive, authorative and topical answers for complex question answering</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">0539B525383514E120488D6EB148C913</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:04+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>The ciqa track investigates the role of interaction in answering complex questions: questions that relate two or more entities by some specified relationship. As in the ciqa 2006, our interest in ciqa 2007 was on contextual factors that may affect how answers are assessed. In ciqa 2006 we investigated factors such as topical knowledge or confidence in assessing answers through direct questioning -asking the ciqa assessors to directly estimate values for such variables using ordinal or categorical scales. In ciqa 2006 we found many useful relationships between personal contextual variables and how assessors judged answers. This year we were keen to follow this line of investigation, following a more specific research question: how do contextual variables affect the judgement of different types of information surrogate.</p><p>We created information surrogates (answers) which contained similar amounts of information but presented the information in different ways; either as neutral, topically related information (topical answers), information that was presented in such a way as to entice the read (persuasive answers), or information that was presented as coming from a named authority (authorative answers). Separately, we gathered contextual information on the assessors' preferences for such answers through the use of HTML interaction forms. Our results show differences in how assessors reacted to these different information surrogates in terms of highly they were to judge the answer as good and how likely they were to read the document containing the answer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Answers</head><p>For the main ciqa assessment we returned a set of manually selected answers from the AQUAINT2 collection. For the interactive component of ciqa we presented, for each topic, a set of manually created answers to the assessor. A sample form is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="1,440.21,560.04,4.12,9.88">1</ref>.</p><p>Each answer was presented within a structured presentation format: one grey field containing the answer text in red font followed by three yellow fields containing our questions to the assessor regarding the answer. These questions were to elicit (1) if the answer was a good answer (yes/no/needed to read the entire document to decide), ( <ref type="formula" coords="1,343.52,623.28,4.27,9.88">2</ref>) if the answer was expected -did the assessor already have an answer in mind when creating the topic and (3) what action would they perform on the answer if shown the answer by a real QA system. In ciqa 2006, this final question was shown to be particularly useful in determining assessors' views on the quality of an answer.</p><p>All answers contain a textual answer with ellipses to denote missing text if the answer is a fragment of a sentence e.g. "..an appearance on Oprah or Today can shoot book sales through the roof…". We deliberately selected short answers, rather than whole sentences or paragraphs, to simulate the main question answering task in which short answers are preferred. Thus, what we were trying to do was investigate interaction with a good questions answering system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1: Answer form</head><p>The content of the answers were either 1. topical answers. These are answers that simply attempt to answer the question by</p><p>providing a neutral answer on the main topic of the question. In Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,442.67,529.68,4.12,9.88">1</ref>, topical answers are "In the pay-per-click model, advertisers on Google's network selected certain keywords to identify the topic of their ads." and "Google expects to add 372,000 advertiser accounts over the next four years." which answers either the question expressed in the topic Question field or a sub-question from the topic Description field (as shown at the topic of Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,267.96,592.92,3.97,9.88">1</ref>).</p><p>2. persuasive answers. These are answers that also attempt to answer the question but contain emotive words or phrases similar to those that might be used in newspapers or advertising to grab a reader's attention. In Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,360.51,643.50,4.12,9.88">1</ref>, persuasive answers are "Inflated amounts charged to advertisers by the search engines have prompted litigation…" and "Google will not divulge much information to advertisers. Google defends the practice, saying it does not want to provide" 3. authorative answers. These are answers which contain a named source for the answer provided, either a person or organisation. Examples in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,400.27,87.30,5.49,9.88">1</ref>  For each topic we created 6 answers, two of each type, which were presented to the assessor. The ordering between types of answer was rotated across forms. The content of the answers was created manually: for each topic one author browsed the general Web and extracted appropriate answers so that each answer reflects, as far as possible, genuine answers. Where there were few answers on the Web we created new answers based on the answers we found.</p><p>Answers may have slightly different lengths, e.g. the authorative answers may be longer to include the source of the answers, and the types of answers may not be mutually exclusive. However, as far as possible, we tried to create good answers of each type that allowed us to compare the effect of answer type against assessor characteristics.</p><p>Assessor characteristics were gathered through HTML interaction forms, essentially questionnaires given to the assessors. Each assessor was given two forms, described separately in sections 3 and 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Preference form</head><p>Our first form elicited information on an assessor's preference for concrete versus abstract information, Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,184.30,398.94,4.12,9.88">2</ref>. We asked a series of questions on the assessor's preference for art, literature, companions (artists, filmmakers, authors vs. scientists and politicians), or gifts.</p><p>We classified answers into reflecting two types of preference: preference for concrete, tangible items (such as non-fiction books and film, realistic art, practical gifts) and preference for abstract items with a stronger emotional appeal (such as fiction literature, genre films, abstract art and people who are artistic rather than practical). The assessor choices are given below<ref type="foot" coords="3,454.20,472.57,3.51,6.32" target="#foot_0">1</ref> in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,499.65,474.84,4.12,9.88">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2: Persuasive form</head><p>Our original intention was to classify assessors into assessors who may be more interested in persuasive, rather than topical, answers. However, as is seen in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,406.21,453.54,4.12,9.88">1</ref>, nearly all assessors fell into one group -those preferring more concrete information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Authority form</head><p>Our second form elicited information on an assessor's preference for sources of information, Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,123.77,108.66,4.12,9.88">3</ref>. We presented a series of 5 scenarios which we felt would be understandable and answerable by the assessors. Each scenario posed a question which required the assessor to choose which source of information they would use to answer the question.</p><p>These sources were of three types: 1. personal experience. These sources reflected the assessor's own personal experience.</p><p>Here we did not assume any personal experience but suggested a method by which the assessor could gain personal experience. For example, Scenario 1 (labelled Question 1 in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,160.12,209.88,4.58,9.88">3</ref>) suggests that the assessor could visit the new neighbourhood; Scenario 2 suggests they could take a course of Vitamin C. In this category what is important is the assessor answers the question based on their own impressions, beliefs or experience rather than trusting or seeking another source. 2. knowledgeable personal contact. These sources also reflect personal experience but the personal experience belongs to named people who have more experience than the assessor. For example a trusted family physician may have more experience of vitamin supplements and knowledge upon which to base his/her recommendation. Similarly, recent graduates of a university can give more information than can be obtained in a single visit. 3. formal information source. The final source was information from formal sources such as Police Departments, the FDA, or a University. In this category we do not assume that the information sources are necessarily neutral. Table <ref type="table" coords="6,209.55,205.80,4.57,9.88">2</ref>: Assessors preferences for information source</p><p>As with the preference form, section 3, we see a distinct preference -in this case for formal information sources, Table <ref type="table" coords="6,215.15,243.66,4.12,9.88">2</ref>. This category accounts for almost half the answers given by the assessors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Results</head><p>Our original intention was to classify assessors according to which might be more attracted to persuasive answers (those who prefer more abstract items) or those who might prefer more authorative answers (those who prefer formal information sources). However, as noted above the assessors did not split into groups of sufficient size to allow such an analysis.</p><p>We do present in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,205.67,365.64,5.49,9.88" target="#tab_2">3</ref> how the assessors judged the answers of different types and their predicted next action for each answer (accept the answer, reject and move to a better answer, or read the document). Topical answers appeared to be the best type of surrogates in the sense that assessors appeared to find it easier to judge these answers with low use of the need more information category and more answers being accepted without requiring further analysis.</p><p>Persuasive answers, on the other hand, had higher rates of rejection (move and poor categories). Both authorative and persuasive answers had higher rates of read decision, in particular the use of a named authority in the answer seemed to lead to the assessor choosing to read a document instead of simply accepting the answer. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="5,246.96,707.16,118.21,9.88;5,99.66,384.78,412.86,306.48"><head>Figure</head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 3: Authority form</figDesc><graphic coords="5,99.66,384.78,412.86,306.48" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" coords="2,90.36,123.06,432.30,327.54"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="2,90.36,123.06,432.30,327.54" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" coords="4,89.94,72.54,417.72,314.58"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="4,89.94,72.54,417.72,314.58" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,125.88,87.30,396.79,73.12"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>are "Google will sell $6.1 billion in ads, nearly double what it sold last year, according to Anthony Noto, an analyst at Goldman Sachs." And "Each [Google] advertiser pays what it's worth to them,"said Greg Stuart, CEO of the Interactive Advertising Bureau." Where the authorative sources are Greg Stuart and Anthony Noto and, by reference, Goldman Sachs and the Interactive Advertising Bureau.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="6,115.26,492.66,381.65,62.26"><head>good poor need more information to decide accept move read</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="6,115.26,518.46,376.47,36.46"><row><cell>topical answers</cell><cell>44</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>41</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>12</cell></row><row><cell>persuasive answers</cell><cell>34</cell><cell>14</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>29</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>19</cell></row><row><cell>authorative answers</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>30</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>22</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="6,113.28,572.04,385.52,9.88"><head>Table 3 : Distribution of answer quality and predicted next action for answer types</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="3,96.12,687.96,426.15,9.02;3,89.88,699.42,432.47,9.02;3,89.88,710.94,329.76,9.02"><p>Naturally we are not making value judgments about these choices. Rather we are reflecting that different people have different tastes and preferences which may affect what information they require. As stated at the start of each form assessors could choose not to answer any of these questions.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" />			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
