<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,151.13,72.35,307.46,16.84;1,193.08,92.27,223.55,16.84">Significant Words Language Models for Contextual Suggestion</title>
				<funder ref="#_zyGJvRu">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_QjcJPeZ">
					<orgName type="full">Netherlands Organization for Scientific Research</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,80.32,137.97,96.66,11.06"><forename type="first">Mostafa</forename><surname>Dehghani</surname></persName>
							<email>dehghani@uva.nl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Logic, Language and Computation</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,211.68,137.97,103.90,11.06"><forename type="first">Hosein</forename><surname>Azarbonyad</surname></persName>
							<email>h.azarbonyad@uva.nl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Informatics Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,350.29,137.97,66.21,11.06"><forename type="first">Jaap</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
							<email>kamps@uva.nl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Logic, Language and Computation</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,451.21,137.97,74.22,11.06"><forename type="first">Maarten</forename><surname>Marx</surname></persName>
							<email>maartenmarx@uva.nl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Informatics Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,151.13,72.35,307.46,16.84;1,193.08,92.27,223.55,16.84">Significant Words Language Models for Contextual Suggestion</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">2F620A08B821A1324F10D20571E08033</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:09+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Contextual Suggestion</term>
					<term>TREC</term>
					<term>Significant Words Language Model</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper, we present the participation of the University of Amsterdam's ExPoSe team in the TREC 2016 Contextual Suggestion Track. The main goal of contextual suggestion track is to evaluate methods for providing suggestions for activities or points of interest to users in a specific location, at a specific time, taking their personal preferences into consideration. One of the key steps of contextual suggestion methods is estimating a proper model for representing different objects in the data like users and attractions. Here, we describe our approach which is employing Significant Words Language Models (SWLM) [2] as an effective method for estimating models representing significant features of sets of attractions as user profiles and sets of users as group profile.</p><p>We observe that using SWLM, we are able to better estimate a model representing the set of preferences positively rated by users as their profile, compared to the case we use standard language model as the profiling approach. We also find that using negatively rated attractions as negative samples along with positively rated attractions as positive samples, we may loose the performance when we use standard language model as the profiling approach. While, using SWLM, taking negatively rated attractions into consideration may help to improve the quality of suggestions. In addition, we investigate groups of users sharing a property (e.g. of a similar age) and study the effect of taking groupbased profiles on the performance of suggestions provided for individual users. We noticed that group-based suggestion helps more when users have a tendency to rate attraction in a neutral way, compared to the case users are more subjective in their rating behavior.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">INTRODUCTION</head><p>This paper presents the participation of University of Amsterdam, ExPoSe team, in the TREC 2016 Contextual Suggestion Track <ref type="bibr" coords="1,97.21,637.96,9.09,7.86" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. Contextual suggestion is the task of searching for complex information needs that are highly dependent on both context and user interests. More precisely, given the information of users including their age, gender, and set of rated places or activities as the user preferences (ratings are in the range of -1 to 4), the task is to generate a list of ranked suggestions from a set of candidate attractions, by giving the user information as well as some information about the context, including location of trip, trip season, trip type, trip duration, and the type of group the person is travelling with.</p><p>One of the key steps of the contextual suggestion methods is estimating a proper model for representing different objects in the data, like users and attractions. Having a proper profile of different objects representing significant features of them, we are able to find connections between data objects and provide effective suggestions based on them.</p><p>Our approach for TREC 2016 Contextual Suggestion Track is based on estimating effective profiles for different objects in the data. Generally speaking, we use Significant Words Language Models (SWLM) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,429.01,325.13,9.71,7.86" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,441.79,325.13,7.16,7.86" target="#b1">2]</ref> as an effective method for estimating models representing significant features of a set of documents. We employed SWLM in different cases for modeling different objects in the contextual suggestion task, including: building a positive profile for each user (as a set of positively rated documents), building a negative profile for each user (as a set of negatively rated documents), building a profile for a group of users (as a set of users sharing a specific property) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,358.02,408.82,9.72,7.86" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,370.80,408.82,6.48,7.86" target="#b3">4]</ref>.</p><p>In this paper, we address two main research questions:</p><p>RQ1 How can SWLM help to estimate better user profiles for the contextual suggestion of venues?</p><p>RQ2 Under what conditions does information of group profiles estimated using SWLM improve the performance of the contextual suggestions?</p><p>Briefly, we have made use of the estimated models by SWLM in different experiments with different settings to investigate how SWLM helps to improve the general performance of contextual suggestion. We observe that using SWLM we are able to better estimate a model representing the set of preferences positively rated by users as their profile, compared to the case we use standard language model as the profiling approach.</p><p>Furthermore, we find that using negatively rated attractions as negative samples along with positively rated attractions as positive samples, we may loose the performance when we use standard language model as the profiling approach. The reason is that standard language model of negatively rated documents contain positive information and using this model as the negative model, we penalize positive candidates. However, employing SWLM we can estimate an effective model represent the essential negative terms which taking this model into consideration as the negative model, we are able to get rid of negative candidates and generally improve the of suggestions. Moreover, we investigate the effect of employing information from groups that users belong to on the performance of suggestions provided for individual users. We observed that providing group-based suggestions helps to improve the performance of contextual suggestion for some users and it is not effective for others. Looking into the differences of these users, we noticed that for users that rate attractions mostly with rates close to the neutral rating, we improve the performance by taking group information into account, while for users that rate attraction in more subjective way, (i.e. giving high rates or low rates), group information do not help too much. The reason would be the fact that in the case of neutral rating behavior, we do not have strong signals and group-based information are counted as complementary signals helping the method to provide better suggestions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">ESTIMATING EFFECTIVE PROFILES</head><p>In this section, we explain how to estimate significant words language models and how to use them in contextual suggestion task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Estimating SWLM</head><p>Having a set of documents, S, in order to estimate SWLM representing the whole set, we assume that there are three models from which each document in the set is generated as a mixture sampling from these models: significant words model, general model, and specific model. The significant words model represents the latent model that is the distribution of terms reflecting the essential features of the object. The general model represents commonly observed terms and the specific model represents the partially observed terms in the set, which we assume as two different patterns of distribution of non-significant terms.</p><p>Each model is represented using a terms distribution, or a unigram language model, θsw, θg, and θs. Based on the generative model, each term in a document in the set, is generated by sampling from a mixture of these three models independently. Thus, the probability of appearance of the term t in the document d is as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,77.82,483.76,215.09,8.38">p(t d) = λ d,sw p(t θsw) + λ d,g p(t θg) + λ d,s p(t θs),<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where λ d,x stands for p(θx d) which is the probability of choosing the model θx given the document d.</p><p>We estimate θg and θs and make them fixed in the estimation process. We consider the collection model, θ C as an estimation for θg:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,107.14,561.27,185.77,23.18">p(t θg) = p(t θ C ) = c(t, C) ∑ t ′ ∈V c(t ′ , C) ,<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where c(t, C) is the frequency of term t in the collection. This way, terms that are well explained in the collection model get high probability and are considered as general terms. Furthermore, we define specificity as being supported by part of documents in the set but not all of them. We estimate θs to represent the probability of a term being partially observed as follows, and rescale all the probabilities, to recover the probability values and establish a well-formed distribution:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,64.92,693.55,227.99,26.75">p(t θs) N ormalized ← d i ∈S p(t θ d i ) d j ∈S j≠i (1 -p(t θ d j )) ,<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,343.67,57.33,115.36,11.14">P (t θ d i ) = c(t,d i ) ∑ t ′ ∈d i c(t ′ ,d i ).</formula><p>Intuitively, Equation <ref type="formula" coords="2,551.45,57.64,4.70,7.86" target="#formula_2">3</ref>calculates the probability of term t to be a specific term. To this end, it considers the probability of a term to be important in one of the document models but not others, marginalizing over all documents in the set. This way, terms that are well explained in only one document in the set but not others get higher probabilities and are considered as insignificant specific terms.</p><p>Having the above assumptions, the goal is to fit the loglikelihood model of generating all terms in the documents in the set to discover the term distribution of the significant words model, θsw. Let S = {d1, . . . , d S } be the set of documents. The log-likelihood function for the entire set of documents is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="2,326.90,210.95,229.02,16.31">log p(S Υ) = d∈S t∈V c(t, d) log x∈{sw,g,s} λ d,x p(t θx) , (4)</formula><p>where c(t, d) is the frequency of the term t in the document d, and Υ determines the set of all parameters that should be estimated, Υ = {λ d,sw , λ d,g , λ d,s } d∈S ∪ {θsw}.</p><p>To fit our model, we estimate the parameters using the maximum likelihood (ML) estimator. Therefore, assuming that documents are represented by a multinomial distribution over the terms, we solve the following problem:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="2,395.19,314.39,160.72,15.60">Υ * ∶= argmax Υ p(S Υ)<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Assuming that X d,t ∈ {sw, g, s} is a hidden variable indicating which model has been used to generate the term t in the document d, we can compute the parameters using the Expectation-Maximization (EM) algorithm. The stages of the EM algorithm are as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="2,316.81,398.64,239.11,39.56">E-Step p(X d,t = x) = p(θx d)p(t θx) ∑ x ′ ∈{sw,g,s} p(θ x ′ d)p(t θ x ′ )<label>(6)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>M-</head><p>Step</p><formula xml:id="formula_7" coords="2,344.72,465.63,211.20,66.65">p(t θsw) = ∑ d∈S c(t, d)p(X d,t = sw) ∑ t ′ ∈V ∑ d∈S c(t ′ , d)p(X d,t ′ = sw) (7) λ d,x = p(θx d) = ∑ t∈V c(t, d)p(X d,t = x) ∑ x ′ ∈{sw,g,s} ∑ t∈V c(t, d)p(X d,t = x ′ )<label>(8)</label></formula><p>As explained above, besides removing common terms by advocating terms that are relatively rare in the collection, the main contribution of SWLM is that it eliminates specific terms by favoring terms occurring in all the feedback documents, not only some of them, which leads to an effective language model as the profile of the object.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">SWLM for Contextual Suggestion</head><p>As it is explained, SWLM is an effective approach to estimated a model representing a set of documents. In our setting, each profile, either for an individual user or for a group of users, is a set of textual documents and we use language models as the representation of profiles.</p><p>In the case of estimating a profile for an individual user, the set of documents contains textual information of attractions rated by the user is the input of SWLM. This is both in the case of estimating a positive user profile using the set of positively rated attractions, and estimating a negative user profile using the set of negatively rated attractions. With regard to the data of the TREC contextual suggestion task, we estimate user positive profile using SWLM on the set of documents that are rated higher than 2 (i.e 3 and 4) and estimate user negative profile using SWLM on the set of documents that are rated lower than 2 (i.e. 1 and 0, with ignoring documents with rate = -1). In order to take given rates by users into account in the process of SWLM, we add a pseudo-count for terms in documents with rate 4 in positive profiling and terms in documents with rate 0 in negative profiling. In other words, we update the value of c(t, d) in the EM algorithm based on the rate of d.</p><p>In addition to the user profile, we estimated profiles representing the group of users for the group-based contextual suggestion and in this case, the set of documents as the input of SWLM contains the textual profile of users in the group. In this paper we take the age of users as the grouping criterion, since it has been shown as one of the most effective grouping approaches on the contextual suggestion task <ref type="bibr" coords="3,282.27,367.44,9.32,7.86" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. We discretize the age of users considering 5 years as the bin size to divide them into different groups.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">EXPERIMENTS</head><p>In this section, we explain about our experiments and describe the results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">User Profiling Using SWLM</head><p>In the first set of experiments, we address our first research question: "How can SWLM help to estimate better user profiles for the contextual suggestion of venues?"</p><p>After estimating user profiles using SWLM, we use the similarity of the standard language model of the candidate attractions with the estimated user profiles to score candidates and rank them. We use the inverse of JS-Divergence as the similarity function in our experiments. As the baseline, we use standard language model for user profiling in the same setting.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="3,88.20,571.28,4.63,7.86" target="#tab_0">1</ref> presents the performance of different systems for user profiling. U serP rof ile + SW LM is based on using user profiles that are estimated by significant words language model and just taking the positive user profile into account for candidate scoring. U serP rof ile + -SW LM is the same approach but taking both positive and negative profiles into consideration in order for scoring candidates. We use simple linear interpolation of the positive score with positive weight and the negative score with negative weight as the final score. U serP rof ile + SLM and U serP rof ile</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>+ -</head><p>SLM are baseline systems with the same settings explained above but using standard language model instead of SWLM for profiling.</p><p>As can be seen in the table, U serP rof ile + -SW LM is the best performing system compare to the others. However, the im- portant point is that using standard language model as the profiling method, we lose performance when we take the negative profiles into account. This is due to the fact that usually negative instances are not focused on a specific topic and estimating a model representing all of them is more difficult compared to positive instances. In this case, using standard language model, we are no able to effectively capture the negative terms and the estimated negative profiles sometimes reflect positive aspects as well and by considering them in the system we penalize the positive candidates. However, SWLM is able to capture the essential terms reflecting the shared commonalities of negatively rated candidates and accidental positive terms in negative candidates are removed from the final estimation. Then, using these significant negative terms as negative profile, we are able to improve the performance in general.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Group Profiling Using SWLM</head><p>Here, we address our second research question: "Under what conditions does information of group profiles estimated using SWLM improve the performance of the contextual suggestions?"</p><p>We group users based on their age (5 years as the bin size) into different categories, and then used SWLM again to estimate profile for each group (as a set of users) with regards to the estimated user profiles for individual users in the group. We estimate just positive group profiles according to the positive user profiles estimated with the settings of U serP rof ile + SW LM system, explained in the previous section. Afterward, given an individual user, we take all the candidate suggestions and the profile of the group that the user belongs to, and then we generate group-based scores of suggestions using the similarity of the group profile with the candidate model employing inverse JS-Divergence. Then, having the group-based score, we combine it with the score achieved using the user profile in the settings of U serP rof ile + -SW LM system, using linear interpolation.</p><p>As the baseline for group profiling approach, we concatenate all the textual information of all members in the group into one document representing the whole group and then we use a standard language model to represent this document as a distribution over terms, and take this model as the group profile.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="3,350.66,615.73,4.52,7.86" target="#tab_1">2</ref> presents the performance of contextual suggestion without help of group profiling (U serP rof ile + -SW LM , the best performing system in the previous section), with help of group profiling, using SWLM as the group profiling approach (U P + GroupP rof ile SW LM ), and using standard language model as the group profiling approach (U P + GroupP rof ile SLM ).</p><p>As can be seen, using group profiles helps to improve the performance of contextual suggestion in case of using SWLM as the profiling approach but using standard language model as the profiling approach we are not able to  improve the performance. However, the improvement we get from employing group profiles estimated by SWLM is not significant. We looked into the data to see in which cases adding group information helps and in which cases it is not effective. We observed that there is a correlation between the amount of improvement in contextual suggestion using group information and the rating behavior of users.</p><p>To do so, we simply take the average rating that user gave to different attractions as their general tendency of rating. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,82.95,397.07,4.63,7.86" target="#fig_1">1</ref> shows the scatter plot of the change in p@10 after employing group-based information based on different rating tendency. According to the plot, group-based information works better when the user has a neutral tendency in her rating (around rate 2) and it is less likely to help when users have rather strong biases by rating attraction with high or low rates. This could be due to the fact that in case of having neutral user, we have less string information coming from his/her profile and then group-based information is compensating this lack of strong signals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">CONCLUSIONS</head><p>In this paper, we presented the participation of University of Amsterdam, ExPoSe team, in the TREC 2016 Contextual Suggestion Track. We described our approach which is employing Significant Words Language Models (SWLM) <ref type="bibr" coords="4,283.21,564.73,9.69,7.86" target="#b1">[2]</ref> as an effective method for estimating models representing significant features of sets of attractions as user profiles and sets of users as group profile.</p><p>We had two main research questions. The first research question was "How can SWLM help to estimate better user profiles for the contextual suggestion of venues?" We observed that using SWLM, we are able to better estimate a model representing the set of preferences positively rated by users as their profile, compared to the case we use standard language model as the profiling approach. We also found that using negatively rated attractions as negative samples along with positively rated attractions as positive samples, we may loose the performance when we use standard language model as the profiling approach. While, using SWLM, taking negatively rated attractions into consideration may help improving the quality of suggestions.</p><p>Our second research question was "Under what conditions does information of group profiles estimated using SWLM improve the performance of the contextual suggestions?" We investigated the effect of employing information from groups that users belong to on the performance of suggestions provided for individual users. We noticed that group-based suggestion helps more when users have tendency to rate attraction in a neutral way, compared to the case users are subjective in their rating behaviour.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,53.80,252.42,240.52,7.01;4,53.80,261.41,239.11,6.99;4,53.80,270.38,34.10,6.99"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Improvement of the performance of contextual suggestion by help of group profiles for users with different rating behavior.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,53.46,54.61,239.45,91.28"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Performance of contextual suggestion: user profiling approaches</figDesc><table coords="3,53.80,86.11,239.11,59.78"><row><cell>Method</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">ndcg@5 recip rank P@5</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">U serP rof ile + SLM</cell><cell>0.1832</cell><cell>0.5015</cell><cell>0.3108</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">U serP rof ile U serP rof ile + + -SLM SW LM</cell><cell>0.1301 0.2672</cell><cell>0.4401 0.5218</cell><cell>0.2312 0.3548</cell></row><row><cell>U serP rof ile</cell><cell>+ -SW LM</cell><cell>0.2711</cell><cell>0.5453</cell><cell>0.3911</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,316.47,54.61,239.45,77.44"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Performance of contextual suggestion: group profiling approaches</figDesc><table coords="3,316.81,86.11,239.11,45.94"><row><cell>Method</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">ndcg@5 recip rank P@5</cell></row><row><cell>U serP rof ile</cell><cell>+ -SW LM</cell><cell>0.2711</cell><cell>0.5453</cell><cell>0.3911</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">U P + GroupP rof ile SLM</cell><cell>0.2612</cell><cell>0.5345</cell><cell>0.3791</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">U P + GroupP rof ile SW LM 0.2756</cell><cell>0.5501</cell><cell>0.3811</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="5.">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>This research is funded in part by <rs type="funder">Netherlands Organization for Scientific Research</rs> through the <rs type="programName">Exploratory Political Search project (ExPoSe, NWO CI #</rs> <rs type="grantNumber">314.99.108</rs>), and by the Digging into Data Challenge through the Digging Into Linked Parliamentary Data project (DiLiPaD, NWO Digging into Data # <rs type="grantNumber">600.006.014</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_QjcJPeZ">
					<idno type="grant-number">314.99.108</idno>
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">Exploratory Political Search project (ExPoSe, NWO CI #</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_zyGJvRu">
					<idno type="grant-number">600.006.014</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.01,289.77,226.70,7.86;4,331.01,300.23,225.02,7.86;4,329.92,310.69,225.99,7.86;4,330.51,321.15,226.69,7.86;4,331.01,331.61,226.70,7.86;4,330.55,341.97,226.30,7.96;4,331.01,352.43,69.51,7.96" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,386.77,289.77,167.50,7.86">Significant words representations of entities</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dehghani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2911451.2911474</idno>
		<ptr target="http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2911451.2911474" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,343.80,300.23,212.23,7.86;4,329.92,310.69,225.99,7.86;4,330.51,321.15,82.71,7.86">Proceedings of the 39th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval, SIGIR &apos;16</title>
		<meeting>the 39th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval, SIGIR &apos;16<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1183" to="1183" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.01,370.16,226.19,7.86;4,331.01,380.63,224.91,7.86;4,331.01,391.09,224.66,7.86;4,329.92,401.55,225.97,7.86;4,329.88,412.01,71.75,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,389.40,380.63,166.52,7.86;4,331.01,391.09,26.62,7.86">Luhn revisited: significant words language models</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dehghani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Azarbonyad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hiemstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Marx</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,377.79,391.09,177.88,7.86;4,329.92,401.55,225.97,7.86;4,329.88,412.01,42.96,7.86">The Proceedings of The ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM&apos;16)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.01,429.64,226.70,7.86;4,331.01,440.10,224.92,7.86;4,329.92,450.56,128.92,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,331.01,440.10,208.77,7.86">Generalized group profiling for content customization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dehghani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Azarbonyad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Marx</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,329.92,450.56,37.31,7.86">CHIIR&apos;16</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="245" to="248" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.01,468.20,226.44,7.86;4,331.01,478.66,226.70,7.86;4,331.01,489.12,113.87,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,520.98,468.20,36.47,7.86;4,331.01,478.66,222.16,7.86">Parsimonious user and group profiling in venue recommendation</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Hashemi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dehghani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,342.50,489.12,46.48,7.86">TREC 2015</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.01,506.75,226.20,7.86;4,331.01,517.21,226.44,7.86;4,331.01,527.67,226.19,7.86;4,331.01,538.13,224.65,7.86;4,329.92,548.60,227.52,7.86;4,331.01,559.06,222.33,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,419.73,517.21,137.72,7.86;4,331.01,527.67,93.42,7.86">Overview of the TREC 2016 contextual suggestion track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Hashemi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L A</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kiseleva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,364.11,538.13,191.55,7.86;4,329.92,548.60,45.22,7.86">Proceedings of the Twenty-Fifth Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ellis</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the Twenty-Fifth Text REtrieval Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>NIST Special Publication</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016. 2017</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>National Institute for Standards and Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
