<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,103.74,72.35,402.23,16.84">UFMG at the TREC 2016 Dynamic Domain track</title>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">CNPq</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_6FeZYD5">
					<orgName type="full">MASWeb</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">FAPEMIG</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_wJVChrF">
					<orgName type="full">InWeb</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,156.28,118.05,75.26,11.06"><forename type="first">Felipe</forename><surname>Moraes</surname></persName>
							<email>felipemoraes@dcc.ufmg.br</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais Belo Horizonte</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>MG</region>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,242.33,118.05,111.89,11.06"><forename type="first">Rodrygo</forename><forename type="middle">L T</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
							<email>rodrygo@dcc.ufmg.br</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais Belo Horizonte</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>MG</region>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,365.02,118.05,64.43,11.06"><forename type="first">Nivio</forename><surname>Ziviani</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais Belo Horizonte</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>MG</region>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Kunumi Belo Horizonte</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>MG</region>
									<country key="BR">Brazil</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,103.74,72.35,402.23,16.84">UFMG at the TREC 2016 Dynamic Domain track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">3A4AA8F6E8BE0378A7ADE7AEC23AD32F</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:09+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In TREC 2016, we focus on tackling the challenges posed by the Dynamic Domain (DD) track. The goal of the TREC DD track is to support research in dynamic, exploratory search within a complex domain. To this end, our participation investigates the suitability of multiple diversification approaches for dynamic information retrieval. In particular, based on fine-grained real-time feedback obtained from a simulated user, we apply diversification strategies that make use of single-source as well multi-source information for mining flat or hierarchical query aspects.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">INTRODUCTION</head><p>The TREC 2016 Dynamic Domain (DD) track <ref type="bibr" coords="1,249.89,358.01,9.72,7.86" target="#b5">[5]</ref> consists of performing an interactive search task in a specific domain. In particular, the goal of this track is to cover multiple aspects of the user's information need as early as possible. Therefore, in this track, each participant relies on a simulated user (called "the jig") to get real-time feedback on a short list of documents that the participant's system returns. This process repeats until the participant's system decides that the user has fulfilled his or her information need.</p><p>The central theme of our participation in the TREC 2016 DD track is to investigate the suitability of search result diversification as a mechanism to increase the coverage of the possible aspects underlying the user's query while requiring as little as possible user interaction. We make use of the exploratory and explicit nature of the user's inputs, whereby he or she directly assists our system in assigning aspects to documents passages. In particular, we investigate approaches for diversification that leverage either flat or hierarchical aspects from a single or from multiple sources. Along with the diversification approaches, we investigate three strategies proposed in the literature for reducing the number of iterations of the retrieval-feedback cycle needed to fulfill the aspects that are of interest to the user.</p><p>The remainder of this paper is structured as follows. In Section 2, we briefly formalize the task tackled in the TREC 2016 DD track and provide an overview of our system. In Section 3, we discuss the results of our official and unofficial runs. In Section 4, we present our conclusions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">INTERACTIVE DIVERSIFICATION</head><p>The TREC DD track invites participants to propose search systems capable of interactively satisfying the multiple aspects associated with the information need of a (simulated) target user. Given a query q posed by the target user, a search system may return a batch D of documents to the user. For each document d ∈ D, the user provides the system with a feedback set F. Each feedback f ∈ F is defined as a tuple f = p, a, g comprising a passage p that the user deemed relevant to aspect a at a given relevance level g. The search system may then return another batch of documents for more feedback or decide to stop the search process.</p><p>Our approach has three components: (i) a baseline ranker, which retrieves a candidate set of documents given a query q; (ii) a diversification strategy, which interactively re-ranks the candidate set to improve the coverage of the possible aspects underlying q; and (iii) a stopping strategy, which determines when to stop the interactive process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Baseline Ranker</head><p>In our experiments, we use Elasticsearch<ref type="foot" coords="1,488.57,372.00,3.65,5.24" target="#foot_0">1</ref> for both indexing and retrieval, after applying Krovetz stemmer and removing standard English stopwords. In particular, we index the title, content, and anchor-text of each document. As a baseline ranker, we use a field-based query likelihood model with Dirichlet smoothing. We set µ = 2, 500, and the weights for the title, content, and anchor-text fields to 0.3, 0.7, and 0.1, respectively. For each query, we retrieve the top 1,000 documents as a candidate set R.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Diversification Strategies</head><p>Given a query q and an initial ranking R produced for this query, we build a new ranking D by iteratively selecting the highest scored document d ∈ R \ D according to:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="1,346.48,537.52,209.44,17.27">d * = arg max d∈R\D (1 -λ)rel (q, d) + λdiv (q, d, D),<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where rel (q, d) and div (q, d, D) are the estimated relevance of d given q and the estimated diversity of d given the already selected documents in D. While rel (q, d) is estimated by the aforementioned relevance ranker, we experiment with multiple diversification strategies for estimating div (q, d, D).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.1">Flat Diversification</head><p>Santos et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="1,377.67,650.51,9.72,7.86" target="#b4">[4]</ref> introduced the xQuAD framework, which estimates div (q, d, D) as the probability that document d covers explicitly identified aspects S underlying the query q that are not well covered by the already selected documents in D. Precisely, xQuAD defines div (q, d, D) as follows: div X (q, d, D) = s∈S P(s|q) P(d|q, s)</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,202.69,76.59,90.21,29.99">d j ∈D (1 -P(dj|q, s)),<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where P(s|q) denotes the relative importance of aspect s given q, P(d|q, s) denotes the coverage of document d with respect to this aspect, and the rightmost product denotes the novelty of any document covering this aspect, based upon how badly this aspect is covered by documents in D.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2">Hierarchical Diversification</head><p>Hu et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,104.51,189.43,9.72,7.86" target="#b2">[2]</ref> proposed HxQuAD as an extension of the xQuAD framework to support diversification using hierarchically organized aspects. Such a hierarchy can be modeled as a tree in which each node represents an aspect and the set of aspects at the i-th level of the tree is denoted Si. Likewise, we can define the diversity of a document d with respect to aspects at the i-th level according to:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,62.98,270.65,229.92,29.99">div i(q, d, D) = s∈S i P(s|q) P(d|q, s) d j ∈D (1 -P(dj|q, s)),<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where both P(s|q) and P(d|q, s) are defined recursively, so that, for any non-leaf aspect s with children C, we have:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,53.80,338.85,244.25,28.22">P(s|q) = c∈C P(c|q) and P(d|q, s) = 1 - c∈C (1 -P(d|q, c)).<label>(4)</label></formula><p>Given these definitions, HxQuAD estimates the overall diversity of document d by linearly combining its diversity estimates at multiple hierarchy levels, according to:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="2,59.68,416.54,233.23,34.54">div H (q, d, D) = αdiv 1(q, d, D) + (1 -α)div 2(q, d, D)+ (1 -α) 2 α div 3(q, d, D) + ... + (1 -α) n-1 α n-2 div n(q, d, D),<label>(5)</label></formula><p>where the α hyperparameter controls the influence of different hierarchy levels in the final estimation, with α = 0.5 indicating that all levels are equally weighted.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.3">Multi-Dimensional Diversification</head><p>Both xQuAD (Equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="2,164.28,509.37,3.84,7.86" target="#formula_1">2</ref>)) and HxQuAD (Equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="2,281.40,509.37,3.84,7.86" target="#formula_4">5</ref>)) assume that query aspects are mined from a single source. Inspired by Dou et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,150.26,530.29,9.20,7.86" target="#b1">[1]</ref>, we extend both frameworks to leverage aspects from multiple sources k ∈ K, such that:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="2,102.38,559.20,190.53,17.86">div M (q, d, D) = k∈K θ k div k (q, d, D),<label>(6)</label></formula><p>where div k (q, d, D) denotes either Equation (2) or Equation (5) leveraging aspects from source k with corresponding weight θ k . In particular, in our experiments, we consider two sources of query aspects, as described next.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.4">Aspect Mining</head><p>Similarly to previous work <ref type="bibr" coords="2,174.76,648.42,9.20,7.86" target="#b4">[4]</ref>, we use query suggestions provided by a major Web search engine as a source of query aspects. Following Hu et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,171.38,669.34,9.20,7.86" target="#b2">[2]</ref>, we only consider two-level hierarchical aspects. In particular, for each query, we collect a first level of aspects by mining suggestions for the initial query. Then, we generate a second level of aspects by mining query suggestions for each first-level aspect.</p><p>In addition to query suggestions, which provide a static surrogate for the actual aspects of interest to the user, we consider a second aspect source built by directly leveraging the user's feedback. In particular, recall that, for each retrieved document d, a user's feedback f = p, a, g includes a passage p that the user deemed relevant to aspect a at a given relevance level g. For the flat diversification performed by xQuAD (Equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="2,408.52,130.86,3.58,7.86" target="#formula_1">2</ref>)), because multiple passages can be deemed relevant to the same aspect, we estimate the coverage of document d with respect to aspect a as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="2,389.83,169.12,166.09,12.71">P(d|q, a) = max p∈a P(d|p),<label>(7)</label></formula><p>where P (d|p) denotes the coverage of passage p by document d. Before the user's feedback is received, this probability is estimated proportionally to the cosine between tf-idf representations of both the passage and the document. Afterwards, this probability is estimated proportionally to the relevance level g directly assigned by the user. In contrast, for HxQuAD (Equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="2,419.94,254.07,3.58,7.86" target="#formula_4">5</ref>)), we directly leverage the hierarchical relationship between the aspect a and each of its associated passages p ∈ a as contributed by the user.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Stopping Strategies</head><p>Based on stopping strategies investigated by Maxwell et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,329.59,317.73,9.20,7.86" target="#b3">[3]</ref>, we evaluate three strategies in our participation: Fixed count. Our system will stop once we have returned x1 documents to the simulated user. We set x1 = 50, which corresponds to 10 iterations.</p><p>Cumulative off-topic count. Our system will stop once we have returned a total of x2 off-topic documents to the simulated user. We set x2 = 10, which corresponds to off-topic documents worth of 2 iterations.</p><p>Windowed off-topic count. Our system will stop once we have returned x3 off-topic documents in a contiguous window. We set x3 = 10, which corresponds to a window of 2 iterations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">EXPERIMENTS</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Runs Summary</head><p>We produced a total of 12 runs in our participation in the TREC DD track, five of which were officially submitted:</p><p>• ufmgXS1 (unofficial) applies flat diversification with single-source aspects and the fixed count stopping condition. We used real-time user feedback as aspects source and xQuAD diversification parameter λ = 0.8.</p><p>• ufmgXS2 (submitted) is similar to ufmgXS1, except that it applies the cumulative stopping condition.</p><p>• ufmgXS3 (unofficial) is similar to ufmgXS1, except that it applies the windowed stopping condition.</p><p>• ufmgXM1 (unofficial) applies flat diversification with multi-source aspects and fixed count stopping condition. We use xQuAD diversification parameter λ = 0.8. At the first iteration, we used only search engine's suggested aspects and in the remaining iterations we used real-time user feedback aspects. • ufmgXM2 (submitted) is similar to ufmgXM1, except that it applies the cumulative stopping condition.</p><p>• ufmgXM3 (unofficial) is similar to ufmgXM1, except that it applies the windowed stopping condition.</p><p>• ufmgHS1 (unofficial) applies hierarchical diversification with single-source aspects and the fixed count stopping condition. We used real-time user feedback as aspects source and HxQuAD diversification parameters λ = 0.8 and α = 1.0.</p><p>• ufmgHS2 (submitted) is similar to ufmgHS1, except that it applies the cumulative stopping condition.</p><p>• ufmgHS3 (unofficial) is similar to ufmgHS1, except that it applies the windowed stopping condition.</p><p>• ufmgHM1 (unofficial) applies hierarchical diversification with multi-source aspects and the fixed count stopping condition. We used HxQuAD diversification parameters λ = 0.8 and α = 1.0. At the first iteration, we used only search engine's suggested aspects and in the remaining iterations we used real-time user feedback aspects.</p><p>• ufmgHM2 (submitted) is similar to ufmgHS1, except that it applies the cumulative stopping condition.</p><p>• ufmgHM3 (submitted) is similar to ufmgHS1, except that it applies the windowed stopping condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Results</head><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="3,351.53,596.12,4.61,7.86" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows the results of our unofficial as well as our officially submitted runs to this task for the official measures Average Cube Test at the 1st, 2nd and 10th iterations. Firstly, we organize the table into models with X and H standing for xQuAD and HxQuAD. Secondly, we divide the table into single-source and multi-source aspects in which F and S mean user real-time feedback and query suggestions, respectively. Finally, we distinguish between the three considered stopping condition strategies where 1, 2 and 3 indicate fixed, cumulative off-topic and windowed offtopic count, respectively. Table <ref type="table" coords="3,449.82,700.72,4.61,7.86" target="#tab_1">2</ref> shows the results of our runs for unofficial measures and is organized in the same way as Table <ref type="table" coords="4,111.93,322.82,3.58,7.86" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. Additionally, Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,212.12,322.82,4.61,7.86">1</ref> shows our system progress over the iterations for our officially submitted runs. We summarize our findings as follows:</p><p>• Our best result uses flat diversification with multisource aspects for the Cube Test, α-nDCG and P@R measures at the 1st iteration and Average Cube Test and P@R at the 2nd iteration. We note improvements regarding Cube Test, α-nDCG and nERR-IA at the 2nd iteration with hierarchical diversification with single-source aspects.</p><p>• Our best result in terms of Average Cube Test and Cube Test at the 10th iteration uses hierarchical diversification with multi-source aspects and a cumulative stopping condition. However, in terms of P@R, our best result at the 10th iteration uses flat diversification with single-source aspects with cumulative stopping condition. In terms of nERR-IA and α-nDCG, our best result at the 10th iteration uses hierarchical diversification with single-source aspects with a fixed count stopping condition.</p><p>• Based on the official measures, our best officially submitted run was ufmgXM2. In Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,229.50,560.48,3.58,7.86">1</ref>, we show how our officially submitted runs perform over all 10 iterations. For the Average Cube Test measure, ufmgXM2 performs distinctively well toward the last iterations, whereas for Cube Test, it outperforms the other alternatives toward the first iterations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">CONCLUSIONS</head><p>In TREC 2016, we participated in the Dynamic Domain track. Our participation focused around diversification approaches, as well as stopping strategies to fulfill the information need of the user as early as possible. Overall, our results on diversification with multi-source aspects in an interactive search process ranked high across iterations compared with the runs submitted by other participants in this track.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,77.47,63.80,454.78,191.63"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Results of our runs on TREC 2016 Dynamic Domain track's official measures</figDesc><table coords="3,77.47,77.12,454.78,178.30"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>Submitted</cell><cell cols="2">Description</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Avg Cube Test</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Cube Test</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="4">Model Source Stop @1</cell><cell>@2</cell><cell>@10</cell><cell>@1</cell><cell>@2</cell><cell>@10</cell></row><row><cell>TREC avg</cell><cell>N/A</cell><cell>N/A</cell><cell>N/A</cell><cell cols="2">N/A 0.1472</cell><cell>0.1361</cell><cell>0.1045</cell><cell>0.2049</cell><cell>0.1388</cell><cell>0.0849</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">TREC median N/A</cell><cell>N/A</cell><cell>N/A</cell><cell cols="2">N/A 0.1516</cell><cell>0.1352</cell><cell>0.0985</cell><cell>0.2174</cell><cell>0.1281</cell><cell>0.0801</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgXS1</cell><cell></cell><cell>X</cell><cell>F</cell><cell>1</cell><cell cols="2">0.1751 0.1587</cell><cell>0.0877</cell><cell>0.2309</cell><cell>0.1506</cell><cell>0.0452</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgXS2</cell><cell></cell><cell>X</cell><cell>F</cell><cell>2</cell><cell cols="2">0.1751 0.1587</cell><cell>0.1188</cell><cell>0.2309</cell><cell>0.1506</cell><cell>0.0786</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgXS3</cell><cell></cell><cell>X</cell><cell>F</cell><cell>3</cell><cell cols="2">0.1751 0.1587</cell><cell>0.1146</cell><cell>0.2309</cell><cell>0.1506</cell><cell>0.0764</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgXM1</cell><cell></cell><cell>X</cell><cell>F+S</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>0.1750</cell><cell cols="2">0.1612 0.0882</cell><cell cols="2">0.2474 0.1574</cell><cell>0.0452</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgXM2</cell><cell></cell><cell>X</cell><cell>F+S</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>0.1750</cell><cell cols="4">0.1612 0.1237 0.2474 0.1574</cell><cell>0.0852</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgXM3</cell><cell></cell><cell>X</cell><cell>F+S</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>0.1750</cell><cell cols="2">0.1612 0.1169</cell><cell cols="2">0.2474 0.1574</cell><cell>0.0797</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgHS1</cell><cell></cell><cell>H</cell><cell>F</cell><cell>1</cell><cell cols="2">0.1751 0.1601</cell><cell>0.0892</cell><cell>0.2309</cell><cell cols="2">0.1578 0.0457</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgHS2</cell><cell></cell><cell>H</cell><cell>F</cell><cell>2</cell><cell cols="2">0.1751 0.1601</cell><cell>0.1219</cell><cell>0.2309</cell><cell cols="2">0.1578 0.0801</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgHS3</cell><cell></cell><cell>H</cell><cell>F</cell><cell>3</cell><cell cols="2">0.1751 0.1601</cell><cell>0.1172</cell><cell>0.2309</cell><cell cols="2">0.1578 0.0763</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgHM1</cell><cell></cell><cell>H</cell><cell>F+S</cell><cell>1</cell><cell cols="2">0.1751 0.1601</cell><cell>0.0893</cell><cell>0.2309</cell><cell>0.1577</cell><cell>0.0463</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgHM2</cell><cell></cell><cell>H</cell><cell>F+S</cell><cell>2</cell><cell cols="2">0.1751 0.1601</cell><cell>0.1219</cell><cell>0.2309</cell><cell>0.1577</cell><cell>0.0842</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgHM3</cell><cell></cell><cell>H</cell><cell>F+S</cell><cell>3</cell><cell cols="2">0.1751 0.1601</cell><cell>0.1181</cell><cell>0.2309</cell><cell>0.1577</cell><cell>0.0808</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,94.69,280.06,420.34,191.63"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results of our runs on TREC 2016 Dynamic Domain track's unofficial measures</figDesc><table coords="3,94.69,293.39,420.34,178.30"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>α-nDCG</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>nERR-IA</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>P@R</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>@1</cell><cell>@2</cell><cell>@10</cell><cell>@1</cell><cell>@2</cell><cell>@10</cell><cell>@1</cell><cell>@2</cell><cell>@10</cell></row><row><cell>TREC avg</cell><cell>0.2999</cell><cell>0.3339</cell><cell>0.3552</cell><cell>0.2821</cell><cell>0.2985</cell><cell>0.3048</cell><cell>0.3486</cell><cell>0.3387</cell><cell>0.2957</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">TREC median 0.2952</cell><cell>0.3142</cell><cell>0.3142</cell><cell>0.2691</cell><cell>0.2777</cell><cell>0.2778</cell><cell>0.3208</cell><cell>0.3038</cell><cell>0.2811</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgXS1</cell><cell>0.3516</cell><cell>0.3987</cell><cell>0.4852</cell><cell cols="2">0.3383 0.3622</cell><cell>0.3849</cell><cell>0.4000</cell><cell cols="2">0.4283 0.3547</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgXS2</cell><cell>0.3516</cell><cell>0.3987</cell><cell>0.4324</cell><cell cols="2">0.3383 0.3622</cell><cell>0.3723</cell><cell>0.4000</cell><cell cols="2">0.4283 0.3871</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgXS3</cell><cell>0.3516</cell><cell>0.3987</cell><cell>0.4458</cell><cell cols="2">0.3383 0.3622</cell><cell>0.3759</cell><cell>0.4000</cell><cell cols="2">0.4283 0.3787</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgXM1</cell><cell cols="2">0.3559 0.4028</cell><cell>0.4786</cell><cell>0.3355</cell><cell>0.3588</cell><cell>0.3786</cell><cell cols="2">0.4226 0.4038</cell><cell>0.3000</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgXM2</cell><cell cols="2">0.3559 0.4028</cell><cell>0.4265</cell><cell>0.3355</cell><cell>0.3588</cell><cell>0.3667</cell><cell cols="2">0.4226 0.4038</cell><cell>0.3504</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgXM3</cell><cell cols="2">0.3559 0.4028</cell><cell>0.4364</cell><cell>0.3355</cell><cell>0.3588</cell><cell>0.3698</cell><cell cols="2">0.4226 0.4038</cell><cell>0.3452</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgHS1</cell><cell>0.3516</cell><cell cols="6">0.4079 0.4921 0.3383 0.3664 0.3887 0.4000</cell><cell>0.4075</cell><cell>0.3479</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgHS2</cell><cell>0.3516</cell><cell cols="2">0.4079 0.4367</cell><cell cols="3">0.3383 0.3664 0.3758</cell><cell>0.4000</cell><cell>0.4075</cell><cell>0.3794</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgHS3</cell><cell>0.3516</cell><cell cols="2">0.4079 0.4504</cell><cell cols="3">0.3383 0.3664 0.3794</cell><cell>0.4000</cell><cell>0.4075</cell><cell>0.3714</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgHM1</cell><cell>0.3516</cell><cell>0.4055</cell><cell>0.4897</cell><cell cols="2">0.3383 0.3653</cell><cell>0.3877</cell><cell>0.4000</cell><cell>0.4075</cell><cell>0.3335</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgHM2</cell><cell>0.3516</cell><cell>0.4055</cell><cell>0.4367</cell><cell cols="2">0.3383 0.3653</cell><cell>0.3754</cell><cell>0.4000</cell><cell>0.4075</cell><cell>0.3716</cell></row><row><cell>ufmgHM3</cell><cell>0.3516</cell><cell>0.4055</cell><cell>0.4481</cell><cell cols="2">0.3383 0.3653</cell><cell>0.3784</cell><cell>0.4000</cell><cell>0.4075</cell><cell>0.3654</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="4,53.80,55.30,502.13,245.25"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Cube Test and Average Cube Test over the iterations (averaged for all topics) for our official runs.</figDesc><table coords="4,53.80,55.30,496.35,245.25"><row><cell></cell><cell>0.16 0.17 0.18</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ufmgXS2 ufmgXM2 ufmgHS2 ufmgHM2 ufmgHM3</cell><cell>0.20 0.25</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ufmgXS2 ufmgXM2 ufmgHS2 ufmgHM2 ufmgHM3</cell></row><row><cell>Avg Cube Test</cell><cell>0.14 0.15</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Cube Test</cell><cell>0.15</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.13</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.10</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.12</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.11</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5 Iteration 6</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>9 10</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5 Iteration 6</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>9 10</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Figure 1:</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,321.42,711.19,185.65,7.86"><p>https://www.elastic.co/products/elasticsearch</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="5.">ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>This work was partially funded by projects <rs type="funder">InWeb</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">MCT/ CNPq 573871/2008-6</rs>) and <rs type="funder">MASWeb</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">FAPEMIG/PRONEX APQ-01400-14</rs>), and by the authors' individual grants from <rs type="funder">CNPq</rs> and <rs type="funder">FAPEMIG</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_wJVChrF">
					<idno type="grant-number">MCT/ CNPq 573871/2008-6</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_6FeZYD5">
					<idno type="grant-number">FAPEMIG/PRONEX APQ-01400-14</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,321.30,388.94,96.81,10.75" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>References</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.00,404.21,199.93,7.86;4,331.01,414.67,223.42,7.86;4,331.01,425.13,129.87,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,331.01,414.67,184.28,7.86">Multi-dimensional search result diversification</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Dou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J.-R</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,533.49,414.67,20.94,7.86;4,331.01,425.13,36.50,7.86">Proc. of WSDM</title>
		<meeting>of WSDM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="475" to="484" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.00,436.59,203.39,7.86;4,331.01,447.05,198.66,7.86;4,331.01,457.51,185.05,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,331.01,447.05,198.66,7.86;4,331.01,457.51,26.00,7.86">Search result diversification based on hierarchical intents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Dou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sakai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J.-R</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,375.28,457.51,57.43,7.86">Proc. of CIKM</title>
		<meeting>of CIKM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="72" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.00,468.97,174.56,7.86;4,331.01,479.43,219.60,7.86;4,331.01,489.89,220.53,7.86;4,331.01,500.35,58.78,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,392.98,479.43,157.62,7.86;4,331.01,489.89,114.16,7.86">Searching and stopping: An analysis of stopping rules and strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Maxwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Azzopardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Järvelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Keskustalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,463.41,489.89,57.43,7.86">Proc. of CIKM</title>
		<meeting>of CIKM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="322" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.00,511.81,183.13,7.86;4,331.01,522.27,214.70,7.86;4,331.01,532.73,224.91,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,331.01,522.27,214.70,7.86;4,331.01,532.73,54.72,7.86">Exploiting query reformulations for web search result diversification</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L T</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,403.90,532.73,57.59,7.86">Proc. of WWW</title>
		<meeting>of WWW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="881" to="890" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,331.00,544.19,219.91,7.86;4,331.01,554.65,195.92,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,474.70,544.19,76.22,7.86;4,331.01,554.65,89.49,7.86">Trec 2015 dynamic domain track overview</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Soboroff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,439.21,554.65,57.96,7.86">Proc. of TREC</title>
		<meeting>of TREC</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
