<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,99.60,148.73,404.03,15.51;1,180.36,170.69,242.47,15.51">ENSM-SE at CLEF 2006 : AdHocUses of fuzzy proximity matching function</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2006-08-20">August 20, 2006</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,212.40,204.07,80.11,9.96"><forename type="first">Annabelle</forename><surname>Mercier</surname></persName>
							<email>annabelle.mercier@emse.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Ecole Nationale Superieure des Mines de Saint Etienne (ENSM-SE)</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>158 cours Fauriel</addrLine>
									<postCode>42023</postCode>
									<settlement>Saint Etienne Cedex 2</settlement>
									<country key="FR">FRANCE</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,315.13,204.07,75.54,9.96"><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Beigbeder</surname></persName>
							<email>michel.beigbeder@emse.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Ecole Nationale Superieure des Mines de Saint Etienne (ENSM-SE)</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>158 cours Fauriel</addrLine>
									<postCode>42023</postCode>
									<settlement>Saint Etienne Cedex 2</settlement>
									<country key="FR">FRANCE</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,99.60,148.73,404.03,15.51;1,180.36,170.69,242.47,15.51">ENSM-SE at CLEF 2006 : AdHocUses of fuzzy proximity matching function</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2006-08-20">August 20, 2006</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">2D9CFF0BC8A5883CD53240EB11B6F64E</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:11+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H</term>
					<term>3 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: H</term>
					<term>3</term>
					<term>3 Information Search and Retrieval term proximity, fuzzy information retrieval</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Starting from the idea that the closer the query terms in a document are to each other the more relevant the document, we propose an information retrieval method that uses the degree of fuzzy proximity of key terms in a document to compute the relevance of the document to the query. Our model handles Boolean queries but, contrary to the traditional extensions of the basic Boolean information retrieval model, does not use a proximity operator explicitly. A single parameter makes it possible to control the proximity degree required. To improve our system we use a stemming algorithm before indexing, we take a specific influence function and we merge fuzzy proximity result list built with different spread of influence function. We explain how we construct the queries and report the results of our experiments in the ad-hoc monolingual French task of the CLEF 2006 evaluation campaign.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In the information retrieval domain, systems are based on three basic models: the Boolean model, the vector model and the probabilistic model. These models have many variations (extended Boolean models, models based on fuzzy sets theory, generalized vector space model,. . . ) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,472.66,658.75,10.00,9.96" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. However, they are all based on weak representations of documents: either sets of terms or bags of terms. In the first case, what the information retrieval system knows about a document is whether it contains a given term or not. In the second case, the system knows the number of occurrences -the term frequency, tf -of a given term in each document. So whatever the order of the terms in the documents, they share the same index representation if they use the same terms. Noteworthy exceptions to this rule are most of the Boolean model implementations which propose a near operator <ref type="bibr" coords="1,131.05,742.51,14.60,9.96" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. This operator is a kind of and but with the constraint that the different terms are within a window of size n, where n is an integral value. The set of retrieved documents can be restricted with this operator. For instance, it is possible to discriminate between documents about "data structures" and those about "data about concrete structures". Using this operator results in an increase in precision of the system <ref type="bibr" coords="2,303.60,147.31,9.91,9.96" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. But the Boolean systems that implement a near operator share the same limitation as any basic Boolean system: these systems are not able to rank the retrieved documents because with this model a document is or is not relevant to a query. Different extensions have been proposed to the basic Boolean systems to circumvent this limitation. These extensions represent the documents with some kind of term weights. Most of the time these weights are computed on a tf basis. Some combining formulas are then applied to compute the document score given the term weights and the query tree. But these extensions are not compatible with the near operator. Some researchers have thus proposed models that attempt to directly score the documents by taking into account the proximity of the query terms within them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Uses of Proximity</head><p>Three methods have been proposed to score documents taking into account different sets of intervals containing the query terms. These methods differ in the set of intervals that are selected in a first step, and then in the formulas used to compute the score for a given interval. The method of Clarke et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,159.61,345.55,10.45,9.96" target="#b1">[2]</ref> selects the shortest intervals that contain all the query terms (this constraint is relaxed if there are not enough retrieved documents), so the intervals cannot be nested. In the method of Hawking et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,220.33,369.43,10.00,9.96" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, for each query term occurrence, the shortest interval containing all the query terms is selected, thus the selected intervals can nest. Rasolofo et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,462.72,381.43,10.45,9.96" target="#b7">[8]</ref> chose to select intervals only containing two terms of the query, but with the additional constraint that the interval is shorter than five words.</p><p>Moreover, passage retrieval methods indirectly use the notion of proximity. In fact, in several methods, documents are ranked by selecting documents which have passages with a high density of query terms, that is to say documents where the query terms are near to each other <ref type="bibr" coords="2,472.44,441.19,15.49,9.96" target="#b10">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,491.40,441.19,7.69,9.96" target="#b2">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,502.44,441.19,7.05,9.96" target="#b5">6]</ref>. The next section presents our method which scores documents on the basis of term proximity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Fuzzy Proximity Matching</head><p>To address the problem of scoring the documents taking into account the relative order of the words in the document, we have defined a new method based on a fuzzy proximity between each position in the document text and a query. This fuzzy proximity function is summed up over to score the document.</p><p>We model the fuzzy proximity to an occurrence of a term with an influence function f that reaches its maximum (value 1) at the value 0 and decreases on each side down to 0. Different types of functions (Hamming, rectangular, gaussian, etc.) can be used. We used an adhoc and a triangular one displayed in figure 1. In the following, the examples and the experiments will be based on a triangular function x → max( k-|x| k , 0). The constant k controls the support of the function and this support represents the extent of influence of each term occurrence. A similar parameter can be found for other shapes.</p><p>So, for a query term t, the fuzzy proximity function to the occurrence at position i of the term t is x → f (xi). Now, we define the term proximity function w d t which models the fuzzy proximity at the position x in the text to the term t by combining the fuzzy proximity functions of the different occurrences of the term t:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,234.36,696.78,134.31,17.23">x → w d t (x) = max i∈Occ(t,d) f (x -i)</formula><p>where Occ(t, d) is the set of the positions of the term t in the document d and f is the influence function. The query model is the classical Boolean model: A tree with terms on the leaves and or or and operators on the internal nodes. At an internal node, the proximity functions of the sons of this node are combined in the query tree with the usual fuzzy set theory formulas. So the fuzzy proximity is computed by w d q or q ′ = max(w d q , w d q ′ ) for a disjunctive node and by w d q and q ′ = min(w d q , w d q ′ ) for a conjunctive node. With a post-order tree traversal a fuzzy proximity function to the query can be computed at the root of the query tree as the fuzzy proximity functions are defined on the leaves.</p><p>So we obtain a function w d q from to the interval [0, 1]. The result of the summation of this function is used as the score of the document:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,251.64,391.95,99.73,30.46">s(q, d) = +∞ x=-∞ w d q (x) .</formula><p>Thus, the computed score s(q, d) depends on the fuzzy proximity functions and enables document ranking according to the query term proximity in the documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments and Evaluation</head><p>We carried out experiments within the context of the clef 2006 evaluation campaign in the adhoc monolingual French task<ref type="foot" coords="3,215.88,511.11,3.97,6.97" target="#foot_0">1</ref> . We used the retrieval search engine Lucy<ref type="foot" coords="3,410.88,511.11,3.97,6.97" target="#foot_1">2</ref> which is based on the Okapi information retrieval model <ref type="bibr" coords="3,243.99,524.47,10.57,9.96" target="#b8">[9]</ref> to index this collection. It was easy to adapt this tool to our method because it keeps the positions of the terms occurring in the documents in the index. Thus, we extended this tool to compute the relevance score values for our fuzzy proximity matching function. Documents in the clef 2006 test collection are newspapers articles in XML format from SDA and Le Monde of the years 1994 and 1995. For each document (tag &lt;DOC&gt;), we keep the fields &lt;DOCNO&gt; with the tag and the document number, the textual contents of the tags &lt;TX&gt;, &lt;LD&gt;, &lt;TI&gt;, &lt;ST&gt; for SDA French and &lt;TEXT&gt;, &lt;LEAD1&gt;, &lt;TITLE&gt; for Le Monde 1995. We used the topics and the relevance judgements to evaluate the different methods by the trec eval program.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Building the Queries</head><p>Each topic is composed of three tags: &lt;FR-title&gt;, &lt;FR-desc&gt;, &lt;FR-narr&gt;. Two sets of queries were built for our experiments.</p><p>Automatically built queries. For this set, a query is built with the terms from the title field where the stop words<ref type="foot" coords="4,183.48,122.07,3.97,6.97" target="#foot_2">3</ref> are removed. Here is an example with the topic #278. The original topic is expressed by: &lt;top&gt; &lt;num&gt; 278 &lt;/num&gt; &lt;FR-title&gt; Les moyens de transport pour handicapés&lt;/FR-title&gt; &lt;FR-desc&gt; A quels problèmes doivent faire face les personnes handicapées physiques lorsquelles empruntent les transports publics et quelles solutions sont proposées ou adoptées? &lt;/FR-desc&gt; &lt;FR-narr&gt; Les documents pertinents devront décrire les difficultés auxquelles doivent faire face les personnes diminuées physiquement lorsquelles utilisent les transports publics et/ou traiter des progrès accomplis pour résoudre ces problèmes. &lt;/FR-narr&gt; &lt;/top&gt; First, the topic number and the title field are extracted and concatenated:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="278">moyens transport handicapés</head><p>From this form, the queries are automatically built by simple derivations:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Lucy:</head><p>278 moyens transport handicapés conjunctive fuzzy proximity: 278 moyens &amp; transport &amp; handicapés disjunctive fuzzy proximity: 278 moyens | transport | handicapés Manually built queries. They are built with all the terms from the title field and some terms from the description field. The general idea was to build conjunctions (which are the basis of our method) of disjunctions. The disjunctions are composed of the plural form of the terms and some derivations to compensate the lack of a stemming tool in Lucy. Sometimes some terms from the same semantic field were grouped together in the disjunctions.</p><p>Queries for the method implemented in the Lucy tool are flat queries composed of different inflectional and/or derivational forms of the terms. Here is an example for topic #278: </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Building the Result Lists</head><p>The Okapi model and our fuzzy method were compared.</p><p>In first time, it is well known that the Okapi method gives one of the best performances. However, a previous study showed that proximity based methods improve retrieval <ref type="bibr" coords="4,466.21,660.79,10.00,9.96" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. If one of our experiments with our proximity based method does not retrieve enough documents (one thousand for the clef experiments), then its results list is supplemented by documents from the Okapi result list that have not yet been retrieved by the proximity based method.</p><p>In second time, we note in past experiments that the higher the area (k = 200 was used) of influence of a term the better the results are. Moreover, we retrieved more documents with fuzzy proximity with a large spread of influence function. So, we merge for each type of queries (title, description and manual), the results obtained with several k values (k equal to 200, 100, 80, 50, 20, 5).  In the official runs, the queries used with fuzzy proximity method and adhoc influence function were:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Submitted Runs</head><p>1. the conjunction of the terms automatically extracted from the title field in run RIMAM06TL;</p><p>2. the conjunction of the terms automatically extracted from the description field in run RIMAM06TDNL and;</p><p>3. manually built queries with terms from the three fields run RIMAM06TDML.</p><p>The run RIMAM06TDMLRef use the triangular influence function.</p><p>Here we present with CLEF 2005 queries the differences obtained between runs with stemming (or not) at indexing step or at query formulation step.</p><p>For the runs where the Okapi method was used, the queries are flat (bag of terms). These runs were produced by using the native Lucy search engine and they provide the baselines for the comparison with our method. The recall precision results are provided in figures 2.</p><p>We can see that the runs with no stemming step before indexing have less precision than the others. The figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,194.29,662.59,4.98,9.96">3</ref> shows also the stemming step provide better results. But we can see that the run TitleDescManual is above the ConjTitle100 which means that the words added for "stemming" queries increase the precision results. The last figure 4 the differences between Okapi Lucy method and fuzzy proximity method. We can see that our method is better than Lucy one (ManualNoStem200 vs. LucyTitleNoStem; StemManual200 vs. ConjTitle200). We can note the run with stemming at indexing and at query time is the better one.</p><p>We have presented our information retrieval model which takes into account the position of the query terms in the documents to compute the relevance scores. We experimented this method on the clef 2006 Ad-Hoc French test collection.</p><p>In these experiment, we submit runs which use different k values in order to retrieve more documents with our method. We think also that the results could be improved by using an automatic stemming procedure. Eventually we think that the user can add query word taken within a thesaurus in order to retrieve more documents with our method. In further experiments, we will use other function at AND and OR nodes and we want to specifies "phrases" in the queries.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,136.32,198.07,330.32,9.96"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The adhoc and triangular influence functions used in experiments</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,90.00,543.33,330.30,9.26;4,194.88,555.39,194.11,9.20;4,90.00,567.21,27.13,8.98;4,175.92,567.27,192.07,9.20;4,194.88,579.27,152.11,9.20"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>fuzzy proximity: 278 (moyen | moyens) &amp; (transport | transports) &amp; (handicap | handicapé | handicapés) Lucy: 278 moyen moyens transport transports handicap handicapé handicapés</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="5,90.00,436.99,422.97,9.96;5,90.00,448.87,353.90,9.96"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Okapi Lucy -Result with stemming at indexing (LucyTitle, StemManualLucy, Ti-tleDescManualLucy) and no stemming (LucyTitleNoStem, LucyManualNoStem).</figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="3,105.24,697.44,79.08,7.97"><p>http://clef.isti.cnr.it/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="3,105.24,706.92,127.30,7.97"><p>http://www.seg.rmit.edu.au/lucy/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="4,105.24,739.68,402.36,7.97"><p>Removed stop words: à, aux, au, chez, et, dans, des, de, du, en, la, les, le, par, sur, uns, unes, une, un, d', l'.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" />			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.52,271.75,402.68,9.96;7,110.52,283.63,105.73,9.96" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,325.44,271.75,129.31,9.96">Modern Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ricardo</forename><surname>Baeza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">-</forename><surname>Yates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Berthier</forename><surname>Ribeiro-Neto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<publisher>ACM Press / Addison-Wesley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.52,303.55,402.56,9.96;7,110.52,315.43,391.69,9.96" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,419.29,303.55,93.80,9.96;7,110.52,315.43,108.66,9.96">Relevance ranking for one to three term queries</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Charles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gordon</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Cormack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Tudhope</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,227.64,315.43,176.64,9.96">Information Processing and Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="291" to="311" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.52,335.35,402.73,9.96;7,110.52,347.35,402.51,9.96;7,110.52,359.23,402.42,9.96;7,110.52,371.23,22.93,9.96" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,278.66,335.35,234.60,9.96;7,110.52,347.35,79.66,9.96">Effective document presentation with a locality-based similarity heuristic</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Owen</forename><surname>De</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Kretser</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alistair</forename><surname>Moffat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,209.16,347.35,303.87,9.96;7,110.52,359.23,291.79,9.96">SIGIR &apos;99: Proceedings of the 22nd ACM SIGIR Annual International Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999-09">9 1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="120" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.52,391.03,402.58,9.96;7,110.52,403.03,347.04,9.96" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,256.47,391.03,189.62,9.96">Proximity operators -so near and yet so far</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hawking</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Thistlewaite</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,167.64,403.03,215.38,9.96">The Fourth Text REtrieval Conference (TREC-4)</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="143" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.52,434.83,402.41,9.96;7,110.52,446.83,160.45,9.96" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,175.69,434.83,277.42,9.96">Some aspects of proximity searching in text retrieval systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Keen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,466.67,434.83,46.26,9.96;7,110.52,446.83,86.02,9.96">Journal of Information Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="98" />
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.52,466.63,402.60,9.96;7,110.52,478.63,402.51,9.96;7,110.52,490.51,402.40,9.96;7,110.52,502.51,402.49,9.96;7,110.52,514.51,133.71,9.96" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,439.92,466.63,73.20,9.96;7,110.52,478.63,402.51,9.96;7,110.52,490.51,41.38,9.96">Passage retrieval based on density distributions of terms and its applications to document retrieval and question answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Koichi</forename><surname>Kise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Markus</forename><surname>Junker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Dengel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Keinosuke</forename><surname>Matsumoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,459.59,490.51,53.32,9.96;7,110.52,502.51,172.27,9.96">Reading and Learning: Adaptive Content Recognition</title>
		<title level="s" coord="7,357.96,502.51,150.70,9.96">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Dengel</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Markus</forename><surname>Junker</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anette</forename><surname>Weisbecker</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2956. 2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="306" to="327" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.52,531.79,402.43,12.48;7,110.52,546.31,402.48,9.96;7,110.52,558.19,22.93,9.96" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,165.96,531.79,347.00,12.48;7,110.52,546.31,219.10,9.96">Étude comparative de trois approches utilisant la proximité entre les termes de la requête pour le calcul des scores des documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mercier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,352.79,546.31,49.53,9.96">INFORSID</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2004-05">2004. mai 2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.52,578.11,402.56,9.96;7,110.52,590.11,402.50,9.96;7,110.52,601.99,133.71,9.96" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,266.53,578.11,246.55,9.96;7,110.52,590.11,18.62,9.96">Term proximity scoring for keyword-based retrieval systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Yves</forename><surname>Rasolofo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jacques</forename><surname>Savoy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,148.08,590.11,260.45,9.96">25th European Conference on Information Retrieval Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2633</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="218" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.52,621.91,402.55,9.96;7,110.52,633.79,402.36,9.96;7,110.52,645.79,65.64,9.96" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,474.63,621.91,38.45,9.96;7,110.52,633.79,23.86,9.96">Okapi at trec-3</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hancock-Beaulieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gatford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,251.28,633.79,256.30,9.96">Overview of the Third Text REtrieval Conference (TREC-3)</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="126" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.52,677.59,402.61,9.96;7,110.52,689.59,95.54,9.96" xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,253.55,677.59,195.67,9.96">Introduction to Modern Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gerard</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mcgill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983">1983</date>
			<publisher>McGraw-Hill Book Company</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,110.52,709.39,402.35,9.96;7,110.52,721.39,402.43,9.96;7,110.52,733.39,316.10,9.96" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,190.93,709.39,189.82,9.96">Effective retrieval of structured documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ross</forename><surname>Wilkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,408.59,709.39,104.28,9.96;7,110.52,721.39,402.43,9.96;7,110.52,733.39,89.30,9.96">SIGIR &apos;94, Proceedings of the 17th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<date>7 1994</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="317" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
