<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,136.98,70.04,348.95,11.84">Evaluating Language Resources for English-Indonesian CLIR</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,216.00,105.70,61.25,8.48"><forename type="first">Herika</forename><surname>Hayurani</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Indonesia Depok</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>16424</postCode>
									<country key="ID">Indonesia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,283.69,105.70,47.18,8.48"><forename type="first">Syandra</forename><surname>Sari</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Indonesia Depok</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>16424</postCode>
									<country key="ID">Indonesia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,352.64,105.70,54.14,8.48"><forename type="first">Mirna</forename><surname>Adriani</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Indonesia Depok</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>16424</postCode>
									<country key="ID">Indonesia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,136.98,70.04,348.95,11.84">Evaluating Language Resources for English-Indonesian CLIR</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">90E37B11C4D5180A6D7590A356D7C761</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:11+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>cross-language information retrieval</term>
					<term>machine translation</term>
					<term>dictionary translation</term>
					<term>parallel corpus</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We present a report on our participation in the Indonesian-English ad hoc bilingual task of the 2006 Cross-Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF). This year we compare the use of several language resources to translate Indonesian queries into English. We used several readable machine dictionaries to perform the translation. We also used two machine translation techniques to translate the Indonesian queries. In addition to translating an Indonesian query set into English, we also translated English documents into Indonesian using the machine readable dictionaries and a commercial machine translation tool. The results show performing the task by translating the queries is better than translating the documents. Combining several dictionaries produced better result than only using one dictionary. However, the query expansion that we applied to the translated queries using the dictionaries reduced the retrieval effectiveness of the queries.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>This year we participate in the bilingual 2006 Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF) ad hoc task, i.e., the English-Indonesian CLIR. As stated in previous work <ref type="bibr" coords="1,297.37,406.12,9.98,8.48" target="#b7">[8]</ref>, a translation step must be done either to the documents <ref type="bibr" coords="1,92.22,416.86,11.01,8.48" target="#b8">[9]</ref> or to the queries <ref type="bibr" coords="1,176.54,416.86,10.23,8.48" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,190.59,416.86,7.08,8.48" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,201.64,416.86,7.86,8.48" target="#b5">6]</ref> in order to overcome the language barrier. The translation can be done using bilingual readable machine dictionaries <ref type="bibr" coords="1,246.22,427.72,10.24,8.48" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,259.56,427.72,6.83,8.48" target="#b1">2]</ref>, machine translation techniques <ref type="bibr" coords="1,394.48,427.72,10.05,8.48" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, or parallel corpora <ref type="bibr" coords="1,485.53,427.72,14.46,8.48" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. We used a commercial machine translation software package called Transtool<ref type="foot" coords="1,381.00,436.60,3.05,5.49" target="#foot_0">1</ref> and an online machine translation system available on the Internet to translate an Indonesian query set into English and to translate English documents into Indonesian. We learned from our previous work <ref type="bibr" coords="1,343.98,460.18,10.16,8.48" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,357.38,460.18,7.94,8.48" target="#b1">2]</ref> that freely available dictionaries on the Internet could not correctly translate many Indonesian terms, as their vocabulary was very limited. We hoped that using machine translation techniques and parallel documents could improve our result this time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The Translation Process</head><p>In our participation, we translate English queries and documents using dictionaries and machine translation techniques. We manually translated the original CLEF query set from English into Indonesian. We then translated the resulting Indonesian queries back into English using dictionaries and machine translation techniques. The dictionaries come from several sources, particularly, the Indonesian National Research and Technology Office (Badan Pengkajian dan Penelitian Teknologi or BPPT) and online dictionaries on the internet, namely http://www.orisinil.com/kamus.php and http://www.kamus.net/main.php. The machine translation systems that we use are Toggletext (www.toggletext.com) and Transtool, a commercial software package.</p><p>Besides translating the queries, we also translate the English documents from CLEF into Indonesian. The translation process is done using the dictionary from BPPT and Transtool. The translation process using the dictionary is done by taking only the first definition for each English word in the document.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Query Expansion Technique</head><p>Adding translated queries with relevant terms, known as query expansion, has been shown to improve CLIR effectiveness <ref type="bibr" coords="2,144.66,92.68,10.16,8.48" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,158.01,92.68,7.09,8.48" target="#b2">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,168.20,92.68,11.23,8.48" target="#b11">12]</ref>. One of the query expansion techniques is called the pseudo relevance feedback <ref type="bibr" coords="2,496.14,92.68,10.27,8.48" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,509.51,92.68,6.81,8.48" target="#b4">5]</ref>. This technique is based on an assumption that the top few documents initially retrieved are indeed relevant to the query, and so they must contain other terms that are also relevant to the query. The query expansion technique adds such terms into the previous query. We apply this technique to the queries in this work. To choose the relevant terms from the top ranked documents we employ the tf*idf term weighting formula <ref type="bibr" coords="2,452.33,136.00,14.49,8.48" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. We added a certain number of terms that have the highest weight scores.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiment</head><p>In the experiments, we used Lemur<ref type="foot" coords="2,225.72,206.26,3.05,5.49" target="#foot_1">2</ref> information retrieval system which is based on the language model to index and retrieve the documents.</p><p>We then applied a pseudo relevance-feedback query-expansion technique to the queries that were translated using the machine translation tool. We used the top 10 relevant documents retrieved for a query from the collection to extract the expansion terms. The terms were then added to the original query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>The results of our CLIR experiments were obtained by applying the three methods of translation, i.e., using the machine translations, using dictionaries, and using parallel corpus. Table <ref type="table" coords="2,368.95,334.60,4.71,8.48">1</ref> shows the result of the first technique, which shows that translating the English queries into Indonesian using Toggletext machine translation tool is better than using Transtool.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="2,153.96,378.34,3.55,8.48">1</ref>. Average retrieval precision in CLIR runs of queries translated using the machine translation tools for title only and combination of title and description. The result of the second technique, which is translating the English queries into Indonesian using dictionaries, is shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,154.99,493.60,3.54,8.48" target="#tab_0">2</ref>. The result shows that using the dictionary from BPPT alone is not as good as using several dictionaries combined.</p><p>The last technique that we use is retrieving documents from parallel corpus created by translating the English document collection into Indonesian using the combined dictionaries and Transtool. The results, as shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,118.77,547.66,3.54,8.48" target="#tab_1">3</ref>, indicate that of retrieving the English version of Indonesian documents that are relevant to an Indonesian query, is much more effective if the parallel corpus is created using the machine translation tool than using the dictionaries. Lastly, we also attempted to improve our CLIR results by expanding the queries translated using the dictionaries. We were unable to do the expansion process to all the translated queries because of time limitation. The results is as shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,165.62,227.86,3.54,8.48" target="#tab_2">4</ref>, which indicates that adding the queries with 5 terms from the top-10 documents obtained from a pseudo relevance feedback technique hurt the retrieval performance of the translated queries. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Summary</head><p>Our experiments demonstrate that translating queries using machine translation tools is better than translating documents. The retrieval performance of queries that were translated using machine translation tools for Bahasa Indonesia was about 14.28%-18.83% of that of retrieving the documents translated using machine translation.</p><p>There was no significant difference in retrieval performance between the two machine translation tools that we used.</p><p>Taking the first definition in the dictionary when translating an English query into Indonesian appeared to be effective. The result of combining several dictionaries is much better than only using one dictionary.</p><p>In order to improve the retrieval performance of the translated queries, we expanded the queries with the terms extracted from the top-10 documents. However, the pseudo relevance feedback technique that is known to improve the retrieval performance did not improve the retrieval performance of our queries.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,126.12,591.40,362.23,87.99"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Average retrieval precision in CLIR runs of queries translated using dictionaries for title only and combination of title and description.</figDesc><table coords="2,201.00,631.06,192.71,48.32"><row><cell>Task</cell><cell>Dic-1</cell><cell>Dic-2</cell></row><row><cell>Title</cell><cell>0.1423</cell><cell>0.2063</cell></row><row><cell>Title + Description</cell><cell>0.1101</cell><cell>0.2650</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,126.12,91.00,362.10,88.04"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Average retrieval precision in the monolingual runs for title only and combination of title and description on a parallel corpus created by translating English documents into Indonesian using dictionaries and a machine translation tool.</figDesc><table coords="3,198.24,141.46,214.79,37.58"><row><cell>Task</cell><cell>Parallel-DIC</cell><cell>Parallel-MT</cell></row><row><cell>Title</cell><cell>0.0201</cell><cell>0.2060</cell></row><row><cell>Title + Description</cell><cell>0.0271</cell><cell>0.2515</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="3,126.12,260.80,362.06,88.05"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Average retrieval precision for the title only and combination of title and description using the query expansion technique with top-10 document method.</figDesc><table coords="3,185.58,300.40,229.22,48.44"><row><cell>Task</cell><cell>Dic-2</cell><cell>Query Expansion</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(5 terms added)</cell></row><row><cell>Title</cell><cell>0.2063</cell><cell>0.1205</cell></row><row><cell>Title + Description</cell><cell>0.2650</cell><cell>0.1829</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,97.62,703.36,181.91,8.48"><p>See "http://www.geocities.com/cdpenerjemah/".</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,97.62,703.36,137.50,8.48"><p>See "http://www.lemurproject.org/".</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="3,95.77,607.12,424.09,8.48;3,109.20,617.98,410.54,8.48;3,109.20,628.72,330.42,8.48" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,268.28,607.12,251.58,8.48;3,109.20,617.98,81.50,8.48">Term Similarity Based Query Expansion for Cross Language Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Adriani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Rijsbergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,208.98,617.98,310.76,8.48;3,109.20,628.72,125.27,8.48">Proceedings of Research and Advanced Technology for Digital Libraries, Third European Conference (ECDL&apos;99)</title>
		<meeting>Research and Advanced Technology for Digital Libraries, Third European Conference (ECDL&apos;99)<address><addrLine>Paris</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999-09">September 1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="322" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,95.77,639.58,423.94,8.48;3,109.20,650.44,143.17,8.48" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,161.01,639.58,230.25,8.48">Ambiguity Problem in Multilingual Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Adriani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,412.68,639.58,107.03,8.48;3,109.20,650.44,36.03,8.48">CLEF 2000 Working Note Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Portugal</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000-09">September 2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,95.77,661.18,424.01,8.48;3,109.20,672.04,410.50,8.48;3,109.20,682.90,103.50,8.48" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,157.04,661.18,221.54,8.48">English-Ducth CLIR Using Query Translation Techniques</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Adriani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,396.54,661.18,123.24,8.48;3,109.20,672.04,210.29,8.48">Proceedings of the Workshop of the Cross-Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2001)</title>
		<title level="s" coord="3,328.10,672.04,141.54,8.48">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop of the Cross-Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2001)<address><addrLine>Darmstadt, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-09">September 2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,95.77,68.92,423.99,8.48;4,109.20,79.72,83.22,8.48;4,192.36,77.74,4.15,5.49;4,199.14,79.72,320.62,8.48;4,109.20,90.52,79.14,8.48" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,299.19,68.92,203.65,8.48">Resolving Ambiguity for Cross-language Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ballesteros</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Bruce</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,109.20,79.72,83.22,8.48;4,192.36,77.74,4.15,5.49;4,199.14,79.72,320.62,8.48;4,109.20,90.52,34.49,8.48">Proceedings of the 21 st International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 21 st International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="64" to="71" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,95.77,101.38,423.95,8.48;4,109.20,112.18,161.80,8.48" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,222.06,101.38,177.03,8.48">Local Feedback in Full-Text Retrieval Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Attar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Fraenkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,405.92,101.38,113.80,8.48;4,109.20,112.18,83.53,8.48">Journal of the Association for Computing Machinery</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="397" to="417" />
			<date type="published" when="1977">1977</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,95.77,122.98,423.99,8.48;4,109.20,133.84,392.86,8.48" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,235.02,122.98,284.74,8.48;4,109.20,133.84,33.17,8.48">A TREC Evaluation of Query Translation Methods for Multi-Lingual Text Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ted</forename><surname>Dunning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,221.49,133.84,182.51,8.48">The Fourth Text Retrieval Conference (TREC-4)</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ed</forename><forename type="middle">D K</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>NIST</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1995-11">November. 1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,95.77,144.64,423.98,8.48;4,109.20,155.44,410.51,8.48;4,109.20,166.30,219.51,8.48" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,284.44,144.64,235.31,8.48;4,109.20,155.44,85.55,8.48">Exeter at CLEF 2001: Experiments with Machine Translation for Bilingual Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gareth</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Lam-Adesina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Adenike</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,212.52,155.44,307.19,8.48;4,109.20,166.30,20.24,8.48">Proceedings of the Workshop of the Cross-Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2001)</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop of the Cross-Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2001)<address><addrLine>Darmstadt, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-09">September 2001</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="114" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,95.77,177.10,423.89,8.48;4,109.20,187.90,395.42,8.48" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,188.75,177.10,330.90,8.48;4,109.20,187.90,37.34,8.48">Should We Translate the Documents or the Queries in Cross-Language Information Retrieval?</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mccarley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,162.84,187.90,268.49,8.48">Proceedings of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL&apos;99)</title>
		<meeting>the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL&apos;99)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="208" to="214" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,95.77,198.70,424.02,8.48;4,109.20,209.56,410.50,8.48;4,109.20,220.36,21.21,8.48" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,232.49,198.70,287.30,8.48;4,109.20,209.56,44.96,8.48">Document Translation for Cross-Language Text Retrieval at the University of Maryland</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Oard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Hackett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,171.26,209.56,230.39,8.48">Proceedings of the Sixth Text Retrieval Conference (TREC-6)</title>
		<meeting>the Sixth Text Retrieval Conference (TREC-6)<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997-11">November 1997</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,100.15,231.16,419.66,8.48;4,109.20,242.02,40.58,8.48" xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,259.56,231.16,172.55,8.48">Introduction to Modern Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gerard</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Mcgill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983">1983</date>
			<publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,100.15,252.82,419.60,8.48;4,109.20,263.62,410.55,8.48;4,109.20,274.48,278.20,8.48" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,242.21,252.82,277.54,8.48;4,109.20,263.62,25.77,8.48">Experiments in Multilingual Information Retrieval using the SPIDER System</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sheridan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Ballerini</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,145.56,263.62,374.19,8.48;4,109.20,274.48,142.13,8.48">Proceedings of the 19th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 19th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval<address><addrLine>Zürich, Switzerland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996-08">August 1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,100.15,285.28,419.56,8.48;4,109.20,296.08,36.82,8.48;4,146.04,294.10,4.73,5.49;4,155.04,296.08,364.73,8.48;4,109.20,306.94,60.34,8.48" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,230.92,285.28,224.42,8.48">Query expansion using local and global document analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jinxi</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Bruce</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,472.74,285.28,46.97,8.48;4,109.20,296.08,36.82,8.48;4,146.04,294.10,4.73,5.49;4,155.04,296.08,364.73,8.48;4,109.20,306.94,33.17,8.48">Proceedings in the 19 th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>in the 19 th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and development in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
