<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,92.10,79.85,410.57,12.90;1,119.60,95.79,356.40,12.90">Alibaba DAMO Academy at TREC Clinical Trials 2021: Exploring Embedding-based First-stage Retrieval with TrialMatcher</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,100.44,129.17,43.52,10.75"><forename type="first">Qiao</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
							<email>qiao.jqa@alibaba-inc.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Alibaba Inc</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,161.25,129.17,67.01,10.75"><forename type="first">Chuanqi</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
							<email>chuanqi.tcq@alibaba-inc.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Alibaba Inc</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,238.97,129.17,81.39,10.75"><forename type="first">Zhengyun</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,331.07,129.17,62.35,10.75"><forename type="first">Zheng</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Tsinghua University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Alibaba Inc</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,410.71,129.17,85.37,10.75"><forename type="first">Songfang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<email>songfang.hsf@alibaba-inc.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Alibaba Inc</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,92.10,79.85,410.57,12.90;1,119.60,95.79,356.40,12.90">Alibaba DAMO Academy at TREC Clinical Trials 2021: Exploring Embedding-based First-stage Retrieval with TrialMatcher</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">75A468319D5FDA58161F3FC7A93A60AE</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:11+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the submissions of Ailbaba DAMO Academy to the TREC 2021 Clinical Trials Track, where the task is to match eligible clinical trials for given patient notes. Our systems follow the standard retrieval-reranking procedure. We propose a novel embeddingbased retrieval model, TrialMatcher, as the retriever. TrialMatcher contains a patient note encoder and a clinical trial encoder pre-trained by 370k clinical trial documents. It retrieves relevant clinical trials based on embedding space distances. We then use different re-rankers to reorder the candidates returned by Trial-Matcher. In automatic runs, the re-rankers are trained by a relevant dataset or a synthetic patient-trial relevance dataset. In manual runs, the re-rankers are trained by annotations derived from a human-in-the-loop active learning strategy. Our automatic runs rank the second in all participants on all four metrics. Our manual runs rank the first on one metric, and the second on three other metrics.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Clinical trials are studies that prospectively study the effects of different treatments on human subjects<ref type="foot" coords="1,91.26,556.97,3.99,6.91" target="#foot_0">1</ref> , which is conceptually similar to the A/B testing in software engineering. In most countries, new therapies should be evaluated by clinical trials before approved. It is vitally important to match eligible patients to clinical trials, because: 1) patients have the potentials to greatly benefit from novel treatments, especially when there is no effective therapy available. For example, late-stage cancer patients can be unresponsive to most firstand second-line therapies <ref type="bibr" coords="1,187.32,680.96,98.38,9.46" target="#b2">(Enzinger et al., 2014)</ref>, and there is even no approved drugs for many rare diseases <ref type="bibr" coords="1,108.38,708.06,84.15,9.46" target="#b3">(Griggs et al., 2009)</ref>; 2) clinical trials need to recruit enough patients to continue and achieve statistically significant results.</p><p>To facilitate automatic patient-to-trial matching, TREC 2021 Clinical Trials (CT) Track<ref type="foot" coords="1,481.34,227.96,3.99,6.91" target="#foot_1">2</ref> releases 75 patient notes (known as topics) and evaluates the relevance of clinical trials returned by participating systems. TREC CT is a challenging task: In terms of topics, they are lengthy, usually containing 5-10 complete sentences. Some are noisy, e.g. with mentions of the husband's disease, or contain ambiguous abbreviations. In terms of the clinical trial documents, they are even longer with many sections such as titles, summaries, inclusion and exclusion criteria. Matching patients with the trials requires entailment-like reference <ref type="bibr" coords="1,468.42,379.05,57.35,9.46;1,306.14,392.60,23.95,9.46" target="#b7">(Zhang et al., 2020)</ref>, since ideally eligible patients should meet all inclusion criteria and no exclusion criteria.</p><p>Traditional first-stage retrievers for this task typically first extract keywords (e.g. using NER models) since the topics are long and noisy, then query the inverted index of clinical trials using BM25 with or without query expansion. However, such methods might not work, since: 1. Keyword extraction tools are imperfect, especially for abbreviations; 2. Diagnoses are not always directly available, so reasoning from symptoms is required; 3. Some records contain many noisy terms that will also be extracted, such as the diseases of relatives and certain past medical histories.</p><p>In this paper, we describe the submissions of Alibaba DAMO academy to the TREC CT 2021 track. We first apply TrialMatcher, a novel method that performs Embedding-Based Retrieval (EBR), to find eligible clinical trial candidates for given patients. We then use different re-rankers based on pre-trained language models to re-order the candidates. Our automatic submissions rank the second among all participating teams in 4/4 metrics. Our manual submissions rank the first in 1/4 metric, and the second in 3/4 metrics. The results show that EBR for clinical matching is a promising future direction to explore. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Methods</head><p>Following the standard practice, our systems contain a retriever and a re-ranker. The retriever is denoted as TrialMatcher, performing EBR. The re-ranker is based on the human-in-the-loop active learning method that won the TREC 2020 Precision Medicine Track <ref type="bibr" coords="2,142.58,363.82,69.23,9.46" target="#b4">(Jin et al., 2020)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">TrialMatcher</head><p>TrialMatcher performs EBR with pre-trained patient note and clinical trial encoders. The pretraining architecture is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,248.41,430.60,5.56,9.46" target="#fig_0">1</ref> and the inference architecture is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,251.76,444.15,4.09,9.46" target="#fig_1">2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.1">Pre-training</head><p>Let Enc patient and Enc trial denote the encoder for free-text patient notes and clinical trial descriptions (consisting of title, condition texts and brief summaries), respectively. They are essentially transformer encoders <ref type="bibr" coords="2,145.69,535.08,96.50,9.46" target="#b6">(Vaswani et al., 2017)</ref> initialized by ClinicalBERT <ref type="bibr" coords="2,147.19,548.63,95.98,9.46" target="#b0">(Alsentzer et al., 2019)</ref>, a clinical version of BERT <ref type="bibr" coords="2,147.04,562.18,85.92,9.46" target="#b1">(Devlin et al., 2019)</ref>. We have:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,95.76,582.72,167.98,36.07">Enc patient (patient note) ∈ R d Enc trial (clinical trial description) ∈ R d</formula><p>where d is the embedding dimension. We use all clinical trial entries (over 370k) from clinicaltrials.gov to pre-train the encoders. Specifically, for each clinical trial entry indexed by i, let's denote its description as D i , inclusion criteria as I i , exclusion criteria as E i . Let D r be the description of another randomly sampled clinical trial description.</p><p>In pre-training, we use inclusion and exclusion criteria as proxies for eligible and ineligible patient notes, respectively. Based on it, we design two contrastive learning tasks: patient-to-trial matching and trial-to patient matching. We optimize the Triplet loss, where the goal is to minimize the distance between the anchor instance embedding and the positive instance embedding and maximize the distance between the anchor instance embedding and the negative instance embedding:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,316.10,384.85,208.31,39.97">L triplet (anc, pos, neg) = max(0, dist(anc, pos) -dist(anc, neg) + m)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where anc, pos, neg denote anchor, positive instance and negative instance embeddings, respectively. dist denotes a specific distance metric, e.g. Euclidean distance. m is the margin hyperparameter in the triplet loss. The losses for the patient-to-trial matching and the trial-to-patient matching tasks are:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,315.42,549.51,208.99,41.31">L patient-to-trial = L triplet (Enc patient (I), Enc trial (D), Enc trial (D r ))<label>(2)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,311.47,622.75,212.94,41.31">L trial-to-patient = L triplet (Enc trial (D), Enc patient (I), Enc patient (E))<label>(3)</label></formula><p>The final pre-training loss is a weighted sum of them:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="2,316.10,721.39,208.31,27.36">L pre-training = αL patient-to-trial + (1 -α)L trial-to-patient (4)</formula><p>where α is the multi-task hyper-parameter to tune. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2">Inference</head><p>During inference, let's denote the given patient note as P .</p><p>TrialMatcher computes a relevance score s for each candidate clinical trial. For clinical trial j, s j = Aggregate(s P,D j , s P,I j , -s P,E j ) (5)</p><p>where Aggregate denotes an aggregation method (e.g. averaging), and: s P,D j = cos(Enc patient (P ), Enc trial (D j )) (6) s P,I j = cos(Enc patient (P ), Enc patient (I j )) (7)</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="3,82.47,536.07,206.66,13.76">s P,E j = cos(Enc patient (P ), Enc patient (E j )) (8)</formula><p>where cos denotes the cosine similarity.</p><p>The clinical trial candidates are ranked by s and the highest ranked ones will be retrieved for reranking.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Re-ranking</head><p>We have submitted five runs, namely damoebr, damoebrsigir, damoebrtog, damohitl and damohitls. They all use the same TrialMatcher retriever, and only differ in the re-ranking step. Damoebr does not re-rank the TrialMatcher results, so it provides a baseline performance of TrialMatcher. Damoebrsigir and damoebrtog use automatic re-rankers, which will be introduced in Section 2.2.1. Damohitl and damohitls use manual re-rankers, which will be described in Section 2.2.2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.1">Automatic re-rankers</head><p>For damoebrsigir, we fine-tune a clinicalBERT with a similar patient-to-trial matching dataset <ref type="bibr" coords="3,305.78,355.98,126.51,9.46" target="#b5">(Koopman and Zuccon, 2016</ref>) that contains 60 patients and 4000 relevance annotations (which we refer to as the SIGIR dataset in this paper), and use the fine-tuned clinicalBERT as the re-ranker. Instead of encoding the patient notes and clinical trials separately, the concatenation of patient notes and clinical trials is sent to clinicalBERT during fine-tuning and re-ranking.</p><p>For damoebrtog, we fine-tune another clinical-BERT to predict whether a set of criteria is the inclusion or exclusion criteria of a given clinical trial description. The motivation is similar to that of the TrialMatcher pre-training, where we consider a set of criteria as a patient summary, so the ability to predict whether the set is inclusion or exclusion criteria can help the prediction of whether a patient is eligible. We use the whole clinicaltrials.gov to construct the finetuning dataset. During fine-tuning, the concatenation of I or E and D are sent to clinicalBERT to predict inclusion as 1 or exclusion as 0. During inference, the concatenation of P and D is fed to the re-ranker to predict the eligibility.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2">Manual re-rankers</head><p>The damohitl and damohitls re-rankers are based on the human-in-the-loop active learning method that won the TREC 2020 Precision Medicine Track <ref type="bibr" coords="3,305.78,750.37,71.16,9.46" target="#b4">(Jin et al., 2020)</ref>. In this year, we have annotated about 1.7k instances in active learning. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Submissions</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head><p>The results of different submissions are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,97.22,449.56,4.09,9.46" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p><p>Automatic submissions: Damoebrtog ranks the second by 4/4 metrics among all participating teams. However, the best submissions (f_t_mt5 and f_t_mt5_2) largely outperform the damoebrtog, indicating that there is still much room for improvements. Within our submissions, damoebrtog is much better than damoebrsigir, which in turn is much better than damoebr. These results show that: 1. clinicalBERT that is fine-tuned on the SIGIR dataset improves the original EBR results; and 2. self-supervised fine-tuning with large-scale instances from clinicaltrials.gov is better than fine-tuning with the clean but small SIGIR dataset.</p><p>Manual submissions: The best manual submissions are better than the best automatic submissions by NDCG@10, R-Prec and MRR, but the best automatic run (f_t_mt5_2) surprisingly outperforms the best manual run (tdminerrun4) by P@10 (0.5933 v.s. 0.5760). Damohitl achieves the highest RPrec of 0.2782, outperforming the second team (0.2455) by a large margin. Damohitl and damohitl rank the second by the other 3/4 metrics, and the results are comparable to the best team (0.7038 v.s. 71.50 by NDCG@10, 0.5693 v.s. 0.5760 by P@10). As expected, our manual submissions damohitl and damohitls are much better than our automatic submissions, showing the importance of training rerankers with task-specific annotations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we describe the submissions of Alibaba DAMO Academy to the TREC Clinical Trials 2021 track. We propose a novel embedding-based retrieval model, TrialMatcher, and use it with several re-rankers fine-tuned by different datasets. The submissions rank the first by 1/8 metric, and the second by all other 7/8 metrics. Overall, our results show that: 1. embedding-based retrieval is useful but not sufficient; 2. re-rankers trained by in-domain annotations can largely improve the performance; 3. a large set of noisy instances might be better than a small set of clean instances for training the re-ranker. Potential future works include thoroughly characterizing the embedding-based retrieval model, and exploring other pre-training schemes for the patient-to-trial matching task.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,192.11,241.49,211.07,8.64"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The TrailMatcher pre-training architecture.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,197.09,273.26,201.10,8.64"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The TrialMatcher inference architecture.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,70.56,76.75,455.50,312.58"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Evaluation results of different submissions, ranked by NDCG@10. Bolded numbers denote best performance, and underlined numbers denote the second best (team-wise) results. All numbers are percentages.</figDesc><table coords="4,91.02,76.75,413.23,275.68"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">NDCG@10 Precision@10 Mean Reciprocal Rank R-Precision</cell></row><row><cell>Automatic runs</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>f_t_mt5_2</cell><cell>71.18</cell><cell>59.33</cell><cell>81.62</cell><cell>26.28</cell></row><row><cell>f_t_mt5</cell><cell>67.92</cell><cell>54.93</cell><cell>71.61</cell><cell>26.39</cell></row><row><cell>damoebrtog (ours)</cell><cell>59.53</cell><cell>40.93</cell><cell>60.83</cell><cell>21.91</cell></row><row><cell>CSIROmed_inc</cell><cell>53.20</cell><cell>31.73</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>CSIROmed_abs</cell><cell>52.85</cell><cell>32.40</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>RM3Filtered</cell><cell>51.49</cell><cell>33.60</cell><cell>49.36</cell><cell>20.78</cell></row><row><cell>ielabr2</cell><cell>49.92</cell><cell>32.40</cell><cell>51.19</cell><cell>19.91</cell></row><row><cell>damoebrsigir (ours)</cell><cell>48.21</cell><cell>40.40</cell><cell>58.41</cell><cell>16.81</cell></row><row><cell>IKR3_BSL</cell><cell>47.85</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>damoebr (ours)</cell><cell>34.09</cell><cell>25.87</cell><cell>42.93</cell><cell>18.65</cell></row><row><cell>Manual runs</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>tdminerrun3</cell><cell>71.50</cell><cell>57.60</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>NA</cell></row><row><cell>tdminerrun4</cell><cell>71.50</cell><cell>57.07</cell><cell>82.57</cell><cell>24.40</cell></row><row><cell>tdminerrun2</cell><cell>71.08</cell><cell>56.80</cell><cell>83.15</cell><cell>24.55</cell></row><row><cell>tdminerrun1</cell><cell>70.78</cell><cell>NA</cell><cell>82.53</cell><cell>24.52</cell></row><row><cell>damohitl (ours)</cell><cell>70.38</cell><cell>56.93</cell><cell>75.75</cell><cell>27.82</cell></row><row><cell>damohitls (ours)</cell><cell>70.28</cell><cell>56.93</cell><cell>75.30</cell><cell>27.73</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,87.01,756.07,161.40,6.31;1,70.87,766.03,161.90,6.31"><p>https://grants.nih.gov/policy/ clinical-trials/definition.htm</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="1,322.28,766.03,178.04,6.31"><p>http://www.trec-cds.org/2021.html</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.87,93.02,219.92,8.64;5,81.78,103.98,207.36,8.64;5,81.78,114.94,209.01,8.64;5,81.78,125.73,207.36,8.81;5,81.45,136.69,208.93,8.58;5,81.78,147.82,209.01,8.64;5,81.78,158.78,145.02,8.64" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,197.95,114.94,92.83,8.64;5,81.78,125.90,92.58,8.64">Publicly available clinical BERT embeddings</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Alsentzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Boag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wei-Hung</forename><surname>Weng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Di</forename><surname>Jindi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Tristan</forename><surname>Naumann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Mcdermott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/W19-1909</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,194.85,125.73,94.28,8.58;5,81.45,136.69,204.17,8.58">Proceedings of the 2nd Clinical Natural Language Processing Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the 2nd Clinical Natural Language Processing Workshop<address><addrLine>Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="78" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.87,178.70,218.27,8.64;5,81.78,189.66,207.36,8.64;5,81.78,200.62,209.02,8.64;5,81.78,211.41,207.35,8.81;5,81.78,222.37,207.36,8.58;5,81.45,233.33,209.34,8.58;5,81.78,244.29,207.35,8.81;5,81.43,255.41,207.87,8.64;5,81.78,266.37,108.49,8.64" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,196.66,189.66,92.47,8.64;5,81.78,200.62,209.02,8.64;5,81.78,211.58,32.52,8.64">BERT: Pre-training of deep bidirectional transformers for language understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Devlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ming-Wei</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Kenton</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Toutanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/N19-1423</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,132.84,211.41,156.29,8.58;5,81.78,222.37,207.36,8.58;5,81.45,233.33,209.34,8.58;5,81.78,244.29,32.72,8.58">Proceedings of the 2019 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<title level="s" coord="5,165.81,244.29,89.32,8.58">Long and Short Papers</title>
		<meeting>the 2019 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies<address><addrLine>Minneapolis, Minnesota</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4171" to="4186" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.87,286.30,218.27,8.64;5,81.78,297.26,207.36,8.64;5,81.78,308.22,207.36,8.64;5,81.78,319.01,207.36,8.81;5,81.78,329.97,209.11,8.81" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,186.00,297.26,103.13,8.64;5,81.78,308.22,207.36,8.64;5,81.78,319.18,168.52,8.64">Clinical trial participation as part of end-of-life cancer care: associations with medical care and quality of life near death</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Enzinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Baohui</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jane</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Weeks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Holly G Prigerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,257.96,319.01,31.18,8.58;5,81.78,329.97,131.64,8.58">Journal of pain and symptom management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1078" to="1090" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.87,350.06,218.27,8.64;5,81.78,361.02,208.60,8.64;5,81.47,371.98,209.41,8.64;5,81.78,382.94,209.01,8.64;5,81.78,393.73,207.36,8.81;5,81.78,404.69,120.10,8.81" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Robert C Griggs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mary</forename><surname>Batshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Rashmi</forename><surname>Dunkle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Gopal-Srivastava</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Kaye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Tan</forename><surname>Krischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Paulus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Merkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="5,108.49,382.94,182.29,8.64;5,81.78,393.73,207.36,8.81;5,81.78,404.69,61.46,8.58">Clinical research for rare disease: opportunities, challenges, and solutions. Molecular genetics and metabolism</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">96</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.87,424.78,219.92,8.64;5,81.78,435.74,209.10,8.64;5,81.78,446.70,207.36,8.64;5,81.78,457.66,207.52,8.64;5,81.78,468.61,209.01,8.64;5,81.78,479.40,207.36,8.81;5,81.22,490.36,207.92,8.58;5,81.78,501.32,209.10,8.58;5,81.53,512.28,209.26,8.81;5,81.78,523.41,209.06,8.64" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,107.59,446.70,181.54,8.64;5,81.78,457.66,207.52,8.64;5,81.78,468.61,209.01,8.64;5,81.78,479.57,50.04,8.64">Aliababa DAMO academy at TREC precision medicine 2020: State-of-the-art evidence retriever for precision medicine with expert-in-the-loop active learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Qiao</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Chuanqi</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mosha</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ming</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Songfang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ningyu</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Xiaozhong</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,153.87,479.40,135.26,8.58;5,81.22,490.36,207.92,8.58">Proceedings of the Twenty-Ninth Text REtrieval Conference, TREC 2020, Virtual Event</title>
		<meeting>the Twenty-Ninth Text REtrieval Conference, TREC 2020, Virtual Event<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, Maryland, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-11-16">2020. November 16-20, 2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1266</biblScope>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.87,543.33,219.92,8.64;5,81.78,554.29,207.36,8.64;5,81.47,565.08,207.67,8.58;5,81.78,576.04,209.01,8.58;5,81.78,587.00,134.06,8.81" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,248.45,543.33,42.33,8.64;5,81.78,554.29,188.30,8.64">A test collection for matching patients to clinical trials</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bevan</forename><surname>Koopman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Guido</forename><surname>Zuccon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,81.47,565.08,207.67,8.58;5,81.78,576.04,209.01,8.58;5,81.78,587.00,65.14,8.58">Proceedings of the 39th International ACM SIGIR conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 39th International ACM SIGIR conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="669" to="672" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.87,607.10,218.27,8.64;5,81.78,618.05,207.36,8.64;5,81.78,629.01,207.36,8.64;5,81.53,639.80,209.26,8.81;5,81.78,650.76,208.43,8.81" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,228.26,629.01,60.88,8.64;5,81.53,639.97,35.51,8.64">Attention is all you need</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ashish</forename><surname>Vaswani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Noam</forename><surname>Shazeer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Niki</forename><surname>Parmar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jakob</forename><surname>Uszkoreit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Llion</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Aidan</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Gomez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ł Ukasz</forename><surname>Kaiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Illia</forename><surname>Polosukhin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,137.59,639.80,153.20,8.58;5,81.78,650.76,61.60,8.58">Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Curran Associates, Inc</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.87,670.86,218.26,8.64;5,81.78,681.82,207.36,8.64;5,81.78,692.61,209.01,8.81;5,81.78,703.56,208.86,8.81;5,81.03,714.69,22.42,8.64" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,129.43,681.82,159.70,8.64;5,81.78,692.77,171.97,8.64">Deepenroll: patient-trial matching with deep embedding and entailment prediction</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Xingyao</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Cao</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lucas</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Glass</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jimeng</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,272.61,692.61,18.18,8.58;5,81.78,703.56,151.39,8.58">Proceedings of The Web Conference 2020</title>
		<meeting>The Web Conference 2020</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1029" to="1037" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
