<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.00,65.85,468.00,20.73">University of Hagen @ TREC2021 News Track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,165.78,105.48,89.42,10.37;1,255.20,102.80,1.54,7.86"><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Wagenpfeil</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Hagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,267.48,105.48,74.67,10.37;1,342.15,102.80,2.05,7.86"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Mc Kevitt</surname></persName>
							<email>p.mckevitt@aisr.org.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Academy for International Science &amp; Research (AISR)</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Derry/Londonderry</settlement>
									<country key="IE">Ireland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,353.92,105.48,87.20,10.37;1,441.12,102.80,1.54,7.86"><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Hemmje</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Hagen</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.00,65.85,468.00,20.73">University of Hagen @ TREC2021 News Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">6D679DBC6F256F971CCE96D06259BAA3</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:11+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>TFIDF</term>
					<term>Graph Codes</term>
					<term>similarity</term>
					<term>relevance calculation</term>
					<term>recommendation</term>
					<term>feature graph</term>
					<term>multimedia</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper discusses University of Hagen's approach for the TREC2021 News Track. The News Track aims at providing relevant background links to documents of the Washington Post article archive.</p><p>Our submitted run is based on research and development in the field of multimedia information retrieval and employs a modified TFIDF (Text Frequency vs. Inverse Document Frequency) algorithm for topic modeling and matrix based indexing operations founded on Graph Codes for the calculation of similarity, relevance, and recommendations. This run was submitted as FUH (Fernuniversität Hagen) and obtained a nDCG@5 of 0.2655.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. INTRODUCTION, MOTIVATION, AND DOCUMENT COLLECTION</head><p>The research area of "Multimedia and Internet Applications" at the University of Hagen has made inroads in the field of Multimedia Information Retrieval (MMIR) in recent decades. Some of these research results form an approach for participation at the News Track of the TREC2021 conference.</p><p>Typically, MMIR is aimed at the processing of multimedia content from various sources (e.g., images, audio, video, social media, and text). Relevant extracted information of these various multimedia objects are called, "feature" <ref type="bibr" coords="1,169.04,611.36,11.64,9.50" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. The approach presented here is based on such multimedia features and can be applied to any kind of multimedia object including text. In the case of the TREC2021 News Track, it has been applied to the Washington Post article archive <ref type="bibr" coords="1,347.02,651.36,11.64,9.50" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, which contains 728,626 news articles and blog posts from January 2012 through December 2020. The topic of the TREC2021 News Track is Background Linking, i.e., the identification of similar and/or relevant articles to a given reference article (called topic) and a set of corresponding questions (called subtopics). For this experiment, a set of 50 topics with additional 3-5 subtopics has been processed. An example of such a topic description is given in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,117.37,91.31,4.11,9.50" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. The articles of the Washington Post archive are stored in JSON format, and include fields for title, byline, date of publication, a section header, article text broken into paragraphs, and links to embedded images and multimedia, for the documents between the years 2012 and 2017. In this paper, we discuss our approach and its application to text-only multimedia objects and results from the TREC2021 News Track evaluation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>II. STATE OF THE ART AND RELATED WORK</head><p>In previous related work <ref type="bibr" coords="2,194.78,434.32,24.64,9.50">[3][4]</ref>[5], we introduced a Generic Multimedia Analysis Framework (GMAF), which provides various plugins for multimedia feature detection in an extensible way. For the TREC2021 News Track, text-processing plugins are required, that are able to process the format of the Washington Post archive into a MultiMedia Feature Graph (MMFG). Such a MMFG is basically a graph structure and can be applied to the representation of MMIR features. A detailed description of this structure is given in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,126.59,534.33,11.64,9.50" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Depending on the type of multimedia object, we discovered and showed <ref type="bibr" coords="2,490.31,534.33,12.13,9.50" target="#b4">[5]</ref> <ref type="bibr" coords="2,502.44,534.33,12.13,9.50" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, that graph algorithms have limited performance on large multimedia collections with a high level-of-detail <ref type="bibr" coords="2,72.00,574.34,11.64,9.50" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Hence, we introduced Graph Codes as a 2D projection of such graphs, which can utilize matrix calculations instead of graph traversal algorithms <ref type="bibr" coords="2,295.87,594.34,11.64,9.50" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. For these Graph Codes, we designed a special set of metrics to perform the parallelized calculation of similarity, recommendation, or inferencing operations.</p><p>In <ref type="bibr" coords="2,85.70,634.34,12.78,9.50" target="#b4">[5]</ref> we showed, that the performance of these operations is in any case superior to graph traversal based operations. Until now, the main focus of the GMAF was the the detection of MMIR features in images and video. However, for participation in the TREC2021 News Track, various text based plugins have been developed. Hence, we will also refer to text relevance algorithms, like TFIDF (Text Frequency vs. Inverse Document Frequency) <ref type="bibr" coords="3,226.02,71.31,11.64,9.50" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, named entity processing <ref type="bibr" coords="3,357.08,71.31,16.80,9.50" target="#b9">[10]</ref>, and general concepts, like the Bag-Of-Words text-processing <ref type="bibr" coords="3,191.21,91.31,18.26,9.50" target="#b10">[11]</ref> in the remainder of this paper. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,391.33,91.31,10.35,9.50" target="#fig_1">2a</ref> shows an overview of such a MMFG, in the form of a conceptual visualisation. In Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,353.92,111.31,9.13,9.50" target="#fig_1">2b</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>III. MODELING AND ALGORITHM OVERVIEW</head><p>Our goal for TREC2021 is to demonstrate, that the concept of Graph Codes not only improves the efficiency of MMIR, which has already been evaluated and outlined in <ref type="bibr" coords="3,405.44,519.55,11.64,9.50" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. Furthermore, we want to demonstrate, that Graph Codes deliver high effectiveness and accurate query results. Therefore, we chose to employ existing text processing algorithms and evaluate, whether Graph Codes based on these algorithms deliver high efficiency and effectiveness without any loss of precision. For the TREC2021 task, we chose the TFIDF algorithm as a purely statistical approach for the modeling of the text processing, and integrated it into the GMAF for MMIR. It may be noted, that the application of any other text processing algorithm would also be supported by the GMAF. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,333.81,639.56,5.48,9.50" target="#fig_2">3</ref> shows the overview of our approach, which can be detailed further as follows:</p><p>1) apply a TFIDF calculation to the documents and terms in the Washington Post archive. This task is performed to detect relevant and irrelevant words. Irrelevant words are then removed, relevant words are stored in a relevance database, from where they can be further used. This processing can be applied to the complete collection of documents in advance. Whenever new documents are added to the collection, a re-processing can be required. However, due to the number of documents, this re-processing does not have to be performed immediately when a single document is added, but can be calculated as a background task with reduced priority.</p><p>2) for each document in the collection, a Graph Code is calculated and stored in a MMIR database.</p><p>3) for each topic of the task description (i.e., the query documents), we apply:</p><p>• a Word Stemmer, that reduces the detected term of each word to its grammatical base form</p><p>• a query to a synonym dictionary, which returns all known synonyms for a given term • a check, if the word (or its synonyms) are relevant within the overall collection • a MMIR feature extraction, that is based on a Bag-Of-Words algorithm and calculates relevant words and word-stems of a given article's content For both the Word Stemmer and the synonym dictionary, the Oxford English Dictionary has been chosen, which is available for download and scientific use <ref type="bibr" coords="4,365.25,568.64,16.80,9.50" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. 4) the detected features of the topic are then transferred to the GMAF, where they are converted into Graph Codes. Here, the Graph Code metrics for similarity and recommendations are applied to order the collection as a ranked list (see also <ref type="bibr" coords="4,305.33,628.65,11.50,9.50" target="#b7">[8]</ref>).</p><p>For the modeling of the subtasks experiment, we append the text representing the subtask to the original query text, so that also the detected terms of each subtask's question will be indexed. This ensures, that both question and original article text are considered in the algorithm. Further details on the implementation are given in the next section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IV. IMPLEMENTATION AND EVALUATION</head><p>The algorithm has been implemented in Java, based on the GMAF, and follows the approach discussed in the previous section. The TFIDF calculation in our setup returned a global word count of 41,920 unique words in 728,627 files. 34,113 words have been marked as relevant, 18,618 as irrelevant. After feature detection, the resulting MMFGs and Graph Codes had an average of 224 relevant keywords per article, that are employed for similarity and recommendation calculations. The Graph Code encoding has been modified in a way, that the terms of a sentence are related via relationship attributes. If a term occurs in several sentences, the corresponding Graph Code fields are also filled accordingly, leading to an increase in the relevance of this term. The algorithms for similarity and the detection of recommendations remain unchanged (see <ref type="bibr" coords="5,144.79,254.78,11.50,9.50" target="#b7">[8]</ref>). An example for such a generated Graph Code is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,468.88,254.78,4.11,9.50" target="#fig_3">4</ref>. The evaluation of our algorithm is performed according to the TREC2021 News Track standards, by employing the corresponding tools, and is based on the TREC run results provided, which have been produced by the TREC2021 team in an anonymized evaluation. Table <ref type="table" coords="5,398.62,638.06,3.65,9.50" target="#tab_1">I</ref> summarizes these results and shows the overall average of all topics, including a selection of three individual topics 1 . The columns 1 In the result list for our experiment, there were zero results for 13 topics. These topics have been removed from the result list in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,119.06,707.98,2.99,7.77" target="#tab_1">I</ref>   "min", "mean", and "max" are taken from the official aggregated results of all participants. The results indicate, that our experiment produced values for precision and recall, that are below the aggregated average of all participants. An analysis of the individual topic runs shows, that there are several topics, which have been sufficiently processed (e.g., topic number 960 and 947), whilst others (e.g., number 937) produced low values for precision and recall. We discovered, that the reason for this is the threshold of the TFIDF algorithm, which marked several search terms of the topics as being irrelevant and hence failed to produce accurate results. For example, topic 937 is described with, "What is the Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS)". However, the TFIDF algorithm marked almost any word in this sentence as irrelevant, as the terms, "what", "is", "the", are irrelevant because they exist in almost any other document, and the words, "Respiratory", and "Syndrome" are marked irrelevant, because they appear in almost no other document. Therefore, the overall result of this topic is below the average.</p><p>In general, for these kind of very specific topic descriptions, the TFIDF algorithm is not the best choice and should be replaced or reconfigured with other parameters. However, the results show that the introduction of Graph Codes does not influence effectiveness of MMIR in a negative way, as the results of runs, without these mentioned TFIDF flaws, are above the average of the overall evaluation.</p><p>This demonstrates, that MMIR based Graph Codes are both efficient and effective.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>V. CONCLUSION AND SUMMARY</head><p>As discussed in the previous section, improvements to our approach must be made to achieve an improved effectiveness. In particular, the TFIDF algorithm and its current settings filters too much data.</p><p>Hence, further runs with different parameters for the TFIDF threshold have been performed, which increase the values for precision and recall up to 15%. These results will be reported in future work</p><p>and not here, as they have not been obtained during the TREC2021 News Track. Furthermore, our experiment shows, that a pure statistical algorithm can produce results comparable with the average of all other TREC2021 participants. With incorporation of the proposed improvements, the results are better than average. As our algorithm is purely based on MMIR features, images, audio, or video content could also be processed similarly. In particular, the fusion of these various multimedia feature sources will further increase the effectiveness of MMIR. This is subject of ongoing and future work.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,224.75,315.44,162.51,9.50;2,72.00,161.82,468.00,136.75"><head>Fig. 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1: Exemplary topic description.</figDesc><graphic coords="2,72.00,161.82,468.00,136.75" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,72.00,400.48,468.00,9.69;3,72.00,420.48,166.13,9.69;3,72.00,221.83,468.00,161.97"><head>Fig. 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2: Overview of Graph Codes as: (a) visualisation (b) simple example, (c) corresponding matrix representation, (c) final Graph Code.</figDesc><graphic coords="3,72.00,221.83,468.00,161.97" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="4,117.12,254.30,377.75,9.50;4,72.00,69.11,468.00,168.32"><head>Fig. 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3: Algorithm overview of the processing steps for the TREC2021 News Track.</figDesc><graphic coords="4,72.00,69.11,468.00,168.32" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="5,72.00,537.24,468.00,9.69;5,72.00,557.24,271.55,9.69;5,72.00,285.29,467.99,235.27"><head>Fig. 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4: Exemplary Graph Code calculated from a random selected element of the Washington Post archive: (a) source article, (b) excerpt of the calculated Graph Code.</figDesc><graphic coords="5,72.00,285.29,467.99,235.27" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,125.18,707.98,46.45,7.77"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(topic = all).</figDesc><table coords="6,147.45,70.50,317.10,201.80"><row><cell>method</cell><cell>topic</cell><cell>5%</cell><cell>10%</cell><cell>15%</cell><cell>20%</cell><cell>min</cell><cell>mean</cell><cell>max</cell></row><row><cell>Precision</cell><cell>all</cell><cell cols="4">0.4768 0.4291 0.3727 0.3285</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Recall</cell><cell>all</cell><cell cols="4">0.6229 0.1036 0.1301 0.1491</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>nDCG@5</cell><cell>all</cell><cell cols="4">0.2655 0.2731 0.2674 0.2664</cell><cell cols="3">0.0 0.3148 0.6342</cell></row><row><cell>Precision</cell><cell>960</cell><cell cols="4">0.8000 0.7000 0.5333 0.5000</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Recall</cell><cell>960</cell><cell cols="4">0.1143 0.2000 0.2286 0.2857</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>nDCG@5</cell><cell>960</cell><cell cols="4">0.3681 0.4558 0.4163 0.4290</cell><cell>0.0</cell><cell>0.278</cell><cell>0.552</cell></row><row><cell>Precision</cell><cell>947</cell><cell cols="4">0.8000 0.8000 0.6667 0.5000</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Recall</cell><cell>947</cell><cell cols="4">0.0870 0.1739 0.2174 0.2174</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>nDCG@5</cell><cell>947</cell><cell cols="4">0.4353 0.4703 0.5293 0.4995</cell><cell>0.0</cell><cell>0.371</cell><cell>0.890</cell></row><row><cell>Precision</cell><cell>937</cell><cell cols="4">0.2000 0.1000 0.1333 0.1000</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Recall</cell><cell>937</cell><cell cols="4">0.0213 0.0213 0.0426 0.0426</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>nDCG@5</cell><cell>937</cell><cell cols="4">0.0424 0.0323 0.0618 0.0539</cell><cell>0.0</cell><cell>0.152</cell><cell>0.761</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="6,166.76,282.34,278.48,9.50"><head>TABLE I :</head><label>I</label><figDesc>Algorithm evaluation selected experimental results.</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,92.42,329.86,447.58,7.93;7,92.42,345.71,146.21,7.77" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,135.03,329.86,234.63,7.72">Feature Extraction and Image Processing for Computer Vision</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Nixon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<publisher>Academic Press by Elsevier Ltd</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>London Wall London EC2Y 5AS UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,92.42,361.40,398.05,7.77" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Post</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.washingtonpost.com" />
		<title level="m" coord="7,189.87,361.40,92.83,7.77">Washington post archives</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-03">Mar. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,92.42,376.94,447.58,7.93;7,92.42,392.63,165.12,7.93" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,212.63,376.94,327.37,7.72;7,92.42,392.63,23.69,7.72">Towards ai-bases semantic multimedia indexing and retrieval for social media on smartphones</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wagenpfeil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hemmje</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,123.20,392.78,88.23,7.77">SMAP 2020 Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-09">Sep. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,92.42,408.32,447.58,7.93;7,92.42,424.01,447.58,7.93;7,92.42,439.86,240.43,7.77" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,302.55,408.32,237.45,7.72;7,92.42,424.01,274.17,7.93">Semantic query construction and result representation based on graph codes, BIRDS 2021: Bridging the Gap between Information Science</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wagenpfeil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Engel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mckevitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hemmje</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2863/#paper-06" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,373.31,424.16,143.29,7.77">Information Retrieval and Data Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-03">Mar. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,92.42,455.55,447.58,7.77;7,92.42,471.24,112.71,7.77" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,271.87,455.55,268.13,7.77;7,92.42,471.24,63.09,7.77">Graph codes -2d projections of multimedia feature graphs for fast and effective retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wagenpfeil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Mckevitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hemmje</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-03">Mar. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,92.42,486.93,447.58,7.77;7,92.42,502.47,447.58,7.93;7,92.42,518.31,195.69,7.77" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,306.78,486.93,233.22,7.77;7,92.42,502.62,83.29,7.77">Ai-based semantic multimedia indexing and retrieval for social media on smartphones</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wagenpfeil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Engel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kevitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hemmje</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3390/info12010043</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.mdpi.com/2078-2489/12/1/43" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,188.04,502.47,41.33,7.72">Information</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">2078-2489</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,92.42,533.85,447.58,7.93;7,92.64,549.69,95.98,7.77" xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,146.90,533.85,362.73,7.93">Graph Algorithms. 1005 Gravenstein Highway North Sebastopol CA 95472: O&apos;Reilly Media Inc</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Needham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">ISBN</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="978" to="979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,92.42,565.23,447.58,7.93;7,92.42,580.92,447.59,7.93;7,92.42,596.77,151.60,7.77" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,298.93,565.38,218.41,7.77">Fast and effective retrieval for large multimedia collections</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wagenpfeil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Vu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">Mc</forename><surname>Kevitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hemmje</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3390/bdcc5030033</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.mdpi.com/2504-2289/5/3/33" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,527.55,565.23,12.45,7.72;7,92.42,580.92,114.80,7.72">Big Data and Cognitive Computing</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">2504-2289</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,92.42,612.31,447.58,7.93;7,92.42,628.00,447.58,7.93;7,92.42,643.84,157.18,7.77" xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,274.92,612.46,176.92,7.77">Explainable and transferrable text categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Eljasik-Swoboda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Engel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hemmje</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>Data Management Technologies and Applications, S. Hammoudi, C. Quix, and J. Bernardino</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="22" />
			<pubPlace>Cham</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,92.42,659.53,447.58,7.77;7,92.42,675.07,447.58,7.93;7,92.42,690.76,447.58,7.93;7,92.42,706.60,73.97,7.77" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,330.41,659.53,209.59,7.77;7,92.42,675.22,203.56,7.77">Towards Enabling Emerging Named Entity Recognition as a Clinical Information and Argumentation Support</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Nawroth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Engel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Eljasik-Swoboda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hemmje</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5220/0006853200470055</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,319.61,675.07,220.39,7.72;7,92.42,690.76,136.05,7.72">Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Data Science, Technology and Applications</title>
		<meeting>the 7th International Conference on Data Science, Technology and Applications</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>SciTePress</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="55" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,92.42,72.45,447.58,7.93;8,92.42,88.15,447.58,7.93;8,92.42,103.99,447.58,7.77;8,92.42,119.68,263.91,7.77" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,142.12,72.61,332.91,7.77">Interpretation of coordinations, compound generation, and result fusion for query variants</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leveling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2484028.2484115</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2484028.2484115" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,495.58,72.45,44.42,7.72;8,92.42,88.15,444.04,7.93">Proceedings of the 36th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval, ser. SIGIR &apos;13</title>
		<meeting>the 36th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval, ser. SIGIR &apos;13<address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="805" to="808" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,92.42,135.37,447.58,7.77;8,92.42,151.06,85.35,7.77" xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,149.63,135.37,112.08,7.77">The oxford english dictionary</title>
		<idno>Download: 11.08.2021</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.oed.com" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-08">Aug. 2021</date>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
