<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,174.02,115.96,83.17,12.62;1,257.19,113.76,5.73,8.77;1,268.80,115.96,172.54,12.62;1,172.61,133.89,270.13,12.62">TREC 2021 ⋆ Clinical Trials Retrieval, Duisburg-Essen University submission</title>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">National Science Foundation</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">National Security Agency</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,237.75,171.56,58.84,8.74"><forename type="first">Sameh</forename><surname>Frihat</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Duisburg-Essen</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Duisburg</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,319.27,171.56,58.34,8.74"><forename type="first">Norbert</forename><surname>Fuhr</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Duisburg-Essen</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Duisburg</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,174.02,115.96,83.17,12.62;1,257.19,113.76,5.73,8.77;1,268.80,115.96,172.54,12.62;1,172.61,133.89,270.13,12.62">TREC 2021 ⋆ Clinical Trials Retrieval, Duisburg-Essen University submission</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">92F5ACA760BDF0AE9A0622D43EB3C76D</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:11+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Clinical Trials</term>
					<term>Patients Recruitment</term>
					<term>Information Retrieval</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Clinical trials are human research studies that aim to evaluate a medical, surgical, or behavioral intervention that is critical to the advancement of medical science. The majority of clinical trials fail because recruitment goals are not met. This issue necessitates the incorporation of automated systems capable of matching patients to ongoing clinical trials. This paper summarizes our participation in the TREC 2021 clinical trials track, which provided all participants with a 5-10 sentence patient description and a clinical trials database from Clinical-Trials.gov for matching. Our submission consists of a variety of retrieval techniques, including BM25, entity recognition, BERT, and others. The results show that a simple BM25 ranking algorithm could outperform neural network-based models, mainly due to the absence of quality training data.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>TREC Biomedical Tracks in 2021 presents the clinical trials challenge for the first time 1 . This track aims to match clinical trial documents with patient case descriptions. On one hand, clinical trial documents contain different fields of information, mainly description, eligibility criteria, and others. Eligibility criteria, which are the most important factors in deciding whether or not to enrol a patient in a clinical trial, have four key components. It begins with demographic information, namely age and gender, and ends with inclusion and exclusion criteria in the form of free text. Inclusion-exclusion criteria contain various types of information such as lab values, genes, diseases, and others. On the other hand, the patient description simulates the first admission statement in an electronic health record (EHR) as 5-10 sentences, which contains the age, gender, and other information.</p><p>Most clinical trials, which are important for medical knowledge development, fail to recruit the minimum number of patients required to power the study, causing the trial to be delayed or terminated. The idea of using EHRs to match patients with trials is introduced, burying the issue of recruiting. We aimed to investigate the performance of five simple information retrieval models for matching patients with trials in our submissions. Filtering and probabilistic techniques, as well as entity extraction, membership functions, and unsupervised BERT models, are used to build the models.</p><p>In Section 3, we present the IR architectures with a deeper look into the results. Results show that a simple probabilistic model based on a combination of BM25 and entity extraction can outperform more complex models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Data</head><p>The 2021 clinical trials track provided 75 topics and 375,580 clinical trial documents for evaluating the models. Each topic contains 5-10 sentences describing a synthetically created patient, inspired by actual patients and modified. This is because extracting real patient data from EHRs was deemed too risky due to ethical and legal constraints.</p><p>The clinical trial document comes in XML format provided by the U.S. National Library of Medicine ClinicalTrials.gov. Each document contains the trial description and the eligibility criteria. The eligibility criteria, which are provided in the form of free text containing the inclusion and exclusion criteria, along with eligible genders and ages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Methods</head><p>The clinical trials track is now operational for the first time. As a result, we chose to modify the baseline model (BM25) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,337.75,443.86,10.52,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref> rather than apply new techniques that necessitate training data in advance, which is currently unavailable. We attempted five different automatic runs, each combining filtering techniques (based on demographic data provided) with probabilistic retrieval techniques such as BM25 and BERT Embeddings <ref type="bibr" coords="2,305.82,491.68,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Preprocessing</head><p>We automatically extracted the gender and age for each topic prior to running the retrieval model. Based on this demographic information, we filtered out clinical trials that do not accept the mentioned patient at the topic. Then, the resulting trial subcollection is fed into the retrieval models for ranking clinical trials based on their relevance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Runs 2</head><p>We performed five runs (retrieval models), described as follows:</p><p>• First run This run is titled with BM25 on eligibility criteria, which could be described as the following: * Retrieve the top 1000 trials using BM25 on the topic and eligibility inclusion criteria from the filtered subcollection for calculating the positive scores. * Assign the BM25 score for each of the 1000 trials on the topic and eligibility exclusion criteria as a negative score. * Re-rank the documents using subtracting the "negative score" from the "positive score", which gives inclusion and exclusion criteria the same weight.</p><p>• Second run This run is titled with BM25 and membership function, which could be described as the following: * Retrieve the top 1000 trials using BM25 on the topic and trial's description from the filtered subcollection. * Assign to each trial the BM25 score on the eligibility inclusion criteria as a positive score. * Assign to each trial the BM25 score on the eligibility exclusion criteria as a negative score. * Re-rank the documents using subtracting the "negative score" from the "positive score", which gives inclusion and exclusion criteria the same weight.</p><p>• Third run This run is titled with BM25 with Named-entity recognition on topics (NER) <ref type="bibr" coords="3,213.74,410.86,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, which could be described as the following: * Assign to each trial the BM25 score on the extracted entities from the eligibility inclusion criteria text as a positive score. * Assign to each trial the BM25 score on the extracted entities from the eligibility exclusion criteria text as a negative scoret. * Re-rank the documents using this formula: 0.5 * BM 25 score + 0.2 * positive score -0.3 * negative score.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>Our main results can be summarized in table 1 in terms of NDCG@5 and NDCG@10. Third run outperforms the other runs as well as the average of the TREC medians for automatic runs, according to the results. Furthermore, Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,151.19,289.56,4.98,8.74">1</ref> compares our best submission to the median and best NDCG scores for 101 automatic TREC runs for each topic, providing a more in-depth look at our best submission. This shows that it performed quite well in most topics, but it failed in a few topics like 34, 69, and 71. However, when compared to the average of the TREC medians for manual runs, all runs performed poorly. Moreover, when our best run is compared with the best and median of 12 manual runs per topic (Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,170.62,361.29,3.87,8.74">2</ref>), in some topics like 17, 48, 56, and 67, it outperformed the median and is very comparable to the best-achieved score. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Discussion</head><p>The best two of our five submissions use the NER technique, which was successful in retrieving most of the topics with relatively good scores. This could imply that there is a link between the use of NER and the results, which worth further investigation. Moreover, it would be very interesting to see how much weight tuning could improve the result, i.e., cross-validation with the data that will be available soon.</p><p>Fig. <ref type="figure" coords="5,154.40,125.87,4.13,7.89">1</ref>. NDCG@10 of the best submitted run compared to the official median NDCG@10 of 101 automatic runs and best achieved score per topic. The result also shows that the idea of using negative weights for the trial exclusion criteria as in First run and Second run is limited and should be implemented differently. Our best IR system failed in topics 10, 34, 36, 69, and 71 with very low recalls. However, the median of all TREC runs (manual and automatic) also failed on some of these topics. Therefore, we would like to investigate the causes by observing these topics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusion</head><p>This paper describes the procedures and outcomes of our participation in the TREC 2021 Clinical Trials track. The results show that one of our IR models works well. This run outperformed the official TREC medians (automatic runs) and contributed the best results in a variety of topics. The results, however, show that our negative score for exclusion criteria methods are not as effective as we had hoped. Some topics should be thoroughly researched in future studies before implementing other IR methods. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Acknowledgemetns</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="6,134.77,186.74,345.83,8.74;6,134.77,198.69,345.83,8.74;6,134.77,210.65,239.70,8.74"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>This work was funded by a PhD grant from the DFG Research Training Group 2535 Knowledge-and data-based personalization of medicine at the point of care (WisPerMed), University of Duisburg-Essen, Germany.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,149.56,405.94,316.25,112.15"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Our runs' results in comparison to the TREC average of the median</figDesc><table coords="4,216.61,426.74,182.13,91.35"><row><cell>Submission</cell><cell cols="2">NDCG@5 NDCG@10</cell></row><row><cell>First run</cell><cell>0.1959</cell><cell>0.1704</cell></row><row><cell>Second run</cell><cell>0.2103</cell><cell>0.1951</cell></row><row><cell>Third run</cell><cell>0.4529</cell><cell>0.4214</cell></row><row><cell>Fourth run</cell><cell>0.1991</cell><cell>0.2023</cell></row><row><cell>Fifth run</cell><cell>0.3262</cell><cell>0.2973</cell></row><row><cell>AVG Median (manual)</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0.6212</cell></row><row><cell>AVG Median (auto)</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0.3040</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,134.77,164.38,345.82,285.48"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fig.2. NDCG@10 of the best submitted run compared to the official median NDCG@10 of 12 manual runs and best achieved score per</figDesc><table coords="5,174.48,164.38,304.42,285.48"><row><cell>1.0</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.8</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.6</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.4</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.0</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>13</cell><cell>14</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>16</cell><cell>17</cell><cell>18</cell><cell>19</cell><cell>20</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>22</cell><cell>23</cell><cell>24</cell><cell>25</cell><cell>26</cell><cell>27</cell><cell>28</cell><cell>29</cell><cell>30</cell><cell>31</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>33</cell><cell>34</cell><cell>35</cell><cell>36</cell><cell>37</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>39</cell><cell>40</cell><cell>41</cell><cell>42</cell><cell>43</cell><cell>44</cell><cell>45</cell><cell>46</cell><cell>47</cell><cell>48</cell><cell>49</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>51</cell><cell>52</cell><cell>53</cell><cell>54</cell><cell>55</cell><cell>56</cell><cell>57</cell><cell>58</cell><cell>59</cell><cell>60</cell><cell>61</cell><cell>62</cell><cell>63</cell><cell>64</cell><cell>65</cell><cell>66</cell><cell>67</cell><cell>68</cell><cell>69</cell><cell>70</cell><cell>71</cell><cell>72</cell><cell>73</cell><cell>74</cell><cell>75</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Topic</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>1.0</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.8</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.6</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.4</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.0</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>13</cell><cell>14</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>16</cell><cell>17</cell><cell>18</cell><cell>19</cell><cell>20</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>22</cell><cell>23</cell><cell>24</cell><cell>25</cell><cell>26</cell><cell>27</cell><cell>28</cell><cell>29</cell><cell>30</cell><cell>31</cell><cell>32</cell><cell>33</cell><cell>34</cell><cell>35</cell><cell>36</cell><cell>37</cell><cell>38</cell><cell>39</cell><cell>40</cell><cell>41</cell><cell>42</cell><cell>43</cell><cell>44</cell><cell>45</cell><cell>46</cell><cell>47</cell><cell>48</cell><cell>49</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>51</cell><cell>52</cell><cell>53</cell><cell>54</cell><cell>55</cell><cell>56</cell><cell>57</cell><cell>58</cell><cell>59</cell><cell>60</cell><cell>61</cell><cell>62</cell><cell>63</cell><cell>64</cell><cell>65</cell><cell>66</cell><cell>67</cell><cell>68</cell><cell>69</cell><cell>70</cell><cell>71</cell><cell>72</cell><cell>73</cell><cell>74</cell><cell>75</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Topic</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,144.73,656.80,301.84,7.86"><p>We used the same run names as provided in the TREC submission results.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="funding">
<div><p>⋆ This project was supported in part by the <rs type="funder">National Science Foundation</rs> and in part by the <rs type="funder">National Security Agency</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,266.12,342.24,7.86;6,146.91,277.08,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,288.04,97.80,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Alsentzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Boag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Weng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Naumann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mcdermott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1904.03323</idno>
		<title level="m" coord="6,223.08,277.08,184.59,7.86">Publicly available clinical bert embeddings</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,299.00,342.25,7.86;6,146.91,309.96,180.81,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Beltagy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cohan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1903.10676</idno>
		<title level="m" coord="6,274.90,299.00,205.70,7.86;6,146.91,309.96,14.95,7.86">Scibert: A pretrained language model for scientific text</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,320.92,342.24,7.86;6,146.91,331.88,333.68,7.86;6,146.91,342.84,25.60,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,353.32,320.92,127.27,7.86;6,146.91,331.88,197.58,7.86">Bert: Pre-training of deep bidirectional transformers for language understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Devlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Toutanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1810.04805</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,353.80,342.25,7.86;6,146.91,364.75,160.86,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,193.83,353.80,103.32,7.86">Named entity recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Mohit</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,320.49,353.80,160.11,7.86;6,146.91,364.75,37.37,7.86">Natural language processing of semitic languages</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="221" to="245" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,138.35,375.71,342.25,7.86;6,146.91,386.67,132.08,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,264.03,375.71,216.57,7.86;6,146.91,386.67,17.61,7.86">The probabilistic relevance framework: BM25 and beyond</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zaragoza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<publisher>Now Publishers Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
