<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,66.96,113.52,441.85,16.59;1,234.96,133.44,105.61,16.59">Solving the Enterprise TREC Task with Probabilistic Data Models</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,93.48,179.02,96.08,11.06"><forename type="first">Jan</forename><forename type="middle">Frederik</forename><surname>Forst</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science Queen Mary</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of London</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>E1 4NS</postCode>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,234.00,179.02,107.38,11.06"><forename type="first">Anastasios</forename><surname>Tombros</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science Queen Mary</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of London</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>E1 4NS</postCode>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,390.96,179.02,86.09,11.06"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Rölleke</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science Queen Mary</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of London</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>E1 4NS</postCode>
									<settlement>London</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,66.96,113.52,441.85,16.59;1,234.96,133.44,105.61,16.59">Solving the Enterprise TREC Task with Probabilistic Data Models</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">587ADEEDBA4EB47FE4029ECD6B68B23C</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Expert identification has become an important information retrieval task. We present and investigate a number of approaches for identifying an expert. Different approaches are based on exploiting the structure of documents in the knowledge base. Furthermore, our system highlights the integration of database technology with information retrieval (DB+IR).</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">INTRODUCTION</head><p>It is vitally important for businesses and organisations to acquire methods and technologies to organise data and retrieve information from data collections, especially with regard to the increasing amounts of data stored in corporate networks. Typically, corporate information is stored in large relational databases, where retrieval is carried out using SQL or other, related, languages.</p><p>One approach at organising data that has gained prominence more recently is that of expert finding. Large organisations spend considerable efforts improving their collaborative infrastructures: intranets and shared document authoring are examples for providing IT support for collaborative work. In such organisations, or in loosely coupled collaborative networks, the requirement for effective identification of experts frequently occurs.</p><p>In this paper, we place special emphasis on the integration of classical DB technologies with the more IR oriented aspects of expert identification. To this end, we used our retrieval framework, HySpirit <ref type="bibr" coords="1,470.00,301.96,9.11,8.97" target="#b9">[9]</ref>, which integrates DB concepts, such as relational data representation and querying languages with probabilistic aspects commonly found in IR. HySpirit is based on results reported in <ref type="bibr" coords="1,341.76,343.72,9.63,8.97" target="#b4">[4]</ref> and <ref type="bibr" coords="1,374.27,343.72,9.11,8.97" target="#b8">[8]</ref>, and has been improved steadily over recent years. This report will highlight the integration of probabilistic information retrieval models with SQL and Datalog expressions commonly found in the DBMS realm. The integration of such database technologies allows retrieval strategies to be implemented using very few lines of code, and enables retrieval systems to benefit from the efficiency of database management systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">BACKGROUND</head><p>A good overview of the particularities and problems encountered in conducting information retrieval in an enterprise environment is given by Hawking <ref type="bibr" coords="1,474.43,486.28,9.11,8.97" target="#b5">[5]</ref>. Among the challenges mentioned are the need to handle heterogeneous data sources such as databases, web-servers, email repositories and content management systems, to allow for fine-grained access-control rights for different users, to support multiple document formats and to integrate all the results in a seamless fashion.</p><p>In earlier work, Hawking et al. introduced their expert finding system, P@NOPTIC Expert <ref type="bibr" coords="1,452.48,580.48,9.11,8.97" target="#b2">[2]</ref>. This system builds fairly simple expert profiles by concatenating all documents published by a person into one long document. Then, in order to retrieve a ranked list of experts for a query, classical document retrieval on all those documents is performed for that query.</p><p>Expert finding approaches based on clustering were developed by Foner, and Reichling et al.. In Foner's Yenta system <ref type="bibr" coords="2,83.99,98.08,9.11,8.97" target="#b3">[3]</ref>, users, and their interests, are represented by agents. Agents representing users with similar interest form clusters in the system, which can be used to identify user groups with common interests, or to find an expert for a given problem.</p><p>Similarly, Reichling et al. use expert profiles to match users in their system <ref type="bibr" coords="2,138.33,171.28,9.63,8.97">[6]</ref> . Their architecture is based on a learning platform; user profiles were built from information directly entered by the users (such as education, current occupation, past experience), and information derived from the browsing activities of users, i.e. documents viewed by users on the learning platform.</p><p>Yimam-Seid and Kobsa present an architecture, DEMOIR <ref type="bibr" coords="2,95.99,255.03,13.37,8.97" target="#b11">[11]</ref>, which covers several aspects of the process of generating and querying expert profiles. Their system covers the three initial stages of building and representing expert-profiles, namely evidence source recognition -using either explicit sources, such as the experts themselves, or implicit sources (e.g. documents authored by expert-candidates), expertise indicator extraction -techniques to extract the salient information from the evidence sources, and expertise models -representations of extracted salient features.</p><p>Apart from research and experimentation in academia, some commercial systems have also developed expert profiles from implicit data sources. Autonomy<ref type="foot" coords="2,241.20,389.90,3.65,4.10" target="#foot_0">1</ref> has included in its IDOL Server the ability to derive user profiles based on the documents that users access and submit on the company intranet. Both KnowledgeMail by Tacit<ref type="foot" coords="2,88.32,431.78,3.65,4.10" target="#foot_1">2</ref> and Discovery Server by Lotus<ref type="foot" coords="2,226.32,431.78,3.65,4.10" target="#foot_2">3</ref> build user profiles by scanning employees' emails.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">KNOWLEDGE REPRESENTATION</head><p>In this section, we present an overview of how the indexed document collection and queries are stored in our system, how term-and document-frequencies (collection frequency) are calculated, and how associations between documents and expert-candidates are modelled.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Representation of documents and queries</head><p>Documents in our system are represented by relations, detailing the content and structure of the documents. Modelling follows the object-relational representation outlined in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,150.34,598.59,9.11,8.97" target="#b7">[7]</ref>. These relations are generated in an indexing stage, which also performs additional pre-processing steps such as stop-word removal and stemming. While the original TREC Enterprise track (ETREC) collection consists of HTML documents, we did not make use of the special markup as such, however, the documents' &lt;body&gt;-tags (or &lt;pre id="body"&gt;) were used to distinguish the actual document-content from the additional surrounding information; only terms occurring inside those tags were indexed, and the tags themselves were removed. The first column of the table gives the probability that a tuple is contained in the relation, a feature which we use to represent information which can be used similar to term-frequency (tf ) in classical information retrieval. This is explained in more detail below. Note that tuple-probabilites are not an argument of the relation, but are used internally to derive probabilities under relational operations.</p><p>Queries are represented in a similar way, with the context being defined simply as "this". In addition, query-terms are weighted with the collection-frequency (idf-frequency), rather than the term-frequency (tffrequency).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Term-and Document-frequencies</head><p>Similar to the way classical IR systems define tf-and idf -frequencies, we derive from our relations probabilities of term occurences. We thus derive both the probability of a term occurring in a document (p(t|d)), and the probability of a term occurring in a collection of documents (p(t|c)). While the former directly corresponds to the tf, the latter allows a derivation of idf, via an inverse log, i.e.:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,128.28,262.72,147.59,8.97">idf := -log(p(t|c))<label>(1)</label></formula><p>To formulate the construction of said probabilities, our system allows for extensions of classical SQL, Datalog and relational algebra with probabilities for facts and rules, and additional operators for deriving probabilities from given relations. To derive the above term-frequency, a "Bayes" operator is applied to the term-relation, using the context-attribute as evidence:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,59.16,388.00,94.16,40.41">CREATE VIEW tf AS SELECT term, context FROM term EVIDENCE KEY 2;</formula><p>This could equivalently be formulated in probabilistic relational algebra (PRA) <ref type="bibr" coords="3,157.31,454.96,9.63,8.97" target="#b4">[4]</ref> as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="3,59.16,486.16,85.70,8.97">tf = Bayes[$2](term);</formula><p>where Bayes is a new operator introduced to the algebra. Yet another way of modelling this probability is by defining the tf -relation as a probabilistic relation, conditional on a context, in probabilistic Datalog <ref type="bibr" coords="3,266.14,549.04,9.63,8.97" target="#b8">[8]</ref> as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="3,59.16,590.80,124.96,8.97">tf(T,D) :-term(T,D) | (D).</formula><p>Similarly, the document-probabilities can be defined, resulting in collection frequencies equivalent to idf in "classical" IR. To derive these probabilities in SQL, a view idf could be defined as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="3,305.16,95.44,110.44,40.41">CREATE VIEW idf AS SELECT term FROM tf ASSUMPTION MAX IDF;</formula><p>where MAX IDF is a probabilistic assumption that triggers the computation of term probabilities as defined for idf, as the log of the total number of documents divided by the number of documents containing a specific term.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Retrieval</head><p>Retrieval of indivdiual documents in this framework is carried out by joining the idf-weighted query terms with tf-weighted terms occurring in the document collection. This is expressed in SQL simply as</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="3,305.16,285.63,127.80,29.97">SELECT DISTINCT context FROM tf, wqterm WHERE qterm.term = tf.term;</formula><p>where wqterm is the weighted variant of the (unweighted) query terms. This returns a list of (distinct) documents in which at least one of the query terms occurs. Due to the weighting of query-and documentterms, all documents returned have associated with them a weight that can be interpreted as a document's retrieval status value.</p><p>The same query could similarly be expressed in probabilistic Datalog as retrieve(D) :-wqterm(T) &amp; tf(T,D); ?-retrieve(D); or in PRA as</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="3,305.16,512.31,132.27,19.41">?-PROJECT DISTINCT[$3] (JOIN[$1=$1](wqterm, tf));</formula><p>The above examples only return document relevant to a given query, but for the ETREC, the goal was to find experts relevant to a given topic. It is therefore necessary to join the list of returned documents with a list of authors of documents, resulting in a list of authors (or experts) relevant to a given query. The implementation of this link is straightforward and follows the examples given above, however, we believe that the association between documents and authors should not be limited to a simple "one author per document" link, but should also be probabilistic, allowing for varying degrees of authorship.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Document-Expert association</head><p>When treating documents as sources of evidence for the expertise of expert-candidates, it is necessary to define an association between these sources of evidence and the candidates. The direct way of associating a document with an expert would be to model these links on the "sender"-information contained in the meta-tags of emails in the list collection. This approach, however, has some severe shortcomings. The ETREC collection does not only consist of emails, but also of other document-types, such as personal web-pages and CVSrepositories, for which information about the author might not be available. Furthermore, a simple link between documents and expert-candidates based on the sender information would not be able to capture expertdocument links for documents authored by multiple persons, or capture links for documents which are about an expert-candidate, who is not the author of that document.</p><p>When QMIR participated in last year's ETREC, results for the expert finding task were rather low, compared to the results achieved by some of the other participants.</p><p>It was assumed that this low performance was caused by an imprecision in the connection of documents and authors (expert candidates), as the "sender"-information alone was not sufficient to capture concepts such as multiple authorship and documents about a person.</p><p>To overcome these limitations, we chose to model the association between documents and expert-candidates as the probability of a document implying a candidate.</p><p>A candidate can thus be seen as a query, reducing the implication to p(d → q) <ref type="bibr" coords="4,153.96,443.79,13.37,8.97" target="#b10">[10]</ref>. The queries were formed from the information on expert-candidates available as part of the ETREC-collection, with queries consisting of the names of experts and their e-mail addresses as query-terms.</p><p>To further gauge the impact different term-weighting strategies might have on modelling the association between expert-candidates and supportive documents, we modelled the association both with tf-idf and Language Modelling weighting.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">EXPERIMENTS</head><p>Here, we describe our strategies for retrieving experts for given topics (queries) from the knowledge base. Queries are represented as described above. For our experiments, we concentrated on variations in the knowledge base used for expert finding, and the impact different knowledge bases might have on retrieval quality.</p><p>All the below strategies make use of some common rela-tions for data representation, so they will be presented here, rather than in the individual subsections. As noted above, we used a probabilistic connection between documents and authors. This is represented in the system by an "author"-relation, that has two attributes, "candidate id" to represent authors, and "context" to represent documents. Each tuple occurring in the relation is preceded by a weight, giving the strength of the association. On a physical level, there exist two different versions of this relation, one for the "lists" collection, and one for the "www" collection, however, conceptually, they are identical and will be treated as such for the present discussion.</p><p>Query terms are contained in a "qterm"-relation; joining this relation with the collection's idf values results in a relation called "wqterm", in which the query terms are weighted by the collection frequencies.</p><p>All other relations necessary for implementing the strategies will be explained in the respective sections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">WWW subcollection</head><p>In a first series of experiments, we limited the knowledge base to those documents which form the "www"-subcollection. This collection consists of personal webpages of W3C researchers, webpages of working groups etc. As mentioned in a previous section, there is no "given" author for any of the documents contained in this part of the collection, we therefore modelled authorship of documents in the collection based on the occurrence of expert-candidates' names or e-mail addresses. Retrieval of expert-candidates on the "www"-collection can be expressed in SQL as: Evaluating the performance of the individual strategies using trec eval, the overall MAP-score achieved by the Body-only approach is 0.0965.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Lists subcollection</head><p>For the remaining experiments, only the "lists"subcollection was used. As the "lists"-subcollection consists of emails sent to a mailing-list, we concentrated on variations in document structure specific in emails; specifically, we used quotations in emails as an additional source of evidence. The rationale behind different treatment of different email parts is that emails will usually only quote significant parts of previous messages. It could thus be argued that quotations in emails are a distilled version of previous emails, containing the salient parts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1">Body-only</head><p>In the "body-only" approach, only the non-quoted parts of emails were used, while terms occurring in quotations inside emails were not considered for the expert finding process. The rationale behind this strategy is that quotations contain information not originally conceived by the author of the present email. Instead, the author quotes material from another email, which should be indicative of expertise of that other email's author. To exclude quotations from emails thus leads to a more "direct" association between terms and authors. So, assuming that the "body"-only portion of emails is contained in a relation called "tf body", which has two attributes -term and context -, the retrieval strategy is expressed in SQL as: Evaluating the performance of the individual strategies using trec eval, the overall MAP-score achieved by the Body-only approach is 0.1376.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">Quotes-only</head><p>The "quotes-only" approach is the exact opposite of the "body-only" approach, and only considers terms which occur inside quoted parts of emails. This follows the idea that quotations contain the most salient information in a thread of emails, and are therefore most indicative of expertise of authors participating in the discussion. The above argument that quotations contain information not originally conceived by the author of the present email still holds in this context, however, it could reasonably be argued that an author in a thread of emails related to a certain topic is still an expert on that topic, even if the most salient terms only occur in quotations. To make this more concrete, it can be reasonably argued that quotations in emails usually occur in replies to previous questions, or in general discussions regarding a specific topic. In either of these cases, an author of such an email (i.e. one containing quotations) might be an expert on the topics at hand. The "quotes-only" strategy can be implemented just like the "body-only" strategy, the only difference being that instead of a "tf body"-relation, a "tf quotes"-relation is used to represent terms occurring in quotations.</p><p>Again using trec eval for measuring the performance of the "quotes-only" approach, the overall MAP score achieved was 0.1242.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.3">Body and Quotes</head><p>The "body+quotes" approach does not distinguish between terms forming quotations, and terms forming email bodies; it is thus most similar to standard document retrieval. This can be seen as a zero hypothesis to the above claim that utilising the structure of documents is beneficial to the task of expert finding. Again, implementing this strategy is a straightforward extension of the previous examples; instead of a "tf quotes" or "tf body" relation, a "tf bodyquotes"relation is used, which represents terms present in either email bodies or quotations.</p><p>To investigate the influence term-weighting might have on the quality of retrieval, we modelled the retrieval task for the Body and Quotes subcollection using both tf-idf and Language Modelling. Furthermore, we compared the quality of retrieval using a stemmed and an unstemmed version of the subcollection, to prevent query-mismatch problems due to overstemming. In conjunction with the two strategies for building documentexpert associations (using tf-idf and Language Modelling), we thus had a total of eight runs: stemmed tf-idf using tf-idf association, stemmed tf-idf using LM association, unstemmed tf-idf using tf-idf association, unstemmed tf-idf using LM association, stemmed LM using tf-idf association, stemmed LM using LM association, unstemmed LM using tf-idf association and unstemmed LM using LM association.</p><p>The overall MAP score for the Body and Quotes approach is 0.1108. Looking at the performance of individual queries, we find that some of the queries fail to return any relevant experts for a query, while other queries find relevant experts with a mean average precision as high as 0.5. The results for the experiments using a stemmed representation of the collection can be seen in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="6,113.63,328.24,3.56,8.97" target="#fig_3">1</ref>.  The MAP scores show that the best retrieval quality is achievable using a combination of tf collection term weighting and tf -weighted candidate association.</p><p>The results for experiments with an unstemmed representation of the collection, as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="6,247.77,601.36,4.61,8.97" target="#fig_5">2</ref> show similar results. Here, applying tf -weighting for both document retrieval and candidate association works best, however, for some of the queries, a combination of LM -weighting on term and tf on candidate associations performs similarly well as a tfidf-tfidf combination, or even outperforms it.  MAP values for unstemmed bodyquotes Our approach delivers the relevant candidates for about 20% of the queries, with MAP scores as high as 0.48. The results also display low MAP scores for some of the queries, significantly lowering the overall MAP scores for the different approaches. Furthermore, the results confirm the findings of the 14th TREC E-TREC overview ( <ref type="bibr" coords="6,340.42,377.44,10.07,8.97" target="#b1">[1]</ref>) that high precision retrieval of experts requires the combination of multiple sources of evidence. The previously mentioned advantage of the tfidf -tfidf approach is also visible in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,435.20,496.72,3.56,8.97" target="#tab_1">1</ref>. The highest MAP achieved by any query with this approach is 0.4822. The number of queries which perform better than the average MAP of 0.1108 is 17, again indicating that the overall performance is affected by a large number of queries that do not perform well. Also note that for the other approaches, the number of queries which perform better than the average is similar, however, due to the low average this is probably not significant.</p><p>The results for the experiments with a stemmed version of the bodyquotes collection were largely mirrored by the experiments with the unstemmed counterpart (Table <ref type="table" coords="6,328.91,632.80,3.57,8.97">2</ref>). Here, too, the tfidf -tfidf approach performs best, with a highest MAP of 0.4594. However, the LMtextittfidf approach works better on the unstemmed representation than on the stemmed one. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Results</head><p>The MAP-scores for the individual strategies indicate that the "body-only" approach performs best in identifying the correct experts for a given query with a MAP of 0.1376. This is followed by the "quotes-only" approach with a MAP score of 0.1242. The "body-quotes" approach, which does not distinguish between different elements of emails only achieves an overall MAP of 0.1108. The "www-only" approach performs worst with a MAP of 0.0965. www body-only quotes-only body-quotes MAP 0.0965 0.1376 0.1242 0.1108</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table 3: MAP values for the different approaches</head><p>More interesting are the results achieved for the different term-weighting and document-candidate association models. Results here show that a stemmed representation clearly outperforms an unstemmed representation, and, more surprisingly, that approaches based on pure tf-idf perform better than pure LM approaches or mixtures of tf-idf and LM.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">CONCLUSION AND FUTURE WORK 5.1 Conclusion</head><p>The Enterprise TREC provides an interesting framework in which experiment with the integration of information retrieval and DBMS techniques: the ETREC data is fairly large and heterogeneous, as is the case with data typically encountered in commercial organisations, but requires the application of typical information retrieval tasks. Our experiments show that our probabilistic IR framework is able to cope with the amount of information provided, and that it is possible to express strategies for expert finding in a simple, straightforward way, without making any changes to the underlying system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Future Work</head><p>The approaches presented in this paper all implement retrieval strategies at a fairly low abstraction level. For expert finding tasks to be applicable by non-expert users, it would need to be possible to express the strategies at a higher abstraction level. Furthermore, expert finding can be seen as a two-phase operation: first, finding documents relevant to a query, followed by associating those documents with expert candidates. Another way of finding experts given a query would be to first aggregate all documents associated with an expert candidate, and then summarise those documents, to generate a profile for that candidate. Such a profile could then be used as a surrogate for the full document collection when querying for an expert. Both of the above issues could be addressed by a summarisation logic. A summarisation logic takes away implementational details, and provides users with a means to express different summarisation strategies (e.g. using stemmed or unstemmed document representations, or using different probabilistic models) via a more abstract syntax, coupled with a well-defined semantics. For this, we propose our summarisation logic POLIS, which uses structural information of knowledge representations to derive a summary. Further research will be necessary to evaluate the quality of expert profiles derived in this fashion.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="4,305.16,511.59,173.86,8.97;4,305.16,522.04,152.53,8.97;4,305.16,532.48,155.02,8.97;4,305.16,542.92,183.88,8.97;4,299.76,568.00,222.02,8.97;4,299.76,578.44,38.91,8.97;4,305.16,607.72,182.52,8.97;4,316.68,618.16,128.79,8.97;4,327.48,628.60,59.69,8.97;4,299.76,653.67,210.93,8.97;5,59.16,95.44,53.61,8.97;5,133.55,95.44,71.00,8.97;5,150.00,105.88,63.31,8.97;5,150.00,116.44,75.88,8.97;5,59.16,126.88,63.62,8.97"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>SELECT DISTINCT candidate id, context FROM wqterm, tf www, www author WHERE wqterm.term = tf www.term AND tf www.context = www author.context; An expression equivalent to the above SQL in PRA would be: ?-PROJECT DISTINCT[$4,$5](JOIN[$3=$2] (JOIN[$1=$1](wqterm,tf www), www author)); Similarly, the same strategy expressed in Datalog is: retrieve(C,D) :-wqterm(T) &amp; tf www(T,D) &amp; www author(C,D); ?-retrieve(C,D);</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="5,59.16,531.27,173.86,8.97;5,59.16,541.72,148.08,8.97;5,59.16,552.16,154.91,8.97;5,59.16,562.60,179.44,8.97;5,53.76,587.67,187.53,8.97;5,59.16,616.96,182.64,8.97;5,70.80,627.40,181.24,8.97;5,53.76,653.67,182.15,8.97;5,305.16,95.43,53.61,8.97;5,379.55,95.43,70.88,8.97;5,396.00,105.87,63.56,8.97;5,396.00,116.44,71.80,8.97;5,305.16,126.88,63.62,8.97"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>SELECT DISTINCT candidate id, context FROM wqterm, tf body, lists author WHERE wqterm.term = tf body.term AND tf body.context = lists author.context; This can equivalently be expressed in PRA as: ?-PROJECT DISTINCT[$4,$5](JOIN[$3=$2] (JOIN[$1=$1](wqterm,tf body),lists author); And equivalently, in probabilistic Datalog as: retrieve(C,D) :-wqterm(T) &amp; tf body(T,D) &amp; lists author(C,D); ?-retrieve(C,D);</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="6,74.44,497.04,2.53,4.21;6,68.11,483.39,8.85,4.21;6,70.64,469.74,6.32,4.21;6,68.11,456.09,8.85,4.21;6,70.64,442.44,6.32,4.21;6,68.11,428.79,8.85,4.21;6,70.64,415.14,6.32,4.21;6,68.11,401.49,8.85,4.21;6,70.64,387.84,6.32,4.21;6,68.11,374.19,8.85,4.21;6,70.64,360.54,6.32,4.21;6,77.80,501.59,5.06,4.21;6,111.17,501.59,5.06,4.21;6,144.58,501.59,5.06,4.21;6,177.96,501.59,5.06,4.21;6,211.34,501.59,5.06,4.21;6,243.48,501.59,7.59,4.21;6,276.86,501.59,7.59,4.21;6,56.56,425.61,4.21,9.86;6,162.92,508.42,33.89,4.21;6,126.89,353.72,105.96,4.21;6,89.71,364.86,22.75,4.21;6,91.98,369.41,20.47,4.21;6,94.25,373.96,18.20,4.21;6,91.98,378.51,20.47,4.21"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>the expert finding queries -stemmed bq-st-lm-lm bq-st-lm-tf bq-st-tf-tf bq-st-tf-lm</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="6,55.92,527.16,217.68,8.08"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Map values for stemmed bodyquotes</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="6,320.43,243.24,2.53,4.21;6,314.11,229.59,8.85,4.21;6,316.64,215.94,6.32,4.21;6,314.11,202.29,8.85,4.21;6,316.64,188.64,6.32,4.21;6,314.11,174.99,8.85,4.21;6,316.64,161.34,6.32,4.21;6,314.11,147.69,8.85,4.21;6,316.64,134.04,6.32,4.21;6,314.11,120.39,8.85,4.21;6,316.64,106.74,6.32,4.21;6,323.80,247.79,5.06,4.21;6,357.17,247.79,5.06,4.21;6,390.58,247.79,5.06,4.21;6,423.96,247.79,5.06,4.21;6,457.34,247.79,5.06,4.21;6,489.48,247.79,7.59,4.21;6,522.86,247.79,7.59,4.21;6,302.56,171.81,4.21,9.86;6,408.92,254.62,33.89,4.21;6,370.36,99.92,111.02,4.21;6,334.65,111.06,26.54,4.21;6,336.92,115.61,24.27,4.21;6,339.19,120.16,22.00,4.21;6,336.92,124.71,24.27,4.21"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>the expert finding queries -unstemmed bq-uns-lm-lm bq-uns-lm-tf bq-uns-tf-tf bq-uns-tf-lm</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5" coords="6,299.76,273.36,49.40,8.08;6,368.89,273.36,153.02,8.08;6,299.76,283.80,53.15,8.08"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: MAP values for unstemmed bodyquotes</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="6,299.76,410.08,222.59,61.57"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>MAP statistic for stemmed bodyquotes</figDesc><table coords="6,305.16,410.08,217.19,40.77"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="4">bq-lm-lm bq-lm-tf bq-tf-tf bq-tf-lm</cell></row><row><cell>high</cell><cell>0.0408</cell><cell>0.1513</cell><cell>0.4822</cell><cell>0.1172</cell></row><row><cell>avg</cell><cell>0.0082</cell><cell>0.0184</cell><cell>0.1108</cell><cell>0.0179</cell></row><row><cell>#Q &gt; avg</cell><cell>19</cell><cell>14</cell><cell>17</cell><cell>18</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,58.44,634.48,80.38,8.97"><p>www.autonomy.com</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,58.44,644.80,59.51,8.97"><p>www.tacit.com</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="2,58.44,655.12,217.33,8.97;2,53.76,664.12,98.78,8.97"><p>following the acquisition of Lotus by IBM, Discovery Server was discontinued.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,304.25,362.79,96.83,10.76" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>References</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,318.59,374.67,203.04,8.97;7,318.60,385.23,172.46,8.97" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,318.60,385.23,168.61,8.97">Overview of the trec-2005 enterprise track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nick</forename><surname>Craswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Arjen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>De Vries</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Soboroff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,318.59,396.63,176.26,8.97;7,318.60,407.07,193.92,8.97;7,318.60,417.51,193.99,8.97;7,318.60,428.07,163.10,8.97;7,318.60,438.51,63.63,8.97" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,445.53,407.07,66.99,8.97;7,318.60,417.51,177.98,8.97">Panoptic expert: Searching for experts not just for documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nick</forename><surname>Craswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Hawking</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Anne-Marie</forename><surname>Vercoustre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Wilkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,318.60,428.07,106.42,8.97">Ausweb Poster Proceedings</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Queensland, Australia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,318.59,449.91,163.11,8.97;7,318.60,460.35,198.25,8.97;7,318.60,470.91,165.44,8.97;7,318.60,481.35,201.75,8.97;7,318.60,491.79,162.14,8.97" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,395.38,449.91,86.31,8.97;7,318.60,460.35,140.80,8.97">Yenta: a multi-agent, referral-based matchmaking system</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Leonard</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Foner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,478.32,460.35,38.53,8.97;7,318.60,470.91,165.44,8.97;7,318.60,481.35,134.94,8.97">AGENTS &apos;97: Proceedings of the first international conference on Autonomous agents</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="301" to="307" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,318.59,503.19,200.27,8.97;7,318.60,513.75,202.58,8.97;7,318.60,524.19,182.43,8.97;7,318.60,534.63,162.04,8.97" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,418.40,503.19,100.46,8.97;7,318.60,513.75,202.58,8.97;7,318.60,524.19,85.82,8.97">A probabilistic relational algebra for the integration of information retrieval and database systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Fuhr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Rölleke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,411.72,524.19,89.31,8.97;7,318.60,534.63,81.42,8.97">ACM Transactions on Information Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="32" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,318.59,546.03,194.27,8.97;7,318.60,556.59,112.11,8.97" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,386.25,546.03,122.69,8.97">Challenges in enterprise search</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Hawking</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,330.12,556.59,17.22,8.97">ADC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="24" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,318.59,567.99,186.81,8.97;7,318.60,578.43,159.42,8.97;7,318.60,588.87,191.60,8.97;7,318.60,599.43,175.11,8.97" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Reichling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Becks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Oliver</forename><surname>Bresser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Volker</forename><surname>Wulf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,389.98,578.43,88.04,8.97;7,318.60,588.87,166.61,8.97">Kontaktanbahnung in Lernplattformen. In Mensch &amp; Computer</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="188" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<publisher>Allgegenwärtige Interaktion</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,318.59,621.27,198.98,8.97;7,318.60,631.71,195.67,8.97;7,318.60,642.27,152.18,8.97;7,318.60,652.71,51.03,8.97" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,370.20,621.27,147.38,8.97;7,318.60,631.71,195.67,8.97;7,318.60,642.27,27.44,8.97">POOL: Probabilistic Object-Oriented Logical Representation and Retrieval of Complex Objects</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Roelleke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<publisher>Shaker Verlag</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Aachen</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Dissertation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,318.59,664.11,192.65,8.97;8,72.60,98.08,197.43,8.97;8,72.60,108.52,193.23,8.97;8,72.60,119.08,181.76,8.97;8,72.60,129.52,188.03,8.97;8,72.60,139.96,167.64,8.97" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,463.77,664.11,47.48,8.97;8,72.60,98.08,139.64,8.97">Information retrieval with probabilistic Datalog</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Rölleke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Norbert</forename><surname>Fuhr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">;</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,231.36,98.08,38.67,8.97;8,72.60,108.52,193.23,8.97;8,72.60,119.08,181.76,8.97;8,72.60,129.52,45.79,8.97">Logic and Uncertainty in Information Retrieval: Advanced models for the representation and retrieval of information</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="221" to="245" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,72.59,151.36,179.50,8.97;8,72.60,161.92,199.08,8.97;8,72.60,172.36,197.13,8.97;8,72.60,182.80,165.03,8.97;8,72.60,193.24,190.71,8.97;8,72.60,203.68,162.14,8.97" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,101.27,161.92,125.38,8.97">The HySpirit retrieval platform</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Rölleke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ralf</forename><surname>Lübeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gabriella</forename><surname>Kazai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,245.52,161.92,26.16,8.97;8,72.60,172.36,197.13,8.97;8,72.60,182.80,165.03,8.97;8,72.60,193.24,146.26,8.97">SIGIR &apos;01: Proceedings of the 24th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">454</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,72.59,215.20,183.92,8.97;8,72.60,225.64,197.44,8.97;8,72.60,236.08,20.80,8.97" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,160.76,215.20,95.75,8.97;8,72.60,225.64,81.90,8.97">A non-classical logic for information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Rijsbergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,161.28,225.64,44.39,8.97">Comput. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="481" to="485" />
			<date type="published" when="1986">1986</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,72.59,247.60,198.87,8.97;8,72.60,258.04,158.58,8.97;8,72.60,268.48,90.49,8.97" xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,198.93,247.60,72.54,8.97;8,72.60,258.04,158.58,8.97;8,72.60,268.48,86.29,8.97">Demoir: A hybrid architecture for expertise modeling and recommender systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Yimam-Seid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kobsa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
