<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,137.52,75.04,337.05,15.49">RMIT University at TREC 2006: Terabyte Track</title>
				<funder ref="#_P4GjeUd">
					<orgName type="full">RMIT University</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Australian Research Council</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,227.40,107.55,66.87,10.76"><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Garcia</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science and IT</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">RMIT University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>GPO Box 2476V</addrLine>
									<postCode>3001</postCode>
									<settlement>Melbourne</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,309.24,107.55,75.38,10.76"><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Lester</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science and IT</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">RMIT University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>GPO Box 2476V</addrLine>
									<postCode>3001</postCode>
									<settlement>Melbourne</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,229.56,121.47,60.62,10.76"><forename type="first">Falk</forename><surname>Scholer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science and IT</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">RMIT University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>GPO Box 2476V</addrLine>
									<postCode>3001</postCode>
									<settlement>Melbourne</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,305.16,121.47,77.24,10.76"><forename type="first">Milad</forename><surname>Shokouhi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science and IT</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">RMIT University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>GPO Box 2476V</addrLine>
									<postCode>3001</postCode>
									<settlement>Melbourne</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,137.52,75.04,337.05,15.49">RMIT University at TREC 2006: Terabyte Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">63341C2481C940CB0F8B034D53F0646C</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The TREC 2006 terabyte track consisted of three tasks: informational (or ad hoc) search, named page finding, and efficient retrieval. This paper outlines RMIT University's participation in these tasks.</p><p>2 The Zettair 0.9 Search Engine Zettair is a publicly available retrieval engine developed by the Search Engine Group at RMIT University, available under a BSD license from http://www.seg.rmit.edu.au/zettair. Since TREC 2005, Zettair has been significantly revised. Major changes between the latest (0.9) and the previous (0.6) versions are:</p><p>• The ability use either a Porter's stemmer <ref type="bibr" coords="1,286.68,347.00,55.10,8.97" target="#b3">(Porter, 1997)</ref>, a "light" stemmer which achieves slightly worse effectiveness than Porter's with far better efficiency, or no stemming.</p><p>• Transparent indexing of gzip files.</p><p>• Similarity metric configuration: an enhanced set of similarity metrics, including Dirichlet-smoothed language modelling <ref type="bibr" coords="1,198.36,402.80,101.78,8.97" target="#b9">(Zhai and Lafferty, 2004)</ref>, Okapi BM25 (Sparck <ref type="bibr" coords="1,398.16,402.80,72.48,8.97" target="#b7">Jones et al., 2000)</ref>, cosine and pivoted cosine <ref type="bibr" coords="1,176.76,414.80,85.76,8.97" target="#b6">(Singhal et al., 1996)</ref> metrics. In addition, Zettair now defines a simple language for implementing new metrics.</p><p>• Impact ordered operation: Zettair can now generate and use impact-ordered <ref type="bibr" coords="1,424.44,442.64,96.80,8.97" target="#b0">(Anh and Moffat, 2002)</ref> inverted lists.</p><p>• Options to control memory usage, resulting in greatly reduced memory consumption, especially during indexing.</p><p>• Increased indexing speed.</p><p>• Integrated trec eval effectiveness evaluation.</p><p>Zettair 0.9 was used for all experiments submitted to TREC 2006 by RMIT, with the exception of the Terabyte track comparative runs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Ad Hoc Task</head><p>This year 50 new topics were created for ad hoc searching over the .GOV2 collection, a 426GB crawl of the .gov domain of the World Wide Web. The RMIT ad hoc runs can be grouped into three classes: first, representative probabilistic and language modelling retrieval runs, as implemented in our search engine, Zettair; second, two data-fusion runs that combine evidence from the output of two search engines, Indri and Zettair; and third, a manual run.  <ref type="bibr" coords="2,90.72,155.24,26.01,8.97">(bpref)</ref>, and precision at the number of relevant documents for each query (R-P). Metrics are calculated over TREC topics 801-850, with relevance judgments constructed using a pool of depth 50.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Run</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Probabilistic and Language Model Runs</head><p>Two runs were submitted to establish baseline performance for representative probabilistic and language model retrieval runs, as implemented in the new version of Zettair. Run ZETABM used the Okapi BM25 similarity function <ref type="bibr" coords="2,169.44,231.68,122.16,8.97" target="#b4">(Robertson and Walker, 1999)</ref>, while ZETADIR used a language model with Dirichlet smoothing <ref type="bibr" coords="2,136.20,243.68,102.71,8.97" target="#b9">(Zhai and Lafferty, 2004)</ref>; the parameters in both models were set to recommended published values.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Data-fusion Runs</head><p>Our first data-fusion run, ZETAMERG, is based on a simple round-robin method. The results returned by two search engines -Zettair and Indri -are sequentially merged according to their ranks. The final merged list consists of the first-rank documents returned by both search engines, followed by the second-rank documents returned by them and so forth. Duplicates are removed, so that documents that are already merged into the final list from one search engine are not added twice.</p><p>Zettair results used the Okapi BM25 <ref type="bibr" coords="2,264.36,362.60,120.68,8.97" target="#b4">(Robertson and Walker, 1999)</ref> similarity measure. Indri, available from www.lemurproject.org/indri, uses a retrieval model based on a combination of language modelling <ref type="bibr" coords="2,133.56,386.48,94.64,8.97" target="#b2">(Ponte and Croft, 1998)</ref> and inference networks <ref type="bibr" coords="2,326.04,386.48,94.08,8.97" target="#b8">(Turtle and Croft, 1991)</ref>.</p><p>The second data-fusion run, ZETAMERG2, merges documents returned by search engines according to their ranks. It can be considered as a variation of the CombSum data-fusion algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="2,433.56,410.48,87.68,8.97" target="#b1">(Fox and Shaw, 1993)</ref> that calculates the final score of documents as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,201.36,445.69,319.88,9.96">S d = (1000 -R d (Zettair )) + (1000 -R d (Indri ))<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where R d (Zettair ) and R d (Indri ) represent the rank of a given document d in the results returned by Zettair and Indri, respectively. Each system returns a maximum of 1000 documents per query. If a document appears in one result list but not in the other, its rank in the second list is set to 1000. Based on a voting principle, documents that are ranked highly by both search engines are more likely to be relevant. This data-fusion technique places such documents towards the top of the final merged list.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Manual</head><p>For the 2006 Terabyte track, it was requested that participants submit a manual run. For the run ZETAMAN, topics were created by starting with the &lt;title&gt; field of the TREC topics, and manually selecting promising keywords from the &lt;description&gt; and &lt;narrative&gt; In particular, words in the latter two fields that seemed to form commonly-used phrases were treated as phrase queries, while keywords in the topics that described features that were described as not being relevant were not included for the manual queries. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Characteristic</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Results</head><p>Results for our ad hoc runs are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,281.40,219.44,3.77,8.97">1</ref>. Metrics are calculated over the 50 new topics (801-850), using relevance judgements constructed using a pool depth of 50. The row labelled Mean shows the average of the median MAP and P10 results of all participants.</p><p>The relatively poor performance of Okapi BM25 (ZETABM) is surprising. The Dirichlet smoothed language modelling approach (ZETADIR) and data-fusion techniques produce the highest MAP values. The manual run (ZETAMAN) resulted in the highest P10.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Efficiency Task</head><p>We submitted a single run for the efficiency task this year. To reduce the size of the index we removed word offsets from the postings lists. This reduced the index size from 43.0 Gb with offsets to 15.8 Gb without offsets. No threading or parallel processing was used, as Zettair processes queries serially in a single stream. Results were ranked using Dirichlet smoothed language modelling, and both stopping and light stemming were used.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="3,115.20,428.84,4.98,8.97" target="#tab_1">2</ref> gives a summary of our submitted Zettair run, as well as an overview of the range of systems that were used by other participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Named Page Finding Task</head><p>This year we investigated the combination of different features for named page finding: the full text of documents, the text in document titles, and inlink anchor text. Each of these three features were indexed separately using the Zettair search engine. A named page query was then run against each index separately, and the results were merged using a simple liner interpolation approach to give a final ranked list. To combine evidence from two features (for example full text and anchor text):</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,239.40,563.89,132.38,9.96">Sim = αSim A + (1 -α)Sim B</formula><p>where 0 ≤ α ≤ 1. To add evidence from a third feature:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="3,204.48,602.17,202.03,9.96">Sim = αSim A + βSim B + (1 -(α + β))Sim C</formula><p>where 0 ≤ α, β, α + β ≤ 1. The values for the interpolation parameters α and β were set empirically, using last year's named page finding topics and relevance judgements (topics NP601-872) to determine regions of good performance.</p><p>We • Zetnpbm: a baseline run using full text only</p><p>• Zetnpfa: full text and inlink anchor text (α = 0.8)</p><p>• Zetnpft: full text and title text (α = 0.85)</p><p>• Zetnpfta: full text, title text and inlink anchor text (α = 0.8, β = 0.1)</p><p>The similarity function used for each run was Okapi BM25.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>The results for the named page finding task are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,343.20,290.12,3.77,8.97" target="#tab_2">3</ref>. The row labelled Mean shows the average of the median MRR results of all participants in this year's named page finding task.</p><p>Our baseline run (ZETNPBM) used full text only (and performed worse than the mean of all runs submitted for this task). Adding inlink anchor text (ZETNPFA) caused a slight decrease in MRR, but the difference is not statistically significant based on a bootstrap test statistic for paired data <ref type="bibr" coords="4,398.64,337.88,52.46,8.97" target="#b5">(Sakai, 2006)</ref>. Using full text, combined with title text as a separate feature (ZETNPFT), leads to a relative increase in MRR of 19.3% (p &lt; 0.01). Combining all three features (ZETNPFTA) leads to an equivalent increase in MRR (p &lt; 0.01) over the full text baseline. Combining all three features leads to the highest proportion of queries for which the named resource was found in the top 10 answers, a 28.7% relative increase over the baseline. We therefore conclude that it is beneficial to include topic data as a separate source of evidence.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,97.20,37.04,417.55,150.69"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Details of the Zettair run submitted for the efficiency task.</figDesc><table coords="3,324.96,37.04,189.79,20.85"><row><cell>Zettair</cell><cell cols="3">All runs submitted</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Maximum</cell><cell>Median</cell><cell>Minimum</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="3,121.20,657.08,150.49,8.97"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>submitted four runs for the 2006 task: Effectiveness of named page finding runs, showing mean reciprocal rank (MRR), the percentage of queries for which an answer was found at rank 1 and within the top 10 documents, and the percentage of queries for which no answer was found. The mean MRR result is calculated over the median MRR of all queries submitted by all participants.</figDesc><table coords="4,115.68,37.04,380.70,69.45"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>Features used</cell><cell>MRR</cell><cell>Rank 1</cell><cell>Top 10</cell><cell>Not found</cell></row><row><cell>Mean</cell><cell></cell><cell>0.371</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>ZETNPBM</cell><cell>Document text</cell><cell>0.326</cell><cell>25.4%</cell><cell>46.4%</cell><cell>19.3%</cell></row><row><cell>ZETNPFA</cell><cell>Document text, anchor text</cell><cell>0.319</cell><cell>21.5%</cell><cell>54.7%</cell><cell>19.3%</cell></row><row><cell>ZETNPFT</cell><cell>Document text, titles</cell><cell>0.389</cell><cell>30.4%</cell><cell>54.7%</cell><cell>19.3%</cell></row><row><cell>ZETNPFTA</cell><cell>Document text, titles, anchor text</cell><cell>0.388</cell><cell>28.7%</cell><cell>59.7%</cell><cell>19.3%</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work is supported by the <rs type="funder">Australian Research Council</rs>. Hardware for some experiments was provided with the support of an <rs type="funder">RMIT University</rs> <rs type="grantName">VRII grant</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_P4GjeUd">
					<orgName type="grant-name">VRII grant</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,90.72,509.08,430.55,8.07;4,100.68,520.00,420.64,8.07;4,100.68,530.92,246.56,8.07" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,206.88,509.08,213.39,8.07">Impact transformation: effective and efficient web retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Anh</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Moffat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,247.34,520.00,273.98,8.07;4,100.68,530.92,136.10,8.07">Proceedings of the ACM SIGIR International Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Beaulieu</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Baeza-Yates</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Myaeng</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Jävelin</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the ACM SIGIR International Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval<address><addrLine>Tampere, Finland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,90.72,548.92,430.54,8.07;4,100.68,559.96,270.08,8.07" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,198.00,548.92,121.62,8.07">Combination of multiple searches</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,339.98,548.92,181.28,8.07;4,100.68,559.96,15.09,8.07">Proceedings of the second Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>the second Text REtrieval Conference<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">500</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="243" to="252" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,90.72,577.96,430.52,8.07;4,100.68,588.88,420.64,8.07;4,100.68,599.80,323.96,8.07" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,224.76,577.96,198.76,8.07">A language modelling approach to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ponte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,300.63,588.88,220.69,8.07;4,100.68,599.80,186.38,8.07">Proceedings of the ACM SIGIR International Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Moffat</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Rijsbergen</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Wilkinson</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zobel</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the ACM SIGIR International Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval<address><addrLine>Melbourne, Australia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="281" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,90.72,617.92,242.96,8.07" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,162.29,617.92,115.16,8.07">An algorithm for suffix stripping</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="316" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,90.72,635.92,430.58,8.07;4,100.68,646.84,420.64,8.07;4,100.68,657.76,151.28,8.07" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,238.32,635.92,98.50,8.07">Okapi/Keenbow at TREC-8</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,507.87,635.92,13.43,8.07;4,100.68,646.84,161.37,8.07">The Eighth Text REtrieval Conference (TREC-8)</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="162" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>National Institute of Standards and Technology Special Publication</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,90.72,38.92,430.53,8.07;5,100.68,49.84,344.72,8.07" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,152.64,38.92,187.32,8.07">Evaluating evaluation metrics based on the bootstrap</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Sakai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,358.83,38.92,162.42,8.07;5,100.68,49.84,241.20,8.07">Proceedings of the ACM SIGIR International Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the ACM SIGIR International Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval<address><addrLine>Seattle, WA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="525" to="532" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,90.72,68.80,430.61,8.07;5,100.68,79.72,362.24,8.07" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,267.12,68.80,142.05,8.07">Pivoted document length normalization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Singhal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,429.99,68.80,91.34,8.07;5,100.68,79.72,314.88,8.07">Proceedings of the ACM SIGIR International Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the ACM SIGIR International Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="29" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,90.72,98.68,430.60,8.07;5,100.68,109.60,307.16,8.07" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,292.98,98.68,228.35,8.07;5,100.68,109.60,88.41,8.07">A probabilistic model of information retrieval: development and comparative experiments</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sparck</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,199.08,109.60,149.01,8.07">Information Processing and Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="779" to="808" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,90.72,128.56,430.60,8.07;5,100.68,139.48,128.72,8.07" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,230.20,128.56,202.94,8.07">Evaluation of an inference network-based retrieval model</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Turtle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,443.40,128.56,77.92,8.07;5,100.68,139.48,73.45,8.07">ACM Transactions on Information Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="187" to="222" />
			<date type="published" when="1991">1991</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,90.72,158.44,430.52,8.07;5,100.68,169.36,57.56,8.07" xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,213.41,158.44,301.35,8.07">A study of smoothing methods for language models applied to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="214" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
