<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,121.87,94.74,354.55,21.49;1,164.90,122.63,268.49,21.49">Experiments with Query Expansion at TREC 2006 Legal Track</title>
				<funder ref="#_uQRcxr3">
					<orgName type="full">UMKC</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,186.59,161.06,62.09,10.37"><forename type="first">Charlie</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Missouri</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kansas City</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,251.67,161.06,73.71,10.37"><forename type="first">Yugyung</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Missouri</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kansas City</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,328.38,161.06,49.12,10.37"><forename type="first">Deep</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Missouri</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kansas City</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,380.49,161.06,31.21,10.37"><surname>Medhi</surname></persName>
							<email>dmedhi@umkc.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computing and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Missouri</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Kansas City</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,121.87,94.74,354.55,21.49;1,164.90,122.63,268.49,21.49">Experiments with Query Expansion at TREC 2006 Legal Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">52244B2CFA3B0F3FC0B262F24AE8F3B0</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the UMKC TREC 2006 Legal Track experiments. We focus on a single technique that uses cooccurrence based thesaurus to expand queries. Our results indicate this technique is effective even towards the enormous vocabulary size in the IIT CDIP collection.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. INTRODUCTION</head><p>The vocabulary problem <ref type="bibr" coords="1,155.21,343.08,11.62,8.64" target="#b0">[1]</ref> in document retrieval is a primary hindrance function to its performance where polysemy may reduce precision and synonymy may reduce recall. Query expansion seeks to mitigate this problem by expanding queries with additional conceptual relevant terms.</p><p>Query expansion is often associated with debatable results <ref type="bibr" coords="1,42.11,414.90,11.62,8.64" target="#b1">[2]</ref>  <ref type="bibr" coords="1,56.09,414.90,11.62,8.64" target="#b2">[3]</ref> when expanding from manually compiled thesaurus like WordNet <ref type="bibr" coords="1,80.90,426.86,10.58,8.64" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. When thesaurus has been re-defined as "any data structure that defines semantic relatedness between words" <ref type="bibr" coords="1,279.06,438.81,10.58,8.64" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, people noticed some important limitations in this approach <ref type="bibr" coords="1,279.06,450.77,10.58,8.64" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Encouraged by some positive results in this research topic <ref type="bibr" coords="1,281.55,462.72,11.62,8.64" target="#b4">[5]</ref> [7], we believe an effective query expansion model has to resolve two fundamental issues. To find those conceptual relevant terms with great affinity to original query terms and further to assign proper weights to them to reflect the overall query emphasis.</p><p>Legal Track provides a unique opportunity to evaluate such query expansion model based on co-occurrence thesaurus. The IIT CDIP collection <ref type="bibr" coords="1,123.07,558.45,11.62,8.64" target="#b7">[8]</ref> has more than 200 million unique terms in our index. It becomes questionable for any query expansion model to excel with the presence of such phenomenal noise in OCR data. Therefore we designed our experiments to explore the effectiveness and robustness of our current query expansion model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>II. OUR QUERY EXPANSION MODEL</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Architecture for Query Expansion</head><p>The knowledge of conceptual relevance between any two terms is a precondition for our model, but this model is applicable regardless the underlying method which yields that knowledge. In this paper, the focus is to discuss our query expansion model rather the method of computing with conceptual relevance. There is no consensus of the definition of relevance regardless of it is actually a core concept in information retrieval. There are many different school of thoughts to compute the conceptual relevance or similarity between two terms whereas our approach is primarily based on statistical analysis of co-occurrence patterns. In our model, we first retrieve conceptual relevance information from the component of relevance storage according to the original query terms. That sets up the initial pool of query expansion candidates. Unfair voting component will discard all those candidates whose votes don't exceed the majority vote. Those winners will then be assigned a weight based on its correlation to the query centroid which is the unique representation of the overall emphasis of query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Unfair Voting</head><p>It is so called unfair voting because the votes casted from original query terms to query expansion candidate terms carry different weights. As the result, even every vote still counts, but those terms which have multilateral conceptual relevance to leading query terms will get high votes. And they will move to the next stage to receive their query term weights.</p><p>The purpose of our unfair voting strategy is for word sense disambiguation. By marginalizing those terms which do not have multilateral relationship with the majority of original query terms, we are able to discern the correct sense based on query context. Then we can discard those candidates if they are misaligned with the current word sense.</p><p>The procedure of unfair voting has three major steps with the following definitions:</p><p>• m: number of original query terms • M V : majority vote threshold • q i : weight for original query term i • β, δ: experimental regulating parameters • v i : original query term i as voter • c j : candidate term j • V j : all votes for candidate term j • CR(v i , c j ): conceptual relevance measure of two terms v i and c j • CS: the set of final query expansion candidate terms 1) Determine the Majority Vote (MV) from weight (q i ) of original query terms</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,85.65,294.98,207.53,43.96">M V = m i αq i , α = 1 q i &gt; β m i qi m 0 else<label>(1)</label></formula><p>2) Cast votes (V j ) for candidate term j (c j ) from all voters (v i )</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,87.15,394.07,206.02,42.90">V j = m i γq i , γ = 1 CR(v i , c j ) &gt; δ 0 else<label>(2)</label></formula><p>3) Form the final query expansion candidate term set (CS)</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,117.60,474.19,175.57,9.65">CS = [• • • c j • • • ] ∀ V j &gt; M V<label>(3)</label></formula><p>C. Query Centroid : query centroid</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,111.54,563.79,112.29,159.54">1 t 2 q c q c t Fig. 2. Query Centroid</formula><p>Query centroid is a unique overall representation of the query in our model. As shown in figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,191.26,761.36,3.74,8.64">2</ref>, it is the center of the mass where circles on the tips of vectors representing the size of mass. So the query centroid always leans to the dominant query terms. Query centroid can be obtained from equation 4 with the following definitions:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="2,315.09,131.02,241.10,96.33">• -→ q c : query centroid • -→ t i : query component i • m i : mass of component i • m tot = m i : total mass -→ q c = -→ t i m i m tot<label>(4)</label></formula><p>After obtaining this query centroid vector, we assign the weight to query expansion candidate terms using equation 5 with the following definitions:</p><p>• -→ W : the weight vector for all query expansion candidate terms • C : the correlation matrix of query expansion candidate terms • C ij : the relevance measure between candidate term i to original query term j • -→ q c T : the transpose of query centroid vector</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="2,406.58,388.34,149.60,16.46">-→ W = C -→ q c T<label>(5)</label></formula><p>We sort the weight vector of -→ W in descending order to obtain the final expanded query with ranked terms. This query can be fairly long, so in order to keep the query turnaround time within expectation, we chop the query to a fixed length. It becomes another tuning parameter to determine the optimal query length in different corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>III. EXPERIMENTS AND RESULTS</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Runs</head><p>All our runs are automatic and queries are distilled from the FinalQuery element within BooleanQuery. Queries were run again the ot element in corpus only, so there is no usage of metadata elements. Therefore all runs fall into the second category of Legal Track runs, namely Good-OCR subset, no use of metadata, automatic queries. The underlying text search engine is an extension of Lucene library <ref type="bibr" coords="2,438.33,614.87,10.58,8.64" target="#b8">[9]</ref>.</p><p>We submitted eight runs to TREC while kept many others for additional benchmarking. The semantics of various runs are explained in table 1, 2 and 3.    </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Analysis</head><p>The experimental results indicates the boolean queries with the consideration of proximity (UMKCSN and UMKCSW) actually degraded the performance when compared with their The expanded queries from individual query terms can further degrade the performance by introducing in some irrelevant terms which is hard to avoid without proper means of word sense disambiguation when expanded from a co-occurrence based thesaurus.</p><p>To justify our query expansion model, we compare the performance between the expanded queries from our model to the original run as their baseline. Where we found some general improvements as shown in table <ref type="table" coords="3,435.46,420.82,3.74,8.64">4</ref>. When we investigated this improvement on individual topic, we were amazed on its effectiveness on some topics. The figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,305.13,564.90,4.98,8.64">6</ref> of the map on topic 22 shows the technique of query expansion based on our model has improved map by almost 9 times. If we consider the statistics on this particular topic from all runs submitted in this year, then this single technique of query expansion even has better performance than topic 22's best map at 0.0303. It also demonstrated that our model is a close-fitting to this type of query from the trend that query performs better with more expanded terms.</p><p>In general, our model does not succeed in every query and in some cases, the expanded query diluted the original query intension, then degradation occurred. There are two possible reasons. First, due to the restrictions of this collection we were not able to zoom into a smaller window size to look up the cooccurrence patterns when building up the thesaurus. Therefore we had only a coarse-grained initial query expansion pool to start with. Second, our model currently missing the feature to expand the query according to its internal boolean query struc- ture which we will address further in the next section.</p><p>While the results indicate our query expansion model still produce the best run within all experiments we have done, we also got disturbed by the overall poor performance of all runs in general. This means the IIT CDIP collection remains a great challenge to our query expansion model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IV. LIMITATIONS AND FUTURE WORK</head><p>Since our primary goal for this experiment is to verify the effectiveness and robustness of our query expansion model, therefore we are not expecting this one technique will be very competitive to other mature search engines which have incorporated many useful techniques. But our experiments still revealed a serious limitation in our model. Our model simply takes the query as a bag of terms and lacks the consideration of normal boolean operators of AND, OR and parenthesis which seams to be necessary to achieve better performance for complex queries in Legal Track. Therefore a specialized query parser is needed in our model to better interpret and expand legal queries.</p><p>Relevance feedback method <ref type="bibr" coords="4,166.31,532.08,16.60,8.64" target="#b9">[10]</ref> has become a standard tool for practitioners in information retrieval, but its effectiveness is largely depending on the very first run. That's why we presented precision at 30 documents (P30) in figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,251.78,567.94,3.74,8.64" target="#fig_2">5</ref>. Hypothetically these significant improvements of precision from our model should naturally become the compound interest for relevance feedback method afterwards. We are very interested to verify this hypothesis in the near future.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>V. CONCLUSION</head><p>Our experiments in this Legal Track was designed to find out the effectiveness and robustness of our query expansion model which was powered by a novel unfair voting strategy and weighting schema based on query centroid. The results indicated even with the possession of enormous noise in the IIT CDIP data, our model still improved query performance from the baseline. With the 100% recall as one of goals in this Legal Track, we consider it is recommendable to further explore the potential of our model, especially in the direction of synthesizing with traditional relevance feedback method.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="1,376.95,463.52,105.41,6.91"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Query Expansion Model</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,142.94,697.93,47.41,6.91"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4. GMap</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="3,391.45,258.45,76.42,6.91"><head>Fig. 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Fig. 5. Precision (P30)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,311.10,671.80,269.31,94.08"><head>TABLE I RUNS</head><label>I</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="2,311.10,684.41,269.31,81.48"><row><cell></cell><cell>WITHOUT QUERY EXPANSION</cell></row><row><cell>Runs</cell><cell>Conditions</cell></row><row><cell>Orig</cell><cell>Boolean query with only OR considered</cell></row><row><cell>UMKCB</cell><cell>Boolean query without proximity</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">UMKCSN Boolean query without positional order for proximity</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">UMKCSW Boolean query with positional order for proximity</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,48.09,86.55,212.63,81.73"><head>TABLE II RUNS</head><label>II</label><figDesc>WITH QUERY EXPANSION ON INDIVIDUAL TERM</figDesc><table coords="3,48.09,122.19,144.51,46.09"><row><cell>Runs</cell><cell>Conditions</cell></row><row><cell>UMKCBQE5</cell><cell>query length ≤ 5</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">UMKCBQE10 query length ≤ 10</cell></row><row><cell>UMKCQE25</cell><cell>query length ≤ 25</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="3,42.11,181.91,245.95,480.44"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The results of above runs are presented in figure3, 4 and 5.</figDesc><table coords="3,42.11,181.91,222.63,480.44"><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">TABLE III</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="8">RUNS WITH QUERY EXPANSION ON OUR MODEL</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Runs Conditions</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>QE5</cell><cell cols="4">query length ≤ 5</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="6">QE10 query length ≤ 10</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="6">QE20 query length ≤ 20</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">B. Results</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Map</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.08</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0745</cell></row><row><cell>0.07</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0692</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0671</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.0629</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.06</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0541</cell></row><row><cell>0.05</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0488</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0472</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0447</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.04</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0381</cell></row><row><cell>0.03</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0247</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.02</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>orig</cell><cell>UMKCB</cell><cell>UMKCSN</cell><cell>UMKCSW</cell><cell cols="3">UMKCBQE5 UMKCBQE10 UMKCQE25</cell><cell>QE5</cell><cell>QE10</cell><cell>QE20</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Fig. 3. Map</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>GMap</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.016</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0146</cell></row><row><cell>0.014</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.012</cell><cell>0.0123</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0113</cell></row><row><cell>0.01</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0089</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.008</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.006</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0057</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0047</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.004</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>0.002</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0022</cell><cell cols="2">0.0016</cell><cell>0.002</cell><cell>0.0018</cell></row><row><cell>0</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>orig</cell><cell>UMKCB</cell><cell>UMKCSN</cell><cell>UMKCSW</cell><cell cols="3">UMKCBQE5 UMKCBQE10 UMKCQE25</cell><cell>QE5</cell><cell>QE10</cell><cell>QE20</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="3,311.10,441.86,189.90,81.73"><head>TABLE IV IMPROVEMENT</head><label>IV</label><figDesc>FROM QUERY EXPANSION</figDesc><table coords="3,311.10,477.50,118.48,46.09"><row><cell cols="2">Measures Most Improved</cell></row><row><cell>Map</cell><cell>18%</cell></row><row><cell>Gmap</cell><cell>19%</cell></row><row><cell>P30</cell><cell>40%</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="4,73.13,110.74,190.27,154.62"><head>Map of Topic 22 Our model most improved: 872.22%</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="4,73.13,124.41,190.27,140.95"><row><cell></cell><cell>0.04</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.035</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0343</cell><cell>0.0341</cell><cell>0.0343</cell><cell>0.0349</cell><cell>0.035</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0328</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.03</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0304</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.025</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0257</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>0.0234</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>map</cell><cell>0.02</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.015</cell><cell>0.0161</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.01</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.005</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0.0036</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>orig</cell><cell>QE10</cell><cell>QE20</cell><cell>QE30</cell><cell>QE40</cell><cell>QE50</cell><cell>QE60</cell><cell>QE70</cell><cell>QE80</cell><cell>QE90</cell><cell>QE100</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>runs</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="6">Fig. 6. Map of Topic 22</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>VI. ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</head><p>The first author was partially supported by <rs type="funder">UMKC</rs>'s <rs type="programName">Preparing Future Faculty Fellowship program</rs> during this research work. And we also would like to acknowledge <rs type="person">Mr. Jim Grant</rs> and <rs type="person">Mr. Brian Koenigsdorf</rs> from <rs type="affiliation">Department of Central Systems of UMKC</rs> for their tremendous support in computing resources.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_uQRcxr3">
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">Preparing Future Faculty Fellowship program</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,323.39,205.59,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,214.36,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,223.13,86.40,6.91" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,544.23,205.59,11.95,6.91;4,323.39,214.36,169.90,6.91">The vocabulary problem in human-system communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Furnas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Landauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gomez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Dumais</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,502.62,214.36,48.60,6.91">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="964" to="971" />
			<date type="published" when="1987">1987</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,323.39,231.90,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,240.66,173.25,6.91" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,427.34,231.90,122.48,6.91">Vector Expansion in a Large Collection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y.-W</forename><surname>Hou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,331.58,240.66,17.89,6.91">TREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="343" to="352" />
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
			<pubPlace>Gaithersburg, Maryland</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,323.39,249.43,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,258.20,200.83,6.91" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,383.79,249.43,172.39,6.91;4,323.39,258.20,18.27,6.91">On Expanding Query Vectors with Lexically Related Words</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,359.15,258.20,17.89,6.91">TREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="223" to="232" />
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993</date>
			<pubPlace>Gaithersburg, Maryland</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,323.39,266.96,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,275.73,55.34,6.91" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,366.73,266.96,125.81,6.91">WordNet: an electronic lexical database</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Fellbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, Mass</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,323.39,284.50,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,293.27,232.79,6.91;4,323.39,302.03,86.40,6.91" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,391.18,284.50,165.00,6.91;4,323.39,293.27,92.36,6.91">A Cooccurance-based Thesaurus and Two Applications to Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A J P</forename><surname>Schutze</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,423.53,293.27,128.69,6.91">Information Processing and Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="307" to="318" />
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,323.39,310.80,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,319.57,232.79,6.91;4,323.39,328.33,33.87,6.91" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,408.01,310.80,148.17,6.91;4,323.39,319.57,147.64,6.91">The limitations of term co-occurrence data for query expansion in document retrieval systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Peat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Willett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,479.74,319.57,18.24,6.91">JASIS</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="378" to="383" />
			<date type="published" when="1991">1991</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,323.39,337.10,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,345.87,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,354.64,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,363.40,82.30,6.91" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,399.70,337.10,99.96,6.91">Concept based query expansion</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Qiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H.-P</forename><surname>Frei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,517.22,337.10,38.96,6.91;4,323.39,345.87,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,354.64,156.02,6.91">Proceedings of the 16th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval Pittsburgh</title>
		<meeting>the 16th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval Pittsburgh<address><addrLine>Pennsylvania, United States</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,323.39,372.17,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,380.94,232.79,6.91;4,323.39,389.70,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,398.47,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,407.24,103.08,6.91" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,326.88,380.94,229.30,6.91;4,323.39,389.70,9.10,6.91">Building a test collection for complex document information processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Agam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Argamon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Frieder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Grossman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Heard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,348.52,389.70,207.66,6.91;4,323.39,398.47,207.96,6.91">Proceedings of the 29th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval Seattle</title>
		<meeting>the 29th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval Seattle<address><addrLine>USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Washington</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,323.39,416.01,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,424.77,77.49,6.91" xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Gospodnetic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hatcher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="4,427.76,416.01,52.47,6.91">Lucene in action</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Greenwich, CT</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Manning Publications</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,323.39,433.54,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,442.31,232.80,6.91;4,323.39,451.07,232.79,6.91;4,323.39,459.84,60.65,6.91" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,370.02,433.54,152.68,6.91">Relevance Feedback in Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rocchio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,543.79,433.54,12.39,6.91;4,323.39,442.31,229.52,6.91">The SMART retrieval system; experiments in automatic document processing</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Englewood Cliffs, N.J.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Prentice-Hall</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1971">1971</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="323" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
