<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,108.26,81.91,378.62,16.07">DUTIR at TREC 2019: Precision Medicine Track</title>
				<funder ref="#_xAhqnXa">
					<orgName type="full">National Key Research and Development Program of China</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,111.02,107.02,62.62,10.91"><forename type="first">Jingkun</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">College of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalian University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116024</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,182.04,107.02,58.74,10.91"><forename type="first">Zhihao</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">College of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalian University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116024</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,249.34,107.02,61.06,10.91"><forename type="first">Zhiqiang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">College of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalian University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116024</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,318.32,107.02,42.42,10.91"><forename type="first">Ling</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">College of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalian University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116024</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,369.32,107.02,57.00,10.91"><forename type="first">Hongfei</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">College of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalian University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116024</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,434.24,107.02,49.90,10.91"><forename type="first">Jian</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">College of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalian University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116024</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,108.26,81.91,378.62,16.07">DUTIR at TREC 2019: Precision Medicine Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">272527D7EE87A3EED675837DF63906B9</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:10+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the system developed for the TREC 2019 Precision Medicine Track by the Team DUTIR from Dalian University of Technology. In the system, we applied a hybrid method to score the related documents for each topic. First, we used Elasticsearch, an open-source Lucene-based full-text search engine, to obtain the initial retrieval results.</p><p>Then we trained several deep models using TREC 2017 PM data. Finally, we applied the pre-trained models to reorder the initial search results. The performance of our system is above the median for the scientific abstracts subtask and below median for the clinical trials subtask.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>INTRODUCTION</head><p>The 2019 Text Retrieval Conference (TREC) Precision Medicine (PM) track continues the prior 2017 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,258.50,535.38,19.10,12.76" target="#b0">[1]</ref> and 2018 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,331.65,535.38,19.06,12.76" target="#b1">[2]</ref> Precision Medicine tracks, which aims to retrieve biomedical articles and clinical trials which can provide useful and precision medicine-related information for treating cancer patients. Given 40 cancer patient topics in this track, participants of the track will be challenged with retrieving (1) scientific abstracts, in the form of biomedical article abstracts, addressing relevant treatments for the given patient, and (2) clinical trials, addressing relevant clinical trials for which the patient is eligible. Same as the 2017 and 2018 PM tracks, each topic includes information on the patient's disease (type of cancer), the relevant genetic variants (which genes), and some basic demographic information (age, sex). Table <ref type="table" coords="2,262.47,145.33,7.02,12.76">1</ref> shows a topic example. In addition, the biomedical articles are largely from MEDILINE/PubMed, while the clinical trials are a snapshot of the ClinicalTrials.gov. The specific descriptions of the PM track are available online <ref type="foot" coords="2,361.87,237.47,4.50,8.10" target="#foot_0">1</ref> . Table <ref type="table" coords="2,202.68,270.38,5.29,12.54">1</ref>. An example of cancer patient topics &lt;topic number="1"&gt; &lt;disease&gt;Acute lymphoblastic leukemia&lt;/disease&gt; &lt;gene&gt;ABL1, PTPN11&lt;/gene&gt; &lt;demographic&gt;12-year-old male&lt;/demographic&gt;</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>&lt;/topic&gt;</head><p>In this report, we present our system for the two subtasks. In scientific abstracts task, we use a hybrid method to retrieve related articles from the collections. We first indexed all documents with Elasticsearch 2 , and then we applied query templates and query expansion to get the initial search results for each topic. Finally, we used deep models which were trained by using the 2017 PM track data to reorder documents of the initial retrieval results. Different from the scientific abstracts task, we only used Elasticsearch with the same query templates and query expansion to obtain retrieval results for clinical trials track. In next section our method used in scientific abstracts task is introduced in detail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>METHODS</head><p>This section describes our IR system designed for the scientific abstracts retrieval subtask of the PM track. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,327.25,207.73,7.02,12.76" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows the architecture of our system. As shown in the figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,268.99,238.93,5.29,12.76" target="#fig_0">1</ref>, our system consists of two parts, initial relevant documents retrieval and retrieved documents re-ranking. In particular, we preprocess the collection of documents before building the index. Then, we utilized query expansion strategy for expanding terms that will be exploited in Elasticsearch queries to refer to diseases and genes. Moreover, we wrote some query templates using structured query language provided by Elasticsearch and combined their search results in different weighting ways.</p><p>For reordering the retrieved documents from the initial results, we used deep learning models to reorder the initial retrieval results in order to further improve the retrieval performance. Specifically, we applied the text classification model to determine whether documents are therapeutically relevant. In addition, we used deep matching models to score documents from disease and gene dimensions.</p><p>In the rest of this section, the main steps of our scientific abstracts retrieval system are introduced in detail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Preprocessing &amp; Indexing</head><p>To make retrieval more efficient, we preprocess the original documents before indexing. Specifically, we removed fields in each document that were not relevant for retrieval. For each XML document, we took into account the following fields: 1) PMID: the ID of the article;</p><p>2) Title: the title of the article;</p><p>3) Abstract: the abstract of the article; 4) Chemical List: the chemicals that appears in the article; 5) Mesh Heading List: Mesh Concepts that article contains.</p><p>For the text content in the above fields, we performed a series of processing such as tokenization, stop word removal and stemming. Finally, we use Elasticsearch's default options for indexing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Query Expansion &amp; Query Templates</head><p>The purpose of query expansion is to support the formulation of queries with a higher recall by gathering alternative expressions useful to the terms mentioned in queries. We paid more attention to the fields of disease and gene of the topic to conduct query expansion.</p><p>For the disease field, we expanded disease with its synonyms and hyponyms via a disease dictionary. While for the gene field, we expanded gene with its synonyms via a gene dictionary. In particular, the two dictionaries mentioned above were built from the disease and gene vocabularies provided by the CTD base <ref type="bibr" coords="5,315.67,332.56,14.78,12.76" target="#b2">[3]</ref>.</p><p>To improve the quality of the initial retrieval results, we wrote a variety of query templates with different focuses. For the same topic, we used all the query templates in turn to obtain the retrieval results, and finally summarized all the results of the same topic with different weights.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Re-Ranking</head><p>The objective of re-ranking is to improve the retrieval performance by adjusting the position of some documents in the initial retrieval result.</p><p>Due to the requirement that retrieved documents should focus on precision medicine, we need to consider whether a document is therapeutically relevant. Specifically, we integrated some classic text classification models such as TextCNN <ref type="bibr" coords="5,192.29,675.81,16.43,12.76" target="#b3">[4]</ref> and TextRCNN <ref type="bibr" coords="5,303.05,675.81,16.43,12.76" target="#b4">[5]</ref> to determine whether a retrieved document focuses on precision medicine. The training data is about 20000 biomedical articles from TREC 2017 PM Track which were annotated with "PM" for "Precision Medicine" and "Not PM" for "Not Precision Medicine". For each retrieved document, we used pre-trained model named PM Matcher to predict whether it is a "PM" document. If a document is "PM", we boost its initial score.</p><p>To assess the relevance of the document from both disease and gene dimensions, we also utilized deep matching models such as DRMM <ref type="bibr" coords="6,489.10,238.93,16.30,12.76" target="#b5">[6]</ref> and PACRR <ref type="bibr" coords="6,164.06,270.16,16.43,12.76" target="#b6">[7]</ref> to score retrieved documents. To train these models, we used the same training corpus as above which had different labels. In particular, we used pre-trained model named DISS Matcher to score documents from disease dimension. Meanwhile, another pre-trained model named GENE Matcher was applied to score documents from gene dimension.</p><p>To obtain the final ranking results, we combined above three scores with different weights.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RESULTS</head><p>We submitted five runs for scientific abstracts subtask and two runs for clinical trials subtask. For both tasks, metrics used are inferred non discounted cumulative gain (infNDCG), precision at rank 10 (P@10) and R-precision (R-Prec).</p><p>For scientific abstracts subtask, we list the average performance of each of our runs and the official median result in table 2. As can be seen from table 2, our results are better than the official median result, which proves the effectiveness of our method. In general, the five runs for retrieving scientific abstracts are described in detail as follows:</p><p>1) DutirRun1: we took this run as a baseline. In this run, we only applied Elasticsearch with query templates and query expansion to obtain retrieval results.</p><p>2) DutirRun2: in order to explore whether the PM Matcher works, we improved documents' scores which were judged as "PM" by PM Matcher. The result of this run proves the effectiveness of PM Matcher.</p><p>3) DutirRun3: in this run, we only utilized DISS Matcher to re-ranking the initial results. Compared with baseline, the result of this run is slightly improved.</p><p>4) DutirRun4: GENE Matcher was applied in this run. There was also a slight improvement during this run.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5) DutirRun5: we combined PM Matcher, DISS Matcher and GENE</head><p>Matcher to re-ranking the initial results in this run. As we can see from the results, the NDCG value increased slightly, but the other two indicators did decrease.</p><p>For clinical trials subtask, we also show our results and the median result in table <ref type="table" coords="8,135.14,270.16,5.30,12.76" target="#tab_1">3</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CONCLUSIONS</head><p>This paper describes the IR system developed for the TREC 2019 Precision Medicine track. In our system, we adopt a hybrid method to retrieve biomedical articles. For scientific abstracts task, we used Elasticsearch with query templates and query expansion to obtain initial results, then we utilize deep models to re-rank the retrieved documents. Experimental results show that the effectiveness of the abstract retrieval can be improved by three models we trained. For clinical trials task, we only used Elasticsearch to search relevant articles. Experimental results show that only using Elasticsearch is not a good method.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,117.62,457.60,360.05,12.54;3,90.00,297.02,415.30,142.75"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. The overview of system for scientific abstracts task</figDesc><graphic coords="3,90.00,297.02,415.30,142.75" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="7,142.34,145.55,300.28,231.93"><head>Table 2 . Results for Scientific Abstracts Subtask</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="7,142.34,177.01,300.28,200.47"><row><cell></cell><cell>InfNDCG</cell><cell>P10</cell><cell>R-Prec</cell></row><row><cell>DutirRun1</cell><cell>0.4980</cell><cell>0.5800</cell><cell>0.3266</cell></row><row><cell>DutirRun2</cell><cell>0.5103</cell><cell>0.5975</cell><cell>0.3273</cell></row><row><cell>DutirRun3</cell><cell>0.5053</cell><cell>0.5825</cell><cell>0.3227</cell></row><row><cell>DutirRun4</cell><cell>0.5035</cell><cell>0.5825</cell><cell>0.3257</cell></row><row><cell>DutirRun5</cell><cell>0.5108</cell><cell>0.5750</cell><cell>0.3250</cell></row><row><cell>Median</cell><cell>0.4559</cell><cell>0.5450</cell><cell>0.2806</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="8,90.02,301.58,415.32,232.40"><head>Table 3 . Results for Clinical Trials Subtask</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="8,90.02,333.04,415.32,200.94"><row><cell></cell><cell>InfNDCG</cell><cell>P10</cell><cell>R-Prec</cell></row><row><cell>Dutir_Cli1</cell><cell>0.5022</cell><cell>0.4579</cell><cell>0.3453</cell></row><row><cell>Dutir_Cli2</cell><cell>0.5038</cell><cell>0.4553</cell><cell>0.3420</cell></row><row><cell>Median</cell><cell>0.5136</cell><cell>0.4657</cell><cell>0.3477</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Our results for clinical trials subtask are not satisfactory, so we can</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">interface that retrieving relevant documents only with Elasticsearch was</cell></row><row><cell>not a good method.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,96.98,747.01,134.43,9.38"><p>http://www.trec-cds.org/2019.html</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,96.98,759.25,185.91,9.38"><p>https://www.elastic.co/cn/products/elasticsearch</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>ACKNOWLEGEMENTS</head><p>This work was supported by the grant from the <rs type="funder">National Key Research and Development Program of China</rs> (No. <rs type="grantNumber">2016YFC0901902</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_xAhqnXa">
					<idno type="grant-number">2016YFC0901902</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="9,111.26,394.96,394.16,12.76;9,90.02,426.16,415.15,12.76;9,90.02,457.38,415.44,12.76;9,90.02,488.58,105.92,12.76" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,90.02,457.38,341.02,12.76">Overview of the TREC 2017 precision medicine track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Kirk</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Dina</forename><surname>Demner-Fushman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ellen</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>William R Hersh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bedrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Shubham</forename><surname>Lazar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Pant</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,466.18,457.38,31.43,12.76">TREC</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,110.90,519.78,394.16,12.76;9,90.02,550.98,198.58,12.76" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,228.46,519.78,276.60,12.76;9,90.02,550.98,26.30,12.76">Overview of the TREC 2018 precision medicine track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Kirk</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,140.06,550.98,31.43,12.76">TREC</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,109.58,582.18,395.66,12.76;9,90.02,613.38,415.17,12.76;9,90.02,644.61,259.57,12.76" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,249.65,613.38,255.54,12.76;9,90.02,644.61,37.39,12.76">The Comparative Toxicogenomics Database: update</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Grondin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sciaky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Mcmorran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wiegers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wiegers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mattingly</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,165.91,644.61,100.62,12.76">Nucleic Acids Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-09-24">2019. 2018 Sep 24</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,112.46,675.81,393.90,12.76;9,90.02,707.01,414.93,12.76;9,90.02,738.21,190.90,12.76" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,253.32,675.81,253.04,12.76;9,90.02,707.01,374.11,12.76">A sensitivity analysis of (and practitioners&apos; guide to) convolutional neural networks for sentence classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Wallace</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1510.03820</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,113.18,82.93,391.92,12.76;10,90.02,114.13,415.42,12.76" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,324.54,82.93,180.57,12.76;10,90.02,114.13,170.48,12.76">Recurrent convolutional neural networks for text classification</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="10,286.96,114.13,30.74,12.76">AAAI</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">333</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2267" to="2273" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,109.94,145.33,395.46,12.76;10,90.02,176.53,415.12,12.76;10,90.02,207.73,352.02,12.76" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,253.18,145.33,252.22,12.76;10,90.02,176.53,50.92,12.76">A deep relevance matching model for ad-hoc retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Fan</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Ai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Q</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,169.23,176.53,335.91,12.76;10,90.02,207.73,231.74,12.76">Proceedings of the 25th ACM International on Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</title>
		<meeting>the 25th ACM International on Conference on Information and Knowledge Management</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="64" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,110.42,238.93,395.00,12.76;10,90.02,270.16,246.12,12.76" xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="10,311.80,238.93,193.63,12.76;10,90.02,270.16,187.15,12.76">PACRR: A Position-Aware Neural IR Model for Relevance Matching</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Yates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Berberich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
