<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,194.90,146.10,213.30,18.75;1,170.40,163.50,254.51,18.75;1,211.40,184.70,172.58,14.06">Detailed Comparison Module In CoReMo 1.9 Plagiarism Detector Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2012</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,186.60,225.07,116.58,9.00"><forename type="first">Diego</forename><forename type="middle">A Rodríguez</forename><surname>Torrejón</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Huelva</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,309.92,225.07,50.24,9.00"><forename type="first">José</forename><surname>Manuel</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Huelva</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,362.58,225.07,57.44,9.00"><forename type="first">Martín</forename><surname>Ramos</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Huelva</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,194.90,146.10,213.30,18.75;1,170.40,163.50,254.51,18.75;1,211.40,184.70,172.58,14.06">Detailed Comparison Module In CoReMo 1.9 Plagiarism Detector Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2012</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">BB30BD99D0751E8DA506E53DC68497A3</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:30+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the process and basics of the Detailed Comparison Module into the CoReMo 1.9 Plagiarism Detector, which has got a highlighted mention in the PAN2012 edition due to its running speed (at least 10 times faster than any other competitor) achieving very good detections. Its high detection efficacy is due to the special features of the contextual and surrounding context n-grams, which working together, increase the opportunity to match, especially when translations or paraphrases happen, but keeping a highly discriminative feature that simplifies the accurate location for plagiarized sections. The independence of external translation systems coupled to its optimized process by high performance C/C++ programming techniques, have yielded its high speed even when it isn't yet multi-core systems optimized.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="842.0" lry="595.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Plagiarism Detection is one of the fields that are awakening interest in the areas of Natural Language Processing and Information Retrieval. The various PAN <ref type="foot" coords="1,432.90,493.64,2.90,5.22" target="#foot_0">1</ref> editions are continuously promoting the improvement of existing techniques, compiling corpus with cases more realistic and difficult to detect, and developing systems, work plans and tasks to design and analyze the individual impact of proposals for the different subtasks about the performance obtained, the necessary hardware resources and time spent, thus facilitating the subsequent combination and improvement proposals in search of the ultimate plagiarism detector. CoReMo <ref type="bibr" coords="1,401.99,565.87,10.64,9.00" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" coords="1,420.56,565.87,10.57,9.00" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" coords="1,439.14,565.87,11.63,9.00" target="#b2">[3]</ref> is a Plagiarism Detection System that was initially designed for participation in PAN issues, obtaining very acceptable performance results, but highlighted for hardware requirements and processing speed (one of the main goals for its developers), which this year has had the opportunity to demonstrate. However, CoReMo uses pruning techniques to avoid the comparison of the suspicious document with any source document if not detected evidence of plagiarism by its High Precision Information Retrieval System (HAIRS) and the Reference Monotony Pruning strategy (RM) delimiting the suspected plagiarized section before making any comparisons with the suspicious document. Therefore, CoReMo did not performed exhaustive documents pair comparisons until the proposal for this PAN issue, forcing to change the design to meet the characteristics of the new edition, which seeks comprehensive comparison for pairs of documents. However, this is not the only new feature included in this CoReMo release, as the detection capability, when compared to the previous edition, was greatly improved by extending the n-grams model used (Contextual N-grams CTnG) to Surrounding Context N-grams (SCnG) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,325.48,222.17,11.63,9.00" target="#b3">[4]</ref> and the use of a post-processing to join closed detections (Granularity Filter).</p><p>The new Detailed Comparison capability design was arranged looking for the maximal computational efficiency, usual in former CoReMo versions, by using maximal efficiency programming techniques for the the new task algorithms.</p><p>Furthermore, it was found that earlier CoReMo versions generated the XML detection files delimiting the offset and length of detections by bytes instead of UTF8 characters, which caused discrepancies between the detection and annotation used in the gold standard corpus, which negatively affected the evaluation, up to 10%. This new version allows detections annotation by either Byte (faster) or UTF8 modes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Surrounding Context N-grams</head><p>One of the most important innovations in CoReMo as regards last year's version is that the documents are modeled by an extended concept of former Contextual N-grams <ref type="bibr" coords="2,165.79,422.37,8.01,9.00" target="#b0">[1]</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,177.80,422.37,8.01,9.00" target="#b1">[2]</ref> (CTnG: case folding, stopwords and short length words removal, stemming and internal sort of n-gram components) to the Surrounding Context N-grams (SCnG) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,200.08,446.47,10.58,9.00" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, which in addition to the former, triple them by including a special type of skip n-grams obtained by excluding the second or the last but one from a group of n+1 relevant terms previous to all the previously explained for CTnG process.</p><p>For instance, modeling "The quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog" to SC3G: The use of SCnG finally gets 3 times as many n-grams than only using CTnG, and it supposes more possibilities to tackle obfuscation cases with almost the same practical high precision in the process. The biggest number of terms obtained acts as a magnifier effect in the analysis. The memory requirements are obviously tripled and processing time almost doubled, but it improves dramatically the performance. Including these skip n-grams almost doesn't decrease the precision. An n-gram frequency study on PAN-PC-2009/2010 (table <ref type="table" coords="3,328.81,222.17,4.17,9.00" target="#tab_1">1</ref>) / 2011 corpora <ref type="bibr" coords="3,412.82,222.17,11.63,9.00" target="#b4">[5]</ref> shows its exclusivity ratio almost unaltered. All n-grams are compared without a difference in the way they are created. The SCnG are especially useful to improve the CTnG effectiveness when words changes (synonyms, negated antonyms, given names, translation or orthographic errors, characters changed by other UTF code having the same aspect, ...), new word insertions (enriched sentences) or removal (summarized sentences). The sentence reordering due to translation or changing from passive to active forms or vice versa are also supported.</p><p>This way gets more matching, especially for paraphrased or translated cases, to identify a possible plagiarism (almost as when using lower grade n-grams, but with higher precision disambiguation instead). However, it gets more unconnected short detections which require to be joined. A distance joining step, named Granularity Filter (GF) gets improved scores. Both SCnG and GF modes combined achieves about 45% best Plagdet score than when using direct CTnG mode. In order to facilitate the CTnGs or SCnGs location, its modeling includes offset and length recording. The benefit of using this extended n-gram modeling compared to the former, based only in Contextual N-grams was shown in <ref type="bibr" coords="4,389.38,210.07,10.64,9.00" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, improving the performance in a former CoReMo version, as can be seen in fig. <ref type="figure" coords="4,383.11,222.17,5.00,9.00">1</ref> and fig. <ref type="figure" coords="4,423.69,222.17,3.75,9.00">2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Detailed Comparison</head><p>As by using the extended SCnG n-gram model, the matching is highly discriminative and more frequent, it's possible to get enough matching n-grams with very low noise, making the comparison tasks easier. For this detailed pair comparison task, alphabetically ordered versions of both SCnG modeled documents, with inner matching annotations and linking, are compared in the way of a modified "mergesort" <ref type="bibr" coords="4,124.90,350.07,11.63,9.00" target="#b5">[6]</ref> algorithm to speed up the job, linking every SCnG to an of external matching list.</p><p>Minimum length and maximum distances between matches (for same detection) are adjusted, on bases of document length, number of n-grams and user settings for minimal monotony and n-grams chunk length (the basics classical adjustments in CoReMo), which differ for crosslingual and monolingual comparison.</p><p>The distances are n-grams for suspicious documents and characters for the sources:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="4,130.50,434.60,319.23,32.00">maxNgramDist = 2 •chunkLength (1) maxCharDist = chunkLength•wordLengthAverage (2)</formula><p>minNgramLength = (monotony-1. 5)•chunkLength</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="4,130.50,474.67,319.23,30.92">(3) minCharLenght = minNgramLength•wordLengthAverage (4)</formula><p>The reliability of the matching n-grams is pondered by its inner matching frequency in both suspicious and source documents, to determine or reject the detected continuous matching sections and to create preliminary XML documents (direct detection). After the end of a detection, a roll-back to the next n-gram happens starting the next possible detection (have in mind that a detection finishes when no new reliable match has been found after several n-grams).</p><p>The direct detections are post-processed by the Granularity Filter to join simultaneously nearby detections in both suspicious and source sections, getting final XML detection documents. Both XML documents could be combined to create a best comparison readable HTML color document to emphasize direct detections within the final zones.</p><p>The use of external translation systems (as i.e. Google Translator<ref type="foot" coords="5,390.40,179.54,2.90,5.22" target="#foot_1">2</ref> ) is a drawback for low response timing, availability and economy goals. Because of that, CoReMo performs its own translations locally when it detects a non English language document. The crosslingual analysis is locally arranged after a direct mapping from every non English word (or its stem) to its translated English stemmed word, using two special dictionaries <ref type="bibr" coords="5,229.05,239.77,11.17,9.00" target="#b2">[3]</ref>[7]: direct2stem (first chance) and stem2stem (second chance, when it first fails). If no logical translation is found, then the non-English word is replaced by its English stem.</p><p>For every new English n-gram, the original offset and length are registered from the non-English document to get an easy and precise source plagiarized sections location.</p><p>When using the crosslingual training subcorpus, the Plagdet score achieved by CoReMo was 0.70176: good results having in mind that they are not being biased by the same Google Translator process in both (obfuscation and detection) phases. The lower results obtained in the test phase (0.2577) are due to the fact that only human translated simulated cases were then used. It is in the expected line after last year's report <ref type="bibr" coords="5,151.87,372.27,10.58,9.00" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. The CoReMo mapped translation process is however in its childhood, and it is expected to be improved in newer versions by several modifications and using better crosslingual stem dictionaries versions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Speed up Methodology</head><p>As one of the main goals for CoReMo is the high speed to obtain reliable detection results, the execution environment and the programming techniques focused on getting a maximal computational efficiency were used from the early design:</p><p>• C++ 64 bits programming • GNU Linux 64bits OS and ext4 file system platform.</p><p>• Internal sort of n-grams is made by bubble sort algorithm.</p><p>• Quick sort algorithm is used to order n-grams into the modeled document.</p><p>• N-gram comparison between both documents is arranged by a modified mergesort algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="5,177.56,564.47,11.72,9.00" target="#b5">[6]</ref> • Local translation when cross-lingual comparisons happens.</p><p>• When comparing pairs list, ordered by suspicious documents (the most usual case after locating source documents candidates), it is taken the advantage of n-grams modeling and inner matching frequency in the suspicious document for consecutive comparisons. It enabled to achieve an average analysis time of 0.19 seconds per pair: 13.6 times faster than the second fastest algorithm, and 31 times faster than the winner one. However, for this version none optimization was arranged to take advantage of multicore features of current processors, but it's expected to be included in the next version.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Tuning Parameters and Evaluation</head><p>The best parameters settings were obtained by using the PAN-PC-2012 training corpus. The results of the training (plagdet 0.6754) are displayed and compared to the ones achieved in the phase of competition (0,6252) in table 2. For both cases, these parameters were:</p><p>• chunk length: 4 n-grams (internally changes to 12 itself when using SCnGs).</p><p>• Cross-lingual chunk length: 47 n-grams (also 3 times bigger when using SCnGs).</p><p>• minimum monotony: 2 chunks (same for monolingual and crosslingual modes).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>Nowadays CoReMo is the fastest detector, but it should be optimized to take the opportunity of multi-core systems advantage.</p><p>The translated subcorpus analysis achieved better results than last year's (comparing human translation only) due to the newest n-gram modeling, but it is still using the same old dictionaries, and only about 50% of the words are translated. Larger and better dictionaries <ref type="bibr" coords="6,254.45,432.27,11.72,9.00" target="#b6">[7]</ref> would benefit this local technique. Other local translation methods could be explored.</p><p>Mixing this n-gram modeling with other NLP resources (WordNet synsets, odd/even skip n-grams, ...) could improve detections when hard obfuscation conditions happen.</p><p>The detailed comparison method got better Plagdet performance for the same corpus than the former method used in CoReMo. This suggests a new change for the traditional full process for local source collections.</p><p>The comparison of the Plagdet progress regarding the PAN2011 must be done with caution, since not being necessary prior source document detection, by using a LEAP 3 detector, could directly get reasonable results, as shown in [8] for the former Intrinsic Detection task.   </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="7,59.60,94.15,290.12,8.10;7,61.80,105.55,251.48,8.10"><head>Fig. 1 .Fig. 2 .</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Fig.1. Plagdet/chunk_length comparative of CoReMo 1.6 using CT3N or SC3N w/wo Granularity Filter on PAN-PC-2011 only English subcorpus<ref type="bibr" coords="7,302.78,105.55,10.49,8.10" target="#b3">[4]</ref> </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,124.90,258.35,337.92,295.12"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>n-gram frequency study on PAN-PC-2010 only english source documents subcorpus</figDesc><table coords="3,132.80,280.47,308.70,273.00"><row><cell>idf</cell><cell>n-grams quantity</cell><cell>ratio</cell><cell>n-grams quantity</cell><cell>ratio</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>CT3N only</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">CT3N + SC3N</cell></row><row><cell>--</cell><cell>105692331</cell><cell>1.0000</cell><cell>300970577</cell><cell>1.0000</cell></row><row><cell>01</cell><cell>97978896</cell><cell>0.9270</cell><cell>273382406</cell><cell>0.9083</cell></row><row><cell>02</cell><cell>5118576</cell><cell>0.0484</cell><cell>17527916</cell><cell>0.0582</cell></row><row><cell>03</cell><cell>1290009</cell><cell>0.0122</cell><cell>4809681</cell><cell>0.0160</cell></row><row><cell>04</cell><cell>517621</cell><cell>0.0049</cell><cell>2016842</cell><cell>0.0067</cell></row><row><cell>05</cell><cell>260442</cell><cell>0.0025</cell><cell>1042349</cell><cell>0.0035</cell></row><row><cell>06</cell><cell>148766</cell><cell>0.0014</cell><cell>609152</cell><cell>0.0020</cell></row><row><cell>...</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>95</cell><cell>24</cell><cell>0.0000</cell><cell>115</cell><cell>0.0000</cell></row><row><cell>96</cell><cell>23</cell><cell>0.0000</cell><cell>129</cell><cell>0.0000</cell></row><row><cell>97</cell><cell>25</cell><cell>0.0000</cell><cell>97</cell><cell>0.0000</cell></row><row><cell>98</cell><cell>35</cell><cell>0.0000</cell><cell>105</cell><cell>0.0000</cell></row><row><cell>99</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>0.0000</cell><cell>106</cell><cell>0.0000</cell></row><row><cell>&gt; 99</cell><cell>1010</cell><cell>0.0000</cell><cell>3666</cell><cell>0.0000</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="7,56.80,329.55,721.30,193.42"><head>Table 2 . CoReMo 1.9UTF achieved scores in training and competition phases with same tuned parameters: chunklength = 4 and monotony = 2 PAN-PC-2012 Training Corpus PAN-PC-2012 Competition Corpus Plagdet Recall Precision Granularity Plagdet Recall Precision Granularity Avg. time (s)</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="7,59.60,390.77,718.50,132.20"><row><cell>No plagiarism</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>0.16112</cell></row><row><cell>No obfuscation</cell><cell>0.87187735</cell><cell>0.82362082</cell><cell>0.92744216</cell><cell>1.0009165</cell><cell>0.93247701</cell><cell>0.96882651</cell><cell>0.89875647</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>0.15786</cell></row><row><cell>Artificial Low</cell><cell>0.77468919</cell><cell>0.73718058</cell><cell>0.81621938</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>0.71393468</cell><cell>0.59334680</cell><cell>0.89603990</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>0.15278</cell></row><row><cell>Artificial High</cell><cell>0.33936519</cell><cell>0.21152910</cell><cell>0.85772527</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>0.12760741</cell><cell>0.06961406</cell><cell>0.76443402</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>0.14492</cell></row><row><cell>Translation</cell><cell>0.70176951</cell><cell>0.59298909</cell><cell>0.85942631</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>0.25774484</cell><cell>0.14825321</cell><cell>0.98580851</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>0.09754</cell></row><row><cell>Human simulated</cell><cell>0.68898017</cell><cell>0.53438117</cell><cell>0.96944527</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>0.67366948</cell><cell>0.57757699</cell><cell>0.81161164</cell><cell>1.0024937</cell><cell>0.43346</cell></row><row><cell>Real cases</cell><cell>---</cell><cell>---</cell><cell>---</cell><cell>---</cell><cell>0.74061972</cell><cell>0.66846300</cell><cell>0.83023925</cell><cell>1.0</cell><cell>0.08212</cell></row><row><cell>Global</cell><cell>0.67536855</cell><cell>0.55155054</cell><cell>0.87106899</cell><cell>1.00012215</cell><cell>0.62520246</cell><cell>0.50042086</cell><cell>0.83442275</cell><cell>1.0009596</cell><cell>0.19009</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,133.40,685.85,68.49,8.10"><p>http://pan.webis.de</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="5,133.40,685.85,96.39,8.10"><p>http://translate.google.com</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>Acknowledgments. To the PAN team, as their development aids, hard job and encourage have been crucial for our work, and to all the PAN competitors teams, as their effort and papers has always been for us a motivational challenge and a source of new ideas to improve our detection system.</p></div>
			</div>			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="8,146.28,228.05,323.91,8.10;8,160.90,238.95,309.39,8.10;8,160.90,249.75,309.44,8.10;8,160.90,260.65,309.31,8.10;8,160.90,271.45,128.88,8.10" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,367.61,228.05,102.57,8.10;8,160.90,238.95,309.39,8.10;8,160.90,249.75,309.44,8.10;8,160.90,260.65,249.40,8.10">Detección de plagio en documentos: sistema externo monolingüe de altas prestaciones basado en n-gramas contextuales&quot; (Plagiarism Detection in Documents: High Performance Monolingual External Plagiarism Detector System Based on Contextual N-grams)</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rodríguez-Torrejón</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Martín-Ramos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,417.22,260.65,52.99,8.10;8,160.90,271.45,89.20,8.10">Procesamiento del Lenguaje Natural. N</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,146.28,282.35,324.15,8.10;8,160.90,293.15,309.50,8.10;8,160.90,304.05,309.72,8.10;8,160.90,314.85,309.51,8.10;8,160.90,325.75,67.73,8.10" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,353.46,282.35,116.96,8.10;8,160.90,293.15,309.50,8.10;8,160.90,304.05,140.60,8.10">CoReMo System (Contextual Reference Monotony) A Fast, Low Cost and High Performance Plagiarism Analyzer System: Lab Report for PAN at CLEF</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rodríguez-Torrejón</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Martín-Ramos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,191.27,314.85,205.77,8.10">Notebook Papers of CLEF 2010 LABs and Workshops</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Braschler</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Harman</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Pianta</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Padua, Italy</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-09-23">2010. 22-23 September. 2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,146.28,336.55,324.28,8.10;8,160.90,347.45,153.18,8.10" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,351.38,336.55,119.18,8.10;8,160.90,347.45,101.46,8.10">Crosslingual CoReMo System: Notebook for PAN at CLEF</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rodríguez-Torrejón</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Martín-Ramos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,146.28,358.25,324.08,8.10;8,160.90,369.15,309.27,8.10;8,160.90,379.95,105.66,8.10" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,339.98,358.25,130.37,8.10;8,160.90,369.15,309.27,8.10;8,160.90,379.95,74.88,8.10">N-gramas de contexto cercano para mejorar la detección de plagio (Surrounding Context N-grams to Improve the Plagiarism Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rodríguez-Torrejón</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Martín-Ramos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,146.28,390.85,324.27,8.10;8,160.90,401.65,309.51,8.10;8,160.90,412.55,309.68,8.10;8,160.90,423.35,97.96,8.10" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,459.55,390.85,11.00,8.10;8,160.90,401.65,172.94,8.10">An Evaluation Framework for Plagiarism Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alberto</forename><surname>Barrón-Cedeño</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,349.98,401.65,120.43,8.10;8,160.90,412.55,169.27,8.10">23rd International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING 10)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computational Linguistics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010-08">August 2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,146.28,434.25,324.32,8.10;8,160.90,445.05,309.80,8.10;8,160.90,455.95,309.74,8.10;8,160.90,466.75,159.23,8.10" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,160.90,445.05,295.97,8.10">A Plagiarism Detection Procedure in Three Steps: Selection, Matches and Squares</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Chiara</forename><surname>Basile</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Dario</forename><surname>Benedetto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Giampaolo</forename><surname>Caglioti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mirko</forename><surname>Degli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Esposti</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,160.90,455.95,309.74,8.10;8,160.90,466.75,63.49,8.10">SEPLN 2009 Workshop on Uncovering Plagiarism, Authorship, and Social Software Misuse (PAN 09)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009. 2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,146.28,477.65,324.10,8.10;8,160.90,488.45,309.38,8.10;8,160.90,499.35,289.16,8.10" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,205.73,488.45,264.56,8.10;8,160.90,499.35,39.04,8.10">Influencia del diccionario en la traducción para la detección de plagio translingüe</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rodríguez-Torrejón</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Barrón-Cedeño</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sidorov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Martín-Ramos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,213.15,499.35,210.47,8.10">Dictionary Influence in Crosslingual Plagiarism Detection)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">11</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,146.28,510.15,323.96,8.10;8,160.90,521.05,309.29,8.10;8,160.90,531.85,209.67,8.10" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,354.00,510.15,116.24,8.10;8,160.90,521.05,265.64,8.10">LEAP: una referencia para la evaluación de sistemas de detección de plagio con enfoque intrínseco</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rodríguez-Torrejón</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Martín-Ramos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,438.88,521.05,31.32,8.10;8,160.90,531.85,186.66,8.10">LEAP: a Baseline for Intrinsic Focusing Plagiarism Detectors</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,146.28,542.75,324.12,8.10;8,160.90,553.55,211.64,8.10" xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,396.45,542.75,73.94,8.10;8,160.90,553.55,180.90,8.10">Overview of the 3rd International Competition on Plagiarism Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Eiselt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Barrón-Cedeño</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,150.40,564.45,319.85,8.10;8,160.90,575.25,246.40,8.10" xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,310.10,564.45,160.15,8.10;8,160.90,575.25,38.83,8.10">Notebook Papers of CLEF 2011 Labs and Workshops</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vivien</forename><surname>Petras</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam, The Netherlands</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-09">September. 2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,150.40,586.15,319.76,8.10;8,160.90,596.95,242.68,8.10" xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://users.dsic.upv.es/grupos/nle/ceri/index.html" />
		<title level="m" coord="8,160.90,586.15,257.22,8.10">II Congreso Español de Recuperación de Información (CERI 2012)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Valencia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-06">June. 2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
