<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,89.29,84.74,404.20,15.42;1,89.29,106.66,371.01,15.42;1,89.29,128.58,78.59,15.43;1,89.29,150.91,231.52,11.96">Domain Context-centered Retrieval for the Content Selection task in the Simplification of Scientific Literature Notebook for the Simple Text Lab at CLEF 2023</title>
				<funder ref="#_zwTbua5">
					<orgName type="full">EU Horizon</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_W3SnGNS">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,89.29,176.82,84.99,11.96"><forename type="first">Óscar</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Mendoza</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Milano Bicocca</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,186.21,176.82,67.18,11.96"><forename type="first">Gabriella</forename><surname>Pasi</surname></persName>
							<email>gabriella.pasi@unimib.it</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Milano Bicocca</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,89.29,84.74,404.20,15.42;1,89.29,106.66,371.01,15.42;1,89.29,128.58,78.59,15.43;1,89.29,150.91,231.52,11.96">Domain Context-centered Retrieval for the Content Selection task in the Simplification of Scientific Literature Notebook for the Simple Text Lab at CLEF 2023</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">1613-0073</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">AC2229783F151B1988A163FA4B47B1AB</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T16:32+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Retrieval</term>
					<term>Topic analysis</term>
					<term>Information gathering</term>
					<term>Document classification</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The DoSSIER team from the University of Milano Bicocca participated in the Simple Text lab from Clef 2023. We focus on analysing the distribution of topics (or themes) for the content selection task and its potential effects in retrieval. We introduce Domain-knowledge through an ontology with different classification algorithms for annotating documents. This allows us to study the diversity in retrieval results and show how constraining them positively impacts the information-gathering task. We constrain results to concentrate them to specific sets of themes built using pseudo-relevance feedback.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>The DoSSIER team from the University of Milano Bicocca participated in the Simple Text lab of Clef 2023. The lab develops around promoting scientific information access through retrieval, mining, and simplification of scientific literature <ref type="bibr" coords="1,305.25,426.61,11.35,10.91" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. We focus on analysing the distribution of topics in the collection for the content selection retrieval task.</p><p>In practical terms, the task has been defined as retrieving all passages from a large corpus of scientific abstracts and bibliographic metadata relevant to given topics <ref type="bibr" coords="1,406.34,467.25,11.45,10.91" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Relevant abstracts should be related to specific themes of the topics. Since this task deals with scientific literature, the retrieved passages are likely to be complex and may require further simplification, covered in the other instances of the Simple Text lab.</p><p>The topics for this task are a selection of press articles from a major international newspaper for a general audience and from Tech Xplore. Queries are keyword-based, manually extracted from topics based on the fact they allow retrieving some relevant passages from the given collection that could be inserted as citations in the press article.</p><p>This task has relevant nuances that we take into account. Based on the previous motivation, queries are given under an informational intent <ref type="bibr" coords="1,313.51,589.20,11.58,10.91" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, i.e., by submitting them to the search system, we want to obtain some related information which is assumed to be available in the collection. Additionally, we aim to solve a task of information gathering, which involves collecting information from multiple sources <ref type="bibr" coords="2,291.37,100.52,11.43,10.91" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p><p>The task also exhibits domain-specific properties, it gives the opportunity to explore domainbased information sources. In particular, domain-specific knowledge is often encoded in ontologies that can be used for document annotation and, in the context of search, it has the potential to constrain the information space to find relevant documents more effectively than in open-domain applications.</p><p>Because of the nature of the task, we focus on broadly analyzing document themes. We introduce contextual knowledge to the task through a large-scale ontology of research topics. This allows us to have feedback on how the information available, and presented as an answer to a query, distributes according to the themes, and then to constrain the results based on these distributions. We specifically investigate the following research questions: RQ1 How a collection of abstracts responds to specific information needs for the content selection task? RQ2 To what extent can the topic the analysis enhance retrieval for the content selection task? RQ3 Can the constraining of topics influence the performance of the retrieval system?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Materials and Methods</head><p>This section describes the methods used to perform our experiments. It mainly consists of a probabilistic lexical ranking, hierarchical document classification, and pseudo-relevance feedback (PRF).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Ad-hoc Retrieval</head><p>In order to study how the information from the collection can meet the information needs, we first retrieved the documents following a probabilistic lexical ranking stage. We retrieve a number of documents from the collection using the given queries. Each set of retrieved documents allows us to study the distribution of topics that the collection gathers, and specifically those that are selected as a response to a given query. To offer a description of our approach, we will use two queries from the given set: "Digital assistance" corresponding to the topic titled "Digital assistants like Siri and Alexa entrench gender biases says UN ", and "privacy" corresponding to the topic titled "Apple contractors 'regularly hear confidential details' on Siri recordings. "</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Hierarchical Classification</head><p>We incorporate domain knowledge through a large-scale ontology and use it for representing the retrieved documents and for studying the themes they are centered on.</p><p>On the one hand, we use the classifier proposed by <ref type="bibr" coords="2,325.53,611.99,11.28,10.91" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, which uses lexical matching between terms in the candidate documents and the ontology, and trained static embeddings to infer semantically related topics from terms identified as informative, using part-of-speech tagging. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,120.62,652.64,5.12,10.91" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows the frequency of themes given a set of retrieved documents with the example queries mentioned previously. We can observe, for instance, that the query "privacy" matches documents mostly about "personal digital assistants, " which is a potential keyword-based query for searching within the collection.</p><p>On the other hand, we train a sequence-to-sequence model <ref type="bibr" coords="3,364.88,365.64,12.82,10.91" target="#b5">[6]</ref> to generate themes from the ontology in a weakly supervised fashion and then use beam search to generate multiple themes so that we can consider the distribution themes described above. We use the score assigned by the decoding algorithm to the generated themes to display how likely a retrieved document will be assigned to a specific set of themes. In our case study, Figures <ref type="figure" coords="3,397.02,419.83,5.05,10.91" target="#fig_1">2</ref> and<ref type="figure" coords="3,423.85,419.83,5.05,10.91" target="#fig_2">3</ref> are heatmaps for the topic distribution of the first 30 ranked documents retrieved using the examples queries (each row then shows how likely each document is to be annotated with a theme). These two examples show the contrast of possible results the collection can offer to specific queries.</p><p>We aim to analyze the distribution of themes the collection can provide for a given query and study the effect of tailoring the search results according to specific patterns. Being able to assign granular topics to the documents, we exploit this tool in further steps.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.">Contextual PRF and Content Selection</head><p>The distribution and the probabilities of themes for the retrieved documents could benefit the content selection process. From the retrieval side, we try a simple instance for exploiting this information. Specifically, given the distribution of topics from the candidates, we first use the most frequent topics to expand the queries. Such that. e.g., "digital assistance" is extended by "personal digital assistants" and "privacy" is extended by "individual privacy. " This is an instance of PRF, which traditionally aims to leverage the most relevant documents retrieved by the initial query to improve the subsequent query. Here the difference is that we do not use the documents directly but their themes.</p><p>Furthermore, we use the distribution of topics to re-rank the documents and select specific  sentences from each document based on the diversity of the themes. We hypothesize that establishing relevant themes, i.e., the most frequent among the candidates retrieved by the search system, the task of content selection could benefit from trimming down to a more focused or concentrated set of documents. Thus, we penalize documents based on the diversity of themes they exhibit and re-rank them based on the same criterion. We can see how documents are relatively diverse by looking at the different distributions, such as those described for the example queries. They are ranked around a specific keyword but still exhibit diversity that does not necessarily help to achieve the task of gathering supporting content. Considering this, we then look at themes at a different level of granularity of the retrieved documents to decide whether specific snippets are even more concentrated in the relevant themes.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,132.67,481.51,5.17,10.91" target="#fig_3">4</ref> shows examples of content selection based on the diversity of themes. For the example queries, we infer the topics highlighted are relevant from its themes distribution feedback. Ideally, the selected content should focus on those topics since dispersed content does not show a clear importance to the task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Experiments and Results</head><p>In this section, we present the results of the experiments described previously. We are mainly interested in analyzing the distribution of themes in the collection, and in understanding retrieval results and how to make them useful for the aim of content selection for simplification rather than focusing on retrieval performance. However, state-of-the-art retrieval models still rely on ad-hoc retrieval models to limit the number of documents to be processed in later stages (pipeline-based models). Thus, it makes sense to study the appropriateness of the set of documents retrieved first to be processed and re-ranked in the later stages.  We use BM25 for retrieval, the CS ontology as domain knowledge, and the different strategies described in section 2.2 for classification.</p><p>We analyze retrieved sets of documents in terms of diversity of themes and entropy of their distribution. Intuitively, a higher entropy, which directly indicates more uncertain, implies a wider range of possible themes <ref type="bibr" coords="5,229.54,550.74,11.40,10.91" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. From the size of the ontology, we derived that the entropy of the distribution of themes in the collection is around 13. We limit the experiments to the top 200 retrieved documents, and the average entropy of the distribution of themes is 6.83 on these sets.</p><p>As discussed before, in general, we are interested in concentrated results, implying lower entropy values and lower diversity.</p><p>Identifying the relevant themes seems to have a positive effect. There is a clear difference between retrieving documents with the original queries (Retrieval in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,434.30,645.58,4.25,10.91" target="#tab_3">1</ref>) and using extensions from relevant themes (PRF in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,290.72,659.13,3.61,10.91" target="#tab_3">1</ref>). On average, documents are annotated with 8</p><p>Candidate: Mobile devices are significantly changing the humancomputer interaction. In particular, the ubiquitous access to remote resources is one of the most interesting characteristics achievable by using mobile devices such as Personal Digital Assistants, cellular phones and tablets. This paper presents an architecture that allows users to search and visualize complex 3D models over Personal Digital Assistants. A peer-to-peer network of brokers manages queries for searching objects among several data providers. The object selected for visualization is forwarded to a specialized graphics provider; this   themes, so it is difficult to measure the effect of constraining the search based on diversity and we can perceive only slight change, but positive, when trying to constrain results by penalizing diversity on documents (re-ranking in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,288.37,534.91,3.57,10.91" target="#tab_3">1</ref>).</p><p>In terms of retrieval performance, Analyzing topics also exhibits a positive impact. Table <ref type="table" coords="6,500.87,548.46,5.12,10.91" target="#tab_4">2</ref> show the retrieval evaluation in terms of multiple metrics, including additional metrics regarding the content selection in terms of the length of the text and the readability (FKGL).  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Discussion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RQ1</head><p>The collection gathers a wide variety of topics. It is clear that for specific topics, retrieval can result in a very focused set of documents, which is the case exemplified in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,500.15,381.34,3.76,10.91" target="#fig_2">3</ref>. Whereas for other topics, the distribution does not exhibit a specific theme concentration (see Figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,166.51,408.44,3.52,10.91" target="#fig_1">2</ref>). We show a sample queries matching the themes found through the PRF. A qualitative evaluation shows that, in general, the feedback from the collection is closely related to the queries with some exceptions, such as "gene editing" and "healthcare" (see Table <ref type="table" coords="7,143.06,449.08,3.57,10.91" target="#tab_5">3</ref>), definitely out of the domain of the task. RQ2 Even though the results have the potential to be tailored to different information needs, documents gather a wide variety of topics individually, so a more granular evaluation should be performed to decide how to incorporate the information from the distribution of topics into the retrieval system, supporting the idea of sentence selection. RQ3 As we hypothesize, constraining topics can contribute to the performance of the retrieval system. Table <ref type="table" coords="7,180.02,530.41,5.07,10.91" target="#tab_4">2</ref> shows results on retrieval performance, and we can see how re-ranking based on the variability of themes improves the overall performance. To gain a deeper understanding and draw more concrete conclusions, it would be beneficial to conduct additional evaluations and analyses, considering various factors such as content selection, which has no clear effects on our current results, as well as alternative retrieval and re-ranking approaches, which we will consider in our future work.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,89.29,300.93,223.19,8.93"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Frequency of themes retrieved by the query.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,89.29,294.87,283.04,8.93;4,204.24,97.97,237.76,142.76"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Theme prediction scores for the query "personal assistant. "</figDesc><graphic coords="4,204.24,97.97,237.76,142.76" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="5,89.29,458.94,238.93,8.93;5,175.40,100.28,324.18,302.51"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Theme prediction scores for the query "privacy. "</figDesc><graphic coords="5,175.40,100.28,324.18,302.51" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="6,89.29,364.73,328.35,8.93"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Example of content selection at document level using theme diversity.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="6,131.25,82.57,333.03,269.10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Privacy awareness is a core determinant of the success or failure of privacy infrastructures: if systems and users are not aware of potential privacy concerns, they cannot effectively discover, use or judge the effectiveness of privacy management capabilities. Yet, privacy awareness is only implicitly described or implemented during the privacy engineering of software systems. In this paper, the author advocates a systematic approach to considering privacy awareness. He characterizes privacy awareness and illustrate its benefits to preserving privacy in a smart mobile environment. The author proposes privacy awareness requirements to anchor the consideration of privacy awareness needs of software systems...</figDesc><table coords="6,131.25,82.57,333.03,269.10"><row><cell>Topic: Digital assistants like Siri and Alexa entrench gender biases says UN</cell></row><row><cell>Query: Digital assistance</cell></row><row><cell>Personal Digital Assistants</cell></row><row><cell>Mobile Devices</cell></row><row><cell>Smart Phones</cell></row><row><cell>Cellular Phone</cell></row><row><cell>Human Computer Interaction</cell></row><row><cell>3d Modelling</cell></row><row><cell>Visualization</cell></row><row><cell>Personal Digital Assistants</cell></row><row><cell>Cell PhonePeer-To-Peer</cell></row><row><cell>Topic: Apple contractors 'regularly hear confidential details' on Siri recordings.</cell></row><row><cell>Query: Privacy</cell></row><row><cell>Candidate: Privacy Individual Privacy</cell></row><row><cell>Privacy Concerns</cell></row><row><cell>Privacy Management</cell></row><row><cell>Privacy And Security</cell></row><row><cell>Privacy</cell></row><row><cell>Individual Privacy</cell></row><row><cell>Mobile Environments</cell></row><row><cell>Software</cell></row><row><cell>Engineering</cell></row><row><cell>Software Systems</cell></row><row><cell>Selected content</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="6,88.99,397.88,315.94,85.98"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Theme concentration analysis.</figDesc><table coords="6,190.35,425.52,214.59,58.34"><row><cell>Experiment</cell><cell cols="2">Diversity</cell><cell cols="2">Entropy</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>@20</cell><cell>@50</cell><cell>@20</cell><cell>@50</cell></row><row><cell>Retrieval</cell><cell>0.4740</cell><cell>0.3222</cell><cell>5.0224</cell><cell>5.5152</cell></row><row><cell>PRF</cell><cell>0.4213</cell><cell>0.2812</cell><cell>4.7444</cell><cell>5.1556</cell></row><row><cell>Re-ranking</cell><cell cols="4">0.4145 0.2791 4.6496 5.0942</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="6,88.99,604.56,385.13,71.40"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Retrieval evaluation.</figDesc><table coords="6,121.16,629.98,352.97,45.98"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">MRR P@10 NDCG Bpref</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>Length FKGL</cell></row><row><cell>Retrieval</cell><cell>0.4536 0.1912 0.2192</cell><cell>0.1384</cell><cell>0.0515</cell></row><row><cell>Re-ranking</cell><cell>0.5201 0.2853 0.2980</cell><cell>0.1898</cell><cell cols="2">0.1141 1024.48 14.77</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Content-selection 0.5202 0.2853 0.2972</cell><cell>0.1873</cell><cell cols="2">0.1111 238.63</cell><cell>15.11</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="7,88.99,122.86,346.73,221.86"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Relevant Themes for a sample of queries.</figDesc><table coords="7,159.55,150.50,276.17,194.22"><row><cell>Query</cell><cell>Relevant themes</cell></row><row><cell>Digital assistant</cell><cell>personal digital assistants, handheld</cell></row><row><cell>Biases</cell><cell>correlation analysis, sensors</cell></row><row><cell>self driving</cell><cell>vehicles, autonomous driving</cell></row><row><cell>humanoid robots</cell><cell>robots, humanoid robot</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">online safety for children internet, education</cell></row><row><cell>cookies</cell><cell>privacy, web content</cell></row><row><cell>light positioning</cell><cell>positioning system, indoor positioning</cell></row><row><cell>intelligent parking</cell><cell>vehicles, sensors</cell></row><row><cell>emotional robot</cell><cell>robots, emotional expressions</cell></row><row><cell>empathy</cell><cell>emotional expressions, affective state</cell></row><row><cell>text classification</cell><cell>text classification, classification models</cell></row><row><cell>character relationship</cell><cell>character recognition, computer games</cell></row><row><cell>gene editing</cell><cell>http, database systems</cell></row><row><cell>conspiracy theories</cell><cell>signature scheme, facebook</cell></row><row><cell>healthcare</cell><cell>communication, information systems</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work was supported by the <rs type="funder">EU Horizon</rs> <rs type="projectName">2020 ITN/ETN on Domain Specific Systems for Information Extraction and Retrieval -DoSSIER</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">H2020-EU.1.3.1</rs>., ID: <rs type="grantNumber">860721</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_zwTbua5">
					<idno type="grant-number">H2020-EU.1.3.1</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">2020 ITN/ETN on Domain Specific Systems for Information Extraction and Retrieval -DoSSIER</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_W3SnGNS">
					<idno type="grant-number">860721</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="8,107.59,111.28,399.60,10.91;8,107.59,124.83,398.39,10.91;8,107.59,138.38,399.60,10.91;8,107.59,151.93,399.59,10.91;8,107.59,165.48,303.82,10.91" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,271.47,124.83,234.51,10.91;8,107.59,138.38,136.90,10.91">Overview of the clef 2022 simpletext lab: Automatic simplification of scientific texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ermakova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sanjuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Huet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ovchinnikova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Nurbakova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Araújo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hannachi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mathurin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bellot</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="8,266.90,138.38,240.29,10.91;8,107.59,151.93,354.73,10.91">Experimental IR Meets Multilinguality, Multimodality, and Interaction: 13th International Conference of the CLEF Association, CLEF 2022</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Bologna, Italy</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2022">September 5-8, 2022. 2022</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="470" to="494" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,107.59,179.03,399.68,10.91;8,107.59,192.57,223.66,10.91" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sanjuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Huet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Ermakova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="8,309.06,179.03,198.21,10.91;8,107.59,192.57,191.74,10.91">Overview of the clef 2022 simpletext task 1: Passage selection for a simplified summary</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,107.59,206.12,399.59,10.91;8,107.59,219.67,50.08,10.91" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,174.17,206.12,121.36,10.91">Query Intent Understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Dou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="101" />
			<pubPlace>Cham</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,107.59,233.22,400.24,10.91;8,107.59,246.77,398.40,10.91;8,107.26,260.32,73.41,10.91" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,270.53,233.22,237.29,10.91;8,107.59,246.77,57.33,10.91">A field study characterizing web-based informationseeking tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kellar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Watters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shepherd</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,173.02,246.77,320.11,10.91">Journal of the American Society for information science and technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="999" to="1018" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,107.59,273.87,398.60,10.91;8,107.59,287.42,398.40,10.91;8,107.26,300.97,53.12,10.91" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,263.08,273.87,243.11,10.91;8,107.59,287.42,212.33,10.91">Cso classifier 3.0: a scalable unsupervised method for classifying documents in terms of research topics</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Salatino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Osborne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Motta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,327.55,287.42,178.43,10.91">International Journal on Digital Libraries</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,107.59,314.52,399.60,10.91;8,107.20,328.07,275.03,10.91" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,262.40,314.52,239.79,10.91">Sequence to sequence learning with neural networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Vinyals</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Le</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,107.20,328.07,230.24,10.91">Advances in neural information processing systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,107.59,341.62,400.24,10.91;8,107.59,355.17,398.40,10.91;8,107.26,368.71,78.48,10.91" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,196.36,355.17,143.75,10.91">Sensing trending topics in twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Aiello</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Petkos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Corney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Papadopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Skraba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Göker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Kompatsiaris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Jaimes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,347.73,355.17,145.74,10.91">IEEE Transactions on multimedia</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1268" to="1282" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
