<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.00,77.76,165.19,14.99">CLEF2023&apos; SIMPLE TEXT</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,72.00,108.66,64.25,10.54"><forename type="first">Darko</forename><surname>Vujica</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Split</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ruđera Boškovića 31</addrLine>
									<postCode>21000</postCode>
									<settlement>Split</settlement>
									<country key="HR">Croatia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,145.85,108.66,64.98,10.54"><forename type="first">Iva</forename><surname>Čatipović</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Split</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Ruđera Boškovića 31</addrLine>
									<postCode>21000</postCode>
									<settlement>Split</settlement>
									<country key="HR">Croatia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,236.55,108.66,90.32,10.54"><forename type="first">Julia</forename><surname>Komorowska</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Gdansk</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Jana Bazynskiego 8</addrLine>
									<postCode>80-309</postCode>
									<settlement>Gdansk</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.00,77.76,165.19,14.99">CLEF2023&apos; SIMPLE TEXT</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">51B38E48D5D3A631242CF3AEA0ED39B1</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T16:33+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>GPT</term>
					<term>PKE</term>
					<term>Wiki</term>
					<term>SimpleT5</term>
					<term>CLEF 2023</term>
					<term>SimpleText</term>
					<term>text simplification</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Understanding scientific texts is crucial for success in education and beyond. However, individuals who lack expertise in a particular scientific field often encounter challenges in comprehending such documents. Scientific articles present difficulties due to their utilization of complex vocabulary, intricate language, and lengthy structures, making them inaccessible without prior knowledge. This working note presents the outcomes of SimpleText tasks 2 and 3, which involve the identification and explanation of difficult concepts, as well as the simplification of complex text passages. Various statistical and AI-based models were employed to tackle these tasks, and their performance was evaluated accordingly. Autoregressive Large Language Models (LLMs) were predominantly utilized to solve these challenges. For effective utilization of BLOOM and BLOOMZ, prompts with examples were employed, while GPT-3 demonstrated greater effectiveness with simple command prompts. In addition to LLMs, statistical and graph-based models were also incorporated into the approach.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="596.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="596.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="596.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="596.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="596.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="596.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="596.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Communicating complex concepts to a general audience and simplifying scientific texts are two challenges often faced in the realm of knowledge dissemination. Explaining difficult concepts in a way that is accessible and understandable to a non-expert audience requires careful consideration of language, context, and relatability. Meanwhile, simplifying scientific texts involves condensing intricate information without compromising accuracy or losing the essence of the content. In this context, leveraging tools such as GPT-3, PKE, and SimpleT5 can aid in the process by providing assistance in generating simplified versions of scientific texts. We will write about exploring strategies for identifying and explaining difficult concepts to a general audience and delves into the simplification of scientific texts, highlighting the potential of using these advanced tools in the pursuit of effective knowledge dissemination.</p><p>Task 2 of the SimpleText lab competition in CLEF 2023 focused on identifying difficult concepts, explaining them, and ranking them based on their level of difficulty. To assist us in this task, we have used GPT-3 and Wiki combined with PKE. On the other hand, Task 3 aimed to generate simplified versions of scientific texts. To accomplish this, we have used GPT-3 and SimpleT5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Approach</head><p>For complexity spotting, we utilized natural language processing techniques and machine learning models. We performed data preprocessing, including cleaning and tokenization. We employed term extraction methods like TF-IDF to identify important terms and assigned difficulty scores to rank them. For the identified difficult terms, we generated short explanations or definitions using rule-based techniques. Evaluation was conducted using term pooling and metrics such as accuracy and NDCG.</p><p>To simplify scientific text, we employed a combination of rule-based approaches and neural network models. Rule-based techniques were used to simplify sentence structures, replace complex terms, and simplify language. We also fine-tuned a neural network model, such as a pre-trained language model, on a large corpus of scientific and simplified text. Evaluation involved measures like SARI, ROUGE, compression ratios, and readability scores to assess the quality of simplifications.</p><p>GPT-3: GPT-3 is a powerful language model that I used to address the challenge of explaining difficult concepts and simplifying scientific texts. With GPT-3, I utilized its text generation capabilities by providing prompts and requesting simplified explanations or text versions suitable for a general audience. PKE (Python Keyphrase Extraction): PKE played a crucial role in the process of identifying key concepts and ideas within the complex texts. By applying PKE, I extracted keyphrases from the text, which helped to pinpoint the essential terms and concepts that required simplification or explanation.</p><p>Wiki: Wikipedia served as a valuable resource for obtaining additional information and context about the identified keyphrases and concepts. I cross-referenced the keyphrases with relevant articles on Wikipedia to gather insights, examples, and concise explanations that assisted in the simplification process.</p><p>SimpleT5: SimpleT5 is a pre-trained text-to-text transfer transformer that can be fine-tuned for specific tasks such as text simplification. To simplify scientific texts, I utilized SimpleT5 by fine-tuning it on a dataset of simplified scientific texts. This allowed me to create a specialized model that generated simplified versions of scientific content with a focus on clarity and readability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Results</head><p>Here is a part of the results we obtained by using GPT-3. (task 2 and 3) Sentence: In the modern era of automation and robotics, autonomous vehicles are currently the focus of academic and industrial research.</p><p>Simplified sentence: Autonomous vehicles are being researched. Autonomous means being self-governing or independent. In this context, autonomous vehicles are vehicles that operate without any human input. They are capable of sensing their environment and navigating on their own. Academic 1 Academic refers to the activities related to studying, teaching, and researching in institutions of higher education such as universities, colleges, and research institutes. Industrial 2 Industrial: relating to or concerned with the manufacturing and production of goods by machines, factories, and other large-scale methods.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table 1 Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Difficult term</head><note type="other">Difficulty</note><p>In Task 2, when comparing the performance of GPT-3 and the combination of Wiki/PKE, we observed the following results:</p><p>Sentence: With the ever increasing number of unmanned aerial vehicles getting involved in activities in the civilian and commercial domain, there is an increased need for autonomy in these systems too. Commercial Domain: The commercial domain, also known as the business domain, is a sector that covers the activities, strategies, and operations related to the production, distribution, and sale of goods and. Systems Automation</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="4,208.88,487.57,6.00,10.54">2</formula><p>Systems Automation is the use of technology and software to automate processes, tasks, and functions previously done manually. It can be used to increase efficiency, reduce costs, and improve accuracy.</p><p>We observed that GPT-3 excelled in identifying more difficult terms and providing detailed definitions. However, it did not perform as effectively in ranking the terms based on their level of difficulty.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Conclusions</head><p>The complexity spotting task aimed to identify and explain difficult concepts in scientific texts for a general audience. Our approach involved a combination of natural language processing techniques and machine learning models. By extracting important terms and assigning difficulty scores, we identified terms that required explanation and contextualization. Short explanations or definitions were generated for these difficult terms. Evaluation using term pooling and metrics helped assess the accuracy of our approach. This task plays a crucial role in enhancing the understanding of complex scientific texts and improving accessibility for a wider audience.</p><p>The text simplification task focused on generating simplified versions of scientific texts. Our approach employed both rule-based techniques and neural network models to simplify sentence structures, replace complex terms, and make the language more accessible. By fine-tuning a neural network model on a large corpus of scientific and simplified text, we aimed to preserve the core meaning while simplifying the language. Evaluation measures such as SARI, ROUGE, compression ratios, and readability scores helped assess the quality of the simplifications. This task contributes to bridging the gap between scientific knowledge and a general audience by making complex information more easily understandable.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Appendix</head><p>Here are GPT-3 prompts that we have used.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>GPT-3 prompt for finding difficult terms def findDifficultScientificTerms(input):</head><p>openai.api_key = "…" response = openai.Completion.create( model="text-davinci-003", prompt="Return a list of maximum 5 difficult scientific terms in the following sentence:\n\n"+input, temperature=0.7, max_tokens=40,</p><p>GPT-3 prompt for rating difficult terms def assign_score_for_difficult_term(sentence, term): import os import openai openai.api_key = …" response = openai.Completion.create( model="text-davinci-003", prompt="Given is the following sentence:\n"+sentence+'\nGiven is the following term in the sentence: ' + term + "\nAssign a score of difficulty for the given term\ using the following Likert scale: </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,125.25,684.06,281.96,47.74"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results of task 2 using Wiki / PKE</figDesc><table coords="3,125.25,721.26,242.04,10.54"><row><cell>Difficult term</cell><cell>Definition</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,86.25,688.54,409.80,79.53"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Image tampering, being readily facilitated and proliferated by today's digital techniques, is increasingly causing problems regarding the authenticity of images.\n\ Simplification: Image tampering has become a serious problem.\n\ \n\ Sentence: Nevertheless, the interesting issue of detecting image tampering and its related operations by using the same quantization matrix has not been fully investigated.\n\ Simplification: Methods based on image compression techniques, like quantization, are rarely applied.\n\ \n\ Sentence: Guest virtual machines are especially vulnerable to attacks coming from their (more privileged) host.\n\ Simplification: Guest virtual machines are vulnerable to attacks from their host.\n\ \n'</figDesc><table coords="5,86.25,688.54,409.80,79.53"><row><cell></cell><cell>presence_penalty=0</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>return response</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">GPT-3 prompt for explaining difficult terms</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">def provide_definition(sentence, difficult_term):</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>openai.api_key = "…"</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>response = openai.Completion.create(</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>model="text-davinci-003",</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>prompt="Given is the following sentence: " + sentence + "\n\</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>This sentence contains the following difficult term: " + difficult_term + "\n\</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Provide a definition for the difficult term.",</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>temperature=0.7,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>max_tokens=40,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>top_p=1,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>frequency_penalty=0,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>presence_penalty=0</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>return response</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">GPT-3 prompt for simplifying sentences</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">prompt = 'Sentence: def simpleMyPrompt(prompt,input):</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>import os</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>import openai</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>openai.api_key = "…"</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>response = openai.Completion.create(</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>model="text-davinci-003",</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>prompt=prompt+'Sentence: '+input+'\nSimplification:', #text completion</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>temperature=0.7,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>max_tokens=40,</cell></row><row><cell>)</cell><cell>top_p=1, frequency_penalty=0, return an integer decimal number.", 1 -easy enough, 2 -difficult, 3 -very difficult. Only presence_penalty=0 temperature=0.7, max_tokens=40, top_p=1, return response</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>frequency_penalty=0,</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,108.00,108.79,414.55,10.54;7,108.00,122.59,414.56,10.54;7,108.00,136.39,414.84,10.54;7,108.00,150.19,415.09,10.54;7,108.00,163.98,414.74,10.54;7,108.00,177.78,414.63,10.54;7,108.00,191.58,364.58,10.54" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,291.04,122.59,231.53,10.54;7,108.00,136.39,211.31,10.54">Overview of SimpleText -CLEF-2023 track on Automatic Simplification of Scientific Texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Liana</forename><surname>Ermakova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Sanjuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Stéphane</forename><surname>Huet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Augereau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hosein</forename><surname>Azarbonyad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jaap</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,458.10,163.98,64.64,10.54;7,108.00,177.78,414.63,10.54;7,108.00,191.58,297.25,10.54">Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Conference of the CLEF Association</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Avi</forename><surname>Arampatzis</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Evangelos</forename><surname>Kanoulas</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Theodora</forename><surname>Tsikrika</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stefanos</forename><surname>Vrochidis</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anastasia</forename><surname>Giachanou</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Aliannejadi</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michalis</forename><surname>Vlachos</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Guglielmo</forename><surname>Faggioli</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the Fourteenth International Conference of the CLEF Association<address><addrLine>CLEF</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023. 2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Experimental IR Meets Multilinguality, Multimodality, and Interaction</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,108.00,219.18,414.55,10.54;7,108.00,232.98,61.64,10.54;7,72.00,246.78,418.63,10.54;7,72.00,260.58,450.92,10.54;7,93.00,274.38,429.76,10.54;7,93.00,288.17,14.99,10.54;7,158.99,288.17,79.40,10.54;7,288.64,288.17,32.99,10.54;7,371.88,288.17,56.09,10.54;7,478.22,288.17,45.00,10.54;7,93.00,301.97,225.10,10.54" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,186.64,246.78,303.99,10.54;7,72.00,260.58,112.09,10.54">CLEF 2023 SimpleText Track: What Happens if General Users Search Scientific Texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Liana</forename><surname>Ermakova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Sanjuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Stéphane</forename><surname>Huet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Augereau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hosein</forename><surname>Azarbonyad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jaap</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-031-28241-6_62</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-28241-6_62" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,206.03,260.58,316.89,10.54;7,93.00,274.38,166.73,10.54;7,438.02,274.38,84.73,10.54;7,93.00,288.17,11.24,10.54">Advances in Information Retrieval: 45th European Conference on Information Retrieval, ECIR 2023</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Dublin, Ireland; Berlin, Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2023-04-02">2023. April 2-6, 2023</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="536" to="545" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings, Part III</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,108.00,329.57,415.13,10.54;7,108.00,343.37,28.65,10.54;7,72.00,357.17,409.24,10.54;7,72.00,370.97,450.82,10.54;7,93.00,384.77,429.87,10.54;7,93.00,398.56,430.22,10.54;7,93.00,412.36,429.95,10.54;7,93.00,426.16,225.10,10.54" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,72.00,370.97,446.02,10.54">Overview of the CLEF 2022 SimpleText Lab: Automatic Simplification of Scientific Texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Liana</forename><surname>Ermakova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Sanjuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jaap</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Stéphane</forename><surname>Huet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Irina</forename><surname>Ovchinnikova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Diana</forename><surname>Nurbakova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sílvia</forename><surname>Araújo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Radia</forename><surname>Hannachi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Elise</forename><surname>Mathurin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Patrice</forename><surname>Bellot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-031-13643-6_28</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-13643-6_28" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,112.75,384.77,410.13,10.54;7,93.00,398.56,340.45,10.54">Experimental IR Meets Multilinguality, Multimodality, and Interaction: 13th International Conference of the CLEF Association, CLEF 2022</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Bologna, Italy; Berlin, Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2022-09-05">2022. September 5-8, 2022</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="470" to="494" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,108.00,481.36,414.93,10.54;7,108.00,495.16,414.73,10.54;7,108.00,508.96,275.95,10.54" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,488.49,481.36,34.43,10.54;7,108.00,495.16,405.47,10.54">YAKE! Keyword extraction from single documents using multiple local features</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Campos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mangaravite</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pasquali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Jorge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Nunes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Jatowt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,108.00,508.96,109.62,10.54">Informaration Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">509</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="289" />
			<date type="published" when="2020-01">Jan. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,108.00,536.55,415.23,10.54;7,108.00,550.08,107.44,9.66" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="https://huggingface.co/docs/api-inference/index" />
		<title level="m" coord="7,113.15,537.21,172.22,9.66">Hosted Inference API&quot; Hugging Face</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">Mai 14, 2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,108.00,602.98,414.97,9.66;7,108.00,615.62,414.53,9.66;7,108.00,628.27,224.71,9.66" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,396.18,602.98,126.78,9.66;7,108.00,615.62,144.70,9.66">A Syntax-Aware Edit-based System for Text Simplification</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Cumbicus-Pineda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Gonzalez-Dios</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Soroa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,267.86,615.62,254.68,9.66;7,108.00,628.27,91.88,9.66">International Conference Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>RANLP</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="324" to="334" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
