<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,90.78,154.76,421.44,10.23;1,109.65,176.68,383.70,10.23">AEHRC &amp; QUT at TREC 2011 Medical Track: a concept-based information retrieval approach</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,120.56,203.05,85.02,11.43"><forename type="first">Bevan</forename><surname>Koopman</surname></persName>
							<email>bevan.koopman@csiro.au</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Australian e-Health Research Centre</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>CSIRO</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Information Systems Disipline</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Brisbane</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,224.05,203.05,61.44,11.43"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Bruza</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Information Systems Disipline</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Brisbane</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,297.39,203.05,88.95,11.43"><forename type="first">Laurianne</forename><surname>Sitbon</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Information Systems Disipline</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Brisbane</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,398.21,203.05,79.49,11.43"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Lawley</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Australian e-Health Research Centre</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>CSIRO</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">The Australian e-Health Research Centre</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,90.78,154.76,421.44,10.23;1,109.65,176.68,383.70,10.23">AEHRC &amp; QUT at TREC 2011 Medical Track: a concept-based information retrieval approach</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">6CBA8ED44A6EAF31B6081913DFB0F805</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>recently participated in the TREC 2011 Medical Records Track. This paper reports on our methods, results and experience using a concept-based information retrieval approach. Our concept-based approach is intended to overcome specific challenges we identify in searching medical records. Queries and documents are transformed from their term-based originals into medical concepts as defined by the SNOMED-CT ontology. Results show our concept-based approach performed above the median in all three performance metrics: bref (+12%), R-prec (+18%) and Prec@10 (+6%).</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The Australian e-Health Research Centre (AEHRC) is a multi-disciplinary research facility applying information and communication technology to improve health services and clinical treatment. The Health Data Semantic group aims to improve access for health data by combining statistical approaches in information retrieval and natural language processing with the formal semantics of the SNOMED CT medical ontology. Hybrid approaches using symbolic and statistical approaches are becoming increasing common <ref type="bibr" coords="1,237.61,506.58,9.96,9.52" target="#b3">[2]</ref>.</p><p>Our system used for the TREC Medical Records Track is concept-based information retrieval using medical domain knowledge provided by the SNOMED CT ontology. In concept-based IR both documents and queries are represented using semantic concepts rather than keywords, retrieval is performed within this concept space. Using high-level concepts makes the retrieval model less dependent on the specific terms being used. Queries and documents are transformed from their original terms to SNOMED-CT concepts, retrieval is then done by matching concepts. Conceptbased approaches have previously demonstrated excellent results -Zhou et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="1,438.40,590.26,10.51,9.52" target="#b10">[9]</ref> concept-based system (using concept from UMLS ontology and MeSH headings) was the top performing at the TREC Geonomics Track.</p><p>We received the track data only a few days before submission were due, as a result our system was used in its generic form as was not adapted to the specific corpus or topics for this years Medical Records Track. However we did develop the system using a subset of the BLULab NLP repository -the same collection from which the Medical Records Track data collection was taken.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Methods -concept-based information retrieval</head><p>This section describes our methods and the design of our concept-based system. We first report on our approach to treating patient visits as the unit of retrieval. We then describe the two main parts of our system: extracting SNOMED-CT concepts from free-text; and indexing and retrieval components.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Documents as visits</head><p>The guidelines for the Medical Records Track stated that the unit of retrieval should a single patient visit. A visit is a single admission for a single patient -if the same patient is admitted on two different occasions these will be viewed as two separate visits. Our approach was to treat individual reports as sub-documents and compile them together with all the other reports pertaining to a single patient admission into a single larger document. The unit of retrieval is then a 'patient visit' rather than individual medical reports. As all reports for a single visit are concatenated together we make no distinction as to the different reports type -radiology, discharge summary, etc.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Concept identification using MetaMap</head><p>In our system all queries and documents are converted from the original term-based representation into medical concepts. For this purpose we used MetaMap, a system developed by the U.S. National Library of Medicine <ref type="bibr" coords="2,220.45,323.90,9.96,9.52" target="#b2">[1]</ref>. It has been widely adopted in medical NLP <ref type="bibr" coords="2,432.19,323.90,10.51,9.52" target="#b7">[6]</ref> and medical IR <ref type="bibr" coords="2,90.00,335.85,10.51,9.52" target="#b5">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,104.13,335.85,7.74,9.52" target="#b9">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,115.50,335.85,7.74,9.52" target="#b4">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,126.86,335.85,7.01,9.52" target="#b6">5]</ref>. Comparisons with human subjects have shown that MetaMap is effective in concept identification tasks (84% precision, 70% recall) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,297.22,347.81,9.96,9.52" target="#b8">[7]</ref>.</p><p>An example output of the MetaMap system using the input string 'heart attack' is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,133.07,371.72,3.87,9.52" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. The advantage of using concepts (rather than just terms) is that different terms with the same meaning are mapped to the same concept -for example the input text 'Myocardial Infarction' and 'heart attack' will both map to the UMLS concept C0027051. Conversion to concepts aims to overcome some of the vocabulary mismatch that exists in medical text.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Concept-based architecture</head><p>We represented both documents and queries not as term-based vectors but as concept-based vectors. The overall process to translate from terms to concepts is illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,482.02,142.14,3.87,9.52" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. The steps required are: MetaMap identifies medical concepts using the UMLS ontology and returns their corresponding UMLS concept ids.</p><p>➋ Each document and query is now represented as a list of UMLS concept ids (e.g. C0027051) rather than the original terms (e.g. heart attack). Documents now only contain medical concepts.</p><p>➌ The UMLS concepts are then mapped to their SNOMED CT equivalents. This mapping is provided as part of the UMLS Metathesaurus.</p><p>➍ Queries and documents are now represented as a list of SNOMED CT concept ids.</p><p>➎ Documents are indexed using the Indri Lemur search engine. The system treats the documents as a bag-of-concepts.</p><p>➏ The queries (represented as SNOMED CT concept ids) are issued to the retrieval engine.</p><p>➐ A ranked list of document results is returned. Appendix A provides an example of converting a single term document into SNOMED CT concepts.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="4,131.68,135.70,4.98,9.52" target="#tab_0">1</ref>  The concept-based representations are considerably longer than the original term-based documents. This is a result of including all the candidate concepts suggested by the MetaMap program, not just those top-ranked concepts. Without candidate concepts the SNOMED CT average document length was 1168 concepts / document, considerably smaller than the term-based 2053 terms per document. Later experimental results show that retrieval performance is improved by including all candidate concepts rather than just choosing the top-ranked concepts suggested by MetaMap. Including candidates could be considered a type of basic query expansion.  Overall, our concept-based approach demonstrates an improvement the median. Analyses for individual topics is provided in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,255.83,549.96,4.98,9.52" target="#fig_4">3</ref> for the three metrics bpref 3(a), R-prec 3(b) and Precision @ 10 3(c).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results and analysis</head><p>Results are heavily dependent on the quality of concept extraction provided by the MetaMap system. MetaMap only identifies UMLS concepts, which are then mapped to SNOMED-CT concepts. Mapping between terminologies may result in a loss in meaning from the original query or document. Certain UMLS concepts have no equivalent in SNOMED-CT, such cases were found in the worst performing queries.</p><p>Performance on individual topics seems to correlate with that of the median, i.e. the conceptbased approach does not differ drastically. Particular topics of interest that showed significant improvement included:</p><p>107 Patients with chronic back pain who receive an intraspinal pain medicine pump:</p><p>In our system this query was converted to the single SNOMED CT concept 82711006, described as Infiltrating duct carcinoma. Our system equalled the best score of 0.9 Prec@10.   concepts meant these different variants all mapped to the SNOMED CT codes 86406008 (Human immunodeficiency virus infection) and 62944002 (Hepatitis C virus). Prec@10 was 0.8, median 0.1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>We have presented an approach to searching electronic medical records that is based on concept matching rather than keyword matching. Queries and documents are transformed from their termbased originals into medical concepts as defined by the SNOMED-CT ontology. Results show our approach performs reasonably well, above the median value from all system for all performance metrics. Our system was generic and due to time constraints was in no way tuned or adapted to the test corpus. Our concept-based approach provides a platform for further development into inferencing based search systems for dealing with medical data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A Converting terms to concepts</head><p>The sections provides an example of converting an original medical document into SNOMED CT concepts. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,167.28,145.57,4.43,9.52">4</ref>(a) shows the original term document. This document is converted to UMLS concepts (b) by the MetaMap system. UMLS concepts are then mapped to SNOMED CT concepts (c). The description for each of the SNOMED CT concepts is provided in Table <ref type="table" coords="7,442.82,169.48,3.87,9.52" target="#tab_4">3</ref>.</p><p>(a) Original medical document  </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,200.28,579.66,202.43,9.52"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: MetaMap output for heart attack.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,146.61,512.97,309.78,9.52"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Architecture for concept-based medical information retrieval.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="4,94.23,721.31,226.11,9.52;4,114.91,733.27,398.09,9.52;4,114.91,745.23,398.09,9.52"><head>125</head><label></label><figDesc>Patients co infected with Hepatitis C and HIV : HIV may have a number of different variants: HIV, AIDS or Human immunodeficiency virus, similarly Hepatitis C could be written as Hep-C or Hep C. Converting to SNOMED CT</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="5,121.69,389.73,359.62,9.52"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Plots comparing concept-based, median and best systems for each topic.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,90.00,135.70,423.00,127.96"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>provides a comparison of the term and concept based representations. It shows average query and document (visit) length for term-based, UMLS and SNOMED CT based representations. Comparison of average query and document lengths for term and concept-based representations. Documents as patient visits.</figDesc><table coords="4,153.78,175.95,295.44,51.16"><row><cell></cell><cell>Queries length</cell><cell>Documents length</cell></row><row><cell>Original terms</cell><cell>9.9 terms / query</cell><cell>2053 words / document</cell></row><row><cell>UMLS concepts</cell><cell>8.2 concepts / query</cell><cell>7451 concepts / document</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">SNOMED concepts 12.5 concepts / query 8140 concepts / document</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,90.00,403.99,422.99,82.20"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>showing the results we obtained in comparison to median values obtained across all systems.</figDesc><table coords="4,159.34,444.10,284.31,42.10"><row><cell></cell><cell>bpref (%∆)</cell><cell>R -p r e c( %∆)</cell><cell>Prec@10 (%∆)</cell></row><row><cell>Median</cell><cell>0.4115</cell><cell>0.3087</cell><cell>0.4764</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">AEHRC1 0.4636 (+12.66%) 0.3640 (+17.91%) 0.5059 (+6.19%)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="4,90.00,502.14,422.99,21.48"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Comparison of our concept-based approach (AEHRC1) to the median result obtained across all systems.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="7,108.97,613.78,385.05,9.52"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Preferred term descriptions for SNOMED CT concepts taken from Figure 4(c).</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="2,161.98,397.15,63.51,6.81;2,161.98,406.62,8.47,6.81;2,161.98,416.08,224.41,6.81;2,161.98,425.55,160.89,6.81;2,161.98,444.47,93.15,6.81;2,161.98,450.19,104.49,10.55;2,170.45,463.40,304.86,6.81;2,170.45,472.87,241.35,6.81;2,170.45,482.33,224.41,6.81;2,170.45,491.80,220.17,6.81;2,170.45,501.26,232.88,6.81;2,170.45,510.73,304.86,6.81;2,170.45,520.19,224.41,6.81;2,170.45,529.65,224.41,6.81" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="2,161.98,425.55,160.89,6.81;2,161.98,444.47,88.92,6.81;2,257.05,450.19,9.42,10.41;2,170.45,463.40,304.86,6.81;2,170.45,472.87,241.35,6.81;2,170.45,482.33,224.41,6.81;2,170.45,491.80,220.17,6.81;2,170.45,501.26,232.88,6.81;2,170.45,510.73,304.86,6.81;2,170.45,520.19,182.06,6.81">➊ 1000 C0027051:Heart attack (Myocardial Infarction) [Disease or Syndrome] 861 C0018787:Heart [Body Part, Organ, or Organ Component] 861 C0277793:Attack, NOS (Onset of illness) [Finding] 861 C0699795:Attack (Attack device) [Medical Device] 861 C1261512:attack (Attack behavior) [Social Behavior] 861 C1281570:Heart (Entire heart) [Body Part, Organ, or Organ Component] 861 C1304680:Attack (Observation of attack)</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="2,161.98,453.94,63.51,6.81">Meta Candidates</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Processing 00000000.tx.1: heart attack Phrase: &quot;heart attack. Finding] 827 C0004063:Attacked (Assault. Injury or Poisoning</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="2,161.98,537.14,100.26,10.55;2,170.45,550.35,304.86,6.81;5,90.00,607.02,75.51,8.52" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="2,252.82,537.14,9.42,10.41;2,170.45,550.35,211.71,6.81">➋ 1000 C0027051:Heart attack (Myocardial Infarction)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1000">1000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Disease or Syndrome</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,626.73,407.49,9.52;5,105.50,638.68,391.27,9.52" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,251.12,626.73,261.87,9.52;5,105.50,638.68,36.70,9.52">An overview of MetaMap: historical perspective and recent advances</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F.-M</forename><surname>Lang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,151.20,642.31,248.74,5.90">Journal of the American Medical Informatics Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="229" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,658.61,407.50,9.52;5,105.50,670.56,407.49,9.52;5,105.50,682.52,321.16,9.52" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,191.04,670.56,321.95,9.52;5,105.50,682.52,68.44,9.52">Automatically structuring domain knowledge from text: An overview of current research</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Kruschwitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Albakour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Dignum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Beresi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fasli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Roeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<publisher>Information Processing &amp; Management, In Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,702.44,407.49,9.52;5,105.50,714.40,407.50,9.52;5,105.50,726.36,407.49,9.52;5,105.50,738.31,79.14,9.52" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,396.60,714.40,116.39,9.52;5,105.50,726.36,199.76,9.52">Health search engine with e-document analysis for reliable search results</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gaudinat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ruch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Joubert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Uziel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Strauss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Thonnet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Baud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Spahni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bonal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Boyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fieschi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Geissbuhler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,314.16,729.98,194.43,5.90">International Journal of Medical Informatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">75</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,111.79,407.50,9.52;6,105.50,123.75,103.27,9.52" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,156.43,115.42,252.45,5.90">Information retrieval: a health and biomedical perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hersh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3rd edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,143.67,407.49,9.52;6,105.50,155.63,302.90,9.52" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,207.57,143.67,305.42,9.52;6,105.50,155.63,83.15,9.52">Knowledge-based query expansion to support scenario-specific retrieval of medical free text</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Chu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,197.12,159.25,92.97,5.90">Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="202" />
			<date type="published" when="2007-01">Jan. 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,175.55,407.50,9.52;6,105.50,187.51,407.50,9.52;6,105.50,199.46,89.10,9.52" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,234.97,175.55,278.03,9.52;6,105.50,187.51,239.48,9.52">Natural language processing to extract medical problems from electronic clinical documents: Performance evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Meystre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Haug</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,357.49,191.13,151.10,5.90">Journal of Biomedical Informatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="589" to="599" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,219.39,407.49,9.52;6,105.50,231.34,407.50,9.52;6,105.50,243.30,112.54,9.52" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,263.52,219.39,249.47,9.52;6,105.50,231.34,41.58,9.52">A study of biomedical concept identification: MetaMap vs. people</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Pratt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Yetisgen-Yildiz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,168.27,234.97,339.22,5.90">Proceedings of American Medical Informatics Association Symposium (AMIA)</title>
		<meeting>American Medical Informatics Association Symposium (AMIA)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-01">Jan. 2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="529" to="533" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,263.22,407.49,9.52;6,105.50,275.18,407.50,9.52;6,105.50,287.13,278.42,9.52" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,421.42,263.22,91.57,9.52;6,105.50,275.18,328.12,9.52">Hierarchical Concept Indexing of Full-text Documents in the UMLS Information Sources Map</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">K G</forename><surname>Nardini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Aronson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Rindflesch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,448.58,278.80,64.41,5.90;6,105.50,290.76,181.63,5.90">Journal of the American Society for Information Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="514" to="523" />
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,307.06,407.50,9.52;6,105.50,319.01,407.50,9.52;6,105.50,334.60,407.50,5.90;6,105.50,342.92,222.57,9.52" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,373.38,307.06,139.61,9.52;6,105.50,319.01,247.36,9.52">Knowledge-intensive conceptual retrieval and passage extraction of biomedical literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Smalheiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Torvik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,377.00,322.64,135.99,5.90;6,105.50,334.60,403.65,5.90">Proceedings of the 30th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 30th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on research and development in information retrieval<address><addrLine>New York, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="655" to="662" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
