<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,122.45,94.77,366.87,16.20">BUPT_WILDCAT at TREC 2011 Session Track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,156.07,123.61,41.35,10.80"><forename type="first">Tang</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Pattern Recognition and Intelligent System Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">P.R.China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,205.51,123.61,68.16,10.80"><forename type="first">Chuang</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<email>zhangchuang@bupt.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Pattern Recognition and Intelligent System Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">P.R.China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,282.12,123.61,40.86,10.80"><forename type="first">Yasi</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Pattern Recognition and Intelligent System Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">P.R.China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,331.82,123.61,60.81,10.80"><forename type="first">Wenjun</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Pattern Recognition and Intelligent System Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">P.R.China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,400.87,123.61,54.94,10.80"><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<email>huanghao511@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Pattern Recognition and Intelligent System Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CN">P.R.China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,122.45,94.77,366.87,16.20">BUPT_WILDCAT at TREC 2011 Session Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">5E722EE0D207398454594A7AE63D0814</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper is an overview of the runs carried out at TREC 2011 Session track, which proposes several approaches to improve the retrieval performance over one session including the search model based on user behavior, VSM_meta similarity model, optimization based on history ranked lists, optimization based on user"s attention time and anchor log. The evaluation results show that our implementations are effective.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This is the second year of session track, and its goal is to test whether systems can improve their performance for a given query by using previous queries and user interactions with the retrieval system <ref type="bibr" coords="1,121.73,442.01,8.08,6.26" target="#b0">[1]</ref> .</p><p>Participates should complete the following four tasks based on ClueWeb09 Category B corpus through taking advantages of the distinct history data: a) RL1:only using the current query b) RL2:using the current query and past query collections c) RL3:using the current query, past query collections ,and the ranked lists of history query d) RL4: using the current query, past query collections, the ranked lists of past query, and the attention time of each webpage which user clicks through</p><p>The result of RL1 is the basic standard, we can judge whether the user"s history action data improve the retrieval results by comparing the retrieval results from RL2 to RL4</p><p>The organizers provide some ClueWeb09 corpus related experiment results <ref type="bibr" coords="1,411.53,639.60,8.08,6.26">[2]</ref> which are processed by some volunteers (mainly from CMU, Waterloo and some other research institution) on ClueWeb09 corpus. We used some of them and ClueWeb09 corpus based search engine Indri which was set up by CMU <ref type="bibr" coords="1,116.45,688.32,16.45,6.26">[3][4]</ref> .</p><p>In this year"s TREC Session Track, our group submitted three runs. The general research structure and all methods used in all runs are clearly listed in processing sequence as below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Table 1 Methods in all Runs</head><p>Run ID Wildcat1 Wildcat2 Wildcat3</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RL1</head><p>• VSM_meta (2.2) • Spam Ranking <ref type="bibr" coords="2,342.38,158.19,6.80,5.40">[5]</ref> • Spam Ranking</p><p>• PageRank <ref type="bibr" coords="2,460.03,174.51,6.80,5.40">[6]</ref> RL2</p><p>• Phrase Recognition  In the following sections, Section 2 introduces the different methods referred above in detail. And evaluation results are shown in Section 3. Lastly, Section 4 draws the conclusion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Methodologies</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Search Model based on User Behavior</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.1">User Behavior Analysis</head><p>In actual search process, users always begin an interaction with a search engine with a series of queries which they will need to reformulate multi times before they find what they are looking for. It is believed that each query has reflected the user"s actual search intention to some extent. Each word in the previous query, which maybe have been discarded or changed, also is believed to be related with the main search topic, only with little importance if compared with the current queries. In purpose of making up for the little information that the latest query can provide, we built the search model based on user behavior, to done query expansion using history queries all with different weights to each word.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2">User Behavior Search Model</head><p>Assume that in one session, q i = (w 1 , w 2 , … w n ) represents the i th input of the user query, W j represents the j th word in q i , T i represents the history query set produced after the i th search behavior.</p><p>The model establishing steps are as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,90.05,249.37,112.82,12.03">a) InitializationT 1 = {q 1 }.</formula><p>b) T 2 = T 1 ∪ q 2 , and as follows,</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,244.42,272.20,177.91,13.68">T i-1 = T i-2 ∪ q i-1 = (w 1 ′ , w 2 ′ , … , w m ′ ).</formula><p>c) Taking T i = T i-1 ∪ q i as an example, we make the detailed analysis as below.</p><p>Assume that each word in the new query which user presents every time is of the same importance value. That is, in the new queryq i = (w 1 , w 2 , … w n ), the weight of w j is . e) Through the analysis of user search behavior, we believe that history queries can provide a positive effect to the search process, only with little importance compared with later ones. So we use history queries to expend later query, in the meanwhile, giving history queries" weight attenuation to a certain extent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Query set expansion:</head><p> </p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="3,293.48,558.24,60.66,12.87">1 i i i T T q  </formula><p>Normalization with expansion of history queries: f) Assume that the number of the words both presented in the history query set and query q i is k.</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="4,192.47,105.70,270.92,14.70">  ' ' ' 2 1 2 k 1 1k () w , w , w w , w , w , , ii T k q m k n       .</formula><p>Query set T i can be divided as below,</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="4,113.81,170.99,332.36,47.21">  ' ' ' ' 1 k k 1 k 1 n 1 m w w , w () w w , w i i i T T q       e 1 ′ , e 2 ′ , … e n ′</formula><p>is the weight vector of T i corresponding to each word.</p><p>Weight normalization with expansion of history queries can be formatted as below corresponding to the Query set T i above.</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="4,90.05,279.37,348.56,159.94">1 1 1 11 [ (1 ) ] [ (1 ) ] 1 k m n ii i i k i k de d d e d nn               g) As a summary, the weight of each element in e 1 ′ , e 2 ′ , … e n ′ is listed below, ' 1 (1 ) , [1, ] , [ 1, ] 1 (1 ) , [ 1, ] i ii de d i k n e de i k m d i m n n                </formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">VSM_meta Similarity Model</head><p>For the purpose of better calculating the similarity between the query and webpage, we established VSM_meta model, which was based on the VSM cosine similarity model, with the expansion usage on the &lt;meta&gt; tag, &lt;title&gt; tag and anchor text information of the webpage, for the consideration that the expansion used information can play a better role of describing the main topic of webpage than others.</p><p>The model establishing steps are as follows: a) For a specified webpage, extract the content of the &lt;title&gt; tag in the html source file as "title". b) Make an analysis on the &lt;meta&gt; tag, extract the value of the content attribute corresponding to the name attribute whose value is keyword and description. Save the string sequence we have extracted above as "keyword" and "description" in order. c) Using the anchor text dataset provided by Twente <ref type="bibr" coords="4,331.58,707.04,8.08,6.26">[7]</ref> , extract the top10 frequency word of the specified webpage as "anchor text". d) Using the html parser we developed to extract the main content of the webpage as "doc text". </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Webpage Comprehensive Evaluation Model</head><p>This model implements the synthesis of indri Rank mark and VSM_meta Similarity mark. Indri Rank mark represents the authority of the Webpage, while VSM_meta Similarity mark represents the relativity between Webpage and query. The comprehensive mark of these two marks is as follows:</p><p>_</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">()</head><p>VSM meta indri mark mark abs mark </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Optimization Based on History Ranked Lists</head><p>University of Lugano implemented generating optimized ranked list of current query by the rank of documents in ranked list of current query and only one past query <ref type="bibr" coords="5,375.98,500.35,8.08,6.26" target="#b1">[8]</ref> . One improved algorithm based on the referred above can be applied to a series of past ranked lists.</p><p>We suppose the ranked lists of history queries are L 1 , L 2 , L 3 ...L n-1 , and L n-1 is the ranked list of the last past query, so the retrieval result of current query is L n . Also, we supposed that L k ′means the optimization of L k when considering the prior past ranked lists. Finally, L n ′is obtained according to history query ranked lists (L 1 -L n-1 ) through the following formula:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="5,113.04,621.65,343.81,50.93">' ' 1 ' 11 1 1 1 ( , ) ( ), 1, 2... ( , ) ( , ) ( , ) k k k k score d L a k n rank d L rank d L rank d L LL           </formula><p>In the above formula, a value stands for the significance degree of historical ranked lists. In our experiment, a is set to 0.2. We can get the rank of L k ′by sorting its score, therefore score(d, L k ′) is the grade of one document d in Lk′, while rank(d, Lk′) is ranking of document d in Lk′.</p><p>At last, re-ranking according to the score(d, L k ′) by ascending order.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Optimization Based on User's Attention Time</head><p>Attention time reflects the usefulness of the information in the document as viewed by the user. Songhua Xu etc. <ref type="bibr" coords="6,169.75,193.54,8.08,6.26" target="#b2">[9]</ref> proposed the attention time prediction algorithm in 2008. It assumes if the contents of two documents are sufficiently similar. We used this method to predict the attention time result lists of current query based on attention time of past click through. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.6">The Anchor Log</head><p>University of Essex developed a method for extracting useful terms and phrases to expand the reformulated query in Session Track 2010 <ref type="bibr" coords="7,268.20,135.70,11.68,6.26" target="#b3">[10]</ref> . On that basis, we modified it with four steps to adapt to the new requirements. In addition, the anchor log for the Category B is available by University of Twente <ref type="bibr" coords="7,123.41,168.34,8.07,6.26">[2]</ref> .</p><p>a) Extract all the document numbers for 2011 Session Data For RL3 in a session.</p><p>b) From the anchor log, we extract the corresponding anchor texts out using document numbers c) For all the anchor texts, we put all the key words in these texts together and count every word"s frequency. Then take the top 10 phrases with highest word frequency as the query expansions. )</p><p>Where r c is the current query, e i is an expanision term or phrase extracted as explained in the previous step.</p><p>e) Filter the result with Spam Ranking.</p><p>f) Repeat step a) to e) for all the other sessions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Evaluation Results</head><p>For 5 main measurements (err, nerr, ndcg, ap, gap) given by NIST, we use nerr@10,ndcg@10 and gap to compare the performance of our system for goal 1 (to test whether systems can improve their performance for a given query by using previous queries and user interactions with the retrieval system ).</p><p>Result in bold means it is the highest in its group while result with a * on the right side means it is under median level of all the results.</p><p>Table2 shows the overall performance for all subtopics using the measures provided by NIST. It also contains the summary results of all participants in the track. Table <ref type="table" coords="8,116.21,335.37,5.28,9.50" target="#tab_3">3</ref> shows the overall performance for last subtopic using the measures provided by NIST. It also contains the summary results of all participants in the track. After analyzing the results, the findings are summarized as follows: a) By using the metric ndcg@10 or nerr@10, it is show that whether in table or table, the general trend of results is: RL1&lt;RL2&lt;RL3&lt;RL4. That indicates that systems can really improve their performance for a given query by using previous queries and user interactions with the retrieval system.</p><p>b) The RL4 group has the best performance in your experiments. That indicates the time factor can also influence the results. c) By comparing overall results in all subtopics and last subtopic, we find some of our results have best performance in subtopics but perform not so well in last subtopic. That may result from that our methods take all the historical data in to consideration. d) In RL2 group, the wildcat3 has the best performance. All the experiments in RL2 group we use the same method before filter spam. After filtering spam, in wildcat3 we only use indri to deal with the data. This may indicate that using indri to deal with data is better than using VSM_meta. e) RL3.wildcat3 has the best score in RL3 group, which indicates using the anchor log for query expansion is useful.</p><p>f) "gap" (graded average precision) is used to evaluate the average precision for the every system.</p><p>Though in ndcg@10 and nerr@10 our system perform quite well, in "gap" we have most scores under median level. We think this may be due to the our result in each experiment is of large quantity. Since the number of most relevant websites is limited, the more the results are, the less relevant websites there will be.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>This year's Session Track provided a platform to evaluate the effectiveness of Information Retrieval systems in improving their performance for a given query by using previous queries and user interactions with the retrieval system (including clicks on ranked results, dwell times, etc.). The results of our runs are promising. We used a number of different techniques to attempt to improve performance over a user session, which will give suggestions for further research.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,503.71,343.03,4.12,7.44;3,503.47,354.55,4.15,7.44;3,513.58,347.85,8.68,9.50;3,132.05,380.51,108.46,9.50;3,267.48,375.69,4.12,7.44;3,267.24,387.21,4.15,7.44;3,274.92,379.50,16.65,10.56;3,253.30,377.85,4.15,7.44;3,253.30,384.57,12.04,7.44;3,291.48,380.51,2.64,9.50;3,90.05,412.38,175.27,12.03;3,264.34,416.97,12.06,7.44;3,279.96,412.38,23.29,10.56;3,303.00,417.21,4.12,7.44;3,303.72,410.97,1.92,7.44;3,307.80,412.38,12.01,10.56;3,319.80,417.21,4.12,7.44;3,320.28,410.97,1.92,7.44;3,324.60,412.38,25.47,10.56;3,350.06,416.97,6.19,7.44;3,350.54,410.97,1.92,7.44;3,357.50,412.38,93.69,12.03;3,451.87,412.38,9.23,10.56;3,460.99,416.97,4.12,7.44;3,465.79,412.38,18.59,10.56;3,484.27,413.39,37.78,11.02;3,104.21,428.70,80.44,10.56;3,183.67,429.71,200.65,11.02;3,405.77,428.70,5.15,10.56;3,410.81,433.29,2.07,7.44;3,416.57,428.70,16.65,10.56;3,391.85,427.05,6.19,7.44;3,391.85,433.77,12.04,7.44"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>user has presented queryq i , T i-1 = (w 1 ′ , w 2 ′ , … , w m ′ ) is the query set, (e 1 , e 2 , … e m ) is the weight vector of T i-1 corresponding to each word. Normalization e i = 1 m i=1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,287.74,646.40,66.87,6.18;3,358.59,624.22,6.05,10.70;3,313.05,631.70,9.06,10.70;3,339.01,631.70,4.03,10.70;3,376.54,631.70,6.05,10.70;3,283.79,627.76,67.63,1.00;3,299.00,642.88,1.94,1.00;3,281.78,651.10,65.31,1.00;3,272.43,639.81,6.05,1.00;3,294.15,639.81,5.37,1.00;3,331.63,639.81,6.05,1.00;3,358.69,649.10,6.05,1.00;3,284.26,646.34,67.21,6.25;3,304.39,631.58,25.27,10.80;3,368.46,631.58,6.64,10.80;3,279.87,630.19,76.29,16.20;3,104.21,674.10,381.10,9.50;3,104.21,690.42,53.76,9.50"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>the attenuation we have set to history query words, d&lt;0.5. We set d=0.4 in our experiments.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="5,90.05,125.56,431.66,9.50;5,108.05,140.39,140.60,10.56;5,248.74,140.39,39.05,12.03;5,287.88,140.39,56.57,12.03;5,344.54,140.39,65.94,12.03;5,410.57,140.39,49.83,12.03;5,460.51,141.40,15.84,11.02;5,90.05,166.36,258.34,9.50;5,186.81,196.85,6.28,10.74;5,240.43,196.85,6.28,10.74;5,307.13,196.85,6.28,10.74;5,382.82,196.85,6.28,10.74;5,445.26,196.85,6.28,10.74;5,210.55,203.37,10.97,6.20;5,264.40,203.37,23.58,6.20;5,331.14,203.37,31.35,6.20;5,406.90,203.37,19.78,6.20;5,469.40,203.37,10.18,6.20;5,150.43,196.85,60.98,10.74;5,233.07,196.85,31.94,10.74;5,300.31,196.85,31.38,10.74;5,374.30,196.85,33.07,10.74;5,438.61,196.85,31.18,10.74;5,169.93,196.73,6.90,10.85;5,224.68,196.73,6.90,10.85;5,291.74,196.73,6.90,10.85;5,365.57,196.73,6.90,10.85;5,430.07,196.73,6.90,10.85;5,90.05,231.42,432.02,9.50;5,108.05,247.74,7.92,9.50"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>e) Calculate the similarity between the query and the extraction data above using the VSM cosine similarity model, denoted as sim title , sim keyword , sim description , sim anchor , sim doc . f) Make a combination of the similarity value above as sim, a series of contrast experiment, we finally set the parameters as a = 4, b = 1, c = 2, d = 4, e = 1.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="6,90.29,253.02,306.05,9.50;6,279.15,274.04,5.71,14.24;6,348.56,274.04,5.71,14.24;6,294.26,282.37,22.22,6.23;6,298.37,275.86,3.02,10.77;6,317.62,275.86,15.80,10.77;6,264.58,282.37,1.94,6.23;6,292.35,282.37,1.94,6.23;6,310.33,282.37,1.94,6.23;6,342.34,282.37,5.44,6.23;6,258.42,275.86,6.04,10.77;6,284.50,275.86,26.04,10.77;6,334.49,275.86,8.05,10.77;6,270.72,275.74,6.63,10.88;6,90.05,310.17,182.02,10.16;6,272.04,307.59,5.40,6.26;6,281.40,310.17,114.23,9.50;6,395.45,307.59,5.40,6.26;6,405.05,310.17,111.58,9.50;6,516.70,307.59,5.40,6.26;6,90.05,326.49,32.62,9.50;6,90.05,350.97,154.82,10.16;6,244.66,348.39,5.40,6.26;6,254.74,350.97,267.22,10.16;6,104.21,367.29,76.40,9.50;6,225.60,395.08,7.34,6.25;6,274.81,448.94,7.34,6.25;6,241.40,388.52,38.63,10.81;6,297.55,388.52,22.72,10.81;6,350.70,388.52,33.89,10.81;6,281.76,406.92,28.55,10.81;6,325.93,406.92,6.00,10.81;6,356.26,406.92,26.66,10.81;6,242.50,414.60,22.73,10.81;6,276.96,424.00,36.78,10.81;6,329.37,424.00,6.00,10.81;6,359.71,424.00,26.66,10.81;6,234.95,442.40,22.72,10.81;6,290.58,442.40,22.72,10.81;6,346.01,442.40,22.72,10.81;6,233.87,326.45,24.31,73.38;6,285.51,326.45,28.85,73.38;6,336.25,326.45,31.28,73.38;6,392.39,326.45,3.08,73.38;6,368.09,344.82,5.02,73.38;6,225.73,352.53,33.55,73.38;6,371.54,361.90,5.02,73.38;6,225.83,380.30,25.89,73.38;6,283.07,380.30,24.31,73.38;6,329.26,380.30,33.55,73.38;6,219.83,269.85,6.68,126.87;6,245.33,269.85,8.01,126.87;6,279.60,269.85,6.68,126.87;6,301.48,269.85,8.01,126.87;6,330.13,269.85,6.68,126.87;6,354.63,269.85,8.01,126.87;6,385.90,269.85,6.00,126.87;6,317.53,288.25,50.69,126.87;6,219.83,295.93,34.62,126.87;6,320.98,305.33,50.69,126.87;6,219.83,323.73,27.06,126.87;6,269.02,323.73,6.68,126.87;6,294.52,323.73,8.01,126.87;6,323.36,323.73,6.68,126.87;6,349.96,323.73,8.01,126.87;6,214.33,386.24,5.93,10.92;6,266.89,388.40,62.01,10.92;6,214.33,397.74,5.93,10.92;6,310.59,406.80,6.59,10.92;6,214.33,407.53,5.93,10.92;6,267.96,414.48,6.59,10.92;6,214.33,416.56,5.93,10.92;6,283.91,423.88,36.75,10.92;6,214.33,428.06,5.93,10.92;6,214.33,439.59,5.93,10.92;6,260.43,442.28,61.52,10.92;6,214.33,446.85,5.93,10.92;6,90.05,473.17,431.92,10.16;6,90.05,489.49,340.92,9.50;6,90.05,513.97,236.60,10.16;6,326.54,511.39,5.64,6.26;6,342.86,513.97,121.01,10.16;6,463.87,511.39,5.40,6.26;6,471.79,513.97,33.09,9.50;6,90.05,538.48,432.04,10.16;6,90.05,554.80,182.04,9.50;6,90.05,579.28,35.32,9.50;6,125.33,576.70,5.64,6.26;6,133.73,579.28,110.69,10.16;6,244.18,576.70,5.41,6.26;6,251.38,579.28,144.61,10.16;6,395.93,576.70,5.63,6.26;6,410.33,579.28,88.18,9.50;6,90.05,595.60,337.91,10.16;6,90.05,620.08,43.74,9.50;6,133.73,617.50,5.64,6.26;6,141.89,620.08,258.60,10.16;6,400.49,617.50,5.64,6.26;6,408.89,620.08,86.90,10.16;6,273.66,642.29,20.36,10.71;6,324.33,642.29,19.14,10.71;6,359.26,642.29,11.52,10.71;6,386.17,642.29,22.92,10.71;6,250.69,580.96,37.58,72.52;6,335.00,580.96,22.51,72.52;6,377.12,580.96,26.06,72.52;6,243.82,524.74,6.99,125.68;6,277.93,524.74,6.29,125.68;6,306.11,524.74,46.68,125.68;6,371.00,524.74,27.45,125.68;6,260.30,648.73,3.98,6.24;6,296.57,642.17,6.90,10.82;6,90.05,667.44,289.05,12.02"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>a) For all clicked document in one session build one training sample set, And S i is the training sample set for the i th session, while C is the k th clicked document in the i th session. b) For each C ik in session i, the k th corresponding attention time T att (k) can be computed by the Time interval is denoted by T inter, time offset is T offset, T att represents the attention time. T end and T start stand for the end time and start time which can be found in click tag respectively.In the second formula rank(C ik ) denotes the ranking of k th clicked document C ik in the i th session.Aiming to reduce the time interval in proportion, we set control parameter d c as 0.1, and parameter d controlling how sharp drop off is set of 0.2. For the j th document d ij of RL3 and k th clicked document C ik in the same i th session, calculate the similarity Sim(d ij , C ik ) by cosine similarity (wildcat2) or KL distance (wildcat3) c) In the i th session, obtain the prediction attention time T pre-att (d ij ) of the j th document d ij in RL3. At last, re-ranking according to the T pre-att (d ij ) by ascending order.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="7,90.05,284.94,432.26,9.50;7,90.05,301.29,93.35,9.50;7,222.82,325.77,47.43,9.50;7,304.44,350.25,70.50,10.16;7,307.08,374.75,76.46,10.16;7,383.42,374.64,15.52,9.60;7,398.81,374.75,10.48,10.16"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>d) Remove stop word from query expansions, combine them with current query to generate new query like this format: #combime( 0.7#combine (r c ) 0.3#combine (e 1 e 2 …e 10 )</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="8,113.81,75.80,368.54,241.90"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Evaluation results in all_subtopics</figDesc><table coords="8,113.81,101.63,368.54,216.08"><row><cell>wildcat</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>min</cell><cell>median</cell><cell>max</cell></row><row><cell>RL1.nerr@10</cell><cell>0.3849 *</cell><cell>0.4672</cell><cell>0.3596 *</cell><cell>0.1878</cell><cell>0.38565</cell><cell>0.4672</cell></row><row><cell>RL2.nerr@10</cell><cell>0.4026</cell><cell>0.449</cell><cell>0.4961</cell><cell>0.1712</cell><cell>0.38735</cell><cell>0.4961</cell></row><row><cell>RL3.nerr@10</cell><cell>0.4358</cell><cell>0.496</cell><cell>0.4901</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.3846</cell><cell>0.496</cell></row><row><cell>RL4.nerr@10</cell><cell>0.4196</cell><cell>0.5374</cell><cell>0.5106</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.3973</cell><cell>0.5374</cell></row><row><cell>RL1.ndcg@10</cell><cell>0.311</cell><cell>0.3496</cell><cell>0.2364 *</cell><cell>0.1384</cell><cell>0.30555</cell><cell>0.3663</cell></row><row><cell>RL2.ndcg@10</cell><cell>0.3248</cell><cell>0.3516</cell><cell>0.3847</cell><cell>0.1279</cell><cell>0.31055</cell><cell>0.4061</cell></row><row><cell>RL3.ndcg@10</cell><cell>0.3446</cell><cell>0.3851</cell><cell>0.3881</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.3084</cell><cell>0.4086</cell></row><row><cell>RL4.ndcg@10</cell><cell>0.3348</cell><cell>0.432</cell><cell>0.3946</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.32625</cell><cell>0.432</cell></row><row><cell>RL1.gap</cell><cell>0.098 *</cell><cell>0.1166 *</cell><cell>0.0772 *</cell><cell>0.0267</cell><cell>0.1171</cell><cell>0.1431</cell></row><row><cell>RL2.gap</cell><cell>0.1203</cell><cell>0.0751 *</cell><cell>0.0669 *</cell><cell>0.023</cell><cell>0.1091</cell><cell>0.1445</cell></row><row><cell>RL3.gap</cell><cell>0.0766 *</cell><cell>0.1181</cell><cell>0.0713 *</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.09895</cell><cell>0.1732</cell></row><row><cell>RL4.gap</cell><cell>0.1076 *</cell><cell>0.1244</cell><cell>0.1159</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.11455</cell><cell>0.1835</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="8,98.45,375.42,393.49,242.33"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Evaluation results in last_subtopics</figDesc><table coords="8,98.45,402.61,393.49,215.14"><row><cell></cell><cell>wildcat1</cell><cell>wildcat2</cell><cell>wildcat3</cell><cell>min</cell><cell>median</cell><cell>max</cell></row><row><cell>RL1.nerr@10</cell><cell>0.267 *</cell><cell>0.3322</cell><cell>0.2140 *</cell><cell>0.1153</cell><cell>0.29255</cell><cell>0.3545</cell></row><row><cell>RL2.nerr@10</cell><cell>0.2568</cell><cell>0.2706</cell><cell>0.3086</cell><cell>0.0826</cell><cell>0.2501</cell><cell>0.3648</cell></row><row><cell>RL3.nerr@10</cell><cell>0.3025</cell><cell>0.3088</cell><cell>0.3153</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.24255</cell><cell>0.3672</cell></row><row><cell>RL4.nerr@10</cell><cell>0.2747</cell><cell>0.3330</cell><cell>0.3285</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.25315</cell><cell>0.3749</cell></row><row><cell>RL1.ndcg@10</cell><cell>0.1954 *</cell><cell>0.2445</cell><cell>0.1351 *</cell><cell>0.0802</cell><cell>0.22075</cell><cell>0.2758</cell></row><row><cell>RL2.ndcg@10</cell><cell>0.1889 *</cell><cell>0.2028</cell><cell>0.2387</cell><cell>0.0648</cell><cell>0.19225</cell><cell>0.3034</cell></row><row><cell>RL3.ndcg@10</cell><cell>0.214</cell><cell>0.2390</cell><cell>0.2550</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.18585</cell><cell>0.3062</cell></row><row><cell>RL4.ndcg@10</cell><cell>0.2019</cell><cell>0.2594</cell><cell>0.2485</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.1972</cell><cell>0.3051</cell></row><row><cell>RL1.gap</cell><cell>0.0889 *</cell><cell>0.122</cell><cell>0.0622 *</cell><cell>0.0228</cell><cell>0.1161</cell><cell>0.1435</cell></row><row><cell>RL2.gap</cell><cell>0.0951</cell><cell>0.0614 *</cell><cell>0.0684 *</cell><cell>0.0178</cell><cell>0.09305</cell><cell>0.1438</cell></row><row><cell>RL3.gap</cell><cell>0.0677 *</cell><cell>0.1076</cell><cell>0.0776 *</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.08385</cell><cell>0.1417</cell></row><row><cell>RL4.gap</cell><cell>0.089 *</cell><cell>0.1149</cell><cell>0.1057</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.0973</cell><cell>0.1511</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="9,105.65,559.12,175.87,9.50" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,105.65,559.12,175.87,9.50">TREC 2011 Session Track Guidelines.pdf</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,105.17,700.98,409.69,9.50;10,90.05,74.17,43.42,9.50" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,311.67,700.98,151.43,9.50">University of Lugano at TREC 2010</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mostafa</forename><surname>Keikha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Parvaz</forename><surname>Mahdabi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Shima</forename><surname>Gerani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Lugano</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,105.17,94.33,381.87,9.50;10,90.05,106.57,411.63,9.50;10,90.05,118.60,51.56,9.50" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="10,338.09,94.33,148.95,9.50;10,90.05,106.57,170.97,9.50">A User-Oriented Webpage Ranking Algorithm Based on User Attention Time</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Songhua</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hao</forename><surname>Jiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Francis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Zhejiang University, Yale University, The University of Hong Kong</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,110.45,138.76,405.58,9.50;10,90.05,150.76,138.17,9.50" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="10,377.90,138.76,138.14,9.50;10,90.05,150.76,48.29,9.50">Autoadapt at the Session track in TREC 2010</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M-Dyaa</forename><surname>Albakour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Udo</forename><surname>Kruschwitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jinzhong</forename><surname>Niu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Fasli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Essex</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
