<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,195.84,75.10,202.50,13.50">UALR at TREC 201l Entity Tradc</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,84.96,107.06,132.25,11.50"><forename type="first">Vcnkata</forename><surname>Swalny Martha十</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,224.63,108.86,74.75,11.50"><forename type="first">Halil</forename><surname>Bisgin+</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,305.13,108.86,92.00,11.50"><forename type="first">Stcphcn</forename><surname>Wallacc+</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,402.88,108.86,69.00,11.50"><forename type="first">Hcmant</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
							<email>hcmant.joshi@ac対om.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Acxlom Corporation</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Littlc Rock</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>72201</postCode>
									<settlement>Arkansas</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,483.38,108.86,28.75,11.50;1,223.92,121.75,56.85,12.00"><forename type="first">Nitin</forename><surname>Agaぃvaltt</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,307.02,123.05,63.00,10.50"><forename type="first">Xiaowci</forename><surname>Xu+1</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Infomation Sciencc Dcpt</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Univcrsity ofArkansas at Littlc Rock</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Littlc Rock</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>72204</postCode>
									<settlement>Arkansas</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,195.84,75.10,202.50,13.50">UALR at TREC 201l Entity Tradc</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">9B85C80813012325FCDF154C2C5E8778</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Thc p」mary obiectiVe Of the track is to accomplish a mechanism to answcr entity related scarches over、 veb data The TREC orgttzers prov■ ded a segmcnt of web data le ClucWeb09 data collection which is uscd for this work An example ofthe cntity rclatcd query isˋˋur7friS ο rtt fhan′ αメ and ra И ″ ブ c々 ′ odandair″ ′ es2' To answer such qucries,it needs twcl phases of processing, onc is omine processing and the other is query time processing During ofainc processhg,the data is indexed using third p征 ,sCarch cngine tool Query time processing involves query refo...lulation, cxtracting rclated documents 螢om the indcx and document analysis to answcr the query.Docwlent analysis is thc heart ofthc research which includc cntity identiflcation and entity ranking based on a query Since there is no readily avdlablc sophisticated cntity identincι 饉on t。 。 1, conscnsus approach is incOっ orated for enity</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="606.24" lry="788.76"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="609.12" lry="788.76"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="606.6" lry="788.76"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="611.28" lry="789.48"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="609.48" lry="790.56"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="614.88" lry="791.28"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="609.48" lry="789.84"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="616.32" lry="791.64"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="611.64" lry="790.92"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="617.4" lry="792.36"/>
		<surface n="11" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="610.2" lry="791.28"/>
		<surface n="12" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="614.88" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="13" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="610.2" lry="790.92"/>
		<surface n="14" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="615.6" lry="791.28"/>
		<surface n="15" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="790.92"/>
		<surface n="16" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="617.04" lry="791.28"/>
		<surface n="17" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="610.2" lry="791.28"/>
		<surface n="18" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="615.24" lry="791.64"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>棚</head><p>:鵠 獣ettS踏 箇 器1細 aSm』 僣 :hr熙 潮篭話 器 : developed to ranlc the entities related to a query ln other worお ,the identifled entities t・ om rclated doculnents are rankcd based on thcir relevancc to the query tenns Variations of query refonnulations are:no refonnula■ on,manual(human refo.1.lulated)and programmed using entity identiflcation tool, resulted three submissions "H刀 Иと ,(И ttDH刀Иι M and aFこ)〃爾 と ハrespccively.In addition to thc above varlations,、 ve also used extcmal web search engine(Bing)tO CXtract related doculnents and submiled the rlln as amHwι a The submission also involvcd■ OD υF71ook up、″ hOh is achieved using organizers provided Sindice dttdttandttb唖 コ</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>1.Intrdudim</head><p>University of Arkansas at Little Rock(vALD in∞ 1labOration with Ac対 om CorporatiOn pFdicゎ ates in cntity track.The main task of this track is to develop a solution for inding rdevant e面es and subscquemy thc士 LOD-UⅢ ugng SimtedatasdttAnexampに of■c query is Otr17rrゎs ο rr7a rnanノ cdar7d fO"力′ c力 ′ Odandair″ ′ α ジ '' To answer such que五 es wc dcveloped a nc• vork smcme mining approach thttis explaincd in the following lContact author: Xiaowei Xu, email: xwxu@ualr.edu 2 $star ardrltecture</p><p>The system consists of two components: Indexing and Query Processing. Index is built offJine independent to queries. We indexed the Clueweb0g dataset ft-iTl with Indri (part of Lemur) softwarefi5]l4Tlfor efficient retrieval. The offJine processing coffinent is presented i{EFi| Distribute dataset among machines Start lndriDaemon at each machine lndex locally at each machine Fittrc l:Off-‖ ne processhg Query pЮ Cessing leverages the index to ttcve query related documcnts.Fwier the query procesSng involves follo宙 ng stepS:l Query rcstructunng,2 1dentitting SCntences in thc qucry relatcd doclmlcnts using HTML parser籠 直Apache OPENNLP sentencc dctection library,3. E■1,rcCOgi■on u"ng an opcn souce enity tag」 ng hbraries(StanfOd NER tagg{回 Apache OPENNLP sente¨e ptts返 コ ,4.Edi,v洲 d面On wi■ DBpeda dataset whth aso rems us entity type infonnation,5 Wei』 ing SCntences by comparing sentcnce terrns宙 th query tcms,and flnally 6.Ranking identifled entitics using a novei neい vork mining approach</p><p>The flowchart ofthe steps is depicted These steps are explained in detail in Section 3.</p><p>Ftwe 2 Query tlme processhg</p><p>The ovα洲 霞 mecm of ow syttemお Ihstrated h Rgv"1帥d Rgu"2 Arch cmalけ Indri search engine is used to index the ClueWeb09 dataset. Since the dataset is large enough to not to fit in a single machine, we segmented the dataset into 46 partitions ( each partition with en4o, en&lt;x+l&gt;, an&lt;x+b directories) and distributed them on to 46 machines which further fed to indri to index locally with standard indri parameters at each machine. With this infrastructure, we were able to achieve faster document retrieval. We configured indri to store documents along with the index; the rational behind doing it is discussed in next section. lndri daemon (server) is started on all the machines and kept available for further steps'</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Toplcsanalyds</head><p>The given queries from the organizers include narrative, type. To avoid inconsistency .upp"d ttrJ given types to generic DBpedia classes. For example, " dwf' "EdL@tionallNitde'.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Relevant documents tFro■ 9い</head><p>321 Quay rdamulatlo (M anual)   As part of the manual run, we reformulated the query narative into indri query language. The main reason behind human intervention is to remove/replace more generic terms, to keep specific terms togeth$ as phrase (particularity entities with two terms). For instance, the query (l) is reformulated as #combine ( # t ( l d atuAi r ) fi (ei nati otts) ) " This nln involves complex proccssing of the qucry nttaive First,cntitics are identiflcd using methodology discusscd in Section-4.3 Thc stop words are removed except the tertnˋˋof', doubthg■ ヽpart of cnities.The phrases are caled 9tla-yゃ 性 置 翡 '.The 9Jgy ttμ 雌 plays an important Юle in wei」 ing Sentences in doculnents.Now the 91ygy粕 降 h7ardS arc transl誠 ed to mdri quc,language.Hcκ we mduded weight whichヽ the Lngth ofthe tms included in the spcciflc ttatnc The automatic refo.1..ulation tumcd the query(1)intO  </p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="7,67.68,191.38,469.34,93.30">荊繭 夢 ˋ7ノ イ cdar7d9プ θ力 F″ 濶 り 54ノブ runtri αttr fhar7′αrand fO面 ′ ″ 渤 r″′ ■,9ノ ′ 御 ″ ■り θノ プ ranfri司 "ノ イ て ガand rOルリ リ ′ ″ adair″ ′ eり ′ 6 ノ friaダ andrO wヵ Fdリ ア ノ プ riodandJ fδ ′ プ rOdandair″ ′ aり 5ノ プ rrrFaリ リ 3.23 Quryrdaantdttmmts Thc refo.</formula><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="7,97.92,605.09,439.85,27.42">蘇 温 i占 W写 柵 ど 酬 鋼 出 易 留 幾 :∬lrili懇 寛 滞 彗 :</formula><p>marks thc cnd of a sentence or not.In thils sens( tHmmed character sequence bem、 cn two punctuation marks The frst and last sentences make an exccption to ths nic.The flrst no,whiteSpace character is assurned to be the beginning of a sentence,and the last non whitcspace charactcr is assumed to be a sentcncc end The OpehNLP Sentence Detector cannot identl,SCntence boundanes bascd on the∞ ntents oftt sentence. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4.3Entitydddlql</head><p>A sentence has set of terms which have specific meaning. Sentence analysis is critical and important task which can affect results significantly. We followed following steps to achieve concise entities and semantic meanings among them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="43.1">Stanlad NER tagger</head><p>This is very naive approach to identiff entities of primitive types person, location, organization. Stanford Ngn tugg"ift2il hkes a senience and tags recognized entities. We ignore entity types *tign"a th. trggiiUffir" the gpes are more generic to filter out target entities. We forwarded the inowledgJadentified entiti;;) to next step. To forward the knowledge, the entities in the s;ntence are-.eilaced by indices (here we :Ufjed XYZ&lt;in&lt;*Ao) which are recognized as single term in the nextstep, we call the resulting sentence "virtual sentence"' 4.3.2 Apache Incubator's Parser</p><p>The sentence (virtual sentence) fiom entity tagger is forwarded lo Apache Incubator.'s Parser m Th" parser identifies tenns with its parts of speech tags. The reason behind using parser 'iiiieua of POS tqgg is to retain tag tree structure. To focus on the given task (entity identification), only-lhtases tagged as we ruru, NNe NNS NNPS are considered as entities.</p><p>Since Np is u pfn*" clause an] lead to its descendants, so all descendant terms of NP tag is considered as an entity. The rational behind using parser instead of PoS tagger is to get the descendant terms of NPtag. Here is an example tags obtained from the parser rTOP rAIPrNPrDT7hり rdた押 た りrd/b 囲 りrArNrox9ハ ハ 6ル ″p〃 rPPrrrvο 8)rAIP rDT″η ,6υ ′ ι 昭 りrrvNda〃 〃 ˋり〃 Once all the nolms arc extracted,the entities found in earlier step(seCtiOn 4.31)are reverted back by replacing indiccs(χ ″k′Л ttχ &gt;)with COrresponding phrases.By thc cnd ofthe step wc had entitics in the sentence.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="43.3">Entity validatim and Entitytypelα ttup</head><p>Thc entities recognizcd are needcd to be validated to avoid noisc.The validation is carned out ushg DB'EDIAdatasttAdvantagehuJngthedatasetお 伍江 i not omy vddates b■ dso g市es flne graned entity types For faster access,we indexed the dataset using均 鮨 dη Lycma Since quenes indude targct entity type,we宙 ped or dithe cmtcs exceptthe oncs we needcd to answer.The rettning entities are rargd"f′ ″ and are ranked in coming steps.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="44">Wdttingまnm嗜</head><p>The sentcnces are glven a rd-剛 e WhiCh represcnts correlation of thc sentcnces to the g市en qucry.Thc score of a sentence is suln ofthe length oftheド 、 ̲し 口 γ dSfOund in the sentcnce''.</p><p>By the cnd of this step,we have f0110wing parameters for documcnts: daQ」cr</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="11,177.12,363.46,188.19,42.61">, ヵ frr̲trQrag′ d だ …</formula><p>e , aは "″ ″ each sentence from all related , sttqw-id 45 Sentqrcto ndwqk tranCatlql</p><p>The processed sentences are translated to network. The vertices in the network are two tlpes: entities and phrase called " sentence -node", formed by writing M-i!, ryd-tre-t4-id and sentenclid iogether i.e. &lt;fu_i6 khtnl_tra_tq_i6 :&lt;ent6;7:p--i6. The stqw-rdd s rctain rel-evan9-Wevalues along with them in the network. Now an edge from an entitY node and a sentence eiists if the entity derived from the sentence. Two sentences are connected only if their sgttg/,@_nO&amp; prefix matches tp 6 9A'/o The limitation leads sentences, with common ancestor at very near to the sentence ln a document html tree, are connected. In this way, we have links among sentences and sentences to entities. 46Ndrruakprodng we applied network mining algorithm to find answer entity nodes in the nelwork. It is-obvious that the answer entities are d=escendants of the sentences or its descendants for which the ."1.u*"" score is high. At the same time, we need to avoid sentences at very high level of the html tree to avoid more generic answers. Less number of rdghbr gltgre will give us the sentences at lowest level. The score that a sentence inherits to its descendants is equally distributed i.e. divided by rcighbrirg attlfieS In summary, the score of a sentence node on the network is: Score of a sentence: (rda/at@-..jwrel (court{naghbor altities,} * count{ rreighbr sffl€)</p><p>The entities might occur in more than one sentence and can inherit score from multiple sentences. The one score maximum of neighbor sentences is an entity's score' Scorc ofan cntity=max{∞ αθ Or り めαα 浦 " } The sentence which inherits the score(maX SCOre)to an entity is suppo面 ng document for thc entity in thc query context 47 Ranking nmork Ⅸ」∝ La gtiti</p><p>The enity nodes with their scores are sorted to rank By this time,wc have answcr endtics with their scores,rank and supporting docurnentid's a variatimsd ttbmittd runs Thanks to super computing facility at our university,wc wcre ablc to setup indH search cnginc lt madc us to tune the framcwork for bctter rcsults.We pickcd best four tunhgs from many For thc submission,we used thc top four variations: l CARDHTMLA:In this rlm we leveraged entity idcntincatiOn method to identi″ phrascs in given qucry namtives and■ en they are translated to indri query languagc to extract related documents.</p><p>2 CARDHTMLM: We manua‖ y identiflcd Phrascs in thc qucry narrativcs and then thcy arc transiatcd to indri query language to extract relatcd documcnts.</p><p>3 CARDHTMLB:For this we took advantage of extcmal wcb search cnghc frrひ The qucry </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>044</head><p>Besides the topic wise analysis of the results, we also summarized target entity type bases analysis' The following chart depicts the summary for run cARDHTMLA (automated query preprocessing).</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="15,201.24,461.54,5.00,8.33">6</ref> : Average Precision scores ofeach topic for the fow runs Automatic run employ high nDCG values while CARDHTML (no query processing) shows high Mean Average Precision (MAP) scores.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="17,111.24,272.54,5.00,8.33">7</ref> : average nDCG and Mean Averag€ Precision oftopics based on entity types for CARDHTMLA run Thc charts i嘔 増 ureコ 巨 Cd血 江 。 W ttproach perfonlts bctterお r bcatbn bascd que五c,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">Cmdudmsand Futurewdk</head><p>The primary aim ofthe track is to answer (in specific, answer entities) a given question. This paper had shown a novel methodologr to identifo entities and to rank them in context to the given query. With the advantage of several thirdlarty parsers like html parser, sentence parser, we were able to extract_semantic relationi-hip among entitiei and ientences. Such relationship constituted to a network which further eased our task to rank thi entities. The results shown are promising when we evaluated the queries with TREC organizers provided results. This work proves one more time that network mining algorithms can address complex problems with simple solutions. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>&amp; Rd€r€ne</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>G. Tummarellffifl</head><p>In ttal,GJR 2977 [101</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="5,217.80,601.22,170.81,9.41"><head>Figure 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3 Finding query r€levant documents</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="7,112.68,274.68,415.00,10.00;7,67.68,286.27,465.78,12.24;7,319.68,305.50,53.50,53.50;7,409.32,304.42,53.50,53.50;7,68.76,359.14,42.50,8.50;7,68.76,378.29,132.38,15.59;7,68.76,405.00,235.04,12.59;7,314.64,400.25,131.75,15.50;7,448.56,406.22,21.50,21.50;7,464.04,413.57,19.50,13.00;7,486.72,405.50,38.42,21.86;7,515.52,411.98,28.00,14.00;7,69.48,421.34,333.00,9.00;7,65.52,431.21,364.56,12.46;7,69.48,488.59,147.58,32.38;7,207.72,500.26,54.34,16.00;7,253.80,487.51,61.90,31.30;7,310.32,497.23,59.50,17.00;7,370.08,485.35,166.68,32.74;7,70.20,523.15,266.00,9.50"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>11lulated qucry is requested to indri whch rems us query rclated docurnent id'S ove use this Crac′ d later for neヽ vork constructioD USing dJwindχ utility of indri,corrcsponding 鸞 鞣 section 4. 4 Doalm日咸 spr一 ng The"are 150 documcnts hm ttc Chewcb09 CO■ e onwhthcmcontJnw髪 瀧 l瞥 ぶ 鵬 :Rコ let us considcrˋˋclucweb09-cn00-123456"is one ofthe rcsult documents i e o IFttu 4卜howsぬ c Steps invo市 ed hぬ c documcnt proccsJng for ranHng cnitお s.胸 庶 出 詭 胤 習 簿 :∬戦 鷺 譜 椒 1:lll濡 絆 見 舅 昴 珊電 ftⅧ and rcprescnts position ofthe text node in the documcnt.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="7,70.20,546.05,112.34,15.50;7,70.56,569.81,435.75,10.50;7,519.48,564.77,17.90,10.50;7,70.56,583.49,455.91,10.72;7,70.92,606.53,23.25,15.50"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>42Smm∝ ddc離:m A text node mlght contain more than onc sentcnce.For thc reason,cach text node is缶 雌r dH■ ed to settent into sentences. Each sentcnce is assigned a unique nurncric id callcd i獄</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="9,201.24,374.42,203.47,11.46"><head>Figure 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4 Document Processing and ftllrking €ntities</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
