<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,168.62,151.07,258.31,13.34">DUTI R at TREC 2011: Chemical I R Track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,194.21,190.56,46.33,8.89"><forename type="first">Ping</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<email>pingzhang@mail.dlut.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Information Retrieval Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalian University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116024</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,253.13,190.56,48.99,8.89"><forename type="first">Hongfei</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
							<email>hflin@dlut.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Information Retrieval Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalian University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116024</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,310.49,190.56,38.66,8.89"><forename type="first">Jiajin</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
							<email>wujiajin@mail.dlut.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Information Retrieval Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalian University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116024</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,359.95,190.56,37.96,8.89"><forename type="first">Yuan</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
							<email>yuanlin@mail.dlut.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Information Retrieval Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalian University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116024</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,168.62,151.07,258.31,13.34">DUTI R at TREC 2011: Chemical I R Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">D05ACEB88075C04C30CE9E706055604A</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:06+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper presents the DUTIR submission to TREC 2011 Chemical IR Track. Several experiments are done mainly with two retrieval models i.e. Language Model for IR and DFR model. In addition, query expansion technology is also applied to enhance retrieval performance.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Our methods for Technology Survey task</head><p>There are several fields could be used in the TS topics, such as title, narrative, chemicals and so on. In general, title field is the most important part in the topic. So we use title field, and adapt some query formatting methods to generate our query and use different retrieval model to get the results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">TSRun1-QL+PE</head><p>Our baseline run is DUT11TSRun1, in which we use Query-Likelihood model as our retrieval model, and the Lemur4.12 toolkit <ref type="bibr" coords="1,329.42,593.69,11.77,8.89" target="#b0">[1]</ref> is used as our basic retrieval system. With the indri query system in Lemur, documents are retrieved for the given query by query-likelihood language model <ref type="bibr" coords="2,302.42,150.24,10.71,8.89" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, in which D-smoothing method <ref type="bibr" coords="2,448.83,150.24,11.79,8.89" target="#b2">[3]</ref> is used. In this run, we empirically set the Dirichlet prior to 1500.</p><p>In addition, we also adapt the Phrase Expansion model <ref type="bibr" coords="2,368.20,174.24,11.75,8.89" target="#b3">[4]</ref> during the process of query generation. The Phrase expansion model can be simply described as follows: query terms are likely to appear in close proximity to each other within relevant documents. Take the topic TS-28 D-ala-D-ala ligase inhibitors for example; relevant documents may contain the phrases D-ala-D-ala and ligase inhibitors within relatively close proximity to each other. The phrase expansion model takes this situation into consideration. For example, to the topic TS-20, we generate the final query:</p><p>#weight (0.85 #combine (tests HCG hormone) 0.1 #combine (#1(tests HCG) #1(HCG hormone) #1(tests HCG hormone)) 0.05 #combine (#uw8 (tests HCG) #uw8 (tests hormone) #uw8 (HCG hormone) #uw12 (tests HCG hormone)))</p><p>With these methods, we generate our baseline run.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">TSRun2-QL+PE+QE</head><p>DUT11TSRun2, which is based on the DUT11TSRun1, also employs the Query-Likelihood retrieval model and use the Phrase Expansion method to construct object query. Moreover, Query Expansion technology is also employed in this run. We mainly use the pseudo-relevance Feedback (PRF) method, which has been shown to be an effective way of improving retrieval performance. We select the top 10 documents in the retrieved document list for a topic, and construct a relevance model from them. Then the original query is extended with the 50 terms that are not stopwords with the highest likelihood from the relevance model. The final form of the Indri query is: # (weight 0.8 #combine (q 1 q N ) 0.2 #combine (e 1 e 50 ))</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">TSRun3-In_expB2</head><p>The DUT11TSRun3 is different from the first two runs, and the In_expB2 weighting model <ref type="bibr" coords="2,194.75,526.37,11.78,8.89" target="#b4">[5]</ref> is employed. This retrieval model is derived from the Divergence from Randomness (DFR) framework. The relevance score between a document d and a query q can be denoted as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,189.94,561.40,280.85,70.76">2 / 1 score( , ) * * *log ( ) _ exp *log (1 / ) ( 1)/( *( 1)) _ exp *(1 ) e t q qtf df N d q TF qtf norm n TF tf avdl dl norm tf df TF n d f e (1)</formula><p>where N denotes the number of the documents in the collection, tf is within-document term frequency, qtf is within-query term frequency, df is the number of documents in which term t is appeared, dl is the length of the document and avdl is the average document length over the whole collection. It is a parameter-free model, so there is no parameter that needs to be tuned. In addition, we use description field in the patent collection as the search field, and take title field in the given topic as the query. Then this run is generated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">TSRun4-In_expB2+QE</head><p>Our official run DUT11TSRun4, which is based on the DUT11TSRun3, is also used the DFR framework. Besides, Query Expansion technology is adopted in this run. We set the description field as the expansion field, and we also select 10 documents in the first retrieval results as the expansion source. Then we select the top 50 terms with the highest likelihood as the expansion terms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Our methods for Prior Art task</head><p>The Prior Art task contains a subtask that asks the participants to submit the results for the first 100 topics (PA-1001 to PA-1100) in the query patent list. We only submit the results for this subtask. With the combination of query generation methods and retrieval methods, we generate 9 runs in all. We divide them into four groups: Simple QL (PARun1-3)&amp;Simple DFR (PARun6, PARun8), Query Generation &amp; DFR (PARun7) and Query Generation &amp; QL (PARun4-5, PARun9). We ll introduce them in details.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Simple QL&amp; Simple DFR</head><p>This group of runs is similar with TSRun1 and TSRun2. DUT11PARun1is a simply Query-likelihood run, and only uses title field in the topic as the query.DUT11PARun2 is based on DUT11PARun1, and adopts the Phrase Expansion technology to form the object query. The DUT11PARun3 is similar to DUT11PARun2; what s more, it also uses the query expansion technology. Simple DFR only takes words from title field in the topic as the query. DUT11PARun6 uses In_expB2 weighting model as retrieval model. And DUT11PARun8 is based on DUT11PARun6; in addition, query expansion technology described is applied.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Query Generation &amp; DFR</head><p>The query patent contains at least four fields i.e. title field, abstract field, claims field and description field. In DUT11PARun7, we generate the query using the words from title field, description field and claims field. We calculate the tf/idf score of each term that is not stopword and appeared in the above three fields in a topic, and select the top 30 terms that appeared in the title field or claims filed with the highest tf/idf scores as the query. The tf/idf equation is denoted as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,213.03,665.35,150.68,40.49">( ) log( ( ) * / ) ( ) ( ) i i i i Field Field i</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Score e tf e idf fieldLength</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Score e Score e (2)</head><p>We also use In_expB2 weighting model as our retrieval model. These generate our official run DUT11PARun7.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Query Generation &amp; QL</head><p>This group of runs uses the query-likelihood model as retrieval model and date filtering method to filter out the patents that are published after the query patent. As we all know, title field is important in the query patent. The DUT11PARun4takes the title field, description field and claims field into consideration. We use all title words and select sets of terms from the above three fields to construct our queries. First, we calculate term frequency of each term appeared in the above fields; second, we select top 30 terms that appeared in title field or claims field with highest term frequency. The final form of the query is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="4,134.78,313.91,297.49,10.19">#weight (w1 #combine (title) w2 #weight (tf 1 term 1 , tf 2 term 2 tf 30 term 30 ))</formula><p>we empirically set parameter w1 to 0.8 and w2 to 0.2, where tf i denotes the term frequency of term i .</p><p>The DUT11PARun5 is similar to the DUT11PARun4 and the only different lies in that it takes the tf/idf score as the criteria of terms selection. With comparison to the DUT11PARun7, the difference is the selection of retrieval model.</p><p>Our final run DUT11PARun9is a re-rank process of DUT11PARun5. The citation network <ref type="bibr" coords="4,160.30,404.31,11.76,8.89" target="#b5">[6]</ref> is introduced. For each retrieved patent i, we use all the scores of patents that reference to patent i and appeared in the retrieval results to enhance patent i. The equation is denoted as follows: where Score(i) is the origin score generated by the retrieval system. The parameter is_referenced i,j denotes that whether patent j is referenced to patent i. The parameter is empirically set to 0.005.With this equation, we calculate the FinalScore for each patent in the retrieved results and sort the patents by FinalScore in descending order. Then the final result is generated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experimental Results</head><p>In the preprocess of the document collection, we filter out some characters, such as -, , , : . Then we use blank space to segment words. During indexing and searching processes, Porter stemming and stopwords removing are done. We present our experimental results as follows.</p><p>Table1 and Table2 show our experimental results for Technology Survey and Prior Art Task respectively. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>In this paper, we present our submission to the TREC 2011 Chemical IR Track. We focus on the query generation and retrieval model selection. For the Technology Survey task, we use phrase expansion method and query expansion method to generate our query, and use Query-likelihood model, DFR model and D-smoothing method to do retrieve. For the Prior Art task, we use term frequency method, tf/idf method to generate our query, and also employ the retrieval model used in TS task to execute our experiments. In our future work, we will explore more novel methods for the query patent process.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="1,133.82,631.33,336.95,8.04;1,134.66,642.25,335.94,8.04;1,134.66,653.29,335.90,8.04;1,334.99,664.33,135.65,8.04;1,134.66,675.25,336.05,8.04;1,134.66,686.29,193.45,8.04"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>This work is supported by grant from the Natural Science Foundation of China (No.60673039and 60973068), the National High Tech Research and Development Plan of China (No.2006AA01Z151), National Social Science Foundation of China (No.08BTQ025), undation for the Returned Overseas Chinese Scholars, State Education Ministry and The Research Fund for the Doctoral Program of Higher Education (No.20090041110002).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,202.37,149.66,190.59,76.38"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Results of TS task in terms of map and ndcg</figDesc><table coords="5,223.37,170.02,160.04,56.02"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>NDCG</cell></row><row><cell>DUT11TSRun1</cell><cell>0.1399</cell><cell>0.3876</cell></row><row><cell>DUT11TSRun2</cell><cell>0.1237</cell><cell>0.3704</cell></row><row><cell>DUT11TSRun3</cell><cell>0.1309</cell><cell>0.3824</cell></row><row><cell>DUT11TSRun4</cell><cell>0.1305</cell><cell>0.3319</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,138.02,248.42,299.48,135.57"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Resuts of PA task for 6 popular measures</figDesc><table coords="5,138.02,268.81,299.48,115.18"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>bpref</cell><cell>MRR</cell><cell>P_20</cell><cell cols="2">Recall_100 NDCG</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">DUT11PARun1 0.0225</cell><cell>0.2944</cell><cell>0.1417</cell><cell>0.0530</cell><cell>0.0967</cell><cell>0.1441</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">DUT11PARun2 0.0259</cell><cell>0.3071</cell><cell>0.1520</cell><cell>0.0630</cell><cell>0.1049</cell><cell>0.1531</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">DUT11PARun3 0.0323</cell><cell>0.3525</cell><cell>0.1552</cell><cell>0.0745</cell><cell>0.1198</cell><cell>0.1758</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">DUT11PARun4 0.0249</cell><cell>0.2993</cell><cell>0.1745</cell><cell>0.0580</cell><cell>0.1020</cell><cell>0.1503</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">DUT11PARun5 0.0293</cell><cell>0.3253</cell><cell>0.1827</cell><cell>0.0665</cell><cell>0.1130</cell><cell>0.1643</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">DUT11PARun6 0.0151</cell><cell>0.2345</cell><cell>0.1186</cell><cell>0.0310</cell><cell>0.0664</cell><cell>0.1110</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">DUT11PARun7 0.0305</cell><cell>0.3457</cell><cell>0.1724</cell><cell>0.0585</cell><cell>0.1307</cell><cell>0.1745</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">DUT11PARun8 0.0207</cell><cell>0.2953</cell><cell>0.1116</cell><cell>0.0350</cell><cell>0.0893</cell><cell>0.1410</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">DUT11PARun9 0.0617</cell><cell>0.3283</cell><cell>0.3529</cell><cell>0.1195</cell><cell>0.1715</cell><cell>0.2109</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,145.22,580.30,159.02,8.04" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://www.lemurproject.org" />
		<title level="m" coord="5,145.22,580.30,50.54,8.04">Lemur Project</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,145.22,590.62,325.33,8.04;5,145.22,600.94,182.11,8.04" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,255.14,590.62,201.68,8.04">A language modeling approach to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ponte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,145.22,600.94,95.35,8.04">Proceedings of SIGIR1998</title>
		<meeting>SIGIR1998</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="281" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,145.22,611.38,325.16,8.04;5,145.22,621.73,322.00,8.04" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,236.32,611.38,234.06,8.04;5,145.22,621.73,73.60,8.04">A study of smoothing methods for language models applied to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lafferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,223.86,621.73,155.09,8.04">ACM Transactions on Information Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="214" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,145.22,632.05,324.97,8.04;5,145.22,642.37,232.13,8.04" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,336.77,632.05,129.63,8.04">Indri at TREC 2004: Terabyte Track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Metzler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Strohman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Turtle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,154.93,642.37,174.33,8.04">Proceedings of 2004 Text Retrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>2004 Text Retrieval Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,145.22,652.81,325.21,8.04;5,145.22,663.13,327.67,8.04" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,188.85,652.81,281.57,8.04;5,145.22,663.13,41.07,8.04">Probabilistic models for information retrieval based on divergence from randomness</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Department of Computing Science, University of Glasgow</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">PhD thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,145.22,673.45,325.13,8.04;5,145.22,683.77,302.84,8.04" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,317.46,673.45,152.89,8.04;5,145.22,683.77,66.80,8.04">Report on the TREC 2009 Experiments: Chemical IR Track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gobeill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Teodoro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Patsche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Ruch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,227.81,683.77,174.40,8.04">Proceedings of 2009 Text Retrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting>2009 Text Retrieval Conference<address><addrLine>TREC</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
