<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,150.26,94.60,294.87,14.36">ICTNET at Web Track 2011 Diversity Task</title>
				<funder ref="#_MCVujYq #_YgyUG2E">
					<orgName type="full">NSF of China</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_PCbnkbK #_yr2xTeD">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,163.94,122.70,50.60,8.96"><forename type="first">Shengxian</forename><surname>Wan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computing Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,221.45,122.70,41.88,8.96"><forename type="first">Yuanhai</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computing Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Graduate School of Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,270.54,122.70,43.16,8.96"><forename type="first">Xiaoming</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computing Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,318.05,122.70,36.19,8.96"><forename type="first">Feng</forename><surname>Guan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computing Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,359.17,122.70,23.65,8.96"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computing Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,387.20,122.70,42.80,8.96"><forename type="first">Xueqi</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Computing Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>100190</postCode>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,150.26,94.60,294.87,14.36">ICTNET at Web Track 2011 Diversity Task</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">9FAEA8B1840C0A002C2A649E401AC2E9</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:06+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.32" lry="841.92"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Traditional IR systems use document-query relevance as the main measure for ranking and consider the relevance is independent of the other documents. However, the only measure of relevance cannot deal with redundant information and can fail to reflect the broad range of user needs that can underlie a query. IR systems need to consider the diversity and novelty of the result list. Diversity task is trying to solve this problem. The goal of diversity task is to return a ranked list of pages that together provide complete coverage for a query, while avoiding excessive redundancy in the result list. This year, the primary evaluation measure is intent aware expected reciprocal rank (ERR-IA) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,444.67,291.54,7.68,5.83" target="#b0">[1]</ref> , some other evaluation measures such as Î±-nDCG <ref type="bibr" coords="1,242.93,307.38,7.56,5.83" target="#b0">[1]</ref> have also been evaluated. This paper is organized as follows. Section 2 describes different clustering methods used for text clustering. Section 3 describes our query expansion method. Section 4 describes the diversity model used for re-ranking. Section 5 analyzes the result and in section 6 we conclude our work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Clustering</head><p>We obtained all relevant documents of a query by techniques used in ad hoc task. The first run of this year's ad hoc task was used as the input of diversity task. In order to diversify the result list, we tried to obtain the sub-topic information of each query and documents relevance of each sub-topic.</p><p>Clustering is a naturally method to cope with this problem, it can divide documents into different set by document similarity. There are different clustering methods can be used, such as k -means, PAM, Hierarchy Clustering, OPTICS and so on. In last year's diversity task, we used bisecting k-means <ref type="bibr" coords="1,487.18,478.16,7.56,5.83" target="#b1">[2]</ref> to cluster the search result and considered that each cluster represented one subtopic.</p><p>There is one obvious drawback of bisecting k-means. It is a hard clustering method and that is to say, each document can belong to only one cluster. This is not true in real scene. One document can contain more than one sub-topic of a query. For example, one wiki page may contain almost every popular sub-topic of a query. In order to solve this problem, we tried to use fuzzy clustering instead of hard clustering and selected fuzzy c-means <ref type="bibr" coords="1,271.25,571.76,7.56,5.83" target="#b2">[3]</ref> as our main clustering method. One problem of using fuzzy c-means is how to determine the argument K just like k-means. Our solution is using bisecting k-means first and then using fuzzy c-means to re-cluster the documents based on the result of bisecting k-means.</p><p>We used vector space model (VSM) to represent documents and used cosine distance between document vectors as the distance between documents. The dimension of document vector was very high if using all the words appeared in the document set. There was too much noise in the high dimension vector and it made document distance inaccurate. We found the words appeared in the keyword region of each document are representative and we used all the keywords of the whole document set as universal word set while ignoring other words. We still considered each cluster as one subtopic, and got document-sub-topic relevance by degree of membership between document and cluster.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Query expansion</head><p>Query expansion is an effective method to boost recall and precision in IR systems. It reformulates a seed query and compensates the problem of insufficient information of the query. In diversity task, the queries are commonly very short and the real user intent is not obvious. We tried to use query expansion to cover as more probable user intents as possible. According to our experience in TREC 2009 and TREC 2010, query expansion is effective to improve the result and we also used this method in TREC 2011.</p><p>We expanded the queries by commercial search engines Bing and Google. For that wiki has little information about most of the queries, we did not use it. We parsed query expansions from Bing's and Google's websites and considered each expansion as one subtopic. We used these expansions as new queries to retrieve documents from the whole corpus. By the result ranking list, we got the relevance between each document and each subtopic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Diversity model</head><p>Many scholars have modeled the diversity and novelty of information retrieval based on different perspectives. Our model is based on xQuAD <ref type="bibr" coords="2,273.29,323.94,7.56,5.83" target="#b3">[4]</ref> proposed by Santos in 2010. xQuAD explicitly models an ambiguous query as a set of sub-queries. It greedily selects one document every time based on the following probability formula:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,177.02,374.98,327.25,23.96">(1 -Î»)P(d|q) + Î» âˆ‘ [ğ‘ƒ(ğ‘ ğ‘– |ğ‘)ğ‘ƒ(ğ‘‘|ğ‘ ğ‘– ) âˆ(1 -ğ‘ƒ(ğ‘‘ ğ‘— |ğ‘ ğ‘– ) ğ‘‘ ğ‘— âˆˆğ‘† ] ğ‘ ğ‘– âˆˆğ‘„ (1)</formula><p>Where q is the initial query, Q is the sub-topic set of qï¼Œğ‘ ğ‘– is a sub-topic in Q, S is documents selected and d represents a document, ğ‘ƒ(ğ‘‘|ğ‘) is the likelihood of document d being observed given the initial query q, ğ‘ƒ(ğ‘ ğ‘– |ğ‘) can be seen as a measure of the relative importance of the sub-topic ğ‘ ğ‘– , ğ‘ƒ(ğ‘‘|ğ‘ ğ‘– ) is a measure of the coverage of document d with respect to the sub-topic ğ‘ ğ‘– . We can regard the first part of the formula as modeling the relevance and the last part as modeling the diversity. The coefficient ğœ† measures the weight between relevance and diversity.</p><p>We changed this model in our work. First, we used more than one method to mining the subtopic.</p><p>Different methods may have different contributions for our problem and thus we tried to mix them all.</p><p>We divided the diversity part of (1) and gave a weight to each method. Second, we considered âˆ (1 -ğ‘ƒ(ğ‘‘ ğ‘— |ğ‘ ğ‘– ))</p><p>ğ‘‘ ğ‘— âˆˆğ‘† of ( <ref type="formula" coords="2,196.98,543.71,3.90,8.96">1</ref>) is to penalize redundant for each sub-topic and gave different subtopic different speed of weight decreasing. There are two reasons, first, if one subtopic is more popular, or more important, more pages may be needed to satisfy people's information needs and thus the speed of weight decreasing should be lower. The second reason is from practical point of view. We may get noise sub-topics in practice, if they are treated the same as correct sub-topics, according to (1), the result list will include many document of the noise sub-topic. We used ğ‘ƒ(ğ‘ ğ‘– |ğ‘), the measure of the subtopic's relative importance, to change the speed of weight decreasing. Besides, the diversity part of (1) will decrease exponentially and make little function quickly. In our work we normalize the weight of sub-topic after redundant punishment each time. Our formula is as follows: </p><p>Where ğ‘€ represents all methods we used in practice and ğ‘¤ ğ‘˜ is the weight of the kth method.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Result</head><p>In TREC 2011, we submitted three runs for diversity task. In run 1, we used both bisecting k-means clustering and query expansion. The method is similar with which we used in TREC 2010 diversity task but we modified the method in details. We considered this run as a baseline. In run 2, we used bisecting k-means first and then used fuzzy c-means to re-cluster the result as we described in Section 2, we used the diversity model described in Section 4 to re-rank the result. In run 3, we used the same clustering method and diversity model of run 2 but we combined the query expansion method in order to see how significant the effective of query expansion is. The result is listed in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,230.99,313.05,3.79,8.96" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. We can see that run 3 is slightly better than run 1.The fuzzy clustering method boosts the result but the effect is not as good as we supposed. According to run 2 and run 3, we can see that query expansion plays an important role in our method.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusion and Future work</head><p>We describe our experiment of diversity task in this report. This year, we applied new clustering method to cluster the documents and used new diversity model to re-rank them. Though fuzzy clustering seems more suitable for diversity task naturally but it only improved the result slightly in our</p><p>experiments. Yet we still believe it is worth for future research. Besides, we find that query expansion improved the result significantly.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,101.30,699.27,107.71,10.32;2,208.61,704.01,4.21,6.96;2,178.58,714.81,21.12,8.31;2,215.21,699.63,53.13,9.96;2,268.13,704.01,2.44,6.96;2,271.25,699.27,29.83,11.40;2,301.25,705.09,15.90,8.43;2,319.49,699.63,22.79,9.96;2,342.07,704.01,2.44,6.96;2,345.19,699.27,69.02,10.32;2,413.35,704.01,3.26,6.96;2,417.31,699.63,8.61,9.96;2,425.71,704.01,2.44,6.96;2,428.83,699.63,8.57,9.96;2,437.47,698.01,23.77,8.67;2,359.83,714.81,15.97,8.43;2,461.71,699.63,10.93,9.96;2,221.21,714.81,15.90,8.43;2,474.82,699.63,5.93,9.96"><head>( 1 -</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Î»)P(d|q) + Î» âˆ‘ ğ‘¤ ğ‘˜ ğ‘š ğ‘˜ âˆˆğ‘€ , âˆ‘ *ğ‘ƒ(ğ‘‘|ğ‘ ğ‘– ) ğ‘ğ‘œğ‘Ÿğ‘š ğ‘ ğ‘– âˆˆğ‘„ (ğ‘ƒ(ğ‘ ğ‘– |ğ‘) âˆ(1 -ğ‘ƒ(ğ‘‘ ğ‘— |ğ‘ ğ‘– )) ğ‘ƒ(ğ‘ ğ‘– |ğ‘)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,108.02,217.10,361.66,74.08"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Performance of our runs in TREC 2011 diversity task</figDesc><table coords="3,108.02,217.10,361.66,57.97"><row><cell>RUN</cell><cell>ERR-IA@20</cell><cell>nERR-IA@20</cell><cell>Î±-DCG</cell><cell>Î±-nDCG</cell></row><row><cell>ICTNET11DVR1</cell><cell>0.4716</cell><cell>0.5102</cell><cell>0.5442</cell><cell>0.5795</cell></row><row><cell>ICTNET11DVR2</cell><cell>0.4603</cell><cell>0.5001</cell><cell>0.5274</cell><cell>0.5638</cell></row><row><cell>ICTNET11DVR3</cell><cell>0.4764</cell><cell>0.5150</cell><cell>0.5458</cell><cell>0.5818</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>Thank all the organizers of TREC 2011. Thank all the participants and assessors. We really appreciate of your efforts. This work is sponsored by <rs type="funder">NSF of China</rs> Grants No. <rs type="grantNumber">60903139</rs> and No. <rs type="grantNumber">60873243</rs>, and by <rs type="programName">863 Program</rs> of China Grants No. <rs type="grantNumber">2010AA012502</rs> and No. <rs type="grantNumber">2010AA012503</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_MCVujYq">
					<idno type="grant-number">60903139</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_YgyUG2E">
					<idno type="grant-number">60873243</idno>
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">863 Program</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_PCbnkbK">
					<idno type="grant-number">2010AA012502</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_yr2xTeD">
					<idno type="grant-number">2010AA012503</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="3,111.86,578.27,393.03,8.96;3,110.06,593.87,303.20,8.96" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,353.54,578.27,151.34,8.96;3,110.06,593.87,141.58,8.96">A Comparative Analysis of Cascade Measures for Novelty and Diversity</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L A</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Craswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Soboroff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ashkan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,269.09,593.87,59.47,8.96">Proc. of WSDM</title>
		<meeting>of WSDM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="84" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,111.86,609.47,379.57,8.96;3,110.06,625.07,211.44,8.96" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,271.73,609.47,204.39,8.96">A Comparison of Document Clustering Techniques</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Steinbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Karypis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,110.06,625.07,127.63,8.96">KDD Workshop on Text Mining</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="34" to="35" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,111.74,640.67,393.65,8.96;3,110.06,656.30,56.73,8.96" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="3,168.98,640.67,250.95,8.96">Pattern Recognition with Fuzzy Objective Function Algoritms</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Bezdek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1981-07-31">July 31, 1981</date>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>1 edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,111.86,671.90,371.61,8.96;3,110.06,687.50,254.90,8.96" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,283.85,671.90,199.62,8.96;3,110.06,687.50,86.49,8.96">Exploiting Query Reformulations for Web Search Result Diversification</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L T</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Ounis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,213.89,687.50,55.31,8.96">Proc. of WWW</title>
		<meeting>of WWW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="881" to="890" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
