<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,138.80,168.52,333.66,10.78;1,285.63,190.44,39.99,10.78">Medical-Miner at TREC 2011 Medical Records Track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,144.70,222.53,68.10,6.50"><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Córdoba</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Huelva</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,227.28,222.53,52.88,6.50"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Maña</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Huelva</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,295.23,222.53,48.53,6.50"><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Cruz</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Huelva</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,357.98,222.53,37.34,6.50"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mata</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Huelva</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Europea de Madrid</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,410.01,222.53,56.10,6.50"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Aparicio</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad Europea de Madrid</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,188.80,236.48,59.26,6.50"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Buenaga</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Vigo</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,262.60,236.48,65.75,6.50"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Glez-Peña</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Universidad de Vigo</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,342.51,236.48,84.68,6.50"><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Fdez-Riverola</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,138.80,168.52,333.66,10.78;1,285.63,190.44,39.99,10.78">Medical-Miner at TREC 2011 Medical Records Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">1373FCFCA005A51C5035C89B88F6F34D</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:06+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper presents work done at Medical Minner Project on the TREC-2011 Medical Records Track. The paper proposes four models for medical information retrieval based on Lucene index approach. Our retrieval engine used an Lucen Index scheme with traditional stopping and stemming, enhanced with entity recognition software on query terms. Our aim in this rst competition is to set a broader project that involves the develop of a congurable Apache Lucene-based framework that allows the rapid development of medical search facilities. Results around the track median have been achieved. In this exploratory track, we think that these results are a good beginning and encourage us for future developments.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Clinical databases have accumulated large quantities of information about patients and their medical conditions. Relationships and patterns within this data could provide new medical knowledge. Unfortunately, few methodologies have been developed and applied to discover this hidden knowledge. In the TREC framework, Medical Records track encourages to research on providing contentbased access to the free-text elds of electronic medical records. Related with this same research area, the Medical Minner initiative 1 works for provide new useful tools in this environment, enabling the achievement of a double benet: rst, to provide specic and relevant mechanisms to a professional environment (biomedical), and secondly, obtaining innovative techniques and signicant advances in research in the area of information retrieval, particularly on this domain, and based on a signicant integration eort. In this context, this paper presents the models developed for our rst participation in TREC, particularly in the Medical Records track.</p><p>1 http://www.medicalminer.org 1 This paper is organised as follows. In Section 2 we describe some of the ways have been used to represent the documents elds in reports processing, and describe the way the index used in our later experiments is built automatically from document collection. In Section 3 we cover the overall architecture of a indexing application and where Lucene ts. The document retrieval models described in Section 4. This section, also covers the further development and elaboration of the models. Data and results tables are given in Section 5 with key results summarised. Finally, in Section 6, some conclusions are provided.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Document Collection Preprocessing</head><p>Assuming the system has access to a large document collection as a knowledge resource for answering medical topics, this collection may need to be processed before querying, in order to transform it into a form which is appropriate for topic answering. Thus, in order to eective TREC medical visits retrieval, some issues need to be solved. First, reports need to be grouped into visits. Next, XML Reports must be adapted to be queried in a rapid and accurate way.</p><p>Additionally, another type of additional processing can be performed. In our case, we used the ICD codes for better retrieval.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Visit Procesing</head><p>As the Medical Records track will use the visit as the answer unit then is there need for additional processing in order to group the reports into visits. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">XML Parsing</head><p>We need to quickly search a collection of XML documents, and, to do this, we need to create an index of terms keeping track of the context in which these terms appear. Our solution uses Apache Lucene and the Java SAX library in order to create an index of Lucene Document objects for the lowest level of granularity to search. In order to have a testing framework as complete as possible, all reports elds have been processed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">ICD9 Mining</head><p>The </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Retrieval approaches</head><p>This section presents the dierent models developed for evaluation. Among the models developed four have been selected for submission: Baseline 2 , Medical Face 3 , BWRTDDD 4 and BWRTDDD2 5 . From the four topics samples review, we consider using some alternative models to the nal runs. Although discard some models, we believe interesting to include a review of these unused models that can have interesting for scientic community. The retrieval module completes the visits retrieval process. The subsequent processes of assessment and results extraction have been implemented according to the TREC eval utilities. The overall process can be seen in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,438.55,153.69,3.87,6.64">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Baseline</head><p>This model has been designed to be the simplest approximation to the task. The Baseline model is based on the method of the bag of words. In this model, topics text is represented as an unordered collection of words, disregarding grammar and even word order. Therefore, the model matches the words in the topic with the words contained in the index. The usefulness of the model is twofold:</p><p>provides a basis results for comparing and, on the other hand, its code serves as a basis for implementing more complex models. In order to maintain the simplicity, the baseline model makes match the topics words with the words contained in the eld report text.</p><p>To develop this model we used a very simple analyzer. The analyzer takes only the topic and provides a set of terms to be searched in the index. Our base analyzer discards stops words with little semantic value, such as "the", "a", "an","for",.... Cutting down on the number of terms indexed can save time and space in an index, but it can also limit accuracy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Medical Face</head><p>MedicalMiner initiative brings together three research groups from Huelva, Vigo and Madrid European Universities. MedicalMiner initiative proposes to analyse, experiment and develop new text and data mining techniques in an interrelated way, in intelligent medical information systems. An intelligent information access system based on them will be developed, oering advanced functionalities able to interrelate medical information, mainly information (text and data) from clinical records and scientic documentation, making use of standard resources of the domain (e.g. UMLS, SNOMED, Gene Ontology). An open source platform will be developed integrating all the elements <ref type="bibr" coords="5,362.20,497.30,9.96,6.64" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. A main component of this platform is Medical Face 6 . Medical Face is a Biomedical text annotation system using multiple ontologies. In its simplest form, Medical Face takes a input text and makes medical entity recognition over this text.</p><p>For our approach, Medical Face has been used to develop an analyzer that extracts relevant entities in the medical domain from the topics. This relevant entities are used to search for relevant documents in the generated index during indexing process. In this model, only the report text eld is taken account.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">BWRTDDD</head><p>The BWRTDDD model is based on the method of the bag of words in a similar way of the baseline model. Unlike the baseline model this model takes into 6 http://orion.esp.uem.es:8080/MedicalFace/mt.html account the report text and the modied discharge diagnosis elds. The modied discharge diagnosis eld is a modied version of the eld that takes account a textual description of ICD9 codes generated during preprocessing process. In addition, a specic analyzer has been developed for processing the items.</p><p>Like our base analyzer, the BWRTDDD analyzer discards common English words with little semantic value, such as "the", "a", "an","for",..... Additionaly, some irrelevant terms are removed from the topic (patient, for example).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Exploring Age and Gender</head><p>In the rst exploration of the sample topics, we think that would be interesting to identify genre and age in the topics and reports. It is easy to detect the occurrence of words that help classify subjects by patient gender and/or age (like woman or elderly). While gender can be detected directly in both the topics and reports, age can be estimated from some labels in the topics (young, adult, elderly,...) and reports (**AGE[in XXs]yearold). With this simple approach we can match those relevant visits to a topic according to age and gender. Unfortunately, this approach has been unsuccessful with the test topics by the small number of examples that show some of these features (only the adult, children, female and women tags have been found by this model).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Explore Negation</head><p>Another way that looked promising was the negation detection. Usually, narrative reports in medical records contain a wealth of information that may augment structured data for managing patient information and predicting trends in diseases. Pertinent negatives are evident in text but are dicult to automatic processing. In our preliminary study of the sample topics, we saw that one of the examples contained a negation.</p><p>Our research group have experience in the development of new text mining techniques adapted to bilingual medical domain. Including basic operations of text categorization and information extraction, capable of addressing specic problems of special relevance in the domain, such as the treatment of negation.</p><p>In <ref type="bibr" coords="6,161.43,521.21,10.51,6.64" target="#b1">[2]</ref> we present a machine learning system that identify the negation and speculation signals in biomedical texts, in particular, in the BioScope corpus.</p><p>Using the <ref type="bibr" coords="6,193.23,545.12,10.51,6.64" target="#b1">[2]</ref> approach, a prototype to handle negation was developed. This model takes a topic to detect negation presence. If the topic has a negative part then the medical entities in the negative clausule are detected. A visit search are performed deleting those visits with presence of these negative entities.</p><p>Unfortunately, no topic with negative part was given, therefore, no model run was sent.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Results</head><p>This section shows the results for our four runs presented to the track (table <ref type="table" coords="8,465.86,423.94,3.87,6.64" target="#tab_2">1</ref>).</p><p>All our models results are around the evaluation median. In this exploratory track, we think that these results are a good beginning and encourage us for future developments. In despite of initial results, more analysis work needs to be developed. A deeply per topic study must be make. Due to the dierent topic types, a harder work should be performed to classify the behavior of each model depending on the topic type. About this idea, we have obtained some initial conclusions from the results in some topics. A rst improve to the overall system must be made in key concepts detection. At present, our research group are working in a open source platform for medical information retrieval.</p><p>By now, this platform uses Medline and Freebase as main source of medical concepts detection. Extreme cases (see gure 2), such as topic 104, show that using Medline and Freebase is not enough to detect key medical concepts such as osteopenia. In a similar way, our systems have dicult to process expressions like "anti-coagulant medications post-op" (topic 128) or "underwent minimally invasive abdominal surgery" (topic 131). On the other hand, this approximation work ne with usual concepts like Hepatitis C, HIV or coronary stent (topics 118 and 125). The use of new ways of keyword extraction based on medical terminology databases, like UMLS <ref type="bibr" coords="8,284.40,639.13,10.51,6.64" target="#b0">[1]</ref> and SNOMED <ref type="bibr" coords="8,363.10,639.13,9.96,6.64" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, are in our future plans.</p><p>About our models, the best results were obtained with the Baseline model.</p><p>Despite being the best model, there are no major dierences with other models.</p><p>When inspecting in detail the topics we have seen that an important number of them (14-15 depending on model) have better results with the alternative models (HUH2MFB, UHU3BWRTDDD, UHU4BWRTDDD2), better even track median (see table <ref type="table" coords="9,200.62,165.65,3.87,6.64" target="#tab_3">2</ref>). This performance in certain topics suggests that a better t in model parameters can give better results if a larger number of sample topics are available.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions</head><p>We have presented a novel runs of looking at the problem of medical text retrieval in the Medical Records Track framework. We feel that our models will provide eective retrieval in the order of track median. In our rst TREC participation, we feel that track goal has been met reasonably well by the runs proposed.</p><p>In the near future, we will make a more detailed study about results. We hope to get more facts about models performance and alternative ways to improve the models.</p><p>Apart from the send runs, new ways to improve the medical text retrieval have been proposed. Mainly we have shown our interest in detection of expressions of negation. We think that the detection of negation must be taken into account in the track future.</p><p>Our research group has gained experience on development of applied retrieval information systems <ref type="bibr" coords="9,225.59,399.74,9.96,6.64" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. We think This rst prototype developed to TREC is feasible to help medical domain experts and medical professionals to carry out patient record searches in a more accurate and eciently way.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="4,230.87,567.14,145.09,6.64"><head>2 3 Figure 1 :</head><label>31</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Prototype architecture.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="8,133.77,358.34,343.71,6.64;8,133.77,370.29,108.34,6.64;8,133.77,124.80,343.71,216.60"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Dierences in bpref between the submitted Medical-Miner runs and median results per topic.</figDesc><graphic coords="8,133.77,124.80,343.71,216.60" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" coords="4,133.77,223.49,343.72,326.72"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="4,133.77,223.49,343.72,326.72" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" coords="7,133.77,325.16,343.72,299.28"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="7,133.77,325.16,343.72,299.28" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="7,163.08,152.29,285.08,117.66"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Medical Minner Medical Records results at TREC 2011.</figDesc><table coords="7,192.85,152.29,225.55,96.10"><row><cell></cell><cell>bpref</cell><cell>R-prec</cell><cell>P@10</cell></row><row><cell>Best</cell><cell>0.7763</cell><cell>0.5917</cell><cell>0.9500</cell></row><row><cell>Median</cell><cell>0.4219</cell><cell>0.2924</cell><cell>0.4500</cell></row><row><cell>Worst</cell><cell>0.0000</cell><cell>0.0000</cell><cell>0.0000</cell></row><row><cell>UHU1BL</cell><cell>0.4534</cell><cell>0.3543</cell><cell>0.4000</cell></row><row><cell>UHU2MFB</cell><cell>0.4382</cell><cell>0.3103</cell><cell>0.3000</cell></row><row><cell>UHU3BWRTDDD</cell><cell>0.3709</cell><cell>0.1657</cell><cell>0.2000</cell></row><row><cell>UHU4BWRTDDD2</cell><cell>0.3709</cell><cell>0.1498</cell><cell>0.1000</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="7,180.18,641.38,246.46,6.64"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Color data indicating results best than median.</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="9,149.26,478.41,328.21,6.64;9,149.26,490.00,328.22,7.13;9,149.26,502.32,22.69,6.64" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,225.74,478.41,251.73,6.64;9,149.26,490.36,100.68,6.64">The unied medical language system (umls): integrating biomedical terminology</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Bodenreider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,263.75,490.00,97.60,7.13">Nucleic acids research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>suppl 1):D267D270</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,149.26,522.24,328.22,6.64;9,149.26,534.20,328.22,6.64;9,149.26,545.79,219.32,7.13" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,312.82,522.24,164.66,6.64;9,149.26,534.20,328.22,6.64;9,149.26,546.16,12.04,6.64">Aprendizaje automático versus expresiones regulares en la detección de la negación y la especulación en biomedicina</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Cruz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Maña</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<publisher>Procesamiento de Lenguaje Natural</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,149.26,566.08,328.21,6.64;9,149.26,578.04,328.22,6.64;9,149.26,589.99,328.21,6.64;9,149.26,601.58,258.06,7.13" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,193.39,578.04,284.09,6.64;9,149.26,589.99,328.21,6.64;9,149.26,601.95,50.17,6.64">Medical-miner: Integración de conocimiento textual explícito en técnicas de minería de datos para la creación de herramientas traslacionales en medicina</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>De Buenaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Fdez-Riverola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Maña</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Puertas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Glez-Peña</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mata</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<publisher>Procesamiento de Lenguaje Natural</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">45</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,149.26,621.87,328.21,6.64;9,149.26,633.46,328.22,7.13;9,149.26,645.42,132.67,7.13" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,381.35,621.87,96.13,6.64;9,149.26,633.83,256.79,6.64">A biomedical information retrieval system based on clustering for mobile devices</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Millán</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Muñoz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Villa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Maña</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<publisher>Procesamiento de Lenguaje Natural</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,149.26,129.78,328.22,6.64;10,149.26,141.37,328.22,7.13;10,149.26,153.33,328.21,7.13;10,149.26,165.65,78.69,6.64" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,409.04,129.78,68.44,6.64;10,149.26,141.74,283.12,6.64">Snomed clinical terms: overview of the development process and project status</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">Q</forename><surname>Stearns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Price</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Spackman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,458.38,141.37,19.10,7.13;10,149.26,153.33,143.88,7.13">Proceedings of the AMIA Symposium</title>
		<meeting>the AMIA Symposium</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">662</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
