<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,205.33,148.60,192.32,12.45;1,170.92,170.51,261.14,12.45">Search for Medical Records: NICTA at TREC 2011 Medical Track</title>
				<funder ref="#_mTpTQpF">
					<orgName type="full">Academy of Finland</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Australian government</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_rGbRGPB">
					<orgName type="full">Australian Research Council</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,127.49,204.71,80.21,10.99"><forename type="first">Sarvnaz</forename><surname>Karimi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept of CSSE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">NICTA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Melbourne</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,229.88,204.71,80.26,10.99"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Martinez</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept of CSSE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">NICTA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Melbourne</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,358.41,204.71,84.33,10.99"><forename type="first">Sumukh</forename><surname>Ghodke</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept of CSSE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">NICTA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Melbourne</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,133.89,218.77,69.09,10.99;1,202.99,217.36,1.88,7.32"><forename type="first">Lumin</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Max Planck Institute for Biological Cybernetic</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,225.60,218.77,87.46,10.99"><forename type="first">Hanna</forename><surname>Suominen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">NICTA and ANU</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">CECS</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,353.01,218.77,95.38,10.99"><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><surname>Cavedon</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept of CSSE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">NICTA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Melbourne</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,205.33,148.60,192.32,12.45;1,170.92,170.51,261.14,12.45">Search for Medical Records: NICTA at TREC 2011 Medical Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">C6321CF6EAA7CE244D9BA670B67CA1E2</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:06+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>NICTA (National ICT Australia) participated in the Medical Records track of TREC 2011 with seven automatic runs. The main techniques used in our submissions involved using Boolean retrieval for filtering, query transformation, and query expansion. Evaluation of our best run ranks our submissions higher than the median of all systems for this track, and stands at rank seven among 109 automatic runs which were submitted by the 29 participating groups.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>A medical record documents pertinent information concerning a given patients medical history, medical care, and current illnesses, typically across time and within a particular healthcare service providers jurisdiction. 1 This includes information needed for organizing, planning, performing, and controlling a good-quality medical care. The records consist of structured or numeric fields (approximately 60 per cent) and free text (approximately 40 per cent) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,393.89,488.08,9.95,9.96" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. More and more medical records are electronic.</p><p>Medical records allow healthcare professionals to provide appropriate and personalized care to their patients and customers. It is therefore important to develop searching capabilities that allow specific information to be extracted from a large number of records. The Medical Records track at TREC challenged participants with search in the free-text fields of electronic medical records. The test document collection for the Medical Records track was a set of de-identified medical records made available through the University of Pittsburgh BLULab NLP Repository. Reports associated with the same patient were identified and marked with unique visit identifiers. Participants received four sample queries, and 35 test queries. For the official evaluations, one of the test queries was omitted.</p><p>The NICTA team participated in the Medical Records track with three runs in the first round for pooling, and four official final runs. The main techniques used in our submission system were Boolean retrieval for filtering, query transformation, and query expansion. Details on these techniques are provided in the following sections. Throughout this report, depending on the context, we use "document" to refer to either each medical report (that is, an individual report in a medical record) or all reports related to a given visit.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Document Collection Pre-processing</head><p>Prior to indexing, we processed all reports in the collection for normalization and document expansion, as described below.</p><p>• The medical records that were provided for this track contained rich metadata on diagnostics associated with each report. We expanded mentions of ICD9 codes<ref type="foot" coords="2,430.53,196.38,3.97,6.72" target="#foot_0">2</ref> of admission and discharge diagnoses in the metadata with their descriptions as provided in ICD9 documents.</p><p>Both the original code and expanded forms were included for indexing.</p><p>• Sections of the report texts were extracted using their headings or hand-crafted patternmatching rules. To answer some of the queries, for example, we required to separate patients' history from their current condition. All reports were therefore processed to extract history (including patient history, past medical history, past surgical history), chief complaint, medications, allergies, admission and discharge diagnoses, and the full-text of the report. We used this information to create fields for Boolean search. The list of all such fields is given in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,153.93,313.06,3.87,9.96" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p><p>• Some of the demographic information, such as gender, age, and specific conditions, such as patients weight, were only mentioned in the text. We used pattern matching to extract and normalize this information. For example, for gender, we replaced mentions of gentleman, man, male, yo m, y/o M, boyW with gendermale, and mentions of lady, woman, female, wm, girlW with genderfemale.</p><p>• Documents were processed to identify negated terms. Identifying negations reduced false positive matches against query terms. For example, if a query asks for patients with chronic back pain documents containing no chronic back pain will match. To resolve this, we created a list of negated words by running NegEx<ref type="foot" coords="2,300.47,521.42,3.97,6.72" target="#foot_1">3</ref> over the entire collection. NegEx finds trigger terms (one word or multi-word expressions) that are clinical conditions negated in texts. Given a single term may have both positive and negative implications, we ignored negations that have more positive occurrences than negative within a report. All negated terms were replaced with a single word, no space, with a "no" prefix: e.g., if negation is implied for "chronic back pain", all instances of "chronic back pain" and its variants are replaced with the word "nochronicbackpain". This replacement is performed in the history, past history, present illness history, report text, medications, and allergies fields.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Query Processing</head><p>We used two levels of query processing to transform the bag-of-words queries into Boolean queries, and expand medical terms, as demonstrated below. Abbreviation seen in the er|presented to the er REPORT:("emergency room" OR ER)</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="3,117.75,433.09,3.87,9.96">2</ref>: Rules (patterns in the queries and their translations) used in the query transformation step. Words that are all in capital letters are field names.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Query Transformation</head><p>We developed a set of manually constructed patterns to map query terms into the available fields (Table <ref type="table" coords="3,122.15,517.17,3.87,9.96" target="#tab_0">1</ref>), translating them to the language of reports, or to expand them. These patternsformed based on the sample clinical questions provided by the National Library of Medicine (NLM) <ref type="bibr" coords="3,123.79,541.09,10.51,9.96" target="#b2">[3]</ref> -covered seven broad categories of age, weight (using body mass index), diagnostics, treatments, medications, history, allergies, and abbreviations. For example, if a query contained "elderly patients", we expanded "elderly" with an equivalent age field that covered people in their 60s to 90+. Table <ref type="table" coords="3,170.13,576.95,4.98,9.96">2</ref> shows the details of the selected transformation rules. For example the query:</p><p>Elderly patients with ventilator-associated pneumonia is translated to:</p><p>PRESTHIS:(ventilator associated pneumonia) OR DISCHDIAG:(ventilator associated pneumonia) OR AGE:(age60 age70 age80 age90) OR REPORT:(elderly with ventilator associated pneumonia).</p><p>A small number of abbreviations, such as ER (emergency room), were also expanded in the queries. <ref type="foot" coords="3,123.01,696.88,3.97,6.72" target="#foot_2">4</ref></p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Query Expansion</head><p>We leveraged external resources to add new terms to our queries, by identifying terms that are strongly related to the query terms. Specifically, we focused on query terms that represent medical categorical concepts (e.g. disease categories). For example, for the query below, we added terms falling under the category of "atypical antipsychotics":</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Patients taking atypical antipsychotics</head><p>Our approach to expansion used two main knowledge sources: the UMLS Metathesaurus (version 2010aa) and DBpedia. In order to select expansion candidates we used MetaMap-2010 from the National Library of Medicine (NLM). We defined manual expansion rules from these resources based on the sample queries and 50 priority queries from the NLM priority list.</p><p>For our final expansion system, we first applied MetaMap to identify phrases linked to terms in the UMLS Metathesaurus. The matched concepts were then used as candidate terms to be expanded; in some cases terms consisted of a primary term followed by a parenthesized description -such as "Intervention (Surgical and medical procedures)" -and in such cases we treated them as separate candidate terms.</p><p>Each candidate term had a Semantic Type (ST) associated with it in the MetaMap output. We used STs to define two expansion groups: safe expansion (for terms which STs include the string "Pharmacologic Substance") and filtered expansion (for terms whose ST is "Therapeutic or Preventive Procedure"). Candidate terms that did not belong to these groups were discarded. For the rest, if they were listed as "category" in DBpedia <ref type="foot" coords="4,346.30,359.86,3.97,6.72" target="#foot_3">5</ref> , we extracted all of the terms listed under the category as our expansion terms. For "safe expansion" the output was the full list of expansion terms; for "filtered expansion", we removed terms which are not UMLS concepts by applying MetaMap to each term.</p><p>In our implementation, we defined a small set of stop-categories that would have otherwise produced undesirable expansions. The following terms were excluded from expansion: "administration", "AMA", "diagnosis", "drug", "functional concept", "medication", and "surgery". We also removed terms with the following strings from the DBpedia output: "code", "history", "mechanism", "poisoning", "toxicity", and "withdrawal".</p><p>During the development process, we also explored expansion using hierarchical relations from the UMLS Metathesaurus; however, we observed that DBpedia offered a higher coverage of some domains, such as newly developed drugs, and less risk of over-expansion. For instance, one sample query contained the term "atypical antipshychotic", which UMLS expanded with 8 more specific drugs (e.g. "Clozapine"). DBpedia, however, identified the same set of drugs and as well as a further 22 new drug and brand names, which seemed correct after manual analysis, and had a stronger presence in the collection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Indexing and Searching</head><p>We used two types of indexing in our runs: visit-based and report-based. In the former approach, all related reports for a visit were concatenated (removing duplicate diagnostics codes) to create a single "multi-document" item for indexing.</p><p>We used stop-word removal both in query processing and indexing; however, we augmented the typical list of stop-words with patient, and removed single characters, and, or, not, and no from the list.</p><p>The search engine used for indexing and searching in our runs was Apache Lucene (v3.2); we used both the BM25 and tf-idf ranking algorithms for Lucene <ref type="bibr" coords="4,356.05,670.27,9.95,9.96" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. We relied on field search in most our runs, i.e., a Boolean search followed by ranking. When Boolean search was turned off, the queries contents still did include field names but no Boolean operator. No stemming was done in our submitted runs. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Evaluation</head><p>We submitted three automatic runs for the first round of submissions, to be used for pooling; we later submitted a further four automatic runs as official runs. Specifications of these runs are summarized in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,183.69,388.72,3.87,9.96" target="#tab_1">3</ref>. For the first three submissions we used Boolean search followed by BM25 ranking, and visit-based indexing. The official runs were a mix: report-based and visit-based indexing; Boolean search turned on and off; and the ranking function used was tf-idf rather than BM25. For all runs, we used query transformation and expansion, by themselves or combined. The TREC organizers chose three metrics for evaluations: precision at 10 documents retrieved (P@10), R-precision (R-Prec), and Bpref <ref type="bibr" coords="5,272.88,448.49,9.95,9.96" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. The results for our submissions are summarised in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,117.92,460.45,3.87,9.96" target="#tab_2">4</ref>. For the first three submissions (NICTA1 to NICTA3), our highest P@10 was achieved using NICTA1, which used only query transformation. However, the combination of query transformation and expansion gained higher Bpref and R-Prec results. Overall, we achieved consistently highest results, for all measures, using the NICTA6 configuration, which again used both steps of query processing -transformation followed by expansion -but with indexing at the report level; documents were processed for negation; and tf-idf was used for ranking. The queries were, however, flattened by removing the field names introduced in the query transformation step, leaving only their contents in the query.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="5,132.16,556.09,4.98,9.96" target="#tab_3">5</ref> compares our best run, NICTA6, to the results of: the ideal best of submitted runs to TREC; the median of all submitted runs; and best run of the team which ranked top among all other submissions. TREC separated the results into judged -runs that participated and judged in the pooling -and unjudged , and reported the best results and median of those submissions. Best in the judged and unjudged categories was an artificial run where the best result of the individual queries were taken from all the submitted runs and formed an ideal run. Our best run is above the median for all three measures, and ranked seventh among 109 automatic runs submitted for this track (more information on the rankings of all teams is given in the track overview paper <ref type="bibr" coords="6,495.85,328.42,10.28,9.96" target="#b4">[5]</ref>). Not all the possible combinations of search parameters -such as ranking function, visit-based indexing or report-based indexing -could be submitted to TREC. For completeness and to investigate changing which parameters help with the task, we ran all other missing configurations. We report some of the best configurations in our system in Tables <ref type="table" coords="6,379.17,376.24,4.98,9.96" target="#tab_4">6</ref> and<ref type="table" coords="6,406.40,376.24,3.87,9.96" target="#tab_5">7</ref>. In all our submissions we had turned off stemming, which did hurt the effectiveness. The positive effect of adding stemming can be clearly seen in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,256.52,400.15,3.87,9.96" target="#tab_5">7</ref>, when we used Porter stemmer. Using BM25 as a ranking function did not outperform tf-idf in any of the configurations. Our best performing run that was not submitted was NICTA13, which used stemming, visit-based indexing, tf-idf ranking, query transformation and expansion on the collection that was pre-processed to accommodate fields and handled negations (see Table <ref type="table" coords="6,219.35,447.97,3.87,9.96" target="#tab_0">1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions</head><p>The NICTA team submitted seven runs to the Medical Track of TREC 2011. We experimented with and submitted a variety of query processing and document processing approaches to this track. All documents were pre-processed to find -and, in specific cases, modify -concepts of interest. Among our submitted runs, the best results were achieved using query transformation -that is, breaking the query into different components and mapping these to their uniform representation as used in the documents -and query expansion using external resources.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,96.98,109.97,397.42,295.17"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>List of fields defined for Boolean search.</figDesc><table coords="3,96.98,109.97,397.42,295.17"><row><cell>Field</cell><cell></cell><cell>Description</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ADMITDIAG</cell><cell>diagnostics during admission</cell></row><row><cell>AGE</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">patients age by decades, for example age30 means people in their thirties</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ALLERGIES</cell><cell>allergies listed in the report</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">CHIEFCOMP</cell><cell cols="2">chief complaint, this may be equal to diagnostics during admission</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">DISCHDIAG</cell><cell>discharge diagnostics</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">GENDER</cell><cell cols="2">patient's gender extracted from text and represented as gendermale and genderfemale</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">HISTORY</cell><cell cols="2">history of the patient's medical condition or past medical illness</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">MEDICATIONS medications</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">PRESTHIS</cell><cell>present illness medical history</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">PASTHIS</cell><cell>past medical history</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">REPORT</cell><cell cols="2">all the free text information, including history, past and present, and allergies</cell></row><row><cell>What</cell><cell>Pattern</cell><cell></cell><cell>Translation</cell></row><row><cell>Gender</cell><cell cols="2">women/female</cell><cell>GENDER:gendermale</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>men/male</cell><cell></cell><cell>GENDER:gendermale</cell></row><row><cell>Age</cell><cell cols="2">young adult</cell><cell>AGE:(age20 age30 age40)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">younger/young</cell><cell>AGE:(agebirth12 ageteen age20 age30 age40)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>adult</cell><cell></cell><cell>AGE:(age20 age30 age40 age50 age60 age70 age80 age90)</cell></row><row><cell>Weight</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Treatments</cell><cell cols="2">taking X (who|with|without|treated)</cell><cell>MEDICATIONS:X</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">who are on X</cell><cell>MEDICATIONS:X</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">patients on X for Y</cell><cell>MEDICATIONS:X</cell></row><row><cell>Admission</cell><cell cols="2">admitted (for|with) X who</cell><cell>CHIEFCOMP:X OR ADMITDIAG:X</cell></row><row><cell>Diagnostics</cell><cell cols="2">treated for X (who|during|while)</cell><cell>PRESTHIS:X OR DISCHDIAG:X</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="3">(patients with|men with|women with) X PRESTHIS:X OR DISCHDIAG:X</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">who were discharged X</cell><cell>DISCHDIAG:X</cell></row><row><cell>History</cell><cell cols="2">with a* history of X (who|now)</cell><cell>HISTORY:X</cell></row><row><cell>Allergy</cell><cell cols="2">with X allergy</cell><cell>ALLERGY:X</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">without allergy</cell><cell>ALLERGY:(noallergies)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,90.00,109.97,423.00,166.72"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Specifications of the three initial runs (NICTA1 to NICTA3), and four official runs (NICTA4 to NICTA7). In indexing, v represents visit-based, and r means report-based.</figDesc><table coords="5,141.97,109.97,319.07,166.72"><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">Submitted Runs</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">NICTA1 NICTA2 NICTA3</cell><cell cols="4">NICTA4 NICTA5 NICTA6 NICTA7</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">transformation</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>expansion</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>negation</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Boolean</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">ranking function</cell><cell>BM25</cell><cell>BM25</cell><cell>BM25</cell><cell>tf-idf</cell><cell>tf-idf</cell><cell>tf-idf</cell><cell>tf-idf</cell></row><row><cell>indexing</cell><cell></cell><cell>v</cell><cell>v</cell><cell>v</cell><cell>v</cell><cell>r</cell><cell>r</cell><cell>r</cell></row><row><cell>stemming</cell><cell></cell><cell>none</cell><cell>none</cell><cell>none</cell><cell>none</cell><cell>none</cell><cell>none</cell><cell>none</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Submitted Runs</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Metric</cell><cell cols="4">NICTA1 NICTA2 NICTA3</cell><cell cols="4">NICTA4 NICTA5 NICTA6 NICTA7</cell></row><row><cell>Bpref</cell><cell>0.392</cell><cell>0.381</cell><cell cols="2">0.398</cell><cell>0.413</cell><cell>0.463</cell><cell>0.490</cell><cell>0.451</cell></row><row><cell>P@10</cell><cell>0.471</cell><cell>0.426</cell><cell cols="2">0.450</cell><cell>0.359</cell><cell>0.432</cell><cell>0.503</cell><cell>0.459</cell></row><row><cell>R-Prec</cell><cell>0.278</cell><cell>0.273</cell><cell cols="2">0.292</cell><cell>0.255</cell><cell>0.295</cell><cell>0.355</cell><cell>0.326</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,90.00,288.69,422.99,21.91"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Evaluation of the three initial runs (NICTA1 to NICTA3), and four official runs (NICTA4 to NICTA7).</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,90.00,658.16,422.99,72.92"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Comparison of our best run (NICTA6) with the ideal best and median of 47 judged and 80 unjudged submissions, and best reported run (last column) among 109 automatic submissions.</figDesc><table coords="5,164.80,658.16,273.39,39.00"><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Judged</cell><cell cols="2">Unjudged</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Metric</cell><cell>NICTA6</cell><cell>Best</cell><cell>Median</cell><cell>Best</cell><cell>Median</cell><cell>Best Run</cell></row><row><cell>Bpref</cell><cell>0.490</cell><cell>0.761</cell><cell>0.412</cell><cell>0.758</cell><cell>0.434</cell><cell>0.552</cell></row><row><cell>P@10</cell><cell>0.503</cell><cell>0.876</cell><cell>0.476</cell><cell>0.859</cell><cell>0.444</cell><cell>0.656</cell></row><row><cell>R-Prec</cell><cell>0.355</cell><cell>0.610</cell><cell>0.309</cell><cell>0.598</cell><cell>0.305</cell><cell>0.440</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="6,90.00,192.29,422.98,83.15"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Specifications of the complementary runs which were not submitted to TREC. In indexing, v represents visit-based, and r means report-based.</figDesc><table coords="6,137.02,236.44,328.97,39.00"><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Complementary Runs</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Metric</cell><cell cols="7">NICTA8 NICTA9 NICTA10 NICTA11 NICTA12 NICTA13 NICTA14</cell></row><row><cell>Bpref</cell><cell>0.495</cell><cell>0.498</cell><cell>0.491</cell><cell>0.498</cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>0.508</cell><cell>0.506</cell></row><row><cell>P@10</cell><cell>0.500</cell><cell>0.485</cell><cell>0.494</cell><cell>0.491</cell><cell>0.506</cell><cell>0.535</cell><cell>0.535</cell></row><row><cell>R-Prec</cell><cell>0.376</cell><cell>0.360</cell><cell>0.336</cell><cell>0.343</cell><cell>0.353</cell><cell>0.377</cell><cell>0.376</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="6,208.15,286.89,186.66,9.96"><head>Table 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Evaluation of the complementary.</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,105.25,691.77,407.66,7.68;2,90.00,701.98,102.02,6.77"><p>International Statistical Classification of Diseases and Related Health Problems: http://en.wikipedia.org/ wiki/List_of_ICD-9_codes</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,105.25,711.49,131.13,6.77"><p>http://code.google.com/p/negex/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_2" coords="3,105.25,717.35,407.69,9.06;3,90.00,727.55,114.21,6.77"><p>A full list of all the transformation rules can be found in: http://http://ww2.cs.mu.oz.au/ ~skarimi/codes/ TRECMED.2011.qprocessing.pl</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5" xml:id="foot_3" coords="4,105.25,723.54,140.73,7.68"><p>http://wiki.dbpedia.org/OnlineAccess</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>NICTA is funded by the <rs type="funder">Australian government</rs> as represented by <rs type="institution">Department of Broadband, Communication and Digital Economy</rs>, and the <rs type="funder">Australian Research Council</rs> through the <rs type="programName">ICT Centre of Excellence programme</rs>.</p><p><rs type="person">Hanna Suominen</rs> was partially funded by the <rs type="funder">Academy of Finland</rs> (decision no. <rs type="grantNumber">136653</rs>). This work was performed while <rs type="person">Lumin Zhang</rs> was a visiting student at the <rs type="affiliation">NICTA Canberra Research Laboratory</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_rGbRGPB">
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">ICT Centre of Excellence programme</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_mTpTQpF">
					<idno type="grant-number">136653</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,105.50,721.17,407.48,9.96;6,105.50,733.46,407.49,9.62;6,105.50,745.07,241.37,9.96" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,246.82,721.17,210.29,9.96">Retrieval evaluation with incomplete information</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,477.09,721.51,35.88,9.62;6,105.50,733.46,407.49,9.62;6,105.50,745.41,89.42,9.62">Proceedings of the 27th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 27th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval<address><addrLine>Sheffield, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="32" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,111.46,407.50,9.96;7,105.50,123.41,407.49,9.96;7,105.50,135.36,227.32,9.96" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,297.87,111.46,215.12,9.96;7,105.50,123.41,87.01,9.96">The stockholm EPR corpus -characteristics and some initial findings</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Dalianis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hassel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Velupillai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,214.98,123.75,298.01,9.62;7,105.50,135.70,61.38,9.62">The 14th International Symposium for Health Information Management Research</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Kalmar, Sweden</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,155.29,402.23,9.96" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,105.50,155.29,372.02,9.96">Institute of Medicine. 100 initial priority topics for comparative effectiveness research</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,175.21,407.47,9.96;7,105.50,187.17,282.26,9.96" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,389.60,175.21,123.37,9.96;7,105.50,187.17,149.43,9.96">Integrating the probabilistic models BM25/BM25F into Lucene</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Perez-Iglesias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Perez-Aguera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Fresno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Feinstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>CoRR, abs/0911.5046</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,207.10,407.50,9.96;7,105.50,219.05,407.50,9.96;7,105.50,231.00,50.89,9.96" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,263.91,207.10,227.77,9.96">Overview of the TREC 2011 medical records track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Voorhees</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Tong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,105.50,219.39,158.68,9.62">The tenth Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint/>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>National Institute of Standards and Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
