<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,109.44,77.12,376.09,14.15;1,228.96,98.50,137.40,12.54">PRIS at TREC 2011 Entity Track: Related Entity Finding and Entity List Completion</title>
				<funder ref="#_hNAkagQ">
					<orgName type="full">NSFC</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,169.92,135.02,50.69,9.00"><forename type="first">Zhanyi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>wangzhanyi@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information and Communication Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,228.24,135.02,46.92,9.00"><forename type="first">Wenlong</forename><surname>Lv</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information and Communication Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,282.24,135.02,31.56,9.00"><forename type="first">Heng</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information and Communication Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,319.68,135.02,59.33,9.00"><forename type="first">Wenyuan</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information and Communication Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,386.28,135.02,34.26,9.00"><forename type="first">Li</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information and Communication Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,174.96,155.18,33.00,9.00"><forename type="first">Xiao</forename><surname>Mo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information and Communication Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,216.01,155.18,59.68,9.00"><forename type="first">Liaoming</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information and Communication Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,282.60,155.18,41.16,9.00"><forename type="first">Weiran</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information and Communication Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,331.56,155.18,47.81,9.00"><forename type="first">Guang</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information and Communication Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,386.65,155.18,33.49,9.00"><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Information and Communication Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Beijing</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,109.44,77.12,376.09,14.15;1,228.96,98.50,137.40,12.54">PRIS at TREC 2011 Entity Track: Related Entity Finding and Entity List Completion</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">5F500E7D280FAE1A2C122D761DF64CA6</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:06+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>BNC WAF WordNet</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The group of PRIS focuses on both tasks in Entity Track this year, Related Entity Finding (REF) and Entity List Completion (ELC). This paper reports the approaches to the two tasks. In REF, three points are improved based the method of last two year: building entity lexicons including more information, introducing a distance algorithm between keywords and entities to entity ranking, allocating homepages in a deeper and more reasonable way. The Entity Activation Force (EAF) and Affinity Measure are used in ELC task for completing and reordering the entity list. The evaluation of experimental results</p><p>shows that the performance is better than previous ones significantly. distance result, the final score keeps the original DCM score. That means the parameter is set as 1 in both cases. In generally, 0&lt; .</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="842.04"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>As the aims of last two years, Entity track is to evaluate entity-related searches on Web data 1 . The track of this year includes two main tasks, Related Entity Finding (REF) and Entity List Completion (ELC). REF is defined as follows: Given an input entity, by its name and homepage, the type of the target entity, as well as the nature of their relation, described in free text, find related entities that are of target type, standing in the required relation to the input entity <ref type="bibr" coords="1,470.88,562.82,11.13,9.32" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. The key changes introduced to the 2010 edition of the REF task are as follows 2   • Only primary homepages are accepted, i.e., relevance is binary. :</p><p>• For each answer, a (single) supporting document is required.</p><p>• Wikipedia pages are (still) not accepted as entity homepages, but they can be supporting documents.</p><p>• Target type is not limited anymore to the four high-level entity types (person, organization, location, product). The target type is extracted from the narrative and is always given in singular form. 1 http://ilps.science.uva.nl/trec-entity/guidelines/guidelines-2010/ 2 http://bit.ly/entity2011-guidelines run, using the Lemur ClueWeb Online Query Service.</p><p>The ELC task is defined as follows: Given an information need and a list of known relevant entity homepages, return a list of relevant entity URIs from a specific collection of Linked Open Data. ELC addresses essentially the same task as REF does: finding entities that are engaged in a specific relation with an input entity. There are two main differences to REF. First, entities are not represented by their homepages, but by a unique URI (from a specific collection, a sample from the Linked Open Data cloud). Second, a number of entity homepages (i.e., ClueWeb docIDs) are made available as part of the topic definition, as examples of known relevant answers.</p><p>In REF, the framework is similar as the description of last year's report <ref type="bibr" coords="2,412.21,260.79,11.14,9.32" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. This year we pay more attention to entity extraction and homepage ranking. Aiming at them, we improve our framework in three points: building entity lexicons including more information, introducing a distance algorithm between keywords and entities to entity ranking, allocating homepages in a deeper and more reasonable way. In ELC, we introduce a new statistic named Entity Activation Force (EAF). It is used to compute affinity measure between two entities for completing and reordering the entity list.</p><p>The report is organized as follows. Section 2 describes our methods of entity extraction. Section 3 introduces the distance algorithm to entity ranking. Section 4 proposes the improvement of allocating homepages. The key arithmetic for ELC is presented in Section 5. Submitted runs show in Section 6 and Section 7 gives the conclusion and future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Entity Extraction</head><p>This year we exact entities in various ways as before. It is described as the figure below: Unlike the method of last year in this section, in order to get accurate and normative entities, we extract the snippets about the entity instead of the entity itself. If the type that recognized by Stanford toolkit is satisfactory, we reserve the text around the entity for further extraction using lexicon.</p><p>We create an entity lexicon with richer types. Besides three basic types, more than twenty kinds of lexicon are created. The source data is Wikipedia. Wikipedia has rich entities and category labels. According to topics, the map of topic and entity is set up manually in advance. A topic maybe corresponds to one or more labels. For example, "manufacturer" ~"manufacturer", "author"~"writer", "film"~"movie", etc. The type of person and organization maps some new labels besides rules proposed by University of Amsterdam <ref type="bibr" coords="3,409.32,260.79,11.13,9.32" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Related Wikipedia pages are collected and the titles are taken as entity names simply.</p><p>The process of entity extraction in ELC task this year is similar to REF. The topic is the same as REF of last year. We adjust the scale of document for extraction, refine the Wikipedia lexicon and filter entities that are too short.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">The Distance Algorithm between Keywords and Entities</head><p>Because the Document-Centered Model (DCM) showed very good performance, we still adopt it as the basic retrieval model. To improve the accuracy, we propose a distance algorithm between keywords and candidate entities. The algorithm is described as follows.</p><p>Step1. Several keywords (1~5 generally) are picked up manually from narrative field in the topic. According to Word Activation Force (WAF) and affinity measure <ref type="bibr" coords="3,403.91,488.66,11.13,9.32" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, more keywords are expanded by in British National Corpus (BNC). We take top 5 words in the affinity list of a keyword and make up the keyword set K. Given a topic t in topic set T and a candidate entity e in the whole set E, entities and keywords generate pairs set {(e,k)|e E,k K}. Step 1</p><p>Step 2</p><p>Step 3</p><p>Figrue 2. Flowchart of distance algorithm between keywords and entities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Homepage Identification and Ranking</head><p>The main problem is how to identify a homepage for an entity from large amounts of data. We define some patterns and values as Table <ref type="table" coords="4,263.53,487.21,3.97,9.32" target="#tab_0">1</ref> In ELC task, homepages are in the Sindice dataset. We take entities as keywords and analyse the searching results in the system. The process of identifying homepages is shown as Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,482.75,296.78,3.83,9.32" target="#fig_2">3</ref>.</p><p>By our observation on the dataset, the DBpedia pages are often considered as homepages. For DBpedia pages, the homepage value is written as</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="5,249.48,351.23,98.38,26.32">match match Dbpeida total total N L S N L .</formula><p>For an entity e, N total is the number of words in e. N match is the number of matched words. L total is the character length of e. L match is the length of matched characters. For entities that are not in a DBpedia page, the first result in the relevant documents is taken as the homepage. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Entity Activation Force in ELC</head><p>The task of ELC refers more to analyzing relations among entities. The entity list is completed and reordered by the relations. So besides the methods in REF task, a novel algorithm for the establishment of entity associations is introduced. Entity Activation Force (EAF) is developed from the activation force statistics which proposed by J. Guo et.al <ref type="bibr" coords="6,371.51,80.77,10.86,9.32" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. The main idea of EAF is to weight the links between words and entities. Here, words are considered as the context of entities.</p><p>We aim at measuring the activation force from an entity to their context words and calculating the affinity of entities. Finally, the entities whose affinities are high to the given entities are helped to improve the entity list.</p><p>Take the forward context as an example, EAF is defined as In this formula, eaf ew means the EAF from an entity e to words w. Correspondingly, the EAF from words to the entity is also existed. f e is the entity frequency in all the training data. f w is the word frequency. f ew is the co-occurrence amount of e and w in a certain distance scale. d ew is the average distance between the entity and the word. In the type of webpage or plain text, distance minus one equals the number of words between them. g is a parameter. Note that the form is pretty similar to the law of universal gravitation. So we name it a kind of "Force". Because the EAF network is a directed graph, the EAF matrix is asymmetric.</p><p>Moreover, the entity affinity measure is proposed. The affinity between two entities e i and e j is defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="6,176.34,422.35,242.86,38.23">1 2 1 1 , , ij ij eaf ij ki kj il jl k K k L ij ij A OR eaf eaf OR eaf eaf K L</formula><p>where K ij ={k|eaf ki &gt;0 or eaf kj &gt;0}, L ij ={l|eaf il &gt;0 or eaf jl &gt;0}, OR(x,y)=min(x,y)/max(x,y).</p><p>The entity list can be modified by the entity affinity measure. For example, the 37 th query is to find people that appeared on the Tavis Smiley show in December 2008. If we are sure that "chris_cillizza" is a correct answer, we give more weight to the entities "thomas_friedman" and "malcolm_gladwell" whose affinity to "chris_cillizza" are very high. Before we fuse this algorithm, the two entities are just 14 th and 30 th in our REF list.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Experiments and Results</head><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="6,119.16,642.37,5.22,9.32" target="#tab_3">3</ref> is REF result of all our runs. PRISREF1 doesn't include the distance algorithm.</p><p>PRISREF2 uses snippets instead of the full text of relevant documents. PRISREF3 includes all the above algorithms. PRISREF4 adjusts parameters of DCM. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.">Conclusions</head><p>This paper reported our approach to the task of Entity Track 2011. We proposed some mining and ranking methods for entities and homepages. We extracted entities in a deeper way. We merged a distance algorithm for entity ranking in the model. We got a breakthrough in homepage identification and ranking. In ELC task, we introduced a novel algorithm for completing and optimizing the entity list. In the future, we will pay more attention to the ELC task and the study of entity associations.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,161.65,657.84,271.89,9.32"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. Flowchart of Automatic Entity Extraction in Task REF.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,100.41,568.94,404.42,9.32;3,89.95,588.75,415.26,9.32;3,89.95,608.90,6.94,9.32;3,282.81,648.01,1.51,5.51;3,333.76,630.81,11.86,9.55;3,274.82,638.61,33.07,9.55;3,237.19,644.44,59.65,9.08;3,336.55,652.84,4.37,5.51;3,317.73,630.81,36.68,9.55;3,231.48,638.61,5.24,9.55;3,333.64,647.02,2.91,9.55;3,90.00,675.49,251.72,9.99;3,100.44,695.65,404.95,9.32;3,90.00,715.46,96.95,9.32;3,304.34,737.83,5.24,9.51;3,235.60,743.64,9.69,5.49;3,275.76,743.64,13.43,5.49;3,341.22,743.64,21.41,5.49;3,230.08,737.83,5.24,9.51;3,270.04,737.83,5.24,9.51;3,335.51,737.83,5.24,9.51;3,364.68,737.77,2.61,9.32;4,184.96,302.83,32.06,7.13;4,184.51,312.42,32.95,7.13;4,125.65,346.13,32.51,7.13;4,124.86,355.71,34.08,7.13;4,233.68,355.16,53.66,7.13;4,365.87,191.04,42.98,7.13;4,368.99,244.68,36.74,7.13;4,360.53,254.26,53.66,7.13;4,378.22,292.34,18.26,7.13;4,434.00,331.82,38.53,7.13;4,369.65,361.96,35.40,7.13"><head>Step2.</head><label></label><figDesc>Distance d between each k and e are counted in all relative documents C. The distance d is defined as c+1. c is the word count between k and the nearest e. The distance score of an entity is , e,k,m) is d in the document m. l m is the length of m. Step3. Now an entity has two values. One is from DCM results. The other is from step 2. Then a new score is merged as 1</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="5,180.36,635.18,234.40,9.32"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3. Flowchart of homepage identification in ELC.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,90.00,487.21,415.29,262.67"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>: Homepage patterns and values.</figDesc><table coords="4,90.00,532.21,415.29,217.66"><row><cell>Homepage pattern</cell><cell>Pattern value</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Example</cell></row><row><cell>consist of entity name directly</cell><cell>10</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">www.entity.(com|net|org|edu)</cell></row><row><cell>include entity name</cell><cell>2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>www…entity…</cell></row><row><cell>in the title field</cell><cell>2</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">&lt;title&gt;…entity…&lt;/title&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>Top 1 in search engine results</cell><cell>3</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">If a URL satisfies one or more patterns in the table, it may be a homepage of an entity.</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">According to the importance, the patterns are given appropriate values. Entity name is generalized</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">here. Specifically, the styles are listed in Table 2(take Michael Jackson as an example).</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Last year, if a webpage was taken for a homepage, it replaced entities directly. But the rank of</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">homepages should not be the same as the order of entities, because it is affected by the relation</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">between homepages and entities. This time we combine the two parts as</cell></row><row><cell>, S Q H</cell><cell>, S Q E</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>S</cell><cell>h</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,89.99,80.77,415.03,185.37"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Different patterns for entity names. is the value generated from DCM. S h is the normalized pattern value. is a variable parameter. In experiments, it is set as 0.3.</figDesc><table coords="5,100.44,105.61,387.89,140.73"><row><cell>Entity name pattern</cell><cell>Example</cell></row><row><cell>Capitalize each word</cell><cell>MichaelJackson</cell></row><row><cell>Uppercase</cell><cell>MICHAELJACKSON</cell></row><row><cell>Lowercase</cell><cell>mickaeljackson</cell></row><row><cell>Uppercase abbreviation</cell><cell>MJ</cell></row><row><cell>Uppercase abbreviation</cell><cell>mj</cell></row><row><cell>A part of words</cell><cell>Michael</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Words linked with connector Michael-Jackson, MICHAEL_JACKSON, mickael jackson</cell></row><row><cell>S(Q,E)</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="6,90.00,702.50,415.17,49.29"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>ELC resultsare not yet published at the time of writing.</figDesc><table /><note coords="6,133.92,702.50,371.25,9.32;6,90.00,722.30,415.02,9.32;6,90.00,742.46,190.50,9.32"><p>shows our REF results in recent three years. Hp_ret means the percentage of homepages that we find. No_hp_topic is the percentage of topics whose homepages we don't find. All the metrics goes better significantly year by year.</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="7,162.72,100.93,265.51,97.16"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>REF runs of PRIS in 2011.</figDesc><table coords="7,162.72,125.77,265.51,72.33"><row><cell>Run_id</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>Num_rel_ret</cell><cell>P@5</cell><cell>P@10</cell></row><row><cell>PRISREF1</cell><cell>0.2509</cell><cell>310</cell><cell>0.4280</cell><cell>0.3340</cell></row><row><cell>PRISREF2</cell><cell>0.2329</cell><cell>300</cell><cell>0.4080</cell><cell>0.3000</cell></row><row><cell>PRISREF3</cell><cell>0.2450</cell><cell>310</cell><cell>0.4160</cell><cell>0.3180</cell></row><row><cell>PRISREF4</cell><cell>0.2448</cell><cell>326</cell><cell>0.4440</cell><cell>0.3260</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="7,150.47,210.01,293.37,81.68"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>REF runs of PRIS from 2009-2011.</figDesc><table coords="7,150.47,235.21,293.37,56.48"><row><cell>Year</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>NDCG</cell><cell>P@10</cell><cell>Hp_ret</cell><cell>No_hp_topic</cell></row><row><cell>'11</cell><cell>0.2509</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0.3340</cell><cell>0.4512</cell><cell>0.0400</cell></row><row><cell>'10</cell><cell>0.1607</cell><cell>0.2846</cell><cell>0.2489</cell><cell>0.4005</cell><cell>0.1702</cell></row><row><cell>'09</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>0.0892</cell><cell>0.0150</cell><cell>0.0180</cell><cell>0.3500</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledge</head><p>This work was supported by <rs type="funder">NSFC</rs> (No.<rs type="grantNumber">60905017</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_hNAkagQ">
					<idno type="grant-number">60905017</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,106.20,587.65,398.83,9.32;7,90.00,607.81,276.54,9.32" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,287.64,587.65,183.14,9.32">Overview of the TREC 2010 Entity Track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Balog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Serdyukov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Vries</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,90.00,607.81,272.03,9.32">Eighteenth Text REtrieval Conference Proceedings (TREC 2010)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.12,627.62,400.13,9.32;7,89.99,647.78,292.06,9.32" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,212.02,627.62,276.78,9.32">PRIS at TREC 2010: Related Entity Finding Task of Entity Track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,105.11,647.78,272.42,9.32">Eighteenth Text REtrieval Conference Proceedings (TREC 2010)</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.46,667.94,399.67,9.32;7,89.98,687.74,414.83,9.32;7,89.98,707.90,165.34,9.32" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,274.65,667.94,230.48,9.32;7,89.98,687.74,124.24,9.32">Result diversity and entity ranking experiments: Text, anchors, links, and wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kaptein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koolen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,251.63,687.74,219.31,9.32">Eighteenth Text REtrieval Conference Proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>TREC</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009. 2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,106.18,727.70,399.03,9.32;7,89.98,747.86,293.81,9.32" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,245.50,727.70,259.71,9.32;7,89.98,747.86,79.47,9.32">An Activation Force-based Affinity Measure for Analyzing Complex Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Guo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/srep00113</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,176.71,747.86,44.86,9.32">Sci. Rep. 1</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">113</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
