<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,87.84,78.20,436.15,14.26">The system RELIEFS : a new approach for information filtering</title>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">INRIA</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,213.84,120.67,97.07,10.80"><forename type="first">Christophe</forename><surname>Brouard</surname></persName>
							<email>brouardc@iro.umontreal.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">succ. Centre Ville</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratoire RALI Département d&apos;Informatique et de Recherche Opérationnelle</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Université de Montréal CP</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>6128, H3C 3J7</postCode>
									<settlement>Montréal</settlement>
									<region>QC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,335.04,120.67,63.00,10.80"><forename type="first">Jian-Yun</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
							<email>nie@iro.umontreal.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">succ. Centre Ville</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratoire RALI Département d&apos;Informatique et de Recherche Opérationnelle</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Université de Montréal CP</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>6128, H3C 3J7</postCode>
									<settlement>Montréal</settlement>
									<region>QC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,87.84,78.20,436.15,14.26">The system RELIEFS : a new approach for information filtering</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">94D3940F2B7A042ACCAB6D69C794562A</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:11+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this year's filtering track, we implemented a system called RELIEFS that tries to learn about the prediction capability of words or conjunctions of words for the relevance of documents. The novelty of the system resides in two main points. First, the features used in the prediction involve both : the implication D-&gt;Q (from document to query), and the reverse implication Q-&gt;D. This is different from usual approaches where only the first of the implication is used. Therefore, the relevance estimation of a document combines the probability that a document containing a term is relevant, and the reverse probability -the probability that a term appears in relevant documents. The second novelty is that, in addition to the use of words as prediction elements, we also consider word combinations (conjunctions). However, not all combinations are significant. Therefore, an incremental algorithm is developped to select only the meaningful conjunctions. To limit the number of conjunctions, we do not use a cut on conjunction length. Rather, we eliminate the conjunctions A&amp;B that bear the same information as A or as B. Our first results prove the feasibility of the approach. Other experiments are ongoing in order to fully evaluate this approach.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>The goal of our participation in TREC9 is to experiment the following two ideas for information filtering :</p><p>The first idea is about the use of the two implications D-&gt;Q (from document to query) and Q-&gt;D. Usually, in Information Retrieval, relevance evaluation is based on the evaluation of D-&gt;Q <ref type="bibr" coords="1,70.80,662.35,116.56,10.80" target="#b2">(van Rijsbergen, 1986)</ref>. If one considers a document as a set of terms, and a query as a specification of what we are looking for, the implication D-&gt;Q may be decomposed to the judgment of "if the term is present then the document is relevant" for each term of the document.</p><p>Even if some authors signal the importance of the reverse implication (Q-&gt;D) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,462.65,76.27,54.70,10.80" target="#b1">(Nie, 1988)</ref>, the relation has not been integrated in relevance evaluation. This relation has been taken into account in probabilistic models as a way to calculate D-&gt;Q. In our approach we will consider both implications simultaneously. the consideration of the reverse implication Q-&gt;D means in practice that we have to consider the relation "if the document is relevant then the term is present in the document". From a pragmatic point of view, the use of Q-&gt;D may be justified by the fact that it allows us to favour terms which have been met many times in relevant documents, comparing to rare terms for which the presence in relevant document is a coincidence. The two implications may be illustrated as two relationships between terms and relevance as in Fig 1 . The two relationships are different in nature and both are important for judging the relevance of a document. Therefore, we will integrate both of them in our approach. The second important aspect in our approach is the use of term combinations. Usually, the learning for adaptive filtering system consists of updating the weights of terms and not term conjunctions. This is because the assumption that terms are independent. It is also due to the fact that considering term combinations would lead to a combinatory explosion. Some methods tried to consider term combinations, but usually limited themselves to a certain length. This solution is not totally satisfactory since the length constraint can not be completely justified. Morever, the number of combinations is still very high. We propose here to update all the implications whithout loosing any information. The economy principle we propose is based on the observation that if two terms t 1 and t 2 are always present simultaneously (in the same documents), it is useless to create the information t 1 &amp;t 2 since this information is the same as t 1 (or t 2 ). In this way, many combinations can be eliminated. We use an incremental algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="2,398.38,623.47,78.31,10.80" target="#b0">(Brouard, 2000)</ref> to determine whether a combination should be added and its weight be updated. relevance term relevance knowing term term knowing relevance</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">System description</head><p>The goal of RELIEFS system is to find words or conjunctions of words that are good predictors of document relevance. The RELIEFS processing can be decomposed in three steps: 1. Selection of N document words from the document, 2. Estimation of the document's relevance, 3. Revision of word's predictability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Step 1 : Selection of N document words</head><p>All the document words are compared with the words which have been extracted from the query, the document examples given for learning and the documents which have been previously selected. The considered words or word conjunctions are elements of prediction p i . They are sorted by the value of their predictability of relevance. This predictability is estimated as the product between the relative frequency of relevance knowing p i and the reverse frequency, i.e.</p><p>F R w F w R i i ( / ). ( / ). If less than N words (in our experiments we choose N=20) can be selected in this way, this selection is completed first by the document words which are related to the query words and finally by the document words in their lecture order. The relatedness between words is estimated using both implications on the training set (Ohsumed 87). In our solution of additional words, those that are related to sereval query words are given priority.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Step 2 : Evaluation of the relevance</head><p>Considering the elements of prediction which appear in the document, the score of the document is computed as follows :</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,70.80,424.02,284.28,83.34">F R p F p R F R p F p R i i i k i i n i ( / ). ( / ) ( / ). ( / ) * * *= = ∑ ∑ 1 1 where F R p i ( / )</formula><p>is the relative frequency of relevance given the presence of the element of prediction p i in this document, F R p i ( / ) is the reverse relative frequency and i* are the indices of the elements of prediction which are present in the document. In RELIEFS, the relevance of a document is estimated as the sum of the implication products for all the elements of prediction present in the document divided by the sum of the implication products for all the elements of prediction. In the example of Fig 2, word5 and word8 are elements of prediction and appear in the document, the implication products of these elements are taken into account and increase the score of the document.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Step 3 : Updating relative frequencies</head><p>If the evaluation of step2 is larger than a defined threshold, then the N words selected in the first step are submitted to an updating process on their relative frequencies, and new conjunctions are also built. The building condition of a conjunction A&amp;B is that F(A/B) and F(B/A) are different from 1. This condition allows us to avoid building useless conjunctions (i.e A&amp;B is equivalent to A or/and to B).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 2 -Relevance evaluation in RELIEFS</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Threshold adaption</head><p>We tried to adjust the thresholds with a very simple mechanism. When a selected document is irrelevant, the threshold is increased with a small value. Each time a document is not selected, the threshold is decreased. The initial threshold is computed on the basis of the score of the two first relevant documents and the amplitude of the threshold modification is based on the difference between the average score of the two last relevant documents and the two last irrelevant documents. Initially, we considered an average of 0 for irrelevant documents. So the change tends to be larger at the begining than at the end. Morever, the product of the change scale by a constant allows us to vary more globally all the thresholds.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Results &amp; Discussion</head><p>We have submitted two runs on Ohsumed collection. The first one considers higher thresholds than the second one (the constant used in the product with the change scale is larger). Its utility score is positive (+1.1). We submitted it for comparison on utility criteria. The comparison is favourable since about 60% of the scores are above the median (table1 We considered also smaller thresholds (decreasing the constant) for a second run in order to increase the number of selected documents which was too small for optimizing precision since when less than 50 document are selected a penalty is applied. This time, the utility score is approximately -1 and the corrected precision is approximately 0.17 (0.28 if not corrected). The comparison of our result with other systems optimized for precision is not favourable (table <ref type="table" coords="5,528.17,142.75,4.37,10.80">2</ref>). However, it is to be noted that our system is not tuned to optimized the precision but utility.We think that the results could be improved if we set lower thresholds in order to keep more documents and then to avoid the under-50 penalty.</p><p>below-median at-median above-median reliefs2 42 11 10 Table <ref type="table" coords="5,174.57,261.31,6.00,10.80">2</ref> : Comparison on precision criteria of adaptive filtering run.</p><p>Globally, these very first results are encouraging, in particular for utility. They show that using a small number of words (20) to represent documents can perform as well as traditional information filtering systems in which much more words are considered. However, it is also necessary to consider word conjunctions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Conclusion</head><p>In our information filtering approach, we take into account two implications, D-&gt;Q and Q-&gt;D. Morever, we developped a solution in order to take into account word conjunctions. Further experiments will be done to evaluate more precisely the avantages of each of these aspects.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,176.88,424.51,258.06,10.80"><head>Figure 1 -</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1 -Relationships between terms and relevance</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,139.68,169.63,349.50,536.40"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>). Comparison on utility criteria of adaptive filtering run.</figDesc><table coords="4,139.68,659.95,349.50,28.80"><row><cell></cell><cell>below-median</cell><cell>at-median</cell><cell>above-median</cell></row><row><cell>relief1</cell><cell>12</cell><cell>14</cell><cell>37</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgment</head><p>This research has been funded by <rs type="funder">INRIA</rs> (<rs type="affiliation">Institut National de Recherche en Informatique et Automatique</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.80,573.55,470.58,10.80;5,70.80,590.11,374.06,10.80" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,166.69,573.55,374.69,10.80;5,70.80,590.11,227.11,10.80">Construction et exploitation de réseaux Sémantiques Flous pour l&apos;Extraction d&apos;Information Pertinente : Le système RELIEFS</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Brouard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,307.04,590.11,125.82,10.80">Thèse de l&apos;université Paris</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.80,623.23,470.52,10.80;5,70.80,639.79,447.32,10.80" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,157.52,623.23,262.66,10.80">An outline of a general model for information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Nie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,427.62,623.23,113.70,10.80;5,70.80,639.79,391.97,10.80">Proceedings of the 11th Annual ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 11th Annual ACM Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval<address><addrLine>Grenoble</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,70.80,673.15,470.39,10.80;5,70.80,689.71,118.43,10.80" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,225.60,673.15,234.54,10.80">A non-classical logic for information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Van Rijsbergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,469.44,673.15,71.75,10.80;5,70.80,689.71,35.29,10.80">The Computer Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="481" to="485" />
			<date type="published" when="1986">1986</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
