<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,110.64,130.57,375.08,14.90">TREC 2005 Genomics Track Experiments at DUTAI</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,169.44,155.23,50.30,9.29"><forename type="first">Zhihao</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<email>yangzh@dlut.edu.cn</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,227.04,155.23,48.26,9.29"><forename type="first">Hongfei</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
							<email>hflin@dlut.edu.cn</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,281.52,155.23,46.67,9.29"><forename type="first">Yanpeng</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,334.55,155.23,48.09,9.29"><forename type="first">Baoyan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,402.20,155.23,24.84,9.29"><forename type="first">Ye</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science and Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalian University of Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">LingGong Road Shahekou District</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116023</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,110.64,130.57,375.08,14.90">TREC 2005 Genomics Track Experiments at DUTAI</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">B6F11DB2C2C4D671CC04415250911037</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:02+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the techniques we applied for the two tasks of the TREC Genomics track, i.e., ad hoc retrieval and categorization tasks. For the ad hoc retrieval task, we used query expansion, different scoring strategy on different parts of Medline record (Title, Abstract, RN, MH, etc.) and pseudo relevance feedback. Our submitted run DUTAdHoc2 obtained a MAP of 0.2349. For the categorization task, our system used a SVM classifier with TFIDF term weighting scheme. In addition concept replacing and filtering methods were adopted. Two of our submitted runs (eDUTCat1 and gDUTCat1) produced a Utility score of 0.8496 and 0.572 respectively ranking third and fourth out of 46 runs submitted for the categorization task.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="841.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="841.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="841.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="841.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="841.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="841.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="841.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="841.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="841.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>It is well understood that biomedical knowledge is growing at an astounding pace and these vast collections of publications offer an excellent opportunity for the discovery of hidden biomedical knowledge by applying information retrieval (IR) and related technologies. To foster the IR and related research in biomedical text, the Text Retrieval Conference (TREC) launched the genomics track in 2003 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,147.84,458.74,11.56,9.72" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, which attracted the largest group of participants among all the tracks. This is the first time that DUTAI (Artificial Intelligence laboratory of DaLian University of Technology) participated in TREC genomics track. We took part in both ad hoc retrieval task and categorization task. The following sections report our proposed methods and the results for the ad hoc retrieval and categorization tasks in turn.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Ad Hoc Retrieval Task</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Overview</head><p>This is a conventional ad hoc retrieval task targeting the biomedical literature. Participants were provided with 50 topics, and for each topic, they were required to retrieve a set of relevant documents sorted according to the estimated relevance. In the 2005 ad hoc retrieval task, topics are more structured than the mostly free-form topics from the 2004 track. Five generic topic templates (GTTs) were developed, each of which have 10 instances, for a total of 50 topics. They are showed in Table <ref type="table" coords="1,113.75,671.47,3.93,9.29" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. In order to get participating groups started with the topics, and in order for them not to "spoil" their automatic status of their official runs by working with the official topics, 10 sample topics were provided, with two coming from each GTT. The document collection for the 2005 ad hoc retrieval task is the same 10-year Medline subset using for the 2004 track. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Framework</head><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,119.04,422.50,5.40,9.72" target="#fig_0">1</ref> depicts the overview of our retrieval system. To retrieve a set of relevant documents for each topic, the following step process is performed: NP extraction, query expansion, search and ranking, re-ranking and pseudo-relevance feedback. The following paragraphs describe the components of our IR system in more detail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>NP extraction</head><p>This process is accomplished by manual. Given a topic, we first extracted noun phrases (NPs) from it as potential query terms. For the verbs in the topic, if possible, they were transformed into corresponding noun phrases.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Query expansion</head><p>The extracted NPs were then expanded using two sources of information to form the final query. Firstly, a gene name dictionary was consulted to find synonyms. The dictionary is compiled from the Entrez Gene database on Pubmed (http://www.ncbi.nih.gov /entrez /query.fcgi) . Every record includes a gene/protein name and its aliases. Gene and protein names follow few, if any, true naming conventions and are subject to great variation in different occurrences of the same name. For example, the protein name "Interferon-beta" has many spelling variants such as "IFN-beta," "IFN-B," and "beta interferon." Experiments showed that query expansion by via of gene name dictionary could improve recall rate greatly.</p><p>The second source of information used in query expansion is UMLS Metathesaurus <ref type="bibr" coords="3,473.97,345.46,11.56,9.72" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. The purpose of NLM's Unified Medical Language System (UMLS) is to facilitate the development of computer systems that behave as if they "understand" the meaning of the language of biomedicine and health. There are three UMLS Knowledge Sources: the Metathesaurus, the Semantic Network, and the SPECIALIST Lexicon. The Metathesaurus is a very large, multi-purpose, and multi-lingual vocabulary database that contains information about biomedical and health-related concepts, their various names, and the relationships among them. In test topics, there are some disease names, each of which may have some synonyms. For example, "Alzheimer's disease" has synonyms such as "Alzheimer disease," and "AD." By via of UMLS Metathesaurus, the diseases' synonyms were found and used for query expansion.</p><p>In addition, other dictionaries were built to perform query expansion. The words expressing method or protocol (such as method, protocol, approach, and technique) were collected in a dictionary, which was used for query expansion in topics 100-109. The words expressing interactions between two or more genes (such as inhibit, suppress, promote, regulate) and their nominal forms were collected in another dictionary, which was used for query expansion in topics 130-139.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Search and ranking</head><p>In this process, terms obtained through query expansion were concatenated by Boolean OR operators, forming the final query. The query was then fed to Zettair <ref type="bibr" coords="3,405.57,630.34,12.72,9.72" target="#b2">[3]</ref> to retrieve a list of candidate abstracts from the corpus, which were used as baseline. We limited the number of retrieved documents to the first 8000 in our test runs. The ranking score produced by Zettair was denoted as score1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Re-ranking</head><p>Zettair doesn't take account of the query terms' position (such as in TI, AB, MH or RN fields) in a Medline record. In fact these different positions can influence a Medline record's relevance. For example, a Medline record in which a query term appears in TI field tends to be more related than one in which a query term appears in AB field.</p><p>Therefore, we designed a set of scoring rules to re-rank the baseline records. Firstly, query terms were divided into two kinds: Necessary term and Optional term. Necessary terms are those that are necessary in related Medline records, i.e., they are directly related and must appear in related records; while Optional query terms are those that are optional in related Medline records, i.e., they are related but not necessary to appear in related records. The examples of Necessary terms and Optional terms are showed in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,293.26,267.22,4.11,9.72" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. Secondly, these two kinds of terms were given different ranking scores according to their positions in Medline records. If there are no Necessary terms found in any of TI, AB, MH or RN fields in a record, the record will be given a score of -200. These scoring rules are showed in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,262.06,312.82,4.23,9.72" target="#tab_2">3</ref>.</p><p>In this way, the baseline records were re-ranked and the ranking score produced by our scoring rules was denoted as score2. The final score of a related record is the sum of score1 and score2. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Pseudo-relevance feedback</head><p>For the submitted run DUTAdHoc2, we applied a simple pseudo-relevance feedback (PRF) method: The pseudo-relevance feedback module assumed the top n ranked documents to be relevant and used MeSH terms (in MH fields) in these documents to refine the query. As a measure of significance, we used TFIDF values. The m MeSH terms with highest TFIDF were sent back to the re-ranking module to add the records including them with a score of 10. We experimentally set n=m=10.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Results</head><p>We submitted two runs (DUTAdHoc1 and DUTAdHoc2) for this task; only the difference between them is that DUTAdHoc2 used pseudo-relevance feedback, while DUTAdHoc2 did not. DUTAdHoc1 obtained a MAP of 0.2344, while DUTAdHoc2 obtained a little better one of 0.2349. Through the experiments, we observed that: l Query expansion helped a lot to improve the retrieval recall rate. l The position that query terms appear influenced a Medline record's relevance. l Our pseudo-relevance feedback method contributed little to the retrieval performance.</p><p>We will introduce more complex pseudo-relevance feedback methods in the future.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Categorization Task</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Overview</head><p>This year, categorization task was divided into four subtasks: allele, expression, GO and tumor.</p><p>We participated in all the four subtasks and submitted two runs for each subtask. Our system used a SVM classifier with TFIDF term weighting scheme. A concept replacing approach was used in our first runs of the allele, expression and tumor subtasks, which proved to enhance the performance slightly by the official result from TREC. In GO subtask, documents were classified three times using different feature selection schemes each time, and the results were processed using a decision algorithm. Finally, the positive instances obtained were filtered according by the numbers of biomedical named entities appearing in it, which improved the normalized utility by 5% in GO subtask.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Text Processing</head><p>The documents provided by TREC were full-text articles in SGML format. We converted them into plain texts, by removing all the SGML tags and replacing non-English characters (e.g., &amp;agr;) by corresponding strings (e.g., alpha) that should appear in the Medline record (http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query/static/entities.html). We also downloaded the documents' corresponding Medline records from Pubmed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Framework</head><p>Different approaches were applied in the four subtasks, while the general step process can be described as: concept replacing, feature selection, training, classifying, decision and filtering. The final two steps were performed only in GO subtask. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,369.59,691.15,5.16,9.29">2</ref> depicts the overview of our categorization system.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="6,222.95,383.23,4.07,9.29">2</ref>: Framework of our categorization system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Concept Replacing</head><p>Articles in the training and test corpus were papers of biomedicine, so there were a large number of named entities in them such as protein and DNA names. However they were not good features for classifier, because many of them appeared very few times in all the articles and some had aliases. So we used ABNER (A Biomedical Named Entity Recognizer <ref type="bibr" coords="6,388.56,464.50,12.06,9.72" target="#b3">[4]</ref>) to find proteins, DNAs, RNAs, cell lines and cell types in all the documents and then replaced them by concept names. We defined five concept names: CONCEPT_PROTEIN, CONCEPT_DNA, CONCEPT_RNA, CONCEPT_CELLLINE, CONCEPT_CELLTYPE. For example, the named entity "type-II transmembrane protein" was replaced by "CONCEPT_PROTEIN". In our submitted runs, this method was used in aDUTCat1, eDUTCat1 and tDUTCat1, but not in aDUTCat2, eDUTCat2 and tDUTCat2. From Table <ref type="table" coords="6,191.52,555.70,4.23,9.72" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, we can see that the former group performed a little better than the latter. In addition, the numbers of feature terms were reduced by 20%.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Feature Selection, Classifying and Decision</head><p>We applied Joachims' SVM light <ref type="bibr" coords="6,226.56,612.82,12.71,9.72" target="#b4">[5]</ref> classifier and set weights using TFIDF <ref type="bibr" coords="6,416.63,612.82,12.48,9.72" target="#b5">[6]</ref> scheme. Methods of feature selection in GO subtask were different from other subtasks. First, full-text articles that had been processed before were divided into the following parts: titles (denoted by f1), abstracts (f2), bodies (f3), subtitles (f4), references (f5) and MeSH (f6). Then we did a great deal of experiments, in which single part or multiple parts were selected as feature part(s).</p><p>We found that MeSH (f6) performed much better than any other kind of features, as was mentioned in last year's papers <ref type="bibr" coords="6,227.51,704.02,11.56,9.72" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. Furthermore, we processed MeSH terms in several different ways, and found that using the main headings only produced the best result. MeSH term "Ataxia Telangiectasia/*genetics/metabolism", we used only "Ataxia Telangiectasia" and discarded all its subheadings. To make full use of full-text articles, we classified the documents three times respectively using f6, f1+f2+f3 (join f1, f2 and f3), and f1+f2 as features and got three results, denoted by r1, r2 and r3. We defined final score as the following Equation (1): final_score = (score1 -thres1) *1.0+ (score2 -thres2) * 0.7 + (score3 -thres3)* 0.5 <ref type="bibr" coords="7,492.23,191.38,12.71,9.72" target="#b0">(1)</ref> where score1,score2 and score3 were the result scores of r1, r2 and r3 given by the SVM classifier, and thres1,thres2 and thres3 were the threshold of the above results, which were assigned -1. Their weights were 1.0, 0.7 and 0.5. One document was judged as a positive instance only if its final_score bigger or equal to 0, otherwise, it was judged as a negative instance. This procedure was denoted by d (f6, f1+f2+f3, f1+f2). Our approaches in allele, expression, and tumor subtasks were almost the same. Titles, abstracts and bodies were selected as feature parts to represent the documents (denoted by f1+f2+f3). However our official run tDUTCat2 use titles and abstracts only, but achieved a normalized utility of 0.8807, which was almost equal to tDUTCat1. It indicated that in this subtask titles and abstracts contained enough information for classification. Decision algorithm was not used in these three subtasks, for MeSH terms didn't perform as well as did in the GO task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Filtering</head><p>In GO subtask, after extracted the five types of named entities, we computed the numbers of protein and DNA names that appeared in each article of the training set. We found that this number in the positive instances was much higher than that in the negatives. In the preceding stage, a large number of positive instances were obtained through the SVM classifier and decision algorithm. If we filter out the instances including less numbers of protein and DNA names from positive instances, the recall rate may be lost while the precision rate could be significantly improved.</p><p>In our run aDUTCat1, we sorted these instances twice (in an descending ordering), firstly, by the rate of protein names (number of proteins / length of the article) and secondly, by the final scores given by the decision algorithm. Instances that had ranked in the first 1/3 both times were removed from positive group as negative instances. As can be seen from Table <ref type="table" coords="7,452.34,573.22,4.23,9.72" target="#tab_4">5</ref>, using this method, the normalized utility increased from 0.5428 to 0.5720 in GO subtask. Among the 214 instances that were filtered out, only four were true positive instances and the rest were negative ones.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Results</head><p>We participated in all the four subtasks and submitted two runs for each subtask. From Table <ref type="table" coords="7,503.00,664.42,5.40,9.72" target="#tab_4">5</ref> and Table <ref type="table" coords="7,134.15,679.54,4.11,9.72" target="#tab_5">6</ref>, we can see most our submitted runs were above the median, and the first group of results (aDUTCat1, eDUTCat1, gDUTCat1 and tDUTCat1) was better than the second one (aDUTCat2, eDUTCat2, gDUTCat2 and tDUTCat2). It suggests that using Named Entity Recognition (NER) technique is an effective way to improve the performance of biomedical </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Conclusion</head><p>This is the first time that DUTAI participated in TREC genomics track. We took part in both ad hoc retrieval task and categorization task. For the ad hoc retrieval task, we used query expansion, different scoring strategy on different parts of Medline record and pseudo relevance feedback. Our submitted run DUTAdHoc2 obtained a MAP of 0.2349. We found that query expansion helped a lot to improve the retrieval recall rate and the position information of query terms could influence a Medline record's relevance. For the categorization task, our system used a SVM classifier with TFIDF term weighting scheme combined with concept replacing and filtering methods. Most our submitted runs were above the median, and the first group of results (aDUTCat1, eDUTCat1, gDUTCat1 and tDUTCat1) was better than the second one (aDUTCat2, eDUTCat2, gDUTCat2 and tDUTCat2). It suggests that using Named Entity Recognition (NER) technique is an effective way to improve the performance of biomedical document classification.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgement</head><p>This work is supported by grant from the Natural Science Foundation of China (60373095). </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,215.28,710.98,166.36,9.72"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Framework of our IR system.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,88.08,124.66,400.75,239.67"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Five generic topic templates.</figDesc><table coords="2,88.08,155.80,400.75,116.38"><row><cell>Generic Topic Type</cell><cell>Topic</cell><cell>Example Sample Topic</cell></row><row><cell>Find articles describing standard methods or</cell><cell cols="2">100-109 Method or protocol: GST fusion</cell></row><row><cell>protocols for doing some sort of experiment or</cell><cell></cell><cell>protein expression in Sf9 insect cells</cell></row><row><cell>procedure</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Find articles describing the role of a gene involved</cell><cell cols="2">110-119 Gene: DRD4 Disease: Alcoholism</cell></row><row><cell>in a given disease</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Find articles describing the role of a gene in a</cell><cell cols="2">120-129 Gene: Insulin receptor gene</cell></row><row><cell>specific biological process</cell><cell></cell><cell>Biological process: Signaling</cell></row></table><note coords="2,347.28,278.68,54.22,8.86;2,88.08,294.28,196.12,8.86;2,88.08,309.40,193.40,8.86;2,88.08,324.52,158.44,8.86;2,303.60,294.28,148.19,8.86;2,347.28,309.40,69.57,8.86;2,88.08,340.12,196.10,8.86;2,88.08,355.48,139.06,8.86;2,303.60,340.12,138.34,8.86;2,347.28,355.48,138.37,8.86"><p>tumorigenesis Find articles describing interactions (e.g., promote, suppress, inhibit, etc.) between two or more genes in the function of an organ or in a disease 130-139 Genes: HMG and HMGB1 Disease: Hepatitis Find articles describing one or more mutations of a given gene and its biological impact 140-149 Gene with mutation: Ret Biological impact: Thyroid function</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,88.08,373.54,388.44,56.52"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Necessary term and optional term.</figDesc><table coords="4,124.08,389.38,352.44,40.68"><row><cell>Topic</cell><cell>Necessary</cell><cell>Optional</cell></row><row><cell>131</cell><cell>L1, L2, HPV11</cell><cell>Virus, viral, capsid</cell></row><row><cell>141</cell><cell>Huntington, mutation</cell><cell>Role</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="4,88.08,451.30,401.29,56.52"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Scoring rules.</figDesc><table coords="4,108.24,467.14,381.13,40.68"><row><cell></cell><cell>Title</cell><cell>Abstract</cell><cell>MeSH, RN</cell><cell>No Found</cell></row><row><cell>Necessary</cell><cell>20</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>-200</cell></row><row><cell>Optional</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>0</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,88.08,124.66,392.28,87.48"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Ad hoc task results.</figDesc><table coords="5,89.52,155.86,390.84,56.28"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>R-Prec</cell><cell>B-Pref</cell><cell>P@10</cell><cell>P@30</cell></row><row><cell>Baseline</cell><cell>0.1457</cell><cell>0.1571</cell><cell>0.6242</cell><cell>0.2469</cell><cell>0.2184</cell></row><row><cell>DUTAdHoc1</cell><cell>0.2344</cell><cell>0.2718</cell><cell>0.6625</cell><cell>0.402</cell><cell>0.3163</cell></row><row><cell>DUTAdHoc2</cell><cell>0.2349</cell><cell>0.2678</cell><cell>0.6616</cell><cell>0.3939</cell><cell>0.315</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="8,88.08,124.66,416.92,165.27"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Results of our official runs.</figDesc><table coords="8,91.92,140.68,413.08,149.26"><row><cell>subtask</cell><cell>runID</cell><cell>feature</cell><cell>Concept</cell><cell cols="3">Filtering Precision Recall Unorm</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Replacing</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>allele</cell><cell>aDUTCat1</cell><cell>f1+f2+f3</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>0.2858</cell><cell>0.9307 0.7939</cell></row><row><cell>allele</cell><cell>aDUTCat2</cell><cell>f1+f2+f3</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>0.2620</cell><cell>0.9217 0.7690</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">expression eDUTCat1</cell><cell>f1+f2+f3</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>0.2383</cell><cell>0.9429 0.8496</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">expression eDUTCat2</cell><cell>f1+f2+f3</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>0.1104</cell><cell>0.9429 0.8241</cell></row><row><cell>GO</cell><cell cols="2">gDUTCat1 d(f6,f1+f2+f3,f1+f2)</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>0.1914</cell><cell>0.9286 0.5720</cell></row><row><cell>GO</cell><cell cols="2">gDUTCat2 d(f6,f1+f2+f3,f1+f2)</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>0.1779</cell><cell>0.9363 0.5428</cell></row><row><cell>tumor</cell><cell>tDUTCat1</cell><cell>f1+f2+f3</cell><cell>Yes</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>0.0745</cell><cell>0.9500 0.8989</cell></row><row><cell>tumor</cell><cell>tDUTCat2</cell><cell>f1+f2</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>No</cell><cell>0.0350</cell><cell>1.0000 0.8807</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="8,88.08,311.86,420.54,152.28"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Results of all runs. document classification. Different from newswire domain, biomedical articles contain more named entities, which play an important role in document classification. So how to recognize and handle these entities is a key problem.</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="9,103.19,139.78,378.98,9.72;9,88.08,155.14,151.50,9.72" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,170.87,139.78,307.05,9.72">Report on TREC 2003 genomics track first-year results and future plans</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Hersh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,88.08,155.14,56.17,9.72">SIGIR Forum</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="72" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,103.43,170.26,404.98,9.72;9,88.08,183.14,143.34,11.97" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,303.83,170.26,159.33,9.72">The unified medical language system</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Dab</forename><surname>Lindberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Humphreys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Mccray</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,470.62,170.26,37.80,9.72;9,88.08,185.38,31.42,9.72">Methods Inf Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="281" to="291" />
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,103.19,200.50,274.18,9.72" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://www.seg.rmit.edu.au/zettair/" />
		<title level="m" coord="9,103.19,200.50,110.34,9.72">The Zettair Search Engine</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,103.19,215.86,405.09,9.72;9,88.08,230.98,268.17,9.72" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,159.35,215.86,348.93,9.72;9,88.08,230.98,82.41,9.72">ABNER: an open source tool for automatically tagging genes, proteins, and other entity names in text</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Burr</forename><surname>Settles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,176.88,230.98,62.09,9.72">Bioinformatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3191" to="3192" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,104.87,246.10,403.14,9.72;9,88.08,261.46,397.01,9.72" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,165.11,246.10,342.91,9.72;9,88.08,261.46,105.38,9.72">Advances in Kernel Methods -Support Vector Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Joachims</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>B. Schölkopf and C. Burges and A. Smola</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<publisher>MIT-Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Making large-Scale SVM Learning Practical</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,107.03,276.58,401.36,9.72;9,88.08,291.70,320.70,9.72" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,299.24,276.58,209.15,9.72;9,88.08,291.70,34.17,9.72">Term-weighting approaches in automatic text retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gerard</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,128.39,291.70,173.74,9.72">Information Processing and Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="513" to="523" />
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,104.15,306.82,404.25,9.72;9,88.08,322.18,342.52,9.72" xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Kazuhiro</forename><surname>Seki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="9,172.55,306.82,335.85,9.72;9,88.08,322.18,277.54,9.72">TREC 2004 Genomics Track Experiments at IUB. NIST Special Publication 500-261: The Thirteenth Text REtrieval Conference Proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>TREC</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
