<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,156.72,75.18,282.08,14.47">Genomics Retrieval Experiments at UTA</title>
				<funder ref="#_x38wNzz">
					<orgName type="full">Academy of Finland</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,270.00,106.82,55.56,11.10"><forename type="first">Ari</forename><surname>Pirkola</surname></persName>
							<email>pirkola@cc.jyu.fi</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Tampere (UTA)</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="FI">Finland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Information Studies</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,156.72,75.18,282.08,14.47">Genomics Retrieval Experiments at UTA</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">C5CE9208A65194A938603FBCCFA283F0</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:02+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.44" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>University of Tampere submitted runs for Genomics Track ad hoc retrieval task. The first run (uta05a) was an automatic and the second (uta05i) an interactive run. The uta05a queries were constructed by using the original topic terms as query keys. The uta05a queries served as a baseline for the uta05i queries which were constructed by expanding the uta05a queries with synonyms for the topic gene names from the Entrez Gene database and by further expanding with synonymous gene names and MH terms from the top documents of an initial uta05i search. The mean average precision for uta05a was 0.2385 and for uta05i 0.1980.</p><p>Next in Section 2.1 we present the indexing methods and the processing of query keys. Section 2.2 considers the retrieval system and query operators. Query formulation is presented in Section 2.3. Section 3 contains the results and conclusions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Methods and data</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Indexing and the processing of query keys</head><p>We used the following approaches and techniques in indexing and for query keys:</p><p>• Genomics Track test collection for the ad hoc task was a subset of the Medline collection. Each record consists of several fields. We indexed the fields TI (title), AB (abstract), MH (MeSH headings), RN (Registry Number), and GS (Gene Symbol) • Letters were normalized to lower case.</p><p>• Query keys and the words of documents were normalized using the morphological analyzer Kstem, which is part of InQuery retrieval system. • Only letters (a-z) and numbers (0-9) were indexed. Hyphens and other characters in strings than letters and numbers were replaced by a space, and were not searchable. • Strings containing both letters and numbers were decomposed into separate alphabetical and numerical strings. In searching the string elements were linked to each other by means of a proximity operator (Section 2.2).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Retrieval system and query operators used in the tests</head><p>The test system was the InQuery retrieval system <ref type="bibr" coords="1,293.99,673.63,89.26,10.80" target="#b0">(Allan et al., 2000;</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,386.15,673.63,91.93,10.80" target="#b2">Larkey et al., 2005)</ref>. InQuery provides a variety of query operators, including the Boolean conjunction operator #band which formed the basis of our both runs. For the #band-operator all its argument keys must occur in a document in order for the operator to contribute to the weight computed for that document.</p><p>Otherwise #band contributes to the document score like the #and-operator. The weight of the #andoperator is computed as the product of the weights of its arguments. For the #sum-operator, the system computes an average of key weights.</p><p>Except for the first 10 topics (topic numbers 100-109) Genomics Track 2005 topics were organized in columns with each column representing one aspect of a topic <ref type="bibr" coords="2,361.85,158.84,64.40,10.80" target="#b1">(Hersh, 2005)</ref>. In the uta05a queries the keys were grouped into #sum-subqueries with each subquery representing one column in a topic. For uta05i, subqueries were constructed based both on the topic structure and an intellectual analysis. For both query types different subqueries were combined to each other by the #bandoperator. In the first 10 queries keys were linked to each other with the #sum-operator.</p><p>Phrases were searched for using the proximity operators of #odn (ordered window operator) and #uwn (unordered window operator). N was set at k+1 (uta05a) and k+2 (uta05i) where k=the number of elements in a phrase.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Query formulation</head><p>Next we describe the uta05a and uta05i query formulation and present example queries. uta05a</p><p>Uta05a queries were Boolean queries based on the column structure of the topics (Section 2.2). Below we present an example of Genomics Track topic (# 112) and an uta05a query derived from it:</p><p>Gene(s) Disease IDE gene Alzheimer's Disease #band(#sum(ide gene ) #sum(alzheimer disease))</p><p>Strings (gene names) containing both letters and numbers were decomposed as described in Section 2.1, and in searching the string elements were combined by means of the proximity operator of #odn. For example, for the gene name MMS2 the proximity statement was as #od3(mms 2).</p><p>uta05i</p><p>The aim of the uta05i run was to investigate the effects of gene name synonym and MH term expansion on retrieval performance. We compare the performance of uta05i to that of uta05a. Uta05i query construction proceeded as follows:</p><p>Synonymous gene names for the topic gene names were retrieved from the Entrez Gene database. Uta05a queries were expanded with the collected synonyms, and the expanded initial uta05i queries were run on the test collection. Final uta05i queries were formulated by further expanding the queries with MH terms (including subheadings) and synonyms found in the top 20 documents of an initial uta05i search.</p><p>An example uta05i query is presented below (query # 112):</p><p>#band(#sum(#od4(ide gene) ide #od5(insulin degrading enzyme) insulinase insulysin) #sum(#uw5(alzheimer disease genetics) #uw4(alzheimer disease)))</p><p>If the first query gave no results the #and-operator was used instead of the #band-operator (this concerns both uta05a and uta05i).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Results and conclusions</head><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="3,117.17,258.20,4.50,10.80">1</ref>. Retrieval performance of the uta05a and uta05i queries. The results of the two runs are presented in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,296.57,403.41,4.42,10.80">1</ref>. As can be seen, for uta05a MAP is 0.2385 and for uta05i 0.1980. The results are unexpected. We expected that interactive retrieval (uta05i) would have given better results than automatic retrieval (uta05a). We will analyze the results, focusing on the question why gene name synonym and/or MH term expansion did not contribute to better retrieval performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Query type MAP</head></div>		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This research is part of the research project <rs type="projectName">NLP-based information retrieval systems</rs> for the biological literature funded by the <rs type="funder">Academy of Finland</rs> (funding decision <rs type="grantNumber">206568</rs>).</p><p>The InQuery search engine was provided by the <rs type="institution">Center for Intelligent Information Retrieval at the University of Massachusetts</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_x38wNzz">
					<idno type="grant-number">206568</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">NLP-based information retrieval systems</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,56.64,100.22,457.03,9.94;4,56.64,113.42,336.23,9.94;4,56.64,126.62,220.08,9.94" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Allan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Connell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F.-F</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://trec.nist.gov/pubs/trec9/t9_proceedings.html" />
		<title level="m" coord="4,398.39,100.22,115.28,9.94;4,56.64,113.42,189.45,9.94">Inquery and TREC-9. The Ninth Text REtrieval Conference (TREC-9)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Gaithesburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,56.64,153.02,239.14,9.94;4,56.64,166.22,201.54,9.94" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hersh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ir.ohsu.edu/genomics/2005protocol.html" />
		<title level="m" coord="4,132.24,153.02,159.24,9.94">TREC 2005 genomics track protocol</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,56.64,192.62,454.04,9.94;4,56.64,205.82,409.15,9.94" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,225.40,192.62,285.28,9.94;4,56.64,205.82,156.11,9.94">Structured queries, language modeling, and relevance modeling in cross-language information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Larkey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Connell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,219.66,205.82,168.87,9.94">Information Processing &amp; Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="457" to="473" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
