<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.00,77.49,288.74,16.71">Style Change Detection based on Prompt</title>
				<funder ref="#_RaXSJ3F">
					<orgName type="full">Natural Science Foundation of Guangdong Province, China</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,72.00,108.63,59.68,11.62"><forename type="first">Zhijie</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Foshan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Foshan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,140.28,108.63,77.64,11.62"><forename type="first">Zhongyuan</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Foshan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Foshan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,227.76,108.63,57.72,11.62"><forename type="first">Leilei</forename><surname>Kong</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Foshan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Foshan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.00,77.49,288.74,16.71">Style Change Detection based on Prompt</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">665F10AFEB4A09F3BC6B8C479E887712</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T16:26+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Style Change Detection</term>
					<term>Prompt</term>
					<term>Mask Language Model</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The Style Change Detection 2022 aims to identify text positions within a given multi-author document at which the author switches. The previous method for detecting the style change used the Pretrained Language Model BERT to extract the interaction features of paragraphs as author style change. However, the models like BERT have a problem of inconsistent train and test objectives as there is no Mask Language Model (MLM) task when fine-tuning the downstream. Moreover, the effectiveness of features certainly lacks interpretability. For the above two points, this paper proposes a method of Style Change Detection based on Prompt (SCDP), a novel way of interacting with building a manual Prompt to reflect the writing style between two adjacent paragraphs or sentences by utilizing a pre-trained MLM. Using the proposed SCDP, we can settle the problem of inconsistent train and test objectives and increase the interpretability of the model, revealing the possibility of using a Pretrained Language Model-based Prompt for Style Change Detection.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>In recent years, we have witnessed the importance of writing style change detection, which is related to problems from the fields of stylometry, intrinsic plagiarism detection, and authorship attribution <ref type="bibr" coords="1,117.39,472.85,12.38,10.70" target="#b0">[1]</ref> <ref type="bibr" coords="1,129.77,472.85,12.38,10.70" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. The style change detection task aims to identify text positions within a given multiauthor document at which the author switches. At PAN 2022 Style Change Detection <ref type="bibr" coords="1,450.26,485.57,13.49,10.70" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, there is one more sentence-level task than PAN 2021. The difficulty level increased as the sentence level meant less information is available, making it more difficult to distinguish the author's writing style.</p><p>The previous method for detecting the style change like Zhang et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="1,411.12,523.49,11.70,10.70" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, using the Pretrained Language Model BERT <ref type="bibr" coords="1,179.49,536.09,16.54,10.70" target="#b5">[6]</ref>; however, research <ref type="bibr" coords="1,291.49,536.09,13.50,10.70" target="#b6">[7]</ref> recently shows the problems of BERT that inconsistent train and test objectives. Moreover, Are the text interaction features extracted after finetuning the BERT features about writing style? We believe that its lacks certain interpretability.</p><p>In response to the above two points, we propose a method of Style Change Detection based on Prompt (SCDP), a novel way of interaction with building a manual Prompt (i.e. manual construction of templates) to reflect the writing style between two adjacent paragraphs or sentences by utilizing a pre-trained MLM. Using the proposed SCDP, we can settle the problem of inconsistent train and test objectives and increase the interpretability of the model, revealing the possibility of using a Pretrained Language Model-based Prompt for Style Change Detection.</p><p>CLEF 2022 -Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum, September 5-8, 2022, Bologna, Italy EMAIL: zhangzhijie5454@gmail.com (A. 1); hanzhongyuan@gmail.com (A. 2)(*corresponding author); kongleilei@fosu.edu.cn (A. 3) ORCID: 0000-0002-4854-0618 (A. 1); 0000-0001-8960-9872 (A. 2); 0000-0002-4636-3507 (A. 3)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Style Change Detection</head><p>This section briefly describes the tasks and datasets.</p><p> Tasks: Style Change Detection 2022 <ref type="bibr" coords="2,256.33,131.33,14.95,10.70" target="#b0">[1]</ref> was divided into three tasks. Specifically, Style Change Basic (Task1): For a text written by two authors that only contains a single style change, find this change's position. Style Change Advanced (Task2): For a text written by two or more authors, find all positions of writing style change. Style Change Real-World (Task3): For a text written by two or more authors, find all positions of writing style change, where style changes now occur between paragraphs and at the sentence level.</p><p> Datasets: Style Change Detection 2022 released new datasets <ref type="bibr" coords="2,368.76,219.77,12.60,10.70" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, which are based on user posts from various sites of the StackExchange network, covering different topics. Three datasets, including ground truth information, are provided (dataset1 for task 1, dataset2 for task 2, and dataset3 for task 3).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Method</head><p>In this section, we briefly outline our approach. We have mainly divided into tasks solution and SCDP model construction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Tasks Solution</head><p>After analyzing three task definitions, we found that Task1 and Task2 were the same as Task2 and Task3 last year, and Task3 is a sentence-level detection. The difficulty level has increased because the sentence level means that less information is available, making it more difficult to distinguish the author's writing style.</p><p>For the solution of the tasks, we followed the previous year's approach <ref type="bibr" coords="2,395.60,449.09,14.52,10.70" target="#b1">[2]</ref> and used only one model to complete three tasks. Specifically, for Task1, we used the model to determine whether the writing style between adjacent paragraphs is the same. A similar goes for Task3 but replacing paragraphs with sentences. While Task2, like Task3 last year, labels the author's serial number from the first paragraph of each text. We referred to the Zhang <ref type="bibr" coords="2,250.29,499.73,14.60,10.70" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, which converts the standard serial number labels into binary labels first, and then judges whether the author between label-related paragraphs is the same (i.e., paragraphs that could affect the label change, please refer to the Zhang <ref type="bibr" coords="2,403.62,525.05,15.37,10.70" target="#b1">[2]</ref> for details).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">SCDP Model</head><p>Based on the above solution, we also need a model that can discriminate the writing style between two paragraphs or sentences, and we mainly modify it for the BERT model. Inspired by Brown <ref type="bibr" coords="2,502.81,595.37,15.20,10.70" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, which has reformulated the different NLP tasks as fill-in-the-blanks problems by different prompts, we propose a prompt-based method using the template to resolve training and testing objective inconsistencies of the Pretrained Language Model (PLM).</p><p>As shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,176.64,646.01,4.14,10.70" target="#fig_0">1</ref>, the Mask Language Model (MLM) is built up by BERT and MLM Head (a network mapping the hidden size to the vocabulary size). After constructing the input sample by a template like They are the [MASK] writing style: and + , where is a placeholder to put paragraph, represents the number of the paragraphs and represents the predicted token, we send it to MLM and start to predict the [MASK] token. Then, MLM will output the prediction vocabulary scores, where the max scores will be mapped to token [same], and its id (namely token id after tokenizer) will be the final label if the style between the previous paragraph and next paragraph has kept, or the final label will be the id of token <ref type="bibr" coords="2,273.48,734.81,44.00,10.70">[different]</ref>. The cross-entropy loss is applied for training to classify vocabulary. During the evaluation phases, the label [same] and [different] will be mapped back to corresponding labels [0] and <ref type="bibr" coords="2,235.08,760.13,11.70,10.70" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Specifically, the blue squares is the template we have constructed, the red squares is the two input text paragraphs, and the green square predicts whether the writing style of the two texts has changed. In this structure, the token predicted by the model will have information about the writing style because MLM is a bi-directional language model that learns the context of the whole sentence through self-attention.</p><p>In this way, the acute problem of whether the extracted interaction features are stylistic features is avoided, and the introduction of the template also allows the model to understand better the problem we are trying to solve. Finally, it adds some interpretability to the model, at least to determine that the output of the model is based on the writing style of template.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Experimental setting</head><p>We conduct experiments on the RTX 3090 and use Pytorch implementation with CUDA to speed up training. The model BERT (bert-base-uncased) is utilized to build up MLM, which is equal to the pre-training phases of BERT. The experimental setting is shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,417.00,508.13,4.14,10.70" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. Finally, evaluate the model on TIRA <ref type="bibr" coords="3,136.56,520.73,15.48,10.70" target="#b7">[8]</ref>.<ref type="foot" coords="3,159.96,520.03,3.43,6.63" target="#foot_0">1</ref>  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Results</head><p>The trained model is evaluated on the validation and test sets, with the results shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,499.56,677.21,4.14,10.70" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. To better measure Task2, two additional evaluations, Diarization Error Rate (DER) and Jaccard Error Rate (JER), were added to Task 2 this year as the labels of each text in Task 2 are interrelated.</p><p>The results show that the validation and test sets are similar, proving that the method is stable. Although it may not be as good as the traditional fine-tuning method, our approach overcomes the model's shortcomings with inconsistent training and test objectives. We will continue to explore how to use the prompt-based model to identify writing style better, believing that it can increase the interpretability of the model. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusion</head><p>This paper proposes a method of Style Change Detection based on Prompt (SCDP), a novel way of interacting with building a manual Prompt to reflect the writing style between two adjacent paragraphs or sentences by utilizing a pre-trained MLM. Using the proposed SCDP, we can settle the problem of inconsistent train and test objectives and increase the interpretability of the model, revealing the possibility of using a Pretrained Language Model-based Prompt for Style Change Detection.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,72.00,284.92,149.42,10.83;3,72.00,72.00,450.84,195.96"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: The illustration of SCDP.</figDesc><graphic coords="3,72.00,72.00,450.84,195.96" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,72.00,546.64,412.20,59.98"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="3,72.00,560.08,412.20,46.54"><row><cell>Experimental setting</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Batch size</cell><cell>Max Length</cell><cell>Learning Rate</cell><cell>Epoch</cell><cell>Report step</cell></row><row><cell>64</cell><cell>256</cell><cell>3e-5</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>125</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,72.00,126.04,434.95,80.86"><head>Table 2 The</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="4,84.84,139.48,422.11,67.42"><row><cell cols="2">result of Datasets</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Datasets</cell><cell>Task1.F1</cell><cell>Task2.F1</cell><cell>Task2.DER</cell><cell>Task2.JER</cell><cell>Task3.F1</cell></row><row><cell>Validation</cell><cell>0.70456</cell><cell>0.43098</cell><cell>0.71707</cell><cell>0.65023</cell><cell>0.66688</cell></row><row><cell>Test</cell><cell>0.71623</cell><cell>0.41741</cell><cell>0.71140</cell><cell>0.64441</cell><cell>0.65814</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="3,76.56,762.96,240.38,7.79"><p>Our source code is publicly available at https://github.com/chigee54/SCDP</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="7.">Acknowledgments</head><p>This work is supported by the <rs type="funder">Natural Science Foundation of Guangdong Province, China</rs> (No. <rs type="grantNumber">2022A1515011544</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_RaXSJ3F">
					<idno type="grant-number">2022A1515011544</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,108.00,466.73,415.05,10.70;4,108.00,479.45,415.08,10.70;4,108.00,492.05,170.16,10.70" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,448.56,466.73,74.50,10.70;4,108.00,479.45,192.43,10.70">Overview of the Style Change Detection Task at PAN 2022</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Eva</forename><surname>Zangerle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Maximilian</forename><surname>Mayerl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,321.96,479.45,148.67,10.70">CLEF 2022 Labs and Workshops</title>
		<title level="s" coord="4,479.64,479.45,43.44,10.70;4,108.00,492.05,165.60,10.70">Notebook Papers, CEUR Workshop Processings</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,108.00,504.77,415.08,10.70;4,108.00,517.37,415.08,10.70;4,108.00,529.97,416.04,10.70" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,333.36,504.77,189.72,10.70;4,108.00,517.37,229.46,10.70">Style Change Detection Based On Writing Style Similarity-Notebook for PAN at CLEF</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Zhijie</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Zhongyuan</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Leilei</forename><surname>Kong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="CEUR-WS.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,143.40,529.97,144.83,10.70">CLEF 2021 Labs and Workshops</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Guglielmo</forename><surname>Faggioli</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-09">2021. September 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Notebook Papers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,108.00,542.69,415.05,10.70;4,108.00,555.29,415.08,10.70;4,108.00,568.01,326.88,10.70" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,108.00,568.01,171.49,10.70">Language models are few-shot learners</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Tom B Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nick</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Melanie</forename><surname>Ryder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jared</forename><surname>Subbiah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Prafulla</forename><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Arvind</forename><surname>Dhariwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Pranav</forename><surname>Neelakantan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Girish</forename><surname>Shyam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><surname>Sastry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Askell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2005.14165</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,108.00,580.61,414.96,10.70;4,108.00,593.33,415.08,10.70;4,108.00,605.93,415.08,10.70;4,108.00,618.53,415.04,10.70;4,108.00,631.13,233.16,10.70" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,232.05,605.93,291.04,10.70;4,108.00,618.53,243.65,10.70">Overview of PAN 2022: Authorship Verification,Profiling Irony and Stereotype Spreaders, and Style Change Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bevendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Chulvi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fersini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kestemont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kredens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mayerl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ortega</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pezik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wolska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Zangerle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,377.04,618.53,146.00,10.70;4,108.00,631.13,157.50,10.70">13th International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF 2022)</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,108.00,643.85,415.08,10.70;4,108.00,656.45,411.59,10.70" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,443.76,643.85,79.32,10.70;4,108.00,656.45,139.69,10.70">Pan22 authorship analysis: Style change detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Zangerle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mayerl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tschuggnall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://zenodo.org/record/6334245#.YiYCcXXMJ8x" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,108.00,669.17,414.93,10.70;4,108.00,681.77,252.84,10.70" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,214.55,669.17,308.38,10.70;4,108.00,681.77,60.27,10.70">Bert: Pre-training of deep bidirectional transformers for language understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Devlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1810.04805</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,108.00,694.37,414.93,10.70;4,108.00,707.09,347.88,10.70" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,227.77,694.37,295.16,10.70;4,108.00,707.09,60.27,10.70">Xlnet: Generalized autoregressive pretraining for language understanding</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Zhilin</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,180.24,707.09,227.02,10.70">Advances in neural information processing systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,108.00,719.69,415.08,10.70;4,108.00,732.41,415.08,10.70;4,108.00,745.01,414.96,10.70;4,108.00,757.73,24.84,10.70" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,397.07,719.69,126.02,10.70;4,108.00,732.41,53.67,10.70">TIRA Integrated Research Architecture</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gollub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,184.92,732.41,338.16,10.70;4,108.00,745.01,69.81,10.70">Information Retrieval Evaluation in a Changing World, ser. The Information Retrieval Series</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019-09">Sep. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
