<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,89.29,84.74,401.05,15.42;1,89.29,106.66,269.97,15.42">Profiling irony and stereotype spreaders on Twitter based on term frequency in tweets</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,89.29,134.97,68.79,11.96"><forename type="first">Dhaval</forename><surname>Taunk</surname></persName>
							<email>dhaval.taunk@research.iiit.ac.in</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">International Institute of Information Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Hyderabad</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,170.73,134.97,54.35,11.96"><forename type="first">Sagar</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
							<email>sagar.joshi@research.iiit.ac.in</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">International Institute of Information Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Hyderabad</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,256.07,134.97,81.15,11.96"><forename type="first">Vasudeva</forename><surname>Varma</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">International Institute of Information Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Hyderabad</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,89.29,84.74,401.05,15.42;1,89.29,106.66,269.97,15.42">Profiling irony and stereotype spreaders on Twitter based on term frequency in tweets</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">1613-0073</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">0FCC30F4667457C8A498DA5BEE6189BB</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T16:25+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Irony</term>
					<term>Stereotype</term>
					<term>Random Forest</term>
					<term>TF-IDF</term>
					<term>Twitter</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The use of stereotypes, irony, mocking and scornful language is prevalent on social media platforms such as Twitter. Identification or profiling of users who are involved in the spread of such content is beneficial for monitoring its spread. In our work, we study the problem of profiling irony and stereotype spreaders on Twitter as a part of the PAN shared task in CLEF 2022. We experiment with machine learning models applied on a TF-IDF representation of user tweets, and find Random Forest to be the best working one.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Metaphorical and figurative style of writing presents a subtle way of communicating across a message on social media. The nature of the message being conveyed can be distinguished based on the use of such linguistic nuances in a message being propagated. Their usage in directed ways can make the message to be either generally harmless, potentially hurtful, or even inherently toxic in nature. The identification of such content is beneficial not only for shielding often targeted demographic groups, but also for reasons such as a better understanding of the textual content on social media. As pointed out in <ref type="bibr" coords="1,334.43,428.00,11.54,10.91" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, a better understanding of sarcasm and irony in text can help improve sentiment analysis because of the difficulty in semantic understanding of text introduced by sarcasm. Apart from the understanding of sarcastic content, a profiling of users who tend to propagate such content can benefit to understand differences in the patterns of sarcasm originating from different sources. It can also ease tracking users indulging in the spread of toxic content through subtle means.</p><p>In our work, we focus on the task of profiling spreaders of ironical and stereotypical content on Twitter, as a part of the PAN <ref type="bibr" coords="1,236.28,522.84,13.00,10.91" target="#b1">[2]</ref> shared task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,306.50,522.84,13.00,10.91" target="#b2">[3]</ref> in CLEF 2022. In this task, we work on a Twitter feed of a set of users in English containing user-level annotations to indicate if the user is a spreader of ironical and stereotypical content. In our implementation of the solution, we treat all the user tweets as a single input and experiment with basic text preprocessing followed by a simple TF-IDF representation. This essentially models the task with simple term-frequency based information from past tweets. Inspite of the simplicity of modeling, however, experiments with simple, lightweight machine learning models gave encouraging results on this task. In the subsequent sections, we detail our methodology, experiments and results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Related Work</head><p>Author profiling is a well-studied problem for the identification of social media users indulging in the spread of fake news, hate speech, gender bias, and other related aspects. Diego et. al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,493.26,172.69,12.73,10.91" target="#b3">[4]</ref> attempted to solve the problem of detecting hate speech against immigrants and women on Twitter in a multilingual setting. To determine if a tweet is hateful or not, they applied SVM on top of TF-IDF representations. Rangel et. al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,304.68,213.34,12.95,10.91" target="#b4">[5]</ref> experimented with several algorithms on labeled Twitter data to detect fake news. Random label generation, LSTM, Neural Network with word n-gram features, SVM with character level n-gram features, and other models were tested by the authors.</p><p>Carracedo et. al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,181.62,279.49,13.00,10.91" target="#b5">[6]</ref> solve the hate speech detection problem by using a Support Vector Machine (SVM) classifier over n-gram features. For detecting irony, Reyes et. al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,439.58,293.04,12.69,10.91" target="#b6">[7]</ref> constructed a three-layer model. They create signatures using three linguistic characteristics: pointedness, counterfactuality, and temporal compression. In emotional circumstances, three language properties are activation, imagery, and pleasantness. Unpredictability based on two literary characteristics: temporal and contextual imbalance. They use the above-mentioned layers to turn text into feature vectors and estimate whether or not an input text contains irony.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Methodology</head><p>The aim of this task is to determine whether or not a given Twitter user is using irony/stereotype in their tweets. This can help in easing the identification of sources creating or propagating such content. In the following sections, we describe our approach on modeling this problem with our experiment based on term-frequency based text preprocessing in conjunction with classical machine learning algorithms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Data Description</head><p>The dataset provided by the task organizers had 420 training instances, each having 200 past tweets for a Twitter user -thus corresponding to 420 user profiles to be labeled. 210 of the user profiles belonged to the class that spreads irony, whereas the remaining 210 did not, hence the dataset to be worked upon was balanced. The test set contained 180 user profiles also bearing 200 tweets per user (but with labels not included as a part of the dataset). The tweets were all monolingual in English. Since there was no explicit dataset provided for validation, we split the given training dataset into train and dev split with a split ratio of 80:20.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Text Pre-processing</head><p>In the data provided, user ids, urls and hashtags were already replaced by #USER#, #URL# and #HASHTAG# placeholders respectively. As a part of our preprocessing, we tried out completely removing the placeholders versus keeping them as a part of the pipeline to see the impact of these features have in determining a piece of content as ironic or stereotypical.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Experiments</head><p>This section explains the approach we followed for the task. Our experimentation pipeline consisting of pre-processing followed by featured extraction and ML-based modeling can be described as below.</p><p>1. Pre-processing: Each of the tweets in a user profile of 200 tweets is preprocessed to either remove or keep the placeholders as described in Section 3.2. We found keeping the placeholders to perform better, hence we adopted this pre-processing in calculating the features. 2. Feature Extraction: A pre-processed tweet text is represented using a TF-IDF vector as a simple term-frequency based tweet representation and the representation of a user is calculated as a summation of all the tweet vectors. The TF-IDF vector values are determined based on the frequency information of words in the train split for all the words in the train split vocabulary. The terms not present in the train split vocabulary are ignored when computing the feature vectors for dev and test splits. 3. Modeling: This step involved trying out different machine learning techniques on the TF-IDF features extracted from the data. We experimented with classifiers based on Logistic Regression, K Nearest Neighbors, Support Vector Machines, Random Forest and XGBoost.</p><p>For training and making predictions on the test set, the Scikit-learn <ref type="bibr" coords="3,399.11,411.71,12.74,10.91" target="#b7">[8]</ref> package was utilised. Different hyperparameters settings were experimented in training the model. To begin, all of the models were trained using the Scikit-learn package's default parameters.</p><p>The best hyperparameter settings were determined for each of the models used using Random Search CV on an 80/20 train/dev split. The selected hyperparameters for finetuning and the range of the values tried out are summarized in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,329.99,479.46,3.74,10.91" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Results</head><p>The results on the dev set using the best model configurations obtained after hyperparameter tuning are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,208.81,542.74,3.74,10.91" target="#tab_1">2</ref>.</p><p>Accuracy was the metric chosen by the task organizers for final evaluation. From the results, it can be seen that Random Forest Classifier gave the best performance on the metric as well as in the precision score for the positive class. F1 score had a tie-up between Random Forest Classifier and XGBoost Classifier, the latter of which turned out to be pretty competitive in the overall performance, while also having the highest recall. K Neighbors Classifier gave the worst performance across all the metrics. The best performing Random Forest Classifier was used to take predictions on the test set and was submitted for evaluation on the TIRA <ref type="bibr" coords="3,450.49,637.58,12.87,10.91" target="#b8">[9]</ref> platform, which gave an accuracy of 95%. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusion</head><p>Based on our ML-based experiments on term frequency representation of user tweets, we were able to achieve a respectable performance which was consistent across datasets used for validation and testing. Hence, if the dataset distribution used for the task matches with the data encountered in actual, in-the-wild tweets, a user-profiling with system good performance can be achieved with minimalistic lightweight techniques.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,88.99,90.49,416.99,316.71"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Hyperparameter variables and ranges of values for which hyperparameter finetuning was performed across models</figDesc><table coords="4,107.67,131.84,379.94,275.36"><row><cell>Model Name</cell><cell>Hyperparameter</cell><cell>Values</cell></row><row><cell>Logistic Regression</cell><cell>C penalty</cell><cell>1e-03, 1e-02, 1e-01, 1e+00, 1e+01, 1e+02, 1e+03 l1, l2</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>n_neighbors</cell><cell>3,4,5,6,7</cell></row><row><cell>K Neighbors Classifier</cell><cell>weights</cell><cell>uniform, distance</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>algorithm</cell><cell>auto, ball_tree, kd_tree, brute</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>C</cell><cell>0.01,0.1,1,10,100</cell></row><row><cell>SVM</cell><cell>kernal</cell><cell>linear, poly, rbf</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>gamma</cell><cell>auto, scale</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>n_estimators</cell><cell>200, 211, 222, 233, 244, 255, 266, 277, 288, 300</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>max_features</cell><cell>auto, sqrt</cell></row><row><cell>Random Forest</cell><cell cols="2">max_depth min_samples_split 2, 5, 10 10, 20, 30, 40, 50, 60, 70, 80, 90, 100, 110</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">min_samples_leaf 1, 2, 4</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>bootstrap</cell><cell>True, False</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>n_estimators</cell><cell>200, 211, 222, 233, 244, 255, 266, 277, 288, 300</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>max_features</cell><cell>auto, sqrt</cell></row><row><cell>XGBoost</cell><cell cols="2">max_depth min_samples_split 2, 5, 10 10, 20, 30, 40, 50, 60, 70, 80, 90, 100, 110</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">min_samples_leaf 1, 2, 4</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>bootstrap</cell><cell>True, False</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,88.99,429.45,418.66,117.69"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Results obtained on dev set after training using the best model configurations determined by hyperpa-</figDesc><table coords="4,89.29,453.41,356.18,93.73"><row><cell>rameter tuning</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Model</cell><cell cols="4">Accuracy F1 Score Precision Recall</cell></row><row><cell>Logistic Regression</cell><cell>87</cell><cell>85</cell><cell>89</cell><cell>82</cell></row><row><cell>K Neighbors Classifier</cell><cell>77</cell><cell>75</cell><cell>78</cell><cell>72</cell></row><row><cell>SVM</cell><cell>88</cell><cell>87</cell><cell>89</cell><cell>85</cell></row><row><cell>Random Forest Classifier</cell><cell>90</cell><cell>89</cell><cell>91</cell><cell>87</cell></row><row><cell>XGBoost Classifier</cell><cell>89</cell><cell>89</cell><cell>86</cell><cell>92</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,107.59,111.28,398.40,10.91;5,107.59,124.83,141.87,10.91;5,270.16,124.83,237.51,10.91;5,107.59,138.38,400.08,10.91;5,107.59,154.37,275.39,7.90" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,294.97,111.28,211.02,10.91;5,107.59,124.83,137.77,10.91">A qualitative analysis of sarcasm, irony and related #hashtags on twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sykora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Elayan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/2053951720972735</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/2053951720972735" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,270.16,124.83,98.65,10.91">Big Data &amp; Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2053951720972735</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,107.59,165.48,400.25,10.91;5,107.59,179.03,399.60,10.91;5,107.59,192.57,398.40,10.91;5,107.59,206.12,400.24,10.91;5,107.59,219.67,398.40,10.91;5,107.59,233.22,399.60,10.91;5,107.59,246.77,65.44,10.91" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,212.81,192.57,293.18,10.91;5,107.59,206.12,217.24,10.91">Overview of PAN 2022: Authorship Verification, Profiling Irony and Stereotype Spreaders, and Style Change Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bevendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Chulvi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fersini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kestemont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kredens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mayerl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ortega-Bueno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pezik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wolska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Zangerle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,347.69,206.12,160.13,10.91;5,107.59,219.67,398.40,10.91;5,107.59,233.22,138.99,10.91">Proceedings of the Thirteenth International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF</title>
		<title level="s" coord="5,354.58,234.24,148.40,9.72">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<meeting>the Thirteenth International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022. 2022</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13390</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Experimental IR Meets Multilinguality, Multimodality, and Interaction</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,107.59,260.32,398.40,10.91;5,107.59,273.87,399.60,10.91;5,107.59,287.42,172.05,10.91" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,371.48,260.32,134.50,10.91;5,107.59,273.87,221.38,10.91">Profiling Irony and Stereotype Spreaders on Twitter (IROSTEREO) at PAN 2022</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O.-B</forename><surname>Reynier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Berta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Francisco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Paolo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Elisabetta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="-WS.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,356.76,273.87,145.06,10.91">CLEF 2022 Labs and Workshops</title>
		<title level="s" coord="5,107.59,287.42,103.05,10.91">Notebook Papers, CEUR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,107.59,300.97,398.40,10.91;5,107.18,314.52,398.80,10.91;5,107.59,328.07,399.60,10.91;5,107.20,341.62,400.46,10.91;5,107.59,355.17,318.14,10.91" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,238.53,300.97,267.46,10.91;5,107.18,314.52,398.80,10.91;5,107.59,328.07,45.72,10.91">GSI-UPM at SemEval-2019 task 5: Semantic similarity and word embeddings for multilingual detection of hate speech against immigrants and women on Twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Diego</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oscar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">C A</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.18653/v1/S19-2070</idno>
		<ptr target="https://aclanthology.org/S19-2070.doi:10.18653/v1/S19-2070" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,176.61,328.07,330.58,10.91;5,107.20,341.62,181.62,10.91">Proceedings of the 13th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation, Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 13th International Workshop on Semantic Evaluation, Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="396" to="403" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,107.59,368.71,398.69,10.91;5,107.59,382.26,399.59,10.91;5,107.20,395.81,398.78,10.91;5,107.59,409.36,398.40,10.91;5,107.59,422.91,367.51,10.91" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,328.80,368.71,177.47,10.91;5,107.59,382.26,227.55,10.91">Overview of the 8th author profiling task at PAN 2020: Profiling fake news spreaders on twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">M R</forename><surname>Pardo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Giachanou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Ghanem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2696/paper_267.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,186.14,395.81,319.84,10.91;5,107.59,409.36,26.91,10.91">Working Notes of CLEF 2020 -Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<title level="s" coord="5,432.30,410.38,73.68,9.72;5,107.59,422.91,77.32,10.91">CEUR Workshop Proceedings, CEUR</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Cappellato</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Eickhoff</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Névéol</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Thessaloniki, Greece</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">September 22-25, 2020. 2696. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,107.59,436.46,399.60,10.91;5,107.59,450.01,398.65,10.91;5,105.74,463.56,402.09,10.91;5,107.59,477.11,400.08,10.91;5,107.59,490.66,217.35,10.91" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,251.78,436.46,182.76,10.91">Profiling hate speech spreaders on twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">À</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Carracedo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mondéjar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2936/paper-152.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,296.83,450.01,209.41,10.91;5,105.74,463.56,207.96,10.91">Proceedings of the Working Notes of CLEF 2021 -Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<title level="s" coord="5,225.42,477.11,148.04,10.91">CEUR Workshop Proceedings, CEUR</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Faggioli</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Joly</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Maistro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Piroi</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the Working Notes of CLEF 2021 -Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum<address><addrLine>Bucharest, Romania</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">September 21st -to -24th, 2021. 2936. 2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1801" to="1807" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,107.59,504.21,400.24,10.91;5,107.59,517.76,399.10,10.91;5,107.59,531.30,256.69,10.91" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,203.83,504.21,304.00,10.91;5,107.59,517.76,89.70,10.91">On the difficulty of automatically detecting irony: beyond a simple case of negation</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Reyes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10115-013-0652-8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10115-013-0652-8.doi:10.1007/s10115-013-0652-8" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,208.54,517.76,75.82,10.91">Knowl. Inf. Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="595" to="614" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,107.59,544.85,399.60,10.91;5,107.59,558.40,399.60,10.91;5,107.59,571.95,398.40,10.91;5,107.59,585.50,176.63,10.91" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,224.92,571.95,183.76,10.91">Scikit-learn: Machine learning in Python</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Pedregosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Varoquaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gramfort</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Thirion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Grisel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Blondel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Prettenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Weiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Dubourg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vanderplas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Passos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Cournapeau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Brucher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Perrot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Duchesnay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,418.54,571.95,87.45,10.91;5,107.59,585.50,82.55,10.91">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2825" to="2830" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,107.59,599.05,399.60,10.91;5,107.59,612.60,398.40,10.91;5,107.59,626.15,399.59,10.91;5,107.59,642.14,123.08,7.90" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,326.42,599.05,176.17,10.91">TIRA Integrated Research Architecture</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gollub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-030-22948-1_5</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,237.51,612.60,268.48,10.91;5,107.59,626.15,125.79,10.91">Information Retrieval Evaluation in a Changing World, The Information Retrieval Series</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
