<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,134.77,115.96,345.83,12.62;1,272.56,133.89,70.24,12.62">MolRec at CLEF 2012 -Overview and Analysis of Results</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,185.53,171.56,92.94,8.74"><forename type="first">Noureddin</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sadawi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Birmingham</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,286.56,171.56,65.72,8.74"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Sexton</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Birmingham</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,374.98,171.56,54.85,8.74"><forename type="first">Volker</forename><surname>Sorge</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Birmingham</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,134.77,115.96,345.83,12.62;1,272.56,133.89,70.24,12.62">MolRec at CLEF 2012 -Overview and Analysis of Results</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">E818953BD6E046CA2FFCC429F14B58D6</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:30+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We present the results and analysis of our chemical structure recognition system, MolRec, in the CLEF 2012 chemical structure recognition task. MolRec analyses a diagram image, extracts vectorised components from the image and applies a rule based system to construct an internal representation of the chemical structure. This internal representation can then be exported to MOL or SMILE format. The task assigned in CLEF was to analyse two sets of chemical diagram images clipped from patent documents. The first set is of 965 diagram images, the results of which could be evaluated automatically using Open-Babel. The second set is a more challenging collection of 95 images which include elements not supported by OpenBabel and which therefore have to be evaluated manually. On the first set, MolRec achieved recognition rates of between 94.91% and 96.18% over 4 runs with slightly different parameters. On the more exacting second set, MolRec's recognition rate was between 46.32% and 58.95%. Overall the results testified to high performance on a large sample of quite complex diagrams but also to the challenges posed by the more difficult images that appear in real patent documents.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="11" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>We present the recognition results of our MolRec system on the CLEF 2012 corpus of chemical molecule diagrams. MolRec is a rule based system, in that after an initial preprocessing phase, the primary recognition task is performed by a rule engine, in which largely disjoint rules are repeatedly applied to an initial set of geometric primitives, thereby rewriting the set into a graph representation of the given molecule diagram. This final graph structure then serves as a basis from which other efficient electronic representation formats, such as MOL files, can be generated.</p><p>A previous implementation of the system has already performed well in the TREC 2011 competition <ref type="bibr" coords="1,248.36,596.34,9.96,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. For CLEF 2012 we have used an improved system with a fully overhauled implementation of the rewrite engine that not only leads to better recognition performance but is also computationally much more efficient.</p><p>In this note we will first give a short overview of the system, detailing its overall structure and briefly summarising the rewriting rules that perform the primary recognition (Sec. 2). For a more detailed overview we refer the reader to <ref type="bibr" coords="2,146.55,130.95,9.96,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. We will then present the results of our system on the CLEF 2012 recognition task (Sec. 3) and follow it up by a more detailed analysis and discussion of images that were not successfully recognised (Sec. 4) but which motivate future improvements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Overview of MolRec</head><p>MolRec employs a rule-based approach for the recognition of chemical structure diagrams. It consists of two modules, a vectoriser and a rule-engine. The vectoriser preprocesses an input image, analyses the chemical structure diagram it represents and generates a set of geometric primitives. These primitives are then picked up by the rule engine which rewrites them into a graph structure representation of the recognised molecule. In a post-processing step this graph structure can then be translated into a variety of output formats such as MOL files <ref type="bibr" coords="2,154.74,306.10,10.52,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref> or SMILES <ref type="bibr" coords="2,220.91,306.10,10.52,8.74" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,231.43,306.10,7.01,8.74" target="#b7">8]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Vectorisation</head><p>The vectorisation works essentially in three steps:</p><p>1. Image binarisation 2. Optical character recognition (OCR)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Separation of bond elements</head><p>Binarisation For the first step of image binarisation we use Otsu's method <ref type="bibr" coords="2,467.31,429.17,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. This is followed by labelling of connected components.</p><p>OCR In a second step optical character recognition is performed by extracting a set of structural features from connected components and applying a nearest neighbour classification based on a Euclidean metric.</p><p>All connected components recognised as characters are removed from the image. Some contextual information is used to disambiguate difficult cases. For example, the lower case, sans serif letter "l" is often visually indistinguishable from short line segments in a molecule diagram, but in all examples we have come across, it does not appear except beside other letters (usually after a capital "C", to denote a Chlorine atom).</p><p>The result of this step is a skeleton molecule with all detected characters removed.</p><p>Separation of Bond Elements At this point we produce a new copy of the (character free) diagram and apply a thinning algorithm to connected components to thin them to a single pixel width. Using the thinned lines as a guide, we walk the corresponding paths in the original image to determine the average line width by finding the largest disk that fits wholly with the stroke width of the line. At the same time, we build a polyline representation of the thinned lines. At every junction where three or more polylines meet, we split them into separate polylines. Closed polylines are also identified.</p><p>Because of scanning, discretisation and thinning artifacts, these polylines are not, as we would like, smooth idealised representations of the lines in the original diagram. Therefore we clean them up by applying the Douglas-Peucker line simplification algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="3,264.44,202.68,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, where we set the simplification threshold to between 1 and 2 average line widths as found above. This is sufficient to smooth out the polylines, removing almost all artifacts, without losing the significant corners in the lines in the diagram. Basing the threshold on the average line width allows the algorithm to adapt to the different line styles that appear in molecule diagrams in practice.</p><p>In addition to detecting and separating polylines we also detect circles as well as lines with arrows heads and solid triangles. The latter two are then annotated with their respective direction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Rule Engine</head><p>The rule engine essentially works with the geometric primitives resulting from the vectorisation. In particular it uses character groups from the OCR step, as well as line segments, circles, solid triangles and arrows from the bond separation. The goal of the rule engine is to rewrite the input set of primitives into a graph structure that represents the molecule in terms of the atoms (or superatoms) and different types of bonds between them.</p><p>Rule are defined in terms of preconditions and consequences. A rule is applicable if there exist geometric objects that satisfies its preconditions. The consequence results in the removal of existing geometric objects and the addition of elements to the graph as well as possibly the addition of new geometric objects. In general, preconditions of different rules are mutually exclusive, and thus the order of rule application is irrelevant. Rules work with a number of parameters, both fuzzy and strict, that set certain thresholds, for instance the minimal bond length, under which decisions will be made. These parameters allow for the customisation of MolRec and its adaptation to particular requirements of datasets. In this section we will only briefly summarise the main rules and present an example. For more details we refer the reader to <ref type="bibr" coords="3,348.49,536.57,9.96,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref>.</p><p>The rule engine consists of 18 rules altogether. Two of these rules have to be applied before all other rules. These two rules deal with the recognition of bridge bonds, 3-dimensional structures representing multiple different connection paths between different parts of the molecule. These are typically presented in a 2 1 /2dimensional perspective drawing form such as in Fig. <ref type="figure" coords="3,369.89,596.34,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_0">1</ref>.</p><p>The other 16 rules can be applied in arbitrary order. They deal with the recognition of a number of other bonds that MolRec can handle and that are presented in Fig. <ref type="figure" coords="3,211.58,632.21,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. All these bonds consist of one or several geometric objects, which a rule can select using its preconditions and rewrite into a corresponding graph entry for the recognised bond type.  However, there are also single geometric objects that possibly represent more than one bond. An example are so called implicit nodes presented in Fig. <ref type="figure" coords="4,449.90,436.18,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_2">3</ref>. Here carbon atoms are understood to be at the grey circled areas separating the bonds. These cases are dealt with by rules that pick double or triple bonds, respectively, while also producing new geometric objects by effectively cutting the bonds at the implicit nodes. These new objects can then be further processed by other rules.</p><p>Not all decisions on bond types can be made by inspecting locally a number of geometric objects only. Consequently some rules mark some of their results as possibly ambiguous. These ambiguities have to be resolved taking context information into account. This is done after all geometric objects have been rewritten within the context of the resulting graph. Furthermore, at this stage MolRec also adds the character groups to the graph, which can be used as further aid for disambiguation. For example, disambiguation of lower case "l", capital case "I", the digit "1" and a vertical single bond is carried out at this stage. In addition character groups identifying more than one atom are identified as superatoms. Their structure is looked up in a dictionary and the character group is replaced with the molecule subgraph corresponding to that superatom. A vectorisation process will most likely turn a wavy bond into a connected sequence of short line segments arranged in a saw-tooth, or a zig-zag, pattern. As illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,241.06,273.31,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_3">4</ref>, a straight line can pass through the centre points of these line segments. A pattern of this form can be identified using the following conditions.</p><p>1. L = {l 1 , . . . , l n }, where n ≥ 3, is a set of line segments, 2. ∀l ∈ L : length(l) ∈ dl , where dl is the dash length: a parameter of the system representing a range of acceptable values for the length of an individual dash in a dashed line. 3. All elements of L are connected. 4. The centre points of the elements of L are approximately collinear. <ref type="foot" coords="5,444.02,379.01,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref>5. Two elements of L, called the end elements, dash-neighbour<ref type="foot" coords="5,416.33,391.17,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_1">2</ref> precisely one other element of L. All other elements of L, called internal elements, dashneighbour precisely two other elements of L. 6. Two end points that are not connected must be the pair of end points that are furthest apart.</p><p>Consequence A wavy bond between the furthest two endpoints. The new wavy bond has unknown direction.</p><p>To understand this rule, note that condition 1 simply selects possible line segments, such as those from Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,289.10,510.19,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_3">4</ref>, for consideration. Condition 2 ensures that each segment is of an appropriate length. That the endpoints of the line segments are connected is guaranteed by condition 3. The approximate collinearity of their centre points in condition 4 ensures that this sequence of line segments, although having a zig-zag form at the micro-structure level, is straight at a macro-structure level. Finally, the last two conditions ensures that the segments form a single sequence as would be obtained from a wavy bond, and not, for example, from any </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Analysis of MolRec's Performance</head><p>We were given a set of 961 test images by CLEF12's organisers. This collection was split into two sets. The first set was of 865 images selected for automatic evaluation by comparison of generated MOL files with the ground truth MOL files using the OpenBabel toolkit <ref type="bibr" coords="6,272.97,359.39,11.47,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. However, there are chemical diagrams whose valid MOL files are beyond OpenBabel's ability to compare (typically because they contain some form of Markush structure) and a second set of 95 such diagrams was selected for manual, visual evaluation. This second set was intentionally included to provide a greater challenge to the participating diagram recognition systems.</p><p>We ran MolRec four times on these sets where we slightly adjusted its internal parameters and MolRec achieved the results illustrated in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,417.78,443.81,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref> and Table <ref type="table" coords="6,472.84,443.81,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. The two tables show the number of correct and incorrect recognitions for the four runs on the manual and automatic evaluation sets respectively. Notice that because most of the diagrams mis-recognised in some runs were also mis-recognised in other runs, there were a total of 52 different diagrams mis-recognised in the manual evaluation set and a total of 46 different diagrams mis-recognised in the automatic evaluation set. Some of these diagrams failed for multiple reasons, so we were able to identify the reasons illustrated in Table <ref type="table" coords="6,380.76,527.50,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_2">3</ref>. </p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="6,191.25,562.35,135.67,7.86">Run # Recognitions # Mis-</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Evaluation and Analysis of Results</head><p>We now briefly discuss some of the problems that have lead to MolRec misrecognising molecule diagrams in the test set.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Character Grouping</head><p>An error in the implementation of our character group formation algorithm lead to the digit "1" being repeated when it appears within a atom group, so, for example, MolRec recognised R 21 incorrectly as R 211 . A separate problem was the difficulty in correctly separating different atom groups which are closely spaced, as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,255.20,538.27,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_4">5</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Touching Characters</head><p>We currently do not handle touching characters and therefore they will likely cause mis-recognition. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="8,265.41,156.90,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_5">6</ref> shows several examples.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">OCR Errors</head><p>There were some cases of OCR errors. These included a "G" interpreted as an "O", and the "alkyl" atom (Figure <ref type="figure" coords="8,296.06,558.38,4.32,8.74">8</ref>(a)) being mis-recognised. Also, as illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="8,207.51,570.34,4.21,8.74">8</ref>(b), there was several cases where an "I" was interpreted as a vertical single bond.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Missed Solid Wedge, Dashed Wedge and Wavy Bonds</head><p>As shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="8,224.19,644.16,3.87,8.74" target="#fig_7">9</ref>, MolRec incorrectly recognised a number of solid wedge, dashed wedge and wavy bonds.   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.8">Errors in the Dataset</head><p>While analysing our results we came across a small number of cases where the ground truth was incorrect and our recognition was correct. As shown in </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions</head><p>Despite scoring high recognition rates throughout four runs, the presented experiments demonstrate that there is still plenty of room to improve MolRec. We believe many of the mis-recognition problems can be solved with some relatively simple enhancements of our system, e.g. the error in character grouping or the vectorisation of four-way junctions. Tackling the notoriously difficult touching character segmentation problem is one aspect where we plan to explore viable solutions. Another area we plan to investigate is the recognition of more general Markush structures. Additionally, robust charge sign spotting, accurate identification of solid wedge bonds and precise identification of dashed wedge bonds are also areas we need to address further. However, we are pleased with the performance of MolRec and hope to participate in similar events in the future so that we can contribute to progress in the state of the art of chemical structure diagrams.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="4,213.02,232.16,189.32,7.89;4,215.48,115.84,69.17,86.61"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Closed and open bridge bonds (circled)</figDesc><graphic coords="4,215.48,115.84,69.17,86.61" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,222.50,386.98,170.35,7.89"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. Bond types recognised by MolRec.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="5,244.42,166.73,126.51,7.89"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3. Implicit Nodes (circled)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="6,243.77,201.19,127.82,7.89;6,238.51,115.84,138.34,60.62"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4. Dashes in a Wavy Bond</figDesc><graphic coords="6,238.51,115.84,138.34,60.62" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="7,258.74,631.99,97.88,7.89"><head>Fig. 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Fig. 5. Atoms too Close</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5" coords="8,226.04,246.74,163.27,7.89"><head>Fig. 6 .</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Fig. 6. Example of Touching Characters</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6" coords="8,188.31,461.52,235.67,7.89;8,238.32,378.64,51.88,53.66"><head>Fig. 7 .</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Fig. 7. Example of Four-way Junctions Missed by MolRec</figDesc><graphic coords="8,238.32,378.64,51.88,53.66" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7" coords="9,267.70,201.91,79.96,7.89;9,322.09,120.82,51.87,51.87"><head>Fig. 9 .</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Fig. 8. OCR Errors</figDesc><graphic coords="9,322.09,120.82,51.87,51.87" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8" coords="9,247.86,534.17,119.64,7.89"><head>Fig. 10 .</head><label>10</label><figDesc>Fig. 10. Missed Charge Signs</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9" coords="10,227.30,199.77,160.75,7.89"><head>Fig. 11 .</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Fig. 11. Other Mis-recognition Reasons</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="6,179.41,562.35,256.53,66.69"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Four Runs on the Manual Evaluation Set (95 images)</figDesc><table coords="6,326.91,562.35,97.20,7.86"><row><cell>Recognitions Accuracy</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="7,167.50,176.58,280.35,178.37"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Four Runs on the Automatic Evaluation Set (865 images)</figDesc><table coords="7,167.50,209.20,280.35,145.75"><row><cell>Reason</cell><cell cols="2">Manual Set Automatic Set</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">#Images #Images</cell></row><row><cell>Character Grouping</cell><cell>26</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>Touching Characters</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Vectorisation of Four-way Junction</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>7</cell></row><row><cell>Missed Solid Wedge</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>6</cell></row><row><cell>Missed Dashed Wedge</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>6</cell></row><row><cell>OCR Errors</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>11</cell></row><row><cell>Missed wavy bond</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Missed charge sign</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>Incorrect Stereocentre</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Atom too close to line endpoint</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Line end too close to closed node</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="7,202.33,357.97,210.69,7.89"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Reasons for Mis-Recognition of Molecules.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="10,134.77,265.33,345.83,178.70"><head>Table 4 ,</head><label>4</label><figDesc>there were 11 images in total. Such ground truth dataset errors are very difficult to avoid in such a complex task.</figDesc><table coords="10,215.29,322.59,184.78,121.44"><row><cell>US20040254236A1 p0037 x0488 y1434 c00146</cell></row><row><cell>US20060122222A1 p0015 x0638 y2146 c00043</cell></row><row><cell>US20060122222A1 p0015 x0638 y2624 c00044</cell></row><row><cell>US20060122222A1 p0025 x0363 y1056 c00070</cell></row><row><cell>US20060122222A1 p0027 x0379 y1064 c00078</cell></row><row><cell>US20060122222A1 p0040 x1313 y0721 c00105</cell></row><row><cell>US20060154945A1 p0017 x0404 y2072 c00059</cell></row><row><cell>US20070155803A1 p0020 x1323 y2114 c00037</cell></row><row><cell>US20070155803A1 p0029 x1358 y1732 c00073</cell></row><row><cell>US20070179154A1 p0046 x1376 y0890 c00066</cell></row><row><cell>US20070270434A1 p0015 x1376 y2386 c00029</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="10,222.02,449.04,171.31,7.89"><head>Table 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Images with Incorrect MOL files</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="5,144.73,602.00,335.87,7.86;5,144.73,612.96,335.87,7.86;5,144.73,623.92,290.82,7.86"><p>Approximate collinearity is a precisely defined relationship under which a set of points can be considered to be collinear within the constraints of the limitations of the construction, printing and scanning technologies used for the image.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="5,144.73,634.88,335.87,7.86;5,144.73,645.84,335.86,7.86;5,144.73,656.80,47.67,7.86"><p>Dash neighbouring is a precisely defined relationship which specify the conditions under which two line segments can be considered to be consecutive dashes in a dashed line.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="11,138.35,186.42,342.24,7.86;11,146.91,197.38,333.68,8.11;11,146.91,208.99,21.39,7.47" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="11,342.17,186.42,138.42,7.86;11,146.91,197.38,33.68,7.86">SMILES -a simplified chemical language</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.daylight.com/dayhtml/doc/theory/theory.smiles.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<publisher>Daylight Chemical Information Systems, Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="11,138.35,219.30,342.24,7.86;11,146.91,230.26,333.68,7.86;11,146.91,241.22,82.42,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="11,319.54,219.30,161.05,7.86;11,146.91,230.26,267.47,7.86">Algorithms for the reduction of the number of points required to represent a digitized line or its caricature</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Douglas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Peucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="11,422.52,230.26,53.93,7.86">Cartographica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="112" to="122" />
			<date type="published" when="1973">1973</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="11,138.35,252.18,311.97,8.12" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://openbabel.org/" />
		<title level="m" coord="11,146.91,252.18,193.82,7.86">Open Babel: The open source chemistry toolbox</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="11,138.35,263.14,342.24,7.86;11,146.91,274.09,257.56,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="11,185.42,263.14,226.32,7.86">A threshold selection method from gray-level histograms</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Otsu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="11,419.92,263.14,60.67,7.86;11,146.91,274.09,158.12,7.86">IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man and Cybernetics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="62" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="1979-01">January 1979</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="11,138.35,285.05,342.24,7.86;11,146.91,296.01,333.67,7.86;11,146.91,306.97,333.68,7.86;11,146.91,317.93,56.46,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="11,377.50,285.05,103.09,7.86;11,146.91,296.01,121.61,7.86">Chemical structure recognition: A rule based approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Noureddin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alan</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Sadawi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Sexton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Volker Sorge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="11,180.19,306.97,269.16,7.86">19th Document Recognition and Retrieval Conference (DRR 2012)</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Viard-Gaudin</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Zanibbi</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>SPIE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012-01">January 2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="11,138.35,328.89,342.25,8.12;11,146.91,340.49,49.63,7.47" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="11,180.28,328.89,56.86,7.86">CTfile formats</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.symyx.com/downloads/public/ctfile/ctfile.jsp" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<publisher>Symyx</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="11,138.35,350.81,342.24,8.11;11,146.91,362.41,195.56,7.47" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="11,303.36,350.81,84.83,7.86">Image2structure task</title>
		<ptr target="http://trec.nist.gov/pubs/trec20/t20.proceedings.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="11,146.92,350.81,144.27,7.86">Text REtrieval Conference (TREC)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="11,138.35,372.72,342.24,7.86;11,146.91,383.68,140.46,7.86" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="11,211.67,372.72,224.50,7.86">SMILES, a chemical language and information system</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Weininger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="11,448.27,372.72,32.32,7.86;11,146.91,383.68,76.86,7.86">J Chem Inform Comput Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
