<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,133.95,101.17,344.96,15.48">ETH Zurich at TREC Precision Medicine 2017</title>
				<funder ref="#_NmncHcX">
					<orgName type="full">Swiss National Science Foundation</orgName>
					<orgName type="abbreviated">SNSF</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,187.06,158.64,99.72,8.96"><forename type="first">Negar</forename><forename type="middle">Foroutan</forename><surname>Eghlidi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science ETH</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Zurich</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,293.46,158.64,62.60,8.96"><forename type="first">Jannick</forename><surname>Griner</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science ETH</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Zurich</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,362.97,158.64,57.23,8.96"><forename type="first">Nicolas</forename><surname>Mesot</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science ETH</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Zurich</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,216.94,169.55,84.30,8.96"><forename type="first">Leandro</forename><surname>Von Werra</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science ETH</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Zurich</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,322.28,169.55,72.78,8.96"><forename type="first">Carsten</forename><surname>Eickhoff</surname></persName>
							<email>c.eickhoff@acm.org</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science ETH</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Zurich</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,133.95,101.17,344.96,15.48">ETH Zurich at TREC Precision Medicine 2017</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">41D3A76F1A424D9650A0F26ADC39EBE6</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:09+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes ETH Zurich's submission to the TREC 2017 Precision Medicine (PM) track. We begin by performing literal query term matching, taking into account the likelihood of document relevance in terms of cancer types, genetic variants, and demographics. In a second, subsequent stage, we re-rank the most relevant results based on a range of deep neural gene embeddings that project literal genetic expressions into a semantics-preserving vector space using feed-forward networks trained on PubMed and NCBI information but also relying on generative adversarial methods to determine the likelihood of co-occurrence of various mutations within the same patient/article. Empirical results show that even without existing expert labels, the proposed method can introduce marginal improvements over competitive tf-idf baselines.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Precision medicine is a modern field of study that aims to use genomic information in finding more effective treatments for patients. Due to the popularity of the new paradigm, the volume of annually published scholarly precision medicine articles has been growing rapidly in recent years. While this considerable amount of scientific research holds a rich and ever increasing well of knowledge, its sheer scale makes it intractable for manual inspection and mandates the development of dedicated automatic retrieval facilities.</p><p>In this paper, we present a modular patient-centric information retrieval system for use in precision oncology settings. Based on patient demographics as well as information regarding the type of tumor and its genetic composition, we rank scholarly articles as well as clinical trials with respect to their relevance for a range of reference patients.</p><p>Our ranking scheme combines evidence from four sources of information: (1) literal presence of keywords in the description of patients, cancer types and genetic variations. (2) dense semanticspreserving vector representations of key biomedical terms (3) functional neural embeddings of gene expressions and their patient context (4) generative adversarial models of gene mutation cooccurrence. After an initial retrieval run evidence for the usefulness of expansion candidates is aggregated across our various sources, resulting in a significantly more robust ranking of resources.</p><p>Lacking historic training data, in this first edition of the TREC Precision Medicine track, we manually annotated a sample of 1800 (1200 abstracts and 600 clinical trials) query-document pairs in order to train and optimize any supervised representation learning and fusion schemes. While these labels were created without direct involvement of domain experts, we see significant performance improvements over training-free exact matching methods.</p><p>Our ranking scheme is centrally based on exact keyword matching (Section 2.1) and subsequently further refined by three neural-network components that estimate a range of compatibility scores between patient and document (Sections 2.2 -2.4). Finally, we apply a number of score fusion methods in order to re-rank the original exact matching results (Section 2.5).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Term-based Exact Matching</head><p>We use patient descriptions (topics) to generate queries that we compare to documents to obtain a similarity score. The theoretical framework adopted for representing both the abstracts and trials is the vector space model as described by Salton et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,310.13,203.02,11.48,8.64" target="#b6">[7]</ref> where term weights corresponf to tf-idf scores. For the practical implementation, we use the open-source framework Lucene <ref type="foot" coords="2,417.95,212.26,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_1">1</ref> . In order to account for varying field importance in structured topics, we apply static weighting factors as detailed in Table1. To further improve recall, we perform term-wise query expansion off all genome identifiers by appending their various synonyms as specified by the HUGO Gene Nomenclature Committee (HGNC) <ref type="foot" coords="2,142.53,255.89,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_2">2</ref> .</p><p>For scientific abstracts, we divide age-specific query terms into three categories (pediatric, adult and geriatric medicine). For each of these categories, we add the age indication terms proposed by Kaster et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,130.39,295.77,10.57,8.64" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. Clinical trial runs are enhanced by performing exact age-range matching on the age range provided by the clinical trial descriptions. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Neural Context Embedding</head><p>In our second approach, we go beyond literal term matching by computing semantic vector representations of gene identifiers in patient descriptions and abstracts. We construct a vocabulary of gene symbols, biomedical concepts and frequent words observed in documents. We then use a neural probabilistic language model according to <ref type="bibr" coords="2,280.42,493.45,10.67,8.64" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, to find continuous embeddings of these words. The similarity of a patient and a scientific abstract or clinical trial document can now be expressed as a distance function applied to their respective vector representations.</p><p>To identify relevant gene identifiers in the document collection, we again consult the HGNC list of gene symbols and their synonyms and apply simple heuristics based on symbol-synonym relations to eliminate ambiguous gene symbols such as CO2 or SARS that also have non-genomic interpretations.</p><p>The biomedical concepts for our vocabulary are given by the Unified Medical Language System (UMLS) <ref type="foot" coords="2,141.30,573.62,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_3">3</ref> . We train our embeddings on all abstracts found in PubMed<ref type="foot" coords="2,377.17,573.62,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_4">4</ref> containing any of the identified relevant gene symbols.</p><p>In a first step we replace all UMLS expressions in the abstracts by their UMLS concept identifiers and apply the CBOW and skip-gram Word2Vec models to find continuous vector representations of all words in the vocabulary. To optimize model parameters, we evaluate the resulting embeddings based on the cosine distances between gene symbol synonym pairs found in the HGNC gene list. We find the best performance for a skip-gram model, using a vocabulary of 150'000 words and a small window size of 1 word before and after the target word and an embedding dimensionality of 250. </p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,174.91,352.99,262.18,30.47">s c (T, D) = gt∈T 3 j=1 w j * (1 + log(tf (d ij ))) * (1 -cos(g t , d ij ))</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Neural Gene Embedding</head><p>In an alternative neural embedding scheme, we aim to model bio-medical properties of genes and mutations trying to establish a Euclidean space in which functionally similar genes are projected to proximal locations. This functional similarity is defined based on the common cancer types that both genes are associated with, making genes that are related to the same cancer types more similar.</p><p>We use the human genome portion of the National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI) dataset <ref type="bibr" coords="3,137.89,480.62,11.55,8.64" target="#b0">[1]</ref> to establish. For each gene, this collection includes chromosomal localization, gene products and their attributes (e.g., protein interactions), associated markers, phenotypes, and interactions. Additionally, for each recorded gene in this dataset, there is a "summary text" field, which contains a summary of all the information about that gene. In this summary, all the cancer types a gene is associated with (if any) are listed. We select all genes that contain at least one human cancer type in their summary text. This procedure results in a total of 1347 distinct genes and 109 cancer types.</p><p>We employ a single-layer feed-forward neural network to embed the genes into a Euclidean space. The input of this network is a one-hot vector that uniquely represents a gene. The output of the network is a vector in which each component corresponds to a specific cancer type. If an input gene is associated with a cancer type, the corresponding element in the output vector indicating that cancer type is set to one. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,209.05,595.19,4.98,8.64" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows the architecture of our neural network.</p><p>The input layer size is equal to the number of genes (1347) while the output layer corresponds to the number of cancer types (109). The hidden layer size is chosen experimentally (50). The maximum cross-validation accuracy of predicting cancer types is 60%. After training the network with these characteristics, we use the gene representation to rank the scholarly articles. For each topic-document pair, we calculate the overall functional relevancy score s f as the aggregated cosine similarity between all genes g t mentioned in the topic and all genes g d mentioned in the document. We consider three aggregation functions a = {mean, max , mean max }</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,218.86,705.19,174.00,9.65">s f (T, D) = a(cos(g t , g d ))∀g t ∈ T, g d ∈ D 2.</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Adversarial Training for Gene Pair Ranking</head><p>In order to measure the compatibility of a patient's gene mutations with mutation mentions in a document, we use a generative adversarial net (GAN). A GAN consists of two networks trained with respect to different objectives: the generator network aims at copying the original data distribution, whereas the discriminator network is fed real and generated data alternately and is tasked to identify the real data point. In optimal settings, the generator's ability to output pseudo-realistic data increases in parallel to the discriminator's power to distinguish real from generated data. For the TREC Precision Medicine Challenge, we use the GAN's discriminator part to determine, if a patient's gene mutations are compatible with a gene mentioned in a document.</p><p>We use the co-occurrence of gene mutations in PubMed abstracts, provided by the TREC precision medicine track, as training data <ref type="bibr" coords="4,238.00,200.97,10.72,8.64" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. The underlying assumption using this approach is, that genes often occurring together also share similarities. We filter 22M abstracts for 614 genes known to be in connection with the formation of cancer according to COSMIC <ref type="bibr" coords="4,369.20,222.79,10.72,8.64" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. For each abstract, we extract pairs of mutated genes from the list of mentioned mutations (i.e., a document with 4 mutations yields 6 pairs). In total, we retrieve 21k unique gene pairs for further use as GAN training data.</p><p>While GANs demonstrate impressive results when generating images, it is widely known that they suffer from poorly defined gradients at the generator/discriminator interface when tasked with discrete variables, such as two-hot vectors representing gene pairs <ref type="bibr" coords="4,336.06,282.82,10.47,8.64" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. We use an approach proposed by Choi et al., named medGAN <ref type="bibr" coords="4,201.56,293.73,10.45,8.64" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. This architecture utilizes the decoder part of a pre-trained autoencoder to translate the real valued generator output vector to a discrete vector. In order to prevent mode-collapse, the generator produces a batch of gene pairs, which are then separately fed to the discriminator along with the average vector of the batch. However, this leaves the discriminator with the possibility to distinguish solely on the basis of the average batch vector, which is neither available nor relevant when looking at a single gene pair. To tackle this issue, we introduce a second training mode which runs in parallel to the batch training. We call it single mode, providing the discriminator with a zero vector instead of the mean batch vector. Using this architecture, we train the GAN with the gene pairs in the form of two-hot vectors as training data.</p><p>Finally, we use the trained GAN to construct a metric to rank documents according to their gene compatibility. For each patient gene g t and gene mention in a given document g d , we calculate the discriminator value for Disc(g t , g d ). For likely real pairs the discriminator outputs 1 and 0 for likely unrelated data, respectively. We combine the values of Disc(.) across all gene mentions in a document by applying an aggregation function a = {min, max , mean}.</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="4,216.13,474.21,179.46,9.65">s g (T, D) = a(Disc(g t , g d ))∀g t ∈ T, g d ∈ D</formula><p>2.5 Score Fusion</p><p>The previously described constituent scores (tfidf(.), s c (.), s f (.) and s g (.)) are fused in 5 different ways based on our manually annotated topic-document pairs. To ensure computational feasibility, the scores of all neural approaches (s c (.), s f (.) and s g (.)) are based on the 1000 top-ranked documents for each topic retrieved by term-based exact matching. In a first step, we combine all constituent scores into a feature vector v, which has 8 components explained in detail in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,439.13,569.11,3.74,8.64">2</ref>.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="4,255.75,594.11,3.88,8.64">2</ref>: Feature vector v description.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Entry Method Value</head><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="4,180.86,631.05,250.29,64.20">v 1 Term-based Exact Matching tf idf (T, D) v 2 Neural Context Embedding s c (T, D) v 3 Functional Gene Embedding mean(s f (T, D)) v 4 Functional Gene Embedding max (s f (T, D)) v 5 Functional Gene Embedding meanmax (s f (T, D)) v 6</formula><p>GAN Gene Pair Ranking mean(s g (T, D)) v 7</p><p>GAN Gene Pair Ranking min(s g (T, D)) v 8</p><p>GAN Gene Pair Ranking max (s g (T, D))</p><p>We present five ways to fuse the score vector into a single value further used to rank the list of documents. These methods of fusing scores make up the runs submitted for the TREC Precision Medicine Track for both abstracts and trials.</p><p>1. Weighted Sum (nDCG) This method is based on the weighted sum of each score vector. The list of documents is ranked according to the weighted sum and evaluated using the nDCG metric. We optimize mixture weights for ideal nDCG on our manually annotated sample.</p><p>2. Pure Term-based Exact Matching This is technically not a run fusion, since it only takes into account the scores from Term-based Exact Matching. We chose this approach to comply with the TREC PM 2017 guidelines, which state that exact matches are required in a document to constitute relevance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Neural Fusion</head><p>The neural approach trains a feed-forward neural network with one fully connected hidden layer (16 neurons) to learn ranking the documents based on the combined score vector.</p><p>The network is trained to map the input vector onto 1 if the underlying document is relevant and 0 otherwise. Again, our annotated documents serve as ground truth data. We use dropout to avoid over fitting, which is likely due to the limited amount of training data available.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Weighted Sum (qrel)</head><p>In contrast to the nDCG method, this approach aims at mapping the score vector onto annotated document labels via linear regression.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Neural Embeddings and GAN Values Exclusively</head><p>The last method is identical to the 4th fusion method with the exception of not considering any tfidf scores. As previously mentioned, the documents are already pre-selected by the exact matching method and this fusion therefore tests if such pre-selection of exact terms suffices to rank documents with neural embedding scores and GAN valuations alone.</p><p>We present a summary of the fusion process and the resulting unofficial nDCG scores in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,498.12,380.28,3.81,8.64" target="#tab_1">3</ref>. We can observe that the weighted sum optimized for nDCG score performs marginally better than the pure exact matching score. This is likely due to the bias towards the exact matching score in the annotated documents due to the annotation of only the best exact matching documents. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head><p>We submitted ten official TREC Precision Medicine 2017 runs for evaluation, five for scientific abstract retrieval and five for clinical trial retrieval. Table <ref type="table" coords="5,336.25,642.58,4.95,8.64" target="#tab_2">4</ref> lists the official performance of each run in terms of inferred nDCG, precision at 10 retrieved documents and R-precision. At this time, no official relevance judgments have been released.</p><p>For both tasks, literal matching represents a strong baseline that can only be marginally improved by including functional and contextual information. The exclusion of explicit matching information results in significant performance drops. We believe that this is due to the particular judging criteria of this track that require exact matches in terms of gene expressions and cancer types in order to </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we provide an overview of ETH Zurich's contribution to the TREC 2017 Precision Medicine track. Using a wide array of neural network approaches, we aim to capture contextual, functional and pairwise genetic information expressed in topics and documents. While immediate performance gains were rather limited, we see considerable potential for future improvement when using this year's official relevance judgments to train supervised models.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,151.28,239.85,309.44,8.64;3,218.32,72.00,175.35,156.45"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Feed-forward network architecture for functional gene embeddings.</figDesc><graphic coords="3,218.32,72.00,175.35,156.45" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,202.81,329.97,206.39,78.62"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Empirically optimal field weights.</figDesc><table coords="2,202.81,350.92,206.39,57.66"><row><cell>Term</cell><cell cols="2">Scientific Abstracts Clinical Trials</cell></row><row><cell>Gender</cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Age</cell><cell>0.05</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Condition 1</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Genes</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>0.2</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,222.86,433.11,166.28,147.02"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>nDCG scores after score fusion.</figDesc><table coords="5,222.86,452.02,166.28,128.12"><row><cell>Fusion Method</cell><cell cols="2">Type nDCG</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Weighted Sum (nDCG) abs.</cell><cell>0.6642</cell></row><row><cell>Exact Matching</cell><cell>abs.</cell><cell>0.6605</cell></row><row><cell>Neural Fusion</cell><cell>abs.</cell><cell>0.5382</cell></row><row><cell>Weighted Sum (qrel)</cell><cell>abs.</cell><cell>0.4770</cell></row><row><cell>Exclusive Gene</cell><cell>abs.</cell><cell>0.2927</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Weighted Sum (nDCG) trial</cell><cell>0.9654</cell></row><row><cell>Exact Matching</cell><cell>trial</cell><cell>0.9647</cell></row><row><cell>Neural Fusion</cell><cell>trial</cell><cell>0.8316</cell></row><row><cell>Weighted Sum (qrel)</cell><cell>trial</cell><cell>0.9187</cell></row><row><cell>Exclusive Gene</cell><cell>trial</cell><cell>0.4024</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="6,108.00,72.27,397.24,207.45"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Experimental results. We can further observe that heavily parametrized methods such as neural fusion, due to lack of training data do not gain a competitive advantage over straight-forward linear fusion methods.</figDesc><table coords="6,108.00,93.23,363.73,164.67"><row><cell>Fusion Method</cell><cell cols="4">Run Identifier Type infnDCG P@10 R-Prec</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Weighted Sum (nDCG) ws</cell><cell>abs.</cell><cell>0.2663</cell><cell>0.3414 0.1941</cell></row><row><cell>Term-based</cell><cell>luc</cell><cell>abs.</cell><cell>0.2632</cell><cell>0.3379 0.1895</cell></row><row><cell>Neural Fusion</cell><cell>nn</cell><cell>abs.</cell><cell>0.2437</cell><cell>0.3034 0.1660</cell></row><row><cell>Weighted Sum (qrels)</cell><cell>wsq</cell><cell>abs.</cell><cell>0.2450</cell><cell>0.3034 0.1627</cell></row><row><cell>Neural + GAN</cell><cell>gws</cell><cell>abs.</cell><cell>0.1453</cell><cell>0.1517 0.1066</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Weighted Sum (nDCG) ws</cell><cell>trial</cell><cell>?</cell><cell>0.0571 0.0439</cell></row><row><cell>Term-based</cell><cell>luc</cell><cell>trial</cell><cell>?</cell><cell>0.0607 0.0453</cell></row><row><cell>Neural Fusion</cell><cell>nn</cell><cell>trial</cell><cell>?</cell><cell>0.0000 0.0019</cell></row><row><cell>Weighted Sum (qrels)</cell><cell>wsb</cell><cell>trial</cell><cell>?</cell><cell>0.0286 0.0257</cell></row><row><cell>Neural + GAN</cell><cell>gwsq</cell><cell>trial</cell><cell>?</cell><cell>0.0036 0.0035</cell></row><row><cell>constitute relevance.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,108.00,734.38,203.24,7.77"><p>26th Text Retrieval Conference (TREC) Notebook 2017.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,124.14,681.61,91.98,7.77"><p>https://lucene.apache.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_2" coords="2,124.14,692.46,102.36,7.77"><p>https://www.genenames.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_3" coords="2,124.14,703.31,143.99,7.77"><p>https://www.nlm.nih.gov/research/umls/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_4" coords="2,124.14,714.16,140.76,7.77"><p>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="5">Acknowledgements</head><p>This research is funded by the <rs type="funder">Swiss National Science Foundation (SNSF) Ambizione Program</rs> under grant agreement no. <rs type="grantNumber">174025</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_NmncHcX">
					<idno type="grant-number">174025</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,124.60,479.41,381.05,8.64;6,124.60,490.32,381.14,8.64" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,251.38,479.41,254.28,8.64;6,124.60,490.32,61.32,8.64">National library of medicine (us), national center for biotechnology information</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,124.60,479.41,20.77,8.64">Gene</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004. 2017 Oct 15</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>internet]. bethesda (md</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,124.60,510.96,381.14,8.64;6,124.60,521.87,381.14,8.64;6,124.60,532.60,159.58,8.82" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,124.60,521.87,376.80,8.64">Generating multi-label discrete electronic health records using generative adversarial networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Edward</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Siddharth</forename><surname>Biswal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bradley</forename><surname>Malin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Duke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Walter</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Stewart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jimeng</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1703.06490</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">arXiv preprint</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,124.60,553.42,380.64,8.64;6,124.60,564.33,379.40,8.64;6,124.60,575.24,379.40,8.64;6,124.60,585.97,379.40,8.82;6,124.29,596.88,149.73,8.82" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,235.89,586.15,204.80,8.64">Cosmic: somatic cancer genetics at high-resolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Simon</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Forbes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Beare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Harry</forename><surname>Boutselakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sally</forename><surname>Bamford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nidhi</forename><surname>Bindal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Tate</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Charlotte</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Cole</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sari</forename><surname>Ward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Elisabeth</forename><surname>Dawson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Ponting</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Raymund</forename><surname>Stefancsik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bhavana</forename><surname>Harsha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Yin</forename><surname>Chai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mingming</forename><surname>Kok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Harry</forename><surname>Jia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Zbyslaw</forename><surname>Jubb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sam</forename><surname>Sondka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Tisham</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Peter</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>De</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Campbell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,448.30,585.97,55.69,8.59;6,124.29,596.88,34.70,8.59">Nucleic Acids Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="777" to="D783" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,124.60,617.69,379.40,8.64;6,124.60,628.42,379.40,8.82;6,124.60,639.33,227.57,8.82" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,303.75,628.60,105.96,8.64">Generative adversarial nets</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Goodfellow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jean</forename><surname>Pouget-Abadie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mehdi</forename><surname>Mirza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Warde-Farley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sherjil</forename><surname>Ozair</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Courville</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Yoshua</forename><surname>Bengio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,427.73,628.42,76.27,8.59;6,124.60,639.33,123.56,8.59">Advances in neural information processing systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2672" to="2680" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,124.60,660.15,379.40,8.64;6,124.60,670.88,151.88,8.82" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,387.64,660.15,116.35,8.64;6,124.60,671.06,44.37,8.64">Age-specific search strategies for medline</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kastner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Nancy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Cindy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kathleen Ann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Brian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,176.88,670.88,73.80,8.59">J Med Internet Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,124.60,691.70,381.06,8.64;6,124.60,702.43,379.40,8.82;6,124.60,713.34,178.03,8.82" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,433.20,691.70,72.45,8.64;6,124.60,702.61,233.46,8.64">Distributed representations of words and phrases and their compositionality</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Tomas</forename><surname>Mikolov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ilya</forename><surname>Sutskever</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Greg</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Corrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,376.61,702.43,127.39,8.59;6,124.60,713.34,74.02,8.59">Advances in neural information processing systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3111" to="3119" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,124.60,75.30,381.15,8.82;7,123.99,86.21,161.55,8.82" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,276.92,75.48,181.56,8.64">A vector space model for automatic indexing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,466.51,75.30,39.23,8.59;7,123.99,86.21,17.42,8.59">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="613" to="620" />
			<date type="published" when="1975-11">November 1975</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,124.60,105.27,380.23,8.64;7,124.60,116.17,92.40,8.64" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,155.52,105.27,95.36,8.64">Precision medicine track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Trec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.trec-cds.org/2017.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-10-18">2017. 2017 Oct 18</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
