<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,101.17,85.16,409.66,12.62">Evaluating Axiomatic Retrieval Models in the Core Track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,222.56,123.28,42.07,8.74"><forename type="first">Yue</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<email>wangyue@udel.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Delaware</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>140 Evans Hall</addrLine>
									<postCode>19716</postCode>
									<settlement>Newark, Delaware</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,273.48,123.28,48.01,8.74"><forename type="first">Peilin</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Delaware</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>140 Evans Hall</addrLine>
									<postCode>19716</postCode>
									<settlement>Newark, Delaware</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,349.18,123.28,40.26,8.74"><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
							<email>hfang@udel.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Delaware</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>140 Evans Hall</addrLine>
									<postCode>19716</postCode>
									<settlement>Newark, Delaware</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,101.17,85.16,409.66,12.62">Evaluating Axiomatic Retrieval Models in the Core Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">08AA99AC160D5983C977EB1B69A6B2B0</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:09+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Axiomatic analysis of the existing retrieval models have shown great power on understanding the retrieval models, which further shows a great opportunities on improve the retrieval performances of existing models. In this work, we tested the axiomatic retrieval models with query expansion on the newly provided data collection. The results show that the proposed method could outperform the baseline methods.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The Core track organized in TREC 2017 is a new track with the purposes of providing a new test collection for the research community. The track is formulated as an ad-hoc retrieval task. With the same topic used in the Robust track, a new data collection, NY times corpus, is provided to the participants. We participated the Phrase 1 of the track using the axiomatic retrieval model with query expansion utilizing semantically related terms to the queries.</p><p>Axiomatic analysis of the existing retrieval methods have been proposed and studied recently <ref type="bibr" coords="1,516.44,387.27,10.52,8.74" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,85.04,399.23,7.01,8.74" target="#b1">2]</ref>. The fundamental idea of the axiomatic analysis is based on a set of reasonable constraints that the retrieval function should follow in order to achieve the satisfying results. Existing work have studied various constraints, starting from the basic ones, such as the basic term frequency constraints, term discrimination constraints, and document length normalization constraints, to the ones capture more sophisticate features, such as semantic term matching constraints and term proximity constraints. Under the same framework, Fang and Zhai <ref type="bibr" coords="1,285.64,459.00,10.52,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref> also studied the query expansion techniques using semantic term matching, in which the mutual information is utilized to compute the similarity between two terms.</p><p>Since the previous studies of axiomatic analysis of the retrieval methods have shown satisfying performances on different well-known data collections <ref type="bibr" coords="1,323.12,507.27,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, we proposed to apply the same method on the newly constructed data set to verify if it is robust.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Axiomatic retrieval model and query expansion</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Axiomatic retrieval model</head><p>Previous study <ref type="bibr" coords="1,153.66,601.68,10.52,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref> revealed that the functions in group F2, i.e., F2-EXP and F2-LOG, would usually outperforms than the ones with F1 and F3. Therefore, we selected the F2-EXP and F2-LOG as the basic retrieval functions for this track. The F2-EXP is defined as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="1,166.50,656.73,360.46,30.50">S(Q, D) = t∈Q∩D C(t, Q) × C(t, Q) C(t, Q) + s + s • |D| avdl × N + 1 df (t) k<label>(1)</label></formula><p>while the F2-LOG is defined as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,171.71,104.52,355.25,27.30">S(Q, D) = t∈Q∩D C(t, Q) × C(t, Q) C(t, Q) + s + s • |D| avdl × ln N + 1 df (t)<label>(2)</label></formula><p>where, Q and D represent the query and document respectively. C(t, Q) is the term frequency of term t in query Q, |D| is the document length, avdl is the average document length in the collection, N is the total number of documents, and df (t) is the document frequency of term t.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Query expansion of semantic term matching</head><p>Query expansion is a commonly used technique to include more relevant terms into the original query, thus the vocabulary gap of the query and the document could be overcame. The semantic term matching method proposed in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,174.71,236.11,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, which is based on three semantic term matching constraints, would evaluated the relevance score of a single term document t with the query Q using the following equation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,256.26,268.49,270.70,23.80">S(Q, t) = q∈Q s(q, t) |Q|<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where s(q, t) = w(q), t = q w(q) × β × s(q,t) s(q,q) , t = q (4)</p><p>where t is a term in the document, q is a term in query. s(q, t) is the semantic similarity between q and t. It is computed using the mutual information:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,185.15,397.46,341.81,41.57">s(q, t) = I(X q , X t |W ) (5) = Xq,Xt∈{0,1} p(X q , X t |W ) • log p(X q , X t |W ) p(X q |W )p(X t |W )</formula><p>where X q and X t are two binary random variables that denote the presence/absence of query term q and term t in document. W is the working set to compute the mutual information.</p><p>We selected the working set from two resources, e.g., the collection itself and a web-based search results snippets collection. We used the snippets from three commercial search engines, e.g. Google, Yahoo, and Bing!, to create a snippets collection for each query. The top 100 results from each search engine is crawled for each query. We denote the collection itself as internal, and the web-based snippet collection as external.</p><p>Each working set is constructed using R relevant documents and N × R randomly selected documents. N is set to 19 based on the previous experiments. We then computed the term similarity using equation 5 with each working set. Top K terms for each query are selected as expansion terms. The similarity score between the expansion term and the whole query is computed using equation 3. M most similar terms are chosen with weight S(Q, t). Both the original query and the expanded query terms are used to evaluated the document. The documents are ranked based on equation 1 and 2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiment</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Data set pre-processing</head><p>The NYT corpus is downloaded and extracted. We used Indri to build the index. The porter stemmer is applied, while stop words is not removed from the collection when we built the index. We did not extract the content from the xml. It is directly built by using indri build index, with the file format set to xml. We did the same pre-processing to the snippets collection.</p><p>We only participated phase 1 of this year's track. We submitted three runs and the details of each run is summarized in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,191.45,122.22,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. The internal query expansion resource refers to using the collection itself as the the working set, while the external query expansion resources refers to the web-based search results snippets collection. The parameters, M , R, K, and β, are tuned using the Robust04 collection. The performance of each run is reported in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,317.63,279.12,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. To compare the performance with other runs, we also included the average of the median performance of all submitted runs, denoted as TREC-Median. By comparing the performance of UDelInfoLOGint with UDelInfoEXPint, we could conclude the F2log method performs better than the F2exp method, which is consistent with the observations from previous study. In addition, all of our three runs could outperform the TREC-Median, which indicates the axiomatic retrieval model is robust on the new data collection.</p><p>The performance of using external resources is significantly worse than using the internal resources, since the UDelInfoLOGint outperforms UDelInfoLOGext. This is inconsistent with previous experiments. Therefore, we further investigate the results by re-train the methods using this year's data collection. The re-trained best performance (in terms of AP) of UDelInfoLOGint is 0.3026, and it is 0.2986 for UDelInfoLOGext. Thus, although the improvement using internal resource is still better than using external resources, the difference is not significant. By taking a close analysis, the huge improvement of using external resources comes from the the parameter β. In the training set, β is about 1.4-1.6 when it reaches the best performance, however in the new collection, it reaches the best performance around 0.4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>We applied the axiomatic retrieval models with semantic term matching on the newly proposed data collection in this year's Core track. The results show that the axiomatic methods are robust on the new collection. In addition, the submitted runs show that selecting the expansion terms from the original document set is better than from the external set, however, after training the parameters on the newly proposed data collection, we found out that the improvement of using internal resources is not significant comparing using the external resources.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,121.25,178.48,369.51,71.95"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Details of submitted runs.</figDesc><table coords="3,121.25,197.51,369.51,52.92"><row><cell></cell><cell>Basic</cell><cell>Expansion</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>retrieval function</cell><cell>resources</cell><cell>M</cell><cell>R</cell><cell>K</cell><cell>β</cell></row><row><cell>UDelInfoLOGint</cell><cell>F2Log</cell><cell>Internal</cell><cell>17</cell><cell>19</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>0.4</cell></row><row><cell>UDelInfoLOGext</cell><cell>F2Log</cell><cell>External</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>23</cell><cell>22</cell><cell>1.5</cell></row><row><cell>UDelInfoEXPint</cell><cell>F2Exp</cell><cell>Internal</cell><cell>17</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>22</cell><cell>0.6</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,178.46,333.44,255.08,72.35"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Performance of submitted runs.</figDesc><table coords="3,178.46,352.47,255.08,53.32"><row><cell></cell><cell>AP</cell><cell>NDCG</cell><cell>P10</cell></row><row><cell>UDelInfoLOGint</cell><cell>0.2984</cell><cell>0.5391</cell><cell>0.5500</cell></row><row><cell>UDelInfoLOGext</cell><cell>0.2516</cell><cell>0.4923</cell><cell>0.5300</cell></row><row><cell>UDelInfoEXPint</cell><cell>0.2844</cell><cell>0.5249</cell><cell>0.5240</cell></row><row><cell>TREC-Median</cell><cell>0.2280</cell><cell>0.4787</cell><cell>0.5480</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,88.62,111.79,438.34,7.86;4,97.19,122.75,429.77,7.86;4,97.19,133.71,212.41,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,220.65,111.79,203.90,7.86">A formal study of information retrieval heuristics</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,450.47,111.79,76.48,7.86;4,97.19,122.75,429.77,7.86;4,97.19,133.71,39.61,7.86">Proceedings of the 27th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval. SIGIR &apos;04</title>
		<meeting>the 27th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval. SIGIR &apos;04<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="56" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,88.62,144.67,438.34,7.86;4,97.19,155.63,429.77,7.86;4,97.19,166.59,221.63,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,176.04,144.67,255.62,7.86">An exploration of axiomatic approaches to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,452.90,144.67,74.06,7.86;4,97.19,155.63,429.77,7.86;4,97.19,166.59,39.61,7.86">Proceedings of the 28th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval. SIGIR &apos;05</title>
		<meeting>the 28th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval. SIGIR &apos;05<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="480" to="487" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,88.62,177.55,438.34,7.86;4,97.19,188.50,429.77,7.86;4,97.19,199.46,263.50,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,172.26,177.55,287.54,7.86">Semantic term matching in axiomatic approaches to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,478.88,177.55,48.08,7.86;4,97.19,188.50,429.77,7.86;4,97.19,199.46,81.49,7.86">Proceedings of the 29th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval. SIGIR &apos;06</title>
		<meeting>the 29th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval. SIGIR &apos;06<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA, ACM</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="115" to="122" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,88.62,210.42,432.53,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,178.32,210.42,263.24,7.86">Evaluating the effectiveness of axiomatic approaches in web track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,463.57,210.42,23.14,7.86">TREC</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
