<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">(FDP)</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_mmCaDFz">
					<orgName type="full">COMSATS Institute of Information Technology, Lahore, Pakistan</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,176.78,173.15,66.69,8.64"><forename type="first">Rao</forename><surname>Muhammad</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,245.96,173.15,51.66,8.64"><forename type="first">Adeel</forename><surname>Nawab</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,305.19,173.15,64.63,8.64"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Stevenson</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,389.18,173.15,49.39,8.64"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
							<email>p.d.clough@sheffield.ac.uk</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Sheffield</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Sheffield</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">B931CF693969C644A0564967DA815AA8</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:25+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>extrinsic plagiarism dteection</term>
					<term>greedy string tiling</term>
					<term>GST</term>
					<term>n-grams</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the University of Sheffield entry for the 2nd international plagiarism detection competition (PAN 2010). Our system attempts to identify extrinsic plagiarism. A three-stage approach is used: pre-processing, candidate document selection (using word n-grams) and detailed analysis (using the Running Karp-Rabin Greedy String Tiling string matching algorithm). This approach achieved an overall performance of 0.20 in the official evaluation with a precision of 0.40, recall of 0.16 and granularity of 1.21.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This paper describes the University of Sheffield entry for the 2nd international plagiarism detection competition (PAN 2010). The system we submitted only attempted to identify extrinsic plagiarism: in this scenario the assumption is that the source (i.e. original) document(s) for a plagiarized document is hidden within a large collection of documents that can be accessed, i.e. within a closed-set of documents. The task is to identify the portions of the documents that have been plagiarized by aligning them with the corresponding text within the relevant source documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">Related Work</head><p>A simple approach to extrinsic plagiarism detection is to compare each suspicious document with a collection of source documents to find the potential source(s) of a plagiarized text. However, the problem is that if the reference collection is very large, for instance the World Wide Web, then the computational resources required can be prohibitive for many approaches. The vector space model is considered as a baseline for the external plagiarism detection task. This model has been used to detect duplicate and near duplicate documents <ref type="bibr" coords="1,241.12,608.62,10.58,8.64" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. A variant of this model was used for copy detection at word level (the SCAM system) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,266.25,620.57,16.60,8.64" target="#b12">[13]</ref> and sentence level (the COPS system) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,446.30,620.57,10.58,8.64" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Fingerprinting is another popular approach. Fingerprints, a means of uniquely identifying texts, are used to represent the contents of the source documents. To query a collection of documents, fingerprints are also generated for the query document. The number of common fingerprints between the source and query document determines the similarity between them. This approach has also been used by other researchers <ref type="bibr" coords="2,435.33,131.27,15.18,8.64" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,450.50,131.27,7.59,8.64" target="#b7">8]</ref>. Another approach that has also proved effective is based upon n-gram overlap. The source and suspicious documents are converted into fixed length n-grams (either characters or words) and the proportion of common n-grams used to determine the similarity between documents. This approach has been applied using different similarity measures, such as the Jaccard, Dice and Overlap coefficients <ref type="bibr" coords="2,304.98,191.04,11.32,8.64" target="#b8">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,316.30,191.04,11.32,8.64" target="#b9">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,327.61,191.04,7.55,8.64" target="#b0">1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,335.16,191.04,7.55,8.64" target="#b5">6]</ref>. Similar approaches were used by several of the systems that participated in the 1st international PAN-PC-09 plagiarism detection competition <ref type="bibr" coords="2,223.87,214.95,15.27,8.64" target="#b14">[15]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">External Plagiarism Detection</head><p>We divided the task of external plagiarism detection into three phases: preprocessing, candidate document selection and detailed analysis using Running Karp-Rabin Greedy String Tiling (RKR-GST).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Preprocessing</head><p>In the first phase we used TextCat<ref type="foot" coords="2,270.04,339.38,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_0">1</ref>  <ref type="bibr" coords="2,276.60,341.05,10.58,8.64" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, an existing language recognizer, to identify the language of each source document. Documents that were identified as being in German or Spanish were translated into English using the Google Translate<ref type="foot" coords="2,417.78,363.30,3.49,6.05" target="#foot_1">2</ref> tools (see <ref type="bibr" coords="2,468.97,364.96,11.62,8.64" target="#b3">[4]</ref> for an overview of the Google translation tools). Each document was preprocessed by converting the text to lowercase and removing any non-alphanumeric characters. Each document was then converted into a set of word n-grams (n = 5). Word n-grams of length 5 were chosen for the text representation since they were found to generate high recall in the 2009 PAN competition (see <ref type="bibr" coords="2,296.83,424.74,14.94,8.64" target="#b14">[15]</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Candidate Document Selection</head><p>Detailed comparison of each suspicious document with all the source documents could be computationally prohibitive. Therefore, for each suspicious document we attempt to identify likely source documents. The similarity between two documents can be computed by counting the number of n-grams they have in common. This technique has been used in copy detection and plagiarism detection <ref type="bibr" coords="2,352.91,520.67,11.88,8.64" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,364.78,520.67,11.88,8.64" target="#b12">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,376.66,520.67,11.88,8.64" target="#b13">14,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,388.54,520.67,11.88,8.64" target="#b9">10]</ref>. We used one such technique, the overlap coefficient <ref type="bibr" coords="2,270.80,532.62,15.27,8.64" target="#b10">[11]</ref>, to compare each suspicious document with the source documents. The overlap coefficient, Sim overlap (A, B), is computed using equation 1, where S(A, n) and S(B, n) are the set of distinct n-grams in documents A and B respectively. Values for the overlap coefficient range from 0 to 1 where 0 means that two documents are entirely different and 1 means that two documents are exactly the same.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,209.58,612.50,271.02,22.31">Sim overlap (A, B) = |S(A, n) S(B, n)| min(|S(A, n)|, |S(B, n)|)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>The potential source documents were sorted in descending order according to their overlap score and the top 10 selected. Any documents with overlap score below a certain threshold, α overlap , are discarded and the remaining source-suspicious pairs passed to the next stage of processing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Detailed Analysis</head><p>In the final stage of processing detailed analysis is carried out using the Greedy String Tiling (GST) algorithm. This performs an alignment between the contents of the suspicious document and each source document to identify potential plagiarized sections from the set of source-suspicious pairs generated by the previous stage. The advantages of using GST compared with alternative string similarity algorithms, such as longest common subsequence or edit distance, is its ability to detect block moves: treating the transposition of a substring of contiguous words as a single move rather than considering each word separately. GST has previously been used in program code plagiarism detection <ref type="bibr" coords="3,195.11,298.61,15.27,8.64" target="#b17">[18]</ref>, biological sequence alignment <ref type="bibr" coords="3,342.63,298.61,16.60,8.64" target="#b16">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,359.23,298.61,12.45,8.64" target="#b15">16]</ref> and measuring text re-use in journalism <ref type="bibr" coords="3,189.94,310.56,10.58,8.64" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. The algorithm has a run time of O(n<ref type="foot" coords="3,350.96,308.67,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_2">3</ref> ), but has been optimised to run in linear time using a string matching algorithm Running Karp-Rabin Greedy String Tiling (RKR-GST) <ref type="bibr" coords="3,213.01,334.47,15.27,8.64" target="#b15">[16]</ref>.</p><p>An example of the output of GST for a fragment of source text and a rewritten (or plagiarized) version is shown below. ( <ref type="bibr" coords="3,287.12,358.39,10.37,8.64" target="#b0">[1]</ref> and <ref type="bibr" coords="3,317.40,358.07,10.52,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref> indicate aligned matches between the two texts.)</p><p>Source A dog <ref type="bibr" coords="3,274.54,383.00,8.48,6.12" target="#b0">[1]</ref> bit the postman <ref type="bibr" coords="3,347.45,383.00,8.48,6.12" target="#b1">[2]</ref> . Rewrite The postman <ref type="bibr" coords="3,301.66,395.52,8.48,6.12" target="#b1">[2]</ref> was bitten by a dog <ref type="bibr" coords="3,390.51,395.52,8.48,6.12" target="#b0">[1]</ref> .</p><p>Match merging heuristics were applied to the output of GST to identify contiguous portions of plagiarized text from suspicious documents. GST computes the length of the longest tile 3 in common between the suspicious and source documents. If this is greater than a pre-defined length, α length , the tiles are combined to identify plagiarized sections. If the distance between adjacent tiles is less than or equal to a given number of characters, α merge , then they are combined into a single section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Evaluation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">System Development</head><p>Candidate Document Selection (Section 2.2). We initially experimented with using a copy detection system (an implementation of SCAM <ref type="bibr" coords="3,352.35,555.27,15.93,8.64" target="#b12">[13]</ref>) to extract candidate documents. However, due to the processing speed and memory problems this approach had to be re-designed. The α overlap threshold was set using a small corpus of 895 source and 88 suspicious documents from the first PAN competition (PAN-PC-09 corpus). We calculated the precision, recall and F1 measures for overlap scores with thresholds from 0.001 to 0.100. The best performing threshold, 0.005, gave a precision, recall and F1 measure of 0.74, 0.93 and 0.78 respectively. Detailed Analysis (Section 2.3). To avoid accidental matches a parameter, α mml , was used to set the minimum length of tiles that could participate in merges. We set α mml to 5. A value of 1 produced the best performance but the processing time was prohibitive. The α length parameter was set using a small set of 22 suspicious and 125 source documents from the PAN-PC-09 corpus. The length of the longest matching substring was computed for each source document and suspicious document in which it appeared. This value was always greater than 10. A small corpus of 30 suspicious documents from the PAN-PC-09 corpus was used to find a suitable value for the α merge parameter for combining the adjacent tiles to create a section. For α merge =250 characters, our heuristic achieved a performance of 0.58 overall, precision of 0.87, recall of 0.49, and granularity of 1.12.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">System Performance</head><p>Our system achieved an overall performance of 0.20, precision of 0.40, recall of 0.16 and granularity of 1.21 in the formal evaluation.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="4,174.74,325.57,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows the performance of the candidate document selection (Section 2.2) and detailed analysis (Section 2.3) stages. Various performance metrics are shown for each stage and results broken down for each of the different types of obfuscation used in the corpus.</p><p>The focus of candidate selection step was to maximise recall, thereby ensuring that the source document is included in the set that are returned so that it can be identified in the detailed analysis stage. However, the recall values are quite low, indicating that the source document is often missed. Recall also varies according to the type of obfuscation. The best recall (0.7105) is obtained for low obfuscation and the worst for the simulated plagiarism (0.4154).</p><p>The results are somewhat different for the detailed analysis stage and the best performance is obtained for simulated plagiarism. We analyzed the documents and found that simulated obfuscated documents contain cases that have not been obfuscated and the number of source documents for this type of obfuscation is very small compared to other types. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Sources of Error</head><p>Preprocessing (Section 2.1). Documents in German and Spanish were translated using Google Translate. These automatic translations contained errors that may have affected the accuracy of later processing stages.</p><p>Candidate Document Selection (Section 2.2) Analysis of the system performance (Section 3.2) showed that the source documents are often not identified.</p><p>Detailed Analysis (Section 2.3). Several parameters (α overlap , α length and α merge ) were set using small training corpora. It is possible that larger training corpora would lead to better values for these thresholds. Processing limitations led the α mml to be set to 5. This is a relatively high value which caused plagiarized sections with different types of obfuscation to be missed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>This paper described the University of Sheffield's entry to the 2nd international PAN plagiarism detection competition which attempted to identify extrinsic plagiarism. Our system did not attempt to identify intrinsic plagiarism. A three stage approach was used: preprocessing, candidate selection and detailed analysis. The approach achieved an overall performance of 0.20 in the evaluation with precision of 0.40, recall of 0.16 and granularity of 1.21 in the formal evaluation in which extrinsic and intrinsic plagiarism cases were evaluation together.</p><p>In the future we plan to improve our approaches for both the candidate document selection and detailed analysis stages. For the candidate document selection stage we plan to experiment with using approaches from information retrieval and copy detection (e.g. SCAM) to identify potential source documents since this may be faster than the approach that is currently used and may also improve recall. For the detailed analysis stage we plan to experiment with alignment techniques that can cope better with high obfuscation and also plan to make more use of approaches from natural language processing to improve matching. We also want to improve our approach at computing byte offsets in the source documents.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,134.77,531.22,345.83,99.73"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Performance of candidate selection and detailed analysis stages for various types of obfuscation.</figDesc><table coords="4,145.56,531.22,324.24,77.91"><row><cell cols="2">Candidate Document Selection</cell><cell cols="2">Detailed Analysis</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Obfuscation Precision Recall</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell cols="3">Precision Recall PlagDet Score Granularity</cell></row><row><cell>None 0.8446 0.6693</cell><cell>0.7468</cell><cell>0.6366 0.2162</cell><cell>0.3205</cell><cell>1.0100</cell></row><row><cell>Low 0.7963 0.7105</cell><cell>0.7510</cell><cell>0.5960 0.1934</cell><cell>0.2619</cell><cell>1.1660</cell></row><row><cell>High 0.6729 0.6907</cell><cell>0.6817</cell><cell>0.6918 0.1775</cell><cell>0.2041</cell><cell>1.6110</cell></row><row><cell>Simulated 0.7643 0.4154</cell><cell>0.5383</cell><cell>0.6659 0.3980</cell><cell>0.4864</cell><cell>1.0330</cell></row><row><cell>Translated 0.9622 0.5941</cell><cell>0.7346</cell><cell>0.3994 0.2219</cell><cell>0.2610</cell><cell>1.3290</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,144.73,645.94,144.13,7.77"><p>http://www.let.rug.nl/vannoord/TextCat/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,144.73,657.08,98.63,7.77"><p>http://translate.google.com/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="3,144.73,646.13,335.86,7.77;3,144.73,657.08,86.09,7.77"><p>A tile is a consecutive subsequence of maximal length that occurs as one-to-one pairing between two input strings.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p><rs type="person">Rao Muhammad Adeel Nawab</rs> thanks the <rs type="funder">COMSATS Institute of Information Technology, Lahore, Pakistan</rs> for funding this work under the <rs type="programName">Faculty Development Program</rs> <rs type="funder">(FDP)</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_mmCaDFz">
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">Faculty Development Program</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,142.61,635.17,337.98,7.77;5,150.95,646.13,329.64,7.77;5,150.95,657.08,57.03,7.77" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,312.25,635.17,168.34,7.77;5,150.95,646.13,70.69,7.77">Finding Plagiarism Based on Common Semantic Sequence Model</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="s" coord="5,241.88,646.13,124.19,7.77">Lecture notes in computer science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="640" to="645" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004. 2004</date>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.61,119.96,337.98,7.77;6,150.95,130.92,329.64,7.77;6,150.95,141.88,172.84,7.77" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,287.70,119.96,176.83,7.77">Copy detection mechanisms for digital documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Brin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Garcia-Molina</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,150.95,130.92,326.20,7.77">Proceedings of the 1995 ACM SIGMOD international conference on Management of data</title>
		<meeting>the 1995 ACM SIGMOD international conference on Management of data<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="398" to="409" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.61,152.84,337.98,7.77;6,150.95,163.80,329.64,7.77;6,150.95,174.76,125.27,7.77" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,257.91,152.84,127.08,7.77">N-Gram-Based Text Categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Cavnar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Trenkle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,403.99,152.84,76.60,7.77;6,150.95,163.80,250.31,7.77">Proceedings of Third Annual Symposium on Document Analysis and Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>Third Annual Symposium on Document Analysis and Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>UNLV Publications/Reprographics</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="175" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.61,183.71,337.98,9.78;6,150.95,196.67,60.76,7.77" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,213.97,183.71,223.02,9.78">Crossâ Ȃ Şlanguage search: The case of Google Language Tools</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Bao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,442.44,185.71,38.15,7.77;6,150.95,196.67,12.95,7.77">First Monday</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.61,207.63,337.98,7.77;6,150.95,218.59,329.64,7.77;6,150.95,229.55,123.05,7.77" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,329.63,207.63,76.05,7.77">Measuring text reuse</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gaizauskas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Piao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wilks</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,425.92,207.63,54.67,7.77;6,150.95,218.59,275.78,7.77">Proceedings of the 40th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics</title>
		<meeting>the 40th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics<address><addrLine>Philadelphia, Pennsylvania</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="152" to="159" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.61,240.51,337.98,7.77;6,150.95,251.47,329.64,7.77;6,150.95,262.43,23.90,7.77" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,246.70,240.51,180.78,7.77">Developing A Corpus of Plagiarised Short Answers</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Stevenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,445.24,240.51,35.35,7.77;6,150.95,251.47,292.15,7.77">Language Resources and Evaluation: Special Issue on Plagiarism and Authorship Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.61,273.39,337.98,7.77;6,150.95,284.34,329.64,7.77;6,150.95,295.30,23.90,7.77" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,223.07,273.39,220.33,7.77">Methods for identifying versioned and plagiarized documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Hoad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zobel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,462.34,273.39,18.25,7.77;6,150.95,284.34,248.27,7.77">Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="203" to="215" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.61,306.26,337.98,7.77;6,150.95,317.22,91.23,7.77" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,270.88,306.26,151.48,7.77">Features Based Text Similarity Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Salim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Johor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,443.16,306.26,37.43,7.77;6,150.95,317.22,38.34,7.77">Journal of Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.61,328.18,337.98,7.77;6,150.95,339.14,228.35,7.77" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,272.03,328.18,173.60,7.77">Demonstration of the Ferret plagiarism detector</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Lane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lyon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Malcolm</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,465.15,328.18,15.44,7.77;6,150.95,339.14,202.20,7.77">Proceedings of the 2nd International Plagiarism Conference</title>
		<meeting>the 2nd International Plagiarism Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.24,350.10,338.35,7.77;6,150.95,361.06,329.64,7.77;6,150.95,372.02,151.91,7.77" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,287.77,350.10,192.82,7.77;6,150.95,361.06,58.07,7.77">Detecting short passages of similar text in large document collections</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lyon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Malcolm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Dickerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,227.33,361.06,253.27,7.77;6,150.95,372.02,74.95,7.77">Proceedings of the 2001 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2001 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="118" to="125" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.24,382.97,338.35,7.77;6,150.95,393.93,249.32,7.77" xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,255.02,382.97,201.16,7.77">Foundations of statistical natural language processing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Manning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Schutze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Massacchusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.24,404.89,338.35,7.77;6,150.95,415.85,329.64,7.77;6,150.95,426.81,135.87,7.77" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,298.75,404.89,181.84,7.77;6,150.95,415.85,27.23,7.77">Winnowing: local algorithms for document fingerprinting</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schleimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wilkerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Aiken</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,196.64,415.85,283.96,7.77;6,150.95,426.81,43.63,7.77">Proceedings of the 2003 ACM SIGMOD international conference on Management of data</title>
		<meeting>the 2003 ACM SIGMOD international conference on Management of data</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="76" to="85" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.24,437.77,338.35,7.77;6,150.95,448.73,329.64,7.77;6,150.95,459.69,134.71,7.77" xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,284.89,437.77,195.70,7.77;6,150.95,448.73,24.12,7.77">SCAM: A copy detection mechanism for digital documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Shivakumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Garcia-Molina</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,195.22,448.73,285.37,7.77;6,150.95,459.69,60.46,7.77">Proceedings of the Second Annual Conference on the Theory and Practice of Digital Libraries</title>
		<meeting>the Second Annual Conference on the Theory and Practice of Digital Libraries<address><addrLine>Austin,Texas</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.24,470.65,338.35,7.77;6,150.95,481.60,329.64,7.77;6,150.95,492.56,57.53,7.77" xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,283.10,470.65,197.49,7.77;6,150.95,481.60,19.72,7.77">Building a scalable and accurate copy detection mechanism</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Shivakumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Garcia-Molina</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,190.48,481.60,272.50,7.77">Proceedings of the first ACM international conference on Digital Libraries</title>
		<meeting>the first ACM international conference on Digital Libraries</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="160" to="168" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.24,503.52,338.35,7.77;6,150.95,514.48,329.64,7.77;6,150.95,525.44,292.12,7.77" xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,364.06,503.52,116.53,7.77;6,150.95,514.48,198.87,7.77">3rd PAN Workshop on Uncovering Plagiarism, Authorship and Social Software Misuse</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Agirre</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,368.70,514.48,111.89,7.77;6,150.95,525.44,176.56,7.77">25th Annual Conference of the Spanish Society for Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>SEPLN</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009. 2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="77" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.24,536.40,338.35,7.77;6,150.95,547.36,281.02,7.77" xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,190.68,536.40,197.65,7.77">Running karp-rabin matching and greedy string tiling</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">463</biblScope>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Basser Department of Computer Science Technical Report, Sydney University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Tech. Rep.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.24,558.32,338.35,7.77;6,150.95,569.28,329.64,7.77;6,150.95,580.23,253.44,7.77" xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,189.31,558.32,291.28,7.77;6,150.95,569.28,127.13,7.77">Neweyes: A system for comparing biological sequences using the running karprabin greedy string-tiling algorithm</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wise</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,297.47,569.28,183.12,7.77;6,150.95,580.23,97.71,7.77">Third International Conference on Intelligent Systems for Molecular Biology</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, England</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="393" to="401" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,142.24,591.19,338.35,7.77;6,150.95,602.15,329.64,7.77;6,150.95,613.11,183.55,7.77" xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,188.11,591.19,277.28,7.77">YAP3: improved detection of similarities in computer program and other texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wise</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,150.95,602.15,329.64,7.77;6,150.95,613.11,34.74,7.77">Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh SIGCSE Technical Symposium on Computer Science Education</title>
		<meeting>the Twenty-Seventh SIGCSE Technical Symposium on Computer Science Education<address><addrLine>Philadelphia, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="130" to="134" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
