<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,99.35,87.93,407.32,15.31">ITC-irst at CLEF 2002: Using N -best query translations for CLIR</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,205.33,118.85,77.35,10.76"><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>Bertoldi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">ITC-irst -Centro per la Ricerca Scientifica e Tecnologica</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>38050</postCode>
									<settlement>Povo, Trento</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,307.92,118.85,92.77,10.76"><forename type="first">Marcello</forename><surname>Federico</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">ITC-irst -Centro per la Ricerca Scientifica e Tecnologica</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>38050</postCode>
									<settlement>Povo, Trento</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,99.35,87.93,407.32,15.31">ITC-irst at CLEF 2002: Using N -best query translations for CLIR</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">0EB22F8EE087F0295A0CCF3B4895A34E</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:04+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper reports on the participation of ITC-irst in the Italian monolingual retrieval track and in the bilingual English-Italian track of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF) 2002. A crosslanguage information retrieval systems is proposed which integrates retrieval and translation scores over the set of N-best translations of the source query. Translations are computed by a statistical translation model, based on an hidden Markov model, and trained over a bilingual dictionary and the target document collection. Retrieval scores result as a combination of a statistical language model and a standard Okapi model.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>This paper reports on the participation of ITCirst in two Information Retrieval (IR) tracks of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF) 2002: the monolingual retrieval task, and the bilingual retrieval task. The language of the queries was Italian for the monolingual track and English for the bilingual track; Italian documents were searched in both tracks. With respect to the 2001 CLEF evaluation <ref type="bibr" coords="1,258.12,387.02,35.98,8.97;1,83.34,398.97,78.88,8.97" target="#b1">(Bertoldi and Federico, 2002)</ref>, the Cross Language IR (CLIR) system was modified in order to work with multiple translations of queries, and with source and target languages in the reverse order. The basic IR engine, used for both evaluations, combines scores of a standard Okapi model and of a statistical language model. For CLIR, a light-weight statistical model for translating queries was developed, which also computes the list of N-best translations for each query. In this way, the basic IR engine is used to integrate retrieval and translation scores over multiple translations <ref type="bibr" coords="1,132.24,530.59,118.18,8.97" target="#b3">(Federico and Bertoldi, 2002)</ref>. Remarkably, training of the system just requires a bilingual dictionary and the target document collection. This paper is organized as follows. Section 2 introduces the statistical approach to CLIR. Sections 3 to 5 describe, respectively, the query-document model, the query-translation model, and the CLIR algorithm. Section 6 presents and discusses experimental results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Statistical CLIR Approach</head><p>From a statistical perspective, the CLIR problem can be formulated as follows. Given a query f in the source language, by convention French, one would like to find relevant documents d in the target language, English, within a collection D. More formally, documents should be ranked according to the posterior probability:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="1,147.51,746.86,146.58,10.63">Pr(d | f ) ∝ Pr(f , d) (1)</formula><p>where the right term of formula (1) follows from the application of Bayes formula and from the constancy of Pr(f ) with respect to the ranking of documents.</p><p>To fill the language difference between query and documents, the hidden variable e is introduced, which represents an English (term-by-term) translation of f . Hence, the following decomposition is derived: </p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="1,333.80,403.97,94.42,21.33">Pr(f , d) = e Pr(f</formula><p>In deriving formula (2), one makes the assumption (or approximation) that the probability of document d given query f and translation e, does not depend on f . Moreover, the main summation in (2) is taken over the set of possible translations of f . As terms of f may typically admit more than one translation, the size of this set can grow exponentially with the length of f . Finally, the denominator in formula (2) requires summing over all document in D and should be computed for every possible translation e.</p><p>In the following, statistical models will be described which, through suitable approximations, permit to efficiently compute formula (2). In particular, we will show how: </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Query-Document Model</head><p>The query-document model computes the joint probability of a query e and a document d, written in the same language. Two query-document models were considered in the experiments. The former is based on a statistical model, the latter on the standard Okapi scoring function.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Witten-Bell Query-Document Model</head><p>The joint probability of a query e a document d can be factored out as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,134.21,376.39,159.89,10.63">Pr(e, d) = Pr(e | d) Pr(d)<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where Pr(e | d) represents the likelihood of e being generated by d, and Pr(d) the a-priori probability of d. In the following, no a-priori knowledge about the documents will be assumed, hence a uniform apriori distribution is taken <ref type="foot" coords="2,190.76,446.77,3.49,6.27" target="#foot_0">1</ref> . For what concerns the probability of e given d, an order-free multinomial (bag-of-word) model is assumed. Hence, assuming e = e 1 , . . . , e n , we have<ref type="foot" coords="2,180.73,482.63,3.49,6.27" target="#foot_1">2</ref> :</p><p>Pr(e = e1, . . . , en</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="2,186.82,501.73,107.27,30.19">| d) = n k=1 p(e k | d) (4)</formula><p>The probability of term q being generated by document d is estimated by the statistical LM:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="2,121.45,572.30,169.15,21.36">p(e | d) = λ N (d, e) N (d) + (1 -λ) p(e) (<label>5</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="2,290.61,579.67,3.48,8.07">)</formula><p>where p(e), the word probability over D, is estimated by interpolating the smoothed relative frequency with the uniform distribution over the vocabulary V of D:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7" coords="2,133.79,647.34,160.30,21.37">p(e) = µ N (e) N + (1 -µ) 1 |V| (6)</formula><p>Parameters λ and µ are estimated according to <ref type="bibr" coords="2,272.91,679.56,16.95,8.97;2,83.34,691.51,74.57,8.97" target="#b9">(Witten and Bell, 1991)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Okapi Query-Document Model</head><p>The query-document model can also be based on a generic scoring function s(e, d). In order to obtain a distribution over queries and documents scores have to be normalized as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8" coords="2,362.05,295.79,160.66,26.43">Pr(e, d) = s(e, d) e ,d s(e , d )<label>(7)</label></formula><p>The denominator of the above formula is considered only for the sake of normalization, but can be disregarded in the computation of equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="2,469.83,354.90,3.53,8.97" target="#formula_2">2</ref>).</p><p>In the experiments the following scoring function was used, whose logarithm corresponds to the standard Okapi formula:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9" coords="2,326.67,406.62,196.04,31.76">s(e = e 1 , . . . , e n , d) = n k=1 idf (e k ) W d (e k )<label>(8)</label></formula><p>where:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10" coords="2,323.68,461.56,199.03,27.69">W d (w) = N (d, w)(k 1 + 1) k 1 (1 -b) + k 1 b N (d) l + N (d, w) (9)</formula><p>scores the relevance of w in d, and:</p><formula xml:id="formula_11" coords="2,365.15,514.01,157.56,24.93">idf (w) = N -N w + 0.5 N w + 0.5<label>(10)</label></formula><p>is the inverted document frequency. As in previous work, the setting k 1 = 1.5 and b = 0.4 were used.</p><p>An explanation of the involved terms can be found in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,311.96,582.22,95.85,8.97" target="#b8">(Robertson et al., 1994)</ref> and other papers referred in it.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.">Combined Query-Document Model</head><p>Previous work <ref type="bibr" coords="2,371.81,628.97,118.27,8.97" target="#b0">(Bertoldi and Federico, 2001)</ref> showed that Okapi and the statistical model rank documents almost independently. Hence, information about the relevant documents can be gained by integrating the scores of both methods. Combination of the two models is implemented by just taking the sum of scores. Actually, in order to adjust scale differences, scores of each model are normalized in the range [0, 1] before summation. The resulting querydocument model was also applied to the monolingual IR track.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Query-Translation Model</head><p>The query-translation model computes the probability of any query-translation pair. This probability is modelled by an HMM <ref type="bibr" coords="3,177.08,114.31,63.44,8.97" target="#b6">(Rabiner, 1990)</ref> in which the observable variable is the Italian query f , and the hidden variable is its English translation e. According to the HMM, the joint probability of a pair (f , e) is decomposed as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12" coords="3,100.16,184.39,193.94,57.31">P r(f = f 1 , . . . , f n , e = e 1 , . . . , e n ) = p(e 1 ) n k=2 p(e k | e k-1 ) n k=1 p(f k | e k )<label>(11)</label></formula><p>Formula ( <ref type="formula" coords="3,124.91,257.66,8.30,8.97" target="#formula_12">11</ref>) puts in evidence two different conditional probabilities: the term translation probabilities p(f | e) and the target LM probabilities p(e | e ).</p><p>Given a query-document model and a query f , the most probable translation e * can be computed through the well known Viterbi search algorithm, while N -best translations of f can be computed with the tree-trellis based algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="3,237.21,342.34,56.89,8.97;3,83.34,354.30,59.07,8.97" target="#b3">(Federico and Bertoldi, 2002)</ref>. Probabilities p(f | e) are estimated from a bilingual dictionary as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13" coords="3,137.02,400.14,157.08,26.43">Pr(f | e) = δ(f, e) f δ(f , e)<label>(12)</label></formula><p>where δ(f, e) = 1 if the term e is one of the translations of term f and δ(f, e) = 0 otherwise. In Section 6, it will be explained how out-of-dictionary words are processed. where C(e, e ) is the number of co-occurrences appearing in the corpus, p(e) is computed according to equation ( <ref type="formula" coords="3,124.28,712.66,3.53,8.97">6</ref>), and the absolute discounting term β is equal to the estimate proposed in <ref type="bibr" coords="3,220.17,724.62,69.63,8.97" target="#b5">(Ney et al., 1994)</ref>. Absolute discounting was chosen for its good performance and suitability to the order-free case.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">CLIR Algorithm</head><p>The CLIR algorithm is in charge of computing formula (2) and sorting documents according to the posterior probability (1). The algorithm relies on two approximations in order to limit the set of possible translations and documents to be taken into account:</p><p>• external summation is taken over T N (f ), the set of the N -best translations of f , and</p><p>• internal summation is over I(e), the set of documents in D containing at least a word of e.</p><p>This corresponds to approximating formula (2) by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_14" coords="3,314.69,235.52,124.94,22.84">Pr(f , d) ≈ e∈T N (f ) Pr(f , e)</formula><p>Pr(e, d)  The CLIR algorithm is illustrated in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,482.58,452.24,3.74,8.97" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. Briefly, given an input query f , the N -best translations T N (f ) and their probabilities P [f , e] are computed first. Then, for each translation e, the addenda in formula (2) are computed only for documents containing at least one term of e. This requires one additional loop over the documents in order to compute the normalization term.</p><formula xml:id="formula_15" coords="3,453.00,242.35,65.78,29.69">d ∈I(e) Pr(e, d )<label>(15</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Experimental Evaluation</head><p>Four runs were submitted to CLEF 2002: one for the Italian monolingual track (IRSTit1) and 3 for the bilingual English-to-Italian track, using 1best, 5-best, and 10-best translation (IRSTen2it1, IRSTen2it2, and IRSTen2it3), respectively. The tracks consisted of 49 topics, for a total of 1072 documents to be retrieved, inside a collection of 108,578 Italian newspaper article from La Stampa and Swiss News Agency, both of 1994. All runs used only title and description parts of the topics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1.">Preprocessing</head><p>Text preprocessing was applied on the target documents before indexing, and on the queries before retrieval. More specifically, the following preprocessing steps were carried out:</p><p>• Tokenization was performed on documents and queries to isolate words from punctuation marks, to recognize abbreviations and acronyms, correct possible word splits across lines, and discriminate between accents and quotation marks.</p><p>• Base forms were computed for Italian words by means of morphological analysis and POS tagging.</p><p>• Stemming was performed on English words by using the Porter's algorithm (Frakes and Baeza-Yates, 1992).</p><p>• Stop-terms removal was applied on the documents by removing terms with a low inverted document frequency (Frakes and Baeza-Yates, 1992).</p><p>• Proper names and numbers in the query were recognized in order to improve coverage of the dictionary.</p><p>• Out-of-dictionary terms which have not been recognized as proper names or numbers were removed from the query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2.">Blind Relevance Feedback</head><p>After document ranking, Blind Relevance Feedback (BRF) can be applied. BRF is a well known technique that allows to improve retrieval performance. The basic idea is to perform retrieval in two steps. First, the documents matching the source query e are ranked, then the B best ranked documents are taken and the R most relevant terms in them are added to the query, and the retrieval phase is repeated. In the CLIR framework, R terms are added to each single translation of the N -best list and the retrieval algorithms is repeated once again. In this work, new search terms are selected from the top B documents according to:</p><formula xml:id="formula_16" coords="4,96.09,559.02,198.01,24.94">r w (r w + 0.5)(N -N w -B + r w + 0.5) (N w -r w + 0.5)(B -r w + 0.5)<label>(16)</label></formula><p>where r w is the number of documents, among the B top documents, which contain term w. In all the performed experiments the values B = 5 and R = 15 were used <ref type="bibr" coords="4,125.93,629.56,116.63,8.97" target="#b0">(Bertoldi and Federico, 2001)</ref>. possible weakness in the preprocessing phase, poor coverage of the dictionary with respect to the terms in the queries, and any other possible causes of poor translation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3.">Official Results</head></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,83.34,487.31,210.75,10.63;3,83.34,500.93,210.75,8.97;3,83.34,512.88,210.75,8.97;3,83.34,524.83,210.75,8.97;3,136.46,552.52,43.65,10.46;3,197.30,545.78,29.26,10.46;3,194.59,564.88,3.78,7.32;3,205.43,559.35,34.35,10.46;3,277.50,554.18,16.60,8.97;3,83.34,582.80,210.75,10.63;3,83.34,594.75,210.75,10.63;3,83.34,608.37,210.75,8.97;3,83.34,620.32,210.75,8.97;3,83.34,632.27,68.38,8.97;3,89.96,658.27,56.57,9.41;3,156.74,652.39,46.18,9.41;3,175.91,664.35,7.36,9.41;3,204.60,658.27,89.49,9.56"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Probabilities p(e | e ) are estimated on the target document collection, through an order-free bigram LM, which tries to compensate for different word positions induced by the source and target languages. Let p(e | e ) = p(e, e ) e p(e , e )(13)where p(e, e ) is the probability of e co-occurring with e , regardless of the order, within a text window of fixed size. Smoothing of this probability is performed through absolute discounting and interpolation as follows:p(e, e ) = max C(e, e ) -β N , 0 + βp(e)p(e ) (14)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="3,518.56,263.07,4.15,8.97;3,317.37,288.51,40.03,10.63;3,317.37,300.47,57.46,10.63;3,374.83,304.50,6.31,7.32;3,382.39,300.47,86.67,10.63;3,317.37,312.42,72.78,10.63;3,390.16,316.46,6.31,7.32;3,397.71,312.42,12.34,10.46;3,317.37,324.37,48.87,10.63;3,317.37,336.34,94.96,10.63;3,317.37,349.96,7.47,8.97;3,347.39,348.29,67.21,10.63;3,317.37,361.91,7.47,8.97;3,347.39,360.24,103.09,10.63;3,317.37,372.20,94.96,10.63;3,317.37,385.82,7.47,8.97;3,347.39,384.15,166.16,10.63;3,312.39,396.10,159.89,10.63"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>) 1. Input f 2. Compute T N (f ) and scores P [f , e] 3. For each e ∈ T N (f ) 4. N = 0 5. For each d ∈ I(e) 6. Compute P [e, d] 7. Update N = N + P [e, d] 8. For each d ∈ I(e) 9. Update P [d] = P [d]+ P [e, d] * P [f , e]/N 10. Order documents according to P [d]</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="1,321.92,667.89,200.79,87.44"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>set of terms occurring in D, and in document d N, N (d) number of term occurrences in D, and in a document d N (w), N (d, w), N (e, w) frequency of term w in D, in document d, and in query e List of often used symbols.</figDesc><table coords="1,321.92,667.89,200.79,87.44"><row><cell>• probability Pr(e, d) is computed by the query-</cell></row><row><cell>document model,</cell></row><row><cell>• probability Pr(f , e) is computed by the query-</cell></row><row><cell>translation model,</cell></row><row><cell>• formula (2) is computed and documents are</cell></row><row><cell>ranked by the CLIR algorithm.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,366.51,419.51,101.64,8.97"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>CLIR algorithm.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="4,83.34,71.31,428.74,686.19"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Table 6.3. reports official results of the submitted runs, and Table 6.3. compares them with the worst, median, and best results of competitors.With respect to previous evaluations, this year we had to perform query translation in the reverse order, i.e. from English to Italian. Given the large gap between monolingual and cross-lingual results, i.e. about 15% absolute, future work will be devoted to investigate Results of the official runs.</figDesc><table coords="4,322.57,71.31,189.51,157.86"><row><cell cols="2">Official Run</cell><cell cols="2">N-best mAvPr</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>IRSTit1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>.4920</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">IRSTen2it1</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>.3444</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">IRSTen2it2</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>.3531</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">IRSTen2it3</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>.3552</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Official Run</cell><cell cols="4">&lt; mdn &gt; mdn wrs bst</cell></row><row><cell>IRSTit1</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>37</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>7</cell></row><row><cell>IRSTen2it1</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>24</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>5</cell></row><row><cell>IRSTen2it2</cell><cell>19</cell><cell>26</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>IRSTen2it3</cell><cell>16</cell><cell>26</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>6</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="4,311.96,241.94,210.76,20.92"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Results of the official runs against the worst, median and best values.</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,99.48,716.12,194.54,8.07;2,83.34,727.07,115.33,8.07"><p>However, this model permits to apply any available prior distribution on documents.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,99.48,736.75,194.56,9.56;2,83.34,749.21,100.32,8.07"><p>Notice the use of p(•) to indicate a probability computed by a statistical model.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,311.96,350.56,210.75,8.97;4,321.87,362.51,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,374.46,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,386.42,200.83,8.97;4,321.87,398.38,65.31,8.97" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,478.18,350.56,44.53,8.97;4,321.87,362.51,156.17,8.97">ITC-irst at CLEF 2000: Italian monolingual track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Bertoldi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Federico</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,346.91,374.46,175.80,8.97;4,321.87,386.42,42.02,8.97">Cross-Language Information Retrieval and Evaluation</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001. 2069</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="261" to="272" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,311.96,410.82,210.75,8.97;4,321.87,422.78,200.84,8.97" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="4,478.18,410.82,44.53,8.97;4,321.87,422.78,197.09,8.97">ITC-irst at CLEF 2001: Monolingual and bilingual tracks</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Bertoldi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Federico</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,321.87,434.73,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,446.69,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,458.65,125.35,8.97" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,417.83,434.73,104.88,8.97;4,321.87,446.69,116.65,8.97">Cross-Language Information Retrieval and Evaluation</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,496.41,446.69,21.04,8.97">LNCS</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2406</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="94" to="101" />
			<publisher>Springer Verlag</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,311.96,471.09,210.75,8.97;4,321.87,483.04,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,495.01,200.85,8.97;4,321.87,506.96,102.41,8.97" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,457.34,471.09,65.37,8.97;4,321.87,483.04,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,495.01,44.70,8.97">Statistical crosslanguage information retrieval using n-best query translations</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Federico</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Bertoldi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,387.88,495.01,134.84,8.97;4,321.87,506.96,22.82,8.97">Proc. of 25th International ACM SIGIR</title>
		<meeting>of 25th International ACM SIGIR<address><addrLine>Tampere, Finland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,311.96,519.40,210.75,8.97;4,321.87,531.36,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,543.32,86.33,8.97" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,321.87,531.36,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,543.32,23.96,8.97">Information Retrieval: Data Structures and Algorithms</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Frakes</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ricardo</forename><surname>Baeza-Yates</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Prentice Hall</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,311.96,555.76,210.75,8.97;4,321.87,567.72,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,579.67,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,591.63,59.30,8.97" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,484.40,555.76,38.31,8.97;4,321.87,567.72,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,579.67,68.19,8.97">On structuring probabilistic dependences in stochastic language modelling</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Essen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Kneser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,403.66,579.67,119.05,8.97;4,321.87,591.63,22.21,8.97">Computer Speech and Language</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="38" />
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,311.96,604.08,210.76,8.97;4,321.87,616.03,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,627.99,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,639.95,165.00,8.97" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,404.44,604.08,118.28,8.97;4,321.87,616.03,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,627.99,22.07,8.97">A tutorial on hidden Markov models and selected applications in speech recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Rabiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,485.63,627.99,37.08,8.97;4,321.87,639.95,91.20,8.97">Readings in Speech Recognition</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lee</forename><surname>Weibel</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990">1990</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="296" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,491.39,639.95,31.32,8.97;4,321.87,651.90,44.54,8.97" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Morgan</forename><surname>Kaufmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,311.96,664.34,210.75,8.97;4,321.87,676.31,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,688.26,200.85,8.97;4,321.87,700.21,18.54,8.97" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,498.36,676.31,24.35,8.97;4,321.87,688.26,41.63,8.97">Okapi at TREC-3</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hancock-Beaulieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gatford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,385.44,688.26,74.37,8.97">Proc. of 3rd TREC</title>
		<meeting>of 3rd TREC<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,311.96,712.66,210.75,8.97;4,321.87,724.62,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,736.57,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,748.53,176.33,8.97" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,480.97,712.66,41.74,8.97;4,321.87,724.62,200.84,8.97;4,321.87,736.57,169.32,8.97">The zerofrequency problem: Estimating the probabilities of novel events in adaptive text compression</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Witten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Bell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,501.13,736.57,21.58,8.97;4,321.87,748.53,85.97,8.97">IEEE Trans. Inform. Theory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1085" to="1094" />
			<date type="published" when="1991">1991</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
