<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,449.85,70.04,26.36,11.84">2005</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,238.80,108.94,54.15,8.48"><forename type="first">Mirna</forename><surname>Adriani</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,311.18,108.94,62.02,8.48"><forename type="first">Rama</forename><surname>Pandugita</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">WEBIR-CLEF</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Indonesia Participation</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Indonesia Depok</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>16424</postCode>
									<country key="ID">Indonesia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,449.85,70.04,26.36,11.84">2005</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">33A145C811243494E569FD10E9C4151D</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:09+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We present a report on our participation in the mixed monolingual web task of the 2005 Cross-Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF). We compared the result of web page retrieval based on the content of the page, the target domain and the page content, and a combination of the page title and the target domain. The result shows that combining the page title and the target domain resulted in better retrieval performance than using only the page content or the target domain and the page content.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The fast growing amount of information on the web motivated many researchers to study how to deal with such information efficiently. Information retrieval forums such as the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF) have included research in the web area. In fact, this year CLEF includes a WEBIR topic as one of the research tracks. This year we, the University of Indonesia IR-group, participated in the mixed monolingual WEBIR -CLEF 2005 task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The Query Process</head><p>The mixed monolingual task searches for web pages in a number of languages. The queries and the documents were processed using the Lucene information retrieval system (see http://lucene.apache.org). Stopword removal was applied only to the English queries and documents. We used three different techniques for indexing the documents in the collection, i.e., based only on the content of the page, based on the target domain and the page content, and based on the combination of the page title and the target domain.</p><p>The first technique considers the content of the page in order to find the most relevant web pages to the query. We used the vector space model <ref type="bibr" coords="1,216.36,520.36,10.24,8.48" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,228.90,520.36,7.87,8.48" target="#b1">2]</ref> to find the similarity value between the query and the pages.</p><p>Since the collection contains documents not only in English, we also used the information in the metadata of the target document. The information about the target domain of the query is matched with the domain metadata of the pages. We then applied the vector space model to obtain the most similar pages to the query based on the page content. For example: &lt;topic_id&gt; &lt;domain&gt; &lt;LANGUAGE&gt; &lt;query&gt; WC0001 eu EN road safety in europe WC0003 nl NL list of dutch eco-labels Query number 1 (WC0001) was used for searching only in the eu (European Union) domain and query number 3 (WC0003) was used for searching only in the nl (Netherland) domain.</p><p>The third technique uses a combination of the page title and the target domain. We used only the terms in the page title as the query terms once the domain of the target pages is found. We then match the title of the pages with the query using the vector space model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiment</head><p>The web collection contains over two million documents from the EUROGOV collection. The collection is divided into 27 European language domains. In this mixed monolingual task, the queries are in various languages and used to find documents in the same language as the queries. There are 547 queries to be used for searching in two categories, namely, the name page search and the homepage search. The average number of words in the queries is 6.29 words.</p><p>In these experiments, we used the Lucene information retrieval system to index and retrieve the documents.</p><p>Lucene retrieval system is based on the vector space model. The documents were indexed in separate indexing files according to the domain. For example, documents from internet domain 'uk' are indexed separately from documents from internet domain 'de'. Lucene has the capability to build separate indexes and to search according to the specified index.</p><p>Lucene is also capable of indexing documents using two separate fields such as the title page and the content, and then searching can be done using either the title page or the content page.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>The results that we have submitted were produced using the three techniques, namely, based on the content only, based on the target domain and page content, and based on a combination of the title page and the target domain.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="2,117.25,389.14,4.71,8.48" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows the result of our experiments. The mean reciprocal rank (MRR) over 547 queries is 0.2165 for using the content, 0.2714 for using the target domain and the content, and 0.2860 for using the combination of the page title and the target domain. The combination of the page title and the target domain resulted in retrieval performance 24.82% better than that of using only the content, and 5.10% better than that of using the target domain and page content. The average of success values of each technique in several ranks (Table <ref type="table" coords="2,380.08,588.82,3.93,8.48">2</ref>) show some differences. The best result was achieved by using the combination of the target domain and the page title, with average success at 1: 0.2249, which is consistent with the MRR result. The retrieval performance of the combination of the target domain and the page title was 33.34% better than that of using the content only and 15.47% better than that of using the target domain and the content. However, the average of success of using the target domain and the page content shows better results at higher ranks than the other two techniques.</p><p>Our result is similar to the work by Westerveld et al. <ref type="bibr" coords="2,297.85,664.54,11.01,8.48" target="#b1">[2]</ref> who obtained better results by using other information in addition to the content.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,133.20,477.22,297.96,87.63"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Mean reciprocal Mean (MRR) of the mixed monolingual queries.</figDesc><table coords="2,135.78,477.22,295.38,54.63"><row><cell>Task : Mixed Monolingual</cell><cell>Mean Reciprocal Rank</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>(MRR)</cell></row><row><cell>Page content</cell><cell>0.2165</cell></row><row><cell>Target domain + Page content</cell><cell>0.2714</cell></row><row><cell>Page title + Target domain</cell><cell>0.2860</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Since this was our first participation in the WEB task, it took us quite a lot of effort to cope with such large collections. There were several document sets that were damaged, possibly in the process of downloading the files. As a result, we could not index those corrupt files. It is possible that those files were relevant to some of the queries.</p><p>The other problem that we had was that we did not prepare Lucene to handle non-Latin characters, and so, the retrieval of documents using queries containing such characters was erroneous.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Summary</head><p>Our results demonstrate that combining the target domain metadata and the page title resulted in better mean reciprocal rank (MRR) compared to searching using the content only and using the target domain metadata and the page content. However the combination of the target domain metadata and the page title achieved best performance only at 1 rank. For the other ranks, using the target domain metadata and page content showed better results compared to the other two techniques. We hope to improve our results in the future by exploring still other methods.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="3,96.13,435.10,423.30,8.48;3,109.50,445.96,54.17,8.48" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="3,312.90,435.10,115.97,8.48">Modern Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Richardo</forename><surname>Baeza-Yates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Berthier</forename><surname>Ribeiro-Neto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,96.13,456.82,423.23,8.48;3,109.50,467.56,40.56,8.48" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="3,259.56,456.82,172.37,8.48">Introduction to Modern Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gerard</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Mcgill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983">1983</date>
			<publisher>McGraw-Hill</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,96.13,478.42,423.32,8.48;3,109.50,489.22,189.78,8.48;3,299.28,487.30,4.79,5.49;3,306.36,489.22,168.81,8.48" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,322.56,478.42,196.89,8.48;3,109.50,489.22,45.97,8.48">Retrieving Web Pages using Content, Links, URLs, and Anchors</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Thisj</forename><surname>Westerveld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wessel</forename><surname>Kraaij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Djoerd</forename><surname>Hiemstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="3,172.26,489.22,127.02,8.48;3,299.28,487.30,4.79,5.49;3,306.36,489.22,140.85,8.48">NIST Special Publication: The 10 th Text Retrieval Conference (TREC-10)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
