<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,194.84,148.86,213.33,15.15;1,193.59,170.78,215.82,15.15">EuroGOV: Engineering a Multilingual Web Corpus</title>
				<funder ref="#_q6B4w59 #_YTcDcwH #_9JKuZqE #_E2n97Kh #_H6amBQk #_XtUx7ny #_4EjxSvJ #_bEVvUqU #_h4GdsbB">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_UsZs6R9">
					<orgName type="full">Netherlands Organization for Scientific Research (NWO)</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,163.83,204.67,98.60,8.74"><forename type="first">Börkur</forename><surname>Sigurbjörnsson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Informatics Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,280.18,204.67,54.43,8.74"><forename type="first">Jaap</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
							<email>kamps@science.uva.nl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Informatics Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Archives and Information Studies</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,358.71,204.67,75.99,8.74"><forename type="first">Maarten</forename><surname>De Rijke</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Informatics Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,194.84,148.86,213.33,15.15;1,193.59,170.78,215.82,15.15">EuroGOV: Engineering a Multilingual Web Corpus</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">760EC7AFF2721BFE27A1E81C6E82C721</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:09+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.3 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: H.3.1 Content Analysis and Indexing</term>
					<term>H.3.3 Information Search and Retrieval</term>
					<term>H.3.4 Systems and Software</term>
					<term>H.3.7 Digital Libraries Measurement, Performance, Experimentation Multilingual web corpus, Web retrieval, Multilingual retrieval</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>EuroGOV is a multilingual web corpus that was created to serve as the document collection for WebCLEF, the CLEF 2005 web retrieval task. EuroGOV is a collection of web pages crawled from the European Union portal, European Union member state governmental web sites, and Russian government web sites. The corpus contains over 3 million documents written in more than 20 different European languages. In this paper we provide a detailed description of the EuroGOV collection.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The world wide web is a natural setting for cross-lingual information retrieval. This is particularly true in Europe: many European searches are essentially cross-lingual. For instance, when organizing to travel abroad for a business trip or a holiday, planning and booking usually involves digesting pages in foreign languages. Similarly, looking for information about European culture, education, sports, economy, or politics, usually requires making sense of web pages in several languages. A case in point is the current European Union, which has no less than 20 official languages.</p><p>The linguistic diversity of European content is "mirrored" by the fact that European searchers tend to be multilingual. Some Europeans are native speakers of multiple languages. Many Europeans have a broad knowledge of several foreign languages, while English functions as the lingua franca of the world wide web. Moreover, many Europeans have a passive understanding of even more languages.</p><p>In light of the linguistic diversity of the European web and European searchers, a cross-lingual web retrieval task, called WebCLEF, was launched at CLEF 2005. Cross-lingual web retrieval requires a new document collection to be constructed, containing web content in many languages. Of course, there are many options for creating such a collection. Multi-lingual documents are abundant on the web. We have chosen to focus on pages of European government-related sites,  <ref type="bibr" coords="2,269.09,402.63,9.97,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. The crawled pages were cleaned-up and organized in a uniform format, bundled and compressed down to manageable sizes. The collection is available under an individual or organizational license restricting its usage to research only; see <ref type="bibr" coords="2,467.73,426.54,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p><p>In this paper we describe the EuroGOV collection in detail. The paper is organized as follows. We start by describing the crawling process in Section 2. Section 3 then lists various characteristics of the resulting collection, including the domains, the languages, and the link structure. We conclude with some discussion and future outlook in Section 4.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Crawling</head><p>Our initial plan for building EuroGOV was to obtain a focused crawl from the European Union seed .eu.int, and branch into the individual member states' governmental sites. However, restricting a crawler to government-related sites proved highly non-trivial. There is no simple way to tell a European government site apart from any other European site. For some government sites the crawling is smooth and we can easily filter out governmental pages (notable examples include .gov.uk and .regeringen.se). Most governmental sites, however, have more complex structures, and we could only focus the crawl by providing an explicit list of domains. As an example, we initially crawled 13 different domains to gather pages from the Finnish government. As the following domain list shows, there is no easy way of identifying Finnish governmental domains: defmin.fi, formin.finland.fi, intermin.fi, ktm.fi, minedu.fi, mintc.fi, mmm.fi, mol.fi, om.fi, stm.fi, vm.fi, vnk.fi, and ymparisto.fi These differences in domain naming traditions will make it difficult to guarantee completeness of some governments. As a result, what we should realistically aim for is that EuroGOV contains the fairly complete content of • the main government portals, and</p><p>• the main ministries of the countries on whose information we want to include in the corpus.</p><p>Our crawling process can be divided into three parts. Our initial seed was made by picking 2-3 main governmental sites for each EU member state. The seed contained 40 URLs and was created by referring to a list from the EU portal. 1 After completing several cycles of this crawl we realized that due to the varying structure of governmental sites, the portion of governmental pages covered differed considerably from one country to another. In order to try to get a better harmony in coverage we began a new crawl, now starting with a seed consisting of a list of ministries for a subset of the EU countries. The subset covered 12 countries and was chosen according to CLEF interests. The left column of Table <ref type="table" coords="3,240.80,207.66,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows the list of main domains. The second seed list consisted of 131 ministries from 9 EU member states (UK, Sweden, and EU itself were considered adequately covered in the initial crawl). The seed was created by browsing the main government portals. The third crawl was performed when interest was expressed in including Russian government pages in the crawl. The Russian crawl was created from a single seed: www.gov.ru. The final collection was created by combining the three crawls into a single collection of pages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">EuroGOV Collection Characteristics</head><p>In this section we provide various statistics concerning the collection, including the domains covered, the languages it contains, and its link structure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Domains</head><p>The EuroGOV collection has pages from the 27 primary domains listed in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,455.19,380.44,3.88,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. There is a set of 13 main domains, shown on the left-hand side of Table <ref type="table" coords="3,355.20,392.39,3.88,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, chosen in accordance with current CLEF interests and plans. We have attempted to include a sufficiently large number of pages from these 13 main domain. There are 14 additional domains, shown on the right-hand side of Table <ref type="table" coords="3,505.25,416.30,3.88,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, from which pages are also included in the collection. The coverage of these additional domains is often less complete than the coverage of the main domains. Note that pages in the languages of the additional domains will 'creep in' anyway. For example, the eu.int domain has ample pages in all of the 20 official languages of the European Union.</p><p>The EuroGOV collection features more languages and countries than are being used in the WebCLEF 2005 evaluation tasks. We made a deliberate choice to go for this extended list of countries and domains. This will facilitate future task extensions for cross-lingual web retrieval, or re-use of the collection for other purposes. We also feel that this reflects the natural situation when building a 'European' search engine.</p><p>The EuroGOV collection contains a total of 3,589,501 pages, and can be compressed in 11 gigabytes of data. Table <ref type="table" coords="3,197.76,547.81,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref> gives the page counts for each of the primary domains in the collection. The first column lists the primary domains in the collection. The second through fifth columns list the total number of web pages per domain; the number of MD5 checksums (of the page's content) that occur more than once; the number of pages that have a repeated MD5 checksum (and thus the same content as another page); and the number of unique pages. The final, sixth, column lists the total size of the pages when compressed. The five domains with the largest numbers of pages are: Finland (661,599), Germany (444,794), European Union (374,484), Hungary (330,822), Czech Republic (324,496). Although the number of pages per domain varies between 661,559 (Finland) and 303 (Greece), the number of pages is generally sufficient to support the building of a test collection. Specifically, the smallest set of pages for one of the main domains is 35,168 (Spain). It is unclear, at this point, to what extent the varying numbers of pages per domain is a result of the available web content, different link structure of different governmental sites, or of our particular choices in crawler software or seed points. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">EuroGOV Language Distributions</head><p>What is the distribution of languages in the collection? To answer this question, we applied the TextCat language identification tool <ref type="bibr" coords="4,248.89,554.31,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, which is based on <ref type="bibr" coords="4,342.96,554.31,9.97,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, using a restricted set of 30 language models covering the European languages only. Table <ref type="table" coords="4,319.69,566.26,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_2">3</ref> shows the results for the whole EuroGOV collection, as well as a breakdown of a selection of primary domains. Since pages may have little text or mixed language content, the language identification may show multiple languages. For over two-thirds of the pages, a single candidate language stands out sufficiently clearly. Below, we analyze the language distribution on these pages. When looking at the distribution of languages over the whole collection, shown on the lefthand side of Table <ref type="table" coords="4,173.17,637.99,3.88,8.74" target="#tab_2">3</ref>, we see that the most frequent languages are Finnish (20%), German (18%), Hungarian (13%), English (10%), and Latvian (9%). It is a surprizing outcome that languages of the Finno-Ugrian family dominate the collection! The distribution of languages over the collection closely corresponds with the number of pages per domain (in numbers of pages, Finnish ranked first and Hungarian ranked fourth, see <ref type="bibr" coords="4,269.42,685.82,36.55,8.74">Table 2)</ref>. A look at the distribution of languages for Germany, France, and the UK, shown in the center of Table <ref type="table" coords="4,362.79,697.77,3.88,8.74" target="#tab_2">3</ref>, confirms this strong correlation between country and official language: In the German domain, 98% of the pages is in German. In the French domain, 94% of the pages are in French, and in the UK domain, 99% of the pages are in English. In countries with more than one official language, such as Finland (with Finnish and Swedish) or Belgium (with Dutch, French, and German), we see more language diversity within the corresponding domains. The language distribution for the Finnish and Belgian domains is also shown in the center of Table <ref type="table" coords="5,215.69,513.06,3.88,8.74" target="#tab_2">3</ref>. Since the languages and domains seem to be closely tied together, the distribution of the mixed language domain of the European Union, shown on the right-hand side of Table <ref type="table" coords="5,146.40,536.97,3.88,8.74" target="#tab_2">3</ref>, is of great interest. Here, we see that English is the most used language, accounting for 33% of the pages, followed by French (18%) and German (9%).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Link Structure</head><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="5,117.75,595.20,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_3">4</ref> lists a number of salient features of the EuroGOV link structure. The second and third columns give the counts of the number of links and the number of realized links (ones whose targets are in EuroGOV; columns 4 and 5 provide the average number of links per page and the average number of realized links per page. The last row but one provides averages over all top level domains, and the last row provides the total number of links in the collection.</p><p>The largest numbers of links can be found in the domains with the largest numbers of pages; just under half of the links are realized in the collection. The average number of links per page varies considerably between domains, and the average realized number of links is just over half of the average number of links, although the relative gap between the two numbers varies quite a lot between domains, (e.g., for it the average realized fan-out is 84% of all links per page, while it is only 16% for ru). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Discussion</head><p>In this section we discuss a few points about EuroGOV availability, limitations, and future.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">EuroGOV Limitations</head><p>EuroGOV was thought of as an experimental collection for evaluating cross-lingual web retrieval. As such, the collection serves its purpose well. However, EuroGOV has several limitations which should be taken into account when working with the current collection and planning for possible future extensions of the collection.</p><p>• Completeness: Quite some effort was put into collecting lists of governmental sites to crawl. This is, however, not a complete list.</p><p>• Incomplete description of the link structure: A full link analysis of the EuroGOV collection has not been performed yet. This is not an inherent limitation of the document collection. However, this sort of analysis is important for evaluating whether the collection is a good representative of a realistic web.</p><p>• Empty pages: The collection contains over 70,000 empty documents. It is not clear why this error ocurred, but it should be avoided in future versions of the collection.</p><p>• Rich document types: In the EuroGOV collection, document types such as PDF and DOC files appear in the collection in the same format as they were crawled, i.e., their text is not extracted. Furthermore, large documents are truncated to avoid the collection growing too big. A truncated PDF or DOC file does not go down well with several off-the-shelf document parsers. From a web document collection perspective, this is a realistic and interesting scenario. From the perspective of a cross-lingual retrieval collection this scenario might, however, be less desirable since participants might spend too much time on these issues rather than focusing on the multi-lingual aspects of the task.</p><p>Despite its limitations EuroGOV is very suitable for the initial exploration of cross-lingual web search.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">EuroGOV II</head><p>As of this moment there are no concrete plans to build an updated version of the collection. There are many interesting open questions in cross-lingual web retrieval evaluation that can be formulated and answered using the current EuroGOV collection. Off the record, the aim is to have a fresh collection ready for WebCLEF 2007 or 2008, assuming that there is interest to continue the task. As well as being a fresh crawl, the new collection should address the limitations listed above:</p><p>• Improved completeness: The collection builders should try to compile a more complete list of the governmental sites of the European countries. This should ideally be performed in cooperation with fluent speakers of the languages involved.</p><p>• Rich document types: Given that the main purpose of the collection is to form a document set for cross-lingual web retrieval, it should give as realistic as possible view of web data, while at the same time trying to make it relatively easy to use by cross-lingual retrieval researchers.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,90.00,119.49,423.01,291.88"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>List of top-level domains covered in the EuroGOV collection. (Left): Domains which which were considered more important, based on previous/current CLEF interests. (Right): Other domains contained in the collection.</figDesc><table coords="2,187.03,165.12,228.95,188.74"><row><cell cols="2">Main domains</cell><cell cols="2">Additional domains</cell></row><row><cell>Domain</cell><cell>Country</cell><cell>Domain</cell><cell>Country</cell></row><row><cell>.cz</cell><cell>Czech Republic</cell><cell>.at</cell><cell>Austria</cell></row><row><cell>.de</cell><cell>Germany</cell><cell>.be</cell><cell>Belgium</cell></row><row><cell>.es</cell><cell>Spain</cell><cell>.cy</cell><cell>Cyprus</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">.eu.int European Union .dk</cell><cell>Denmark</cell></row><row><cell>.fi</cell><cell>Finland</cell><cell>.ee</cell><cell>Estonia</cell></row><row><cell>.fr</cell><cell>France</cell><cell>.gr</cell><cell>Greece</cell></row><row><cell>.hu</cell><cell>Hungary</cell><cell>.ie</cell><cell>Ireland</cell></row><row><cell>.it</cell><cell>Italy</cell><cell>.lt</cell><cell>Lithuania</cell></row><row><cell>.nl</cell><cell cols="2">The Netherlands .lu</cell><cell>Luxemburg</cell></row><row><cell>.pt</cell><cell>Portugal</cell><cell>.lv</cell><cell>Latvia</cell></row><row><cell>.ru</cell><cell>Russia</cell><cell>.mt</cell><cell>Malta</cell></row><row><cell>.se</cell><cell>Sweden</cell><cell>.pl</cell><cell>Poland</cell></row><row><cell>.uk</cell><cell cols="2">United Kingdom .si</cell><cell>Slovenia</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>.sk</cell><cell>Slovakia</cell></row></table><note coords="2,90.00,378.72,423.00,8.74;2,90.00,390.67,423.01,9.30;2,90.00,402.63,176.20,8.74"><p><p><p>where collection building is less restricted by intellectual property rights. The resulting collection, which we think of as a European counterpart of the .GOV collection</p><ref type="bibr" coords="2,388.14,390.67,9.97,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref></p>, is called EuroGOV and has been made available in January 2005</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,137.67,118.94,327.67,379.89"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Statistics of the EuroGOV collection over primary domains.</figDesc><table coords="4,137.67,142.59,327.67,356.23"><row><cell>Domain</cell><cell></cell><cell>Pages</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Size</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Total</cell><cell cols="2">Duplicated Duplicates</cell><cell>Unique</cell><cell>(compressed)</cell></row><row><cell>.at</cell><cell>10,065</cell><cell>457</cell><cell>950</cell><cell>9,115</cell><cell>24M</cell></row><row><cell>.be</cell><cell>69,011</cell><cell>819</cell><cell>2,066</cell><cell>66,945</cell><cell>115M</cell></row><row><cell>.cy</cell><cell>1,972</cell><cell>52</cell><cell>52</cell><cell>1,920</cell><cell>7.9M</cell></row><row><cell>.cz</cell><cell>324,496</cell><cell>10,808</cell><cell>25,915</cell><cell>298,581</cell><cell>519M</cell></row><row><cell>.de</cell><cell>444,794</cell><cell>1,682</cell><cell>4,658</cell><cell>440,136</cell><cell>1.1G</cell></row><row><cell>.dk</cell><cell>2,144</cell><cell>497</cell><cell>519</cell><cell>1,625</cell><cell>5.4M</cell></row><row><cell>.ee</cell><cell>16,768</cell><cell>486</cell><cell>3,960</cell><cell>12,808</cell><cell>44M</cell></row><row><cell>.es</cell><cell>35,168</cell><cell>3,372</cell><cell>9,297</cell><cell>25,871</cell><cell>298M</cell></row><row><cell>.eu.int</cell><cell>374,484</cell><cell>32,838</cell><cell>58,415</cell><cell>316,069</cell><cell>1.9G</cell></row><row><cell>.fi</cell><cell>661,559</cell><cell>5,815</cell><cell>85,289</cell><cell>576,270</cell><cell>1.3G</cell></row><row><cell>.fr</cell><cell>156,450</cell><cell>11,144</cell><cell>21,894</cell><cell>134,556</cell><cell>545M</cell></row><row><cell>.gr</cell><cell>303</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>288</cell><cell>416K</cell></row><row><cell>.hu</cell><cell>330,822</cell><cell>361</cell><cell>1,082</cell><cell>329,740</cell><cell>1.5G</cell></row><row><cell>.ie</cell><cell>12,754</cell><cell>1,431</cell><cell>1,982</cell><cell>10,772</cell><cell>32M</cell></row><row><cell>.it</cell><cell>89,836</cell><cell>10,056</cell><cell>17,011</cell><cell>72,825</cell><cell>324M</cell></row><row><cell>.lt</cell><cell>10,765</cell><cell>751</cell><cell>1,131</cell><cell>9,634</cell><cell>8.8M</cell></row><row><cell>.lu</cell><cell>8,521</cell><cell>52</cell><cell>837</cell><cell>7,684</cell><cell>33M</cell></row><row><cell>.lv</cell><cell>317,404</cell><cell>10,357</cell><cell>25,711</cell><cell>291,693</cell><cell>675M</cell></row><row><cell>.mt</cell><cell>13,991</cell><cell>1,300</cell><cell>1,372</cell><cell>12,619</cell><cell>57M</cell></row><row><cell>.nl</cell><cell>149,949</cell><cell>6,097</cell><cell>18,911</cell><cell>131,038</cell><cell>434M</cell></row><row><cell>.pl</cell><cell>66,885</cell><cell>3,746</cell><cell>4,889</cell><cell>61,996</cell><cell>330M</cell></row><row><cell>.pt</cell><cell>147,445</cell><cell>2,454</cell><cell>8,744</cell><cell>138,701</cell><cell>753M</cell></row><row><cell>.ru</cell><cell>104,659</cell><cell>10,676</cell><cell>20,049</cell><cell>84,610</cell><cell>479M</cell></row><row><cell>.se</cell><cell>102,457</cell><cell>2,506</cell><cell>15,068</cell><cell>87,389</cell><cell>155M</cell></row><row><cell>.si</cell><cell>12,434</cell><cell>73</cell><cell>224</cell><cell>12,210</cell><cell>27M</cell></row><row><cell>.sk</cell><cell>58,020</cell><cell>3,288</cell><cell>3,764</cell><cell>54,256</cell><cell>128M</cell></row><row><cell>.uk</cell><cell>66,345</cell><cell>1,688</cell><cell>2,987</cell><cell>63,358</cell><cell>331M</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell>3,589,501</cell><cell>122,816</cell><cell cols="2">336,792 3,252,709</cell><cell>11G</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,95.98,118.94,413.48,333.12"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Breakdown of the EuroGOV collection over document languages.</figDesc><table coords="5,95.98,151.22,413.48,300.84"><row><cell cols="2">EuroGOV Collection</cell><cell cols="2">Domain .be.</cell><cell cols="2">Domain .eu.int.</cell></row><row><cell>Language</cell><cell>Percent.</cell><cell cols="2">Language Percent.</cell><cell>Language</cell><cell>Percent.</cell></row><row><cell>finnish</cell><cell>20.28%</cell><cell>french</cell><cell>36.78%</cell><cell>english</cell><cell>33.26%</cell></row><row><cell>german</cell><cell>18.20%</cell><cell>dutch</cell><cell>24.32%</cell><cell>french</cell><cell>18.08%</cell></row><row><cell>hungarian</cell><cell>12.58%</cell><cell>german</cell><cell>21.61%</cell><cell>german</cell><cell>9.08%</cell></row><row><cell>english</cell><cell>10.16%</cell><cell>english</cell><cell>16.74%</cell><cell>finnish</cell><cell>6.24%</cell></row><row><cell>latvian</cell><cell>8.80%</cell><cell cols="2">Domain .de.</cell><cell>spanish</cell><cell>5.75%</cell></row><row><cell>french</cell><cell>6.98%</cell><cell cols="2">Language Percent.</cell><cell>dutch</cell><cell>5.29%</cell></row><row><cell>swedish</cell><cell>5.32%</cell><cell>german</cell><cell>97.70%</cell><cell>danish</cell><cell>5.13%</cell></row><row><cell>portuguese</cell><cell>3.93%</cell><cell>english</cell><cell>1.37%</cell><cell>portuguese</cell><cell>4.47%</cell></row><row><cell>dutch</cell><cell>3.91%</cell><cell>french</cell><cell>0.74%</cell><cell>swedish</cell><cell>3.26%</cell></row><row><cell>polish</cell><cell>2.14%</cell><cell cols="2">Domain .fi.</cell><cell>greek-iso8859-7</cell><cell>2.92%</cell></row><row><cell>italian</cell><cell>1.70%</cell><cell cols="2">Language Percent.</cell><cell>italian</cell><cell>2.64%</cell></row><row><cell>spanish</cell><cell>1.39%</cell><cell>finnish</cell><cell>81.15%</cell><cell>latvian</cell><cell>1.13%</cell></row><row><cell>czech-iso8859 2</cell><cell>1.13%</cell><cell>swedish</cell><cell>11.52%</cell><cell>polish</cell><cell>1.05%</cell></row><row><cell>slovak-windows1250</cell><cell>0.89%</cell><cell>english</cell><cell>7.26%</cell><cell>estonian</cell><cell>0.60%</cell></row><row><cell>russian-windows1251 danish</cell><cell>0.60% 0.49%</cell><cell cols="2">Domain .fr. Language Percent.</cell><cell>lithuanian hungarian</cell><cell>0.51% 0.40%</cell></row><row><cell>estonian russian-koi8 r slovak-ascii greek-iso8859-7 lithuanian irish welsh</cell><cell>0.39% 0.30% 0.27% 0.27% 0.19% 0.03% 0.01%</cell><cell cols="2">french german english spanish Domain .uk. 94.25% 2.49% 2.24% 0.81% Language Percent. english 99.05%</cell><cell>czech-iso8859 2 slovak-windows1250 romanian slovak-ascii russian-koi8 r icelandic russian-windows1251</cell><cell>0.05% 0.04% 0.03% 0.02% 0.02% 0.01% 0.01%</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="6,171.99,118.94,259.04,379.89"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Salient properties of the EuroGOV link structure.</figDesc><table coords="6,171.99,130.64,259.04,368.19"><row><cell>Domain</cell><cell cols="2">Number of links</cell><cell cols="2">Avg # links/page</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>True</cell><cell>Realized</cell><cell>True</cell><cell>Realized</cell></row><row><cell>at</cell><cell>438,591</cell><cell>367,590</cell><cell>43.5759</cell><cell>36.5216</cell></row><row><cell>be</cell><cell>729,597</cell><cell>340,415</cell><cell>10.5703</cell><cell>4.93191</cell></row><row><cell>cy</cell><cell>42,407</cell><cell>33,231</cell><cell>21.5046</cell><cell>16.8514</cell></row><row><cell>cz</cell><cell>10,602,034</cell><cell>6,286,711</cell><cell>32.6723</cell><cell>19.3738</cell></row><row><cell>de</cell><cell>15,890,499</cell><cell>2,881,943</cell><cell>35.7179</cell><cell>6.47789</cell></row><row><cell>dk</cell><cell>33,572</cell><cell>26,158</cell><cell>15.6586</cell><cell>12.2006</cell></row><row><cell>ee</cell><cell>291,709</cell><cell>180,085</cell><cell>17.3968</cell><cell>10.7398</cell></row><row><cell>es</cell><cell>318,696</cell><cell>218,448</cell><cell>9.0621</cell><cell>6.21156</cell></row><row><cell>eu.int</cell><cell>11,754,603</cell><cell>7,402,189</cell><cell>31.3886</cell><cell>19.7663</cell></row><row><cell>fi</cell><cell>17,505,000</cell><cell>3,881,257</cell><cell>26.4602</cell><cell>5.86683</cell></row><row><cell>fr</cell><cell>6,101,468</cell><cell>5,080,196</cell><cell>38.9990</cell><cell>32.4713</cell></row><row><cell>gr</cell><cell>7,973</cell><cell>6,007</cell><cell>26.3135</cell><cell>19.8251</cell></row><row><cell>hu</cell><cell>14,412,108</cell><cell>5,345,513</cell><cell>43.5645</cell><cell>16.1583</cell></row><row><cell>ie</cell><cell>397,159</cell><cell>279,833</cell><cell>31.1400</cell><cell>21.9408</cell></row><row><cell>it</cell><cell>2,435,376</cell><cell>2,048,472</cell><cell>27.1091</cell><cell>22.8024</cell></row><row><cell>lt</cell><cell>161,601</cell><cell>87,511</cell><cell>15.0117</cell><cell>8.12922</cell></row><row><cell>lu</cell><cell>186,984</cell><cell>146,270</cell><cell>21.9439</cell><cell>17.1658</cell></row><row><cell>lv</cell><cell>9,325,789</cell><cell>5,547,302</cell><cell>29.3807</cell><cell>17.4767</cell></row><row><cell>mt</cell><cell>273,873</cell><cell>215,417</cell><cell>19.5749</cell><cell>15.3968</cell></row><row><cell>nl</cell><cell>7,087,202</cell><cell>3,636,065</cell><cell>47.2635</cell><cell>24.2484</cell></row><row><cell>pl</cell><cell>1,632,655</cell><cell>1,187,235</cell><cell>24.4092</cell><cell>17.7499</cell></row><row><cell>pt</cell><cell>9,046,688</cell><cell>5,613,440</cell><cell>61.3564</cell><cell>38.0714</cell></row><row><cell>ru</cell><cell>4,880,064</cell><cell>783,246</cell><cell>46.6282</cell><cell>7.48379</cell></row><row><cell>se</cell><cell>4,766,234</cell><cell>1,280,677</cell><cell>46.5148</cell><cell>12.4984</cell></row><row><cell>si</cell><cell>213,239</cell><cell>152,137</cell><cell>17.1497</cell><cell>12.2356</cell></row><row><cell>sk</cell><cell>1,167,119</cell><cell>892,326</cell><cell>20.1155</cell><cell>15.3794</cell></row><row><cell>uk</cell><cell>1,847,259</cell><cell>1,286,001</cell><cell>27.8407</cell><cell>19.3818</cell></row><row><cell>Avg</cell><cell>4,501,833</cell><cell>2,044,655</cell><cell>29.1971</cell><cell>16.9391</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell cols="2">121,549,499 55,205,675</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="4,105.24,740.61,230.51,7.21"><p>URL: http://europa.eu.int/abc/governments/index_en.htm</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="5">Acknowledgments</head><p>Thanks to <rs type="person">Craig Macdonald</rs> for advise at various stages during the creation of EuroGOV, to the Melange group for sharing their normalized links with us, and to <rs type="person">Krisztian Balog</rs> for help with exploring EuroGOV's link structure.</p><p>The building of EuroGOV was supported by the <rs type="funder">Netherlands Organization for Scientific Research (NWO)</rs> under project numbers <rs type="grantNumber">017.001.190</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">220-80-001</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">264-70-050</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">354-20-005</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">612-13-001</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">612.000.106</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">612.000.207</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">612.066.302</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">612.069.006</rs>, and <rs type="grantNumber">640.001.501</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_UsZs6R9">
					<idno type="grant-number">017.001.190</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_q6B4w59">
					<idno type="grant-number">220-80-001</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_YTcDcwH">
					<idno type="grant-number">264-70-050</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_9JKuZqE">
					<idno type="grant-number">354-20-005</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_E2n97Kh">
					<idno type="grant-number">612-13-001</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_H6amBQk">
					<idno type="grant-number">612.000.106</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_XtUx7ny">
					<idno type="grant-number">612.000.207</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_4EjxSvJ">
					<idno type="grant-number">612.066.302</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_bEVvUqU">
					<idno type="grant-number">612.069.006</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_h4GdsbB">
					<idno type="grant-number">640.001.501</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,602.58,407.50,8.74;7,105.50,614.53,399.47,8.74" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,257.22,602.58,144.57,8.74">N-gram-based text categorization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Cavnar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Trenkle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,423.66,602.58,89.34,8.74;7,105.50,614.53,301.17,8.74">Proceedings of Third Annual Symposium on Document Analysis and Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>Third Annual Symposium on Document Analysis and Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="175" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,634.46,407.50,9.02;7,105.50,647.13,23.69,8.30" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Gov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://es.csiro.au/TRECWeb/govinfo.html" />
		<title level="m" coord="7,141.47,634.46,85.72,8.74">TREC Web Corpus</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>GOV</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,666.34,407.50,9.02;7,105.50,679.01,44.61,8.30" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,151.44,666.34,122.61,8.74">Language identification tool</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Textcat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://odur.let.rug.nl/~vannoord/TextCat/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,105.50,698.22,407.50,9.02" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,156.97,698.22,112.59,8.74">Cross-lingual web retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Webclef</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ilps.science.uva.nl/webclef/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
