<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,146.52,117.00,322.21,12.62;1,246.48,134.88,122.27,12.62">A Visual Search of Multimedia Documents in ImageCLEF 2014</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,135.96,172.60,76.74,8.74"><forename type="first">Sana</forename><surname>Fakhfakh</surname></persName>
							<email>sanafakhfakh@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratoire Miracl ISIMS Pole Technologique de Sfax BP 242</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Sakiet Ezzit Sfax. TUNISIE</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>-3021</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,222.61,172.60,86.58,8.74"><forename type="first">Belhassen</forename><surname>Akrout</surname></persName>
							<email>bakrout@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratoire Miracl ISIMS Pole Technologique de Sfax BP 242</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Sakiet Ezzit Sfax. TUNISIE</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>-3021</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,319.34,172.60,67.99,8.74"><forename type="first">Mohamed</forename><surname>Tmar</surname></persName>
							<email>mohamed.tmar@isimsf.rnu.tn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratoire Miracl ISIMS Pole Technologique de Sfax BP 242</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Sakiet Ezzit Sfax. TUNISIE</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>-3021</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,415.33,172.60,63.96,8.74"><forename type="first">Walid</forename><surname>Mahdi</surname></persName>
							<email>walid.mahdi@isimsf.rnu.tn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratoire Miracl ISIMS Pole Technologique de Sfax BP 242</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Sakiet Ezzit Sfax. TUNISIE</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>-3021</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,146.52,117.00,322.21,12.62;1,246.48,134.88,122.27,12.62">A Visual Search of Multimedia Documents in ImageCLEF 2014</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">5D70BB0A090F411D411A59F61CCD6BD6</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:37+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Future extraction</term>
					<term>Plant identification</term>
					<term>Hamming distance</term>
					<term>Signature extraction</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The Image search by content is an area that is based on a set of low-level features such as histograms, textures, the distribution of colors, shapes an brightness. The structure element is a shortcut of the image may vary depending on the designer of the XML document and which may change according to application needs. The visual appearance of the image is a permanent factor that undergoes no change. Therefore, we present in this paper a new method of search by content based on Harris detector, Haar wavelet and Color histogram for the step of feature extraction to extract a binary signature for all multimedia documents.Finally We estimate the similarities between codes and search relevant images with Hamming distance.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The research of the image content was the subject of numerous studies in recent years. Techniques developed aim to extract and represent effectively the content of images. The image indexing can be done either on the basis of low-level features or those of semantics. The need for methods of indexing and retrieval directly based on the content of the image is no longer evident. The first prototype system has been proposed in 1970 and this system has attracted the attention of many researchers. Some systems become commercial systems such as QBIC (Query By Image Content) IBM <ref type="bibr" coords="1,157.92,597.40,10.56,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref> and CIRES <ref type="bibr" coords="1,224.89,597.40,9.99,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. The Frip (Finding Regions in the Pictures) system <ref type="bibr" coords="1,365.74,609.28,10.56,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref> KoB05 proposes to research by regions of interest to drawn by the user <ref type="bibr" coords="1,345.35,621.28,10.56,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref> . RETIN system (REcherche and Hunt Interactive) <ref type="bibr" coords="1,232.69,633.16,10.56,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref> developed at the University of Cergy-Pontoise France, selects a random set of pixels in each image to extract their color values. The texture of these pixels is obtained by applying the method of Gabor filters <ref type="bibr" coords="1,467.28,657.16,9.99,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref>.</p><p>These values are grouped and classified using a neural network. The comparison between the images is done by calculating the similarity between their feature vectors <ref type="bibr" coords="2,253.33,143.92,9.99,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. Some studies have proposed to change their field of research, for example changing the color feature space <ref type="bibr" coords="2,385.21,155.92,10.56,8.74" target="#b7">[8]</ref> . Sometimes the user wants to query such as "Find all the images of the database with certain regions similar to those of the query image" <ref type="bibr" coords="2,395.50,179.80,9.99,8.74" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. Some work has been done, or the system segments an image or a spatial structure is used. In the first case, having a segmented image, the user selects some regions that we want from the segmented image. In the second case, the spatial structure is used. A structure is often used quadtree <ref type="bibr" coords="2,287.13,227.56,9.99,8.74" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. This structure is used to store the visual characteristics of different image regions and filter images by increasing progressively as the level of detail. Some work has proceeded to minimize the search space using the technique of calculating the nearest neighbors to group similar data in classes <ref type="bibr" coords="2,420.11,275.44,14.69,8.74" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. Thus the search for an image is done by searching a class. The disadvantage of these systems is that the user does not always have an image that expresses real need, which makes use of such a system difficult. One solution to this problem is the technique of vectorization, which allows to find relevant images to a query and which are not returned by the initial system. Its sequence requires the choice of a set of said reference material. The choice of these references is still problematic for the construction of the vector space. In this context, it is necessary to select a heterogeneous set of documents. The number of references is also problematic. Indeed, the number of documents is the new dimension of vector space. If we choose a small set of documents, we may not be able to properly represent all documents. These references are randomly selected by <ref type="bibr" coords="2,185.76,418.84,15.60,8.74" target="#b10">[11]</ref> , or the first results of an initial search or through the selection of the centers of gravity of homogeneous grouping images <ref type="bibr" coords="2,388.57,430.84,14.69,8.74" target="#b11">[12]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Proposed approach</head><p>In this section, we propose a description of the proposed visual system. In fact, the search for multimedia documents requires a critical step in the abstract offline indexing. This step requires the feature extraction from the image to give a general description of documents. Following this course indexing we can go in search of the visual image based on the descriptors already studied. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,475.55,547.00,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_0">1</ref> describes the steps mentioned by an explanatory diagram.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Feature extraction from the image</head><p>The objective of extracting descriptors is the set up the search method contained in the images. One example is the search for a database containing images of plants mentioned. Images are indexed from the local descriptors such as Harris detector <ref type="bibr" coords="2,173.65,657.16,15.60,8.74" target="#b12">[13]</ref> to calculate point of interest, the Haar wavelet <ref type="bibr" coords="2,399.86,657.16,15.60,8.74" target="#b13">[14]</ref> to analyze the In fact, Harris and Stephens <ref type="bibr" coords="3,258.23,509.44,15.60,8.74" target="#b12">[13]</ref> defined a sensor that recognizes the first derivatives on a window signal representing an image and provide better results in two important criteria <ref type="bibr" coords="3,216.23,533.32,15.60,8.74" target="#b14">[15]</ref> . The first criterion is based on their robustness with respect to rotation and scale changes of the camera and points of view. The second is summed up in his power with respect to variations of illumination.</p><p>Harris detector was applicable at the beginning only the grayscale image. Montesinos <ref type="bibr" coords="3,167.76,581.08,15.60,8.74" target="#b14">[15]</ref> generalized Harris detector for color images. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,416.05,581.08,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_1">2</ref> shows an example of detection of interest points in an image. </p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="4,253.80,444.56,226.82,31.68">h(j, k; x) = 2 j/2 2H(2 j x -k)<label>(1)</label></formula><p>With H(x) = 1 f or x in ]0, 1/2[, H(x) = -1 f or x in ]1/2, 1[ and H(x) = 0 ailleurs form a complete orthogonal set for space L 2 (R). The Haar wavelet is simple to study and implement. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,304.30,503.80,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_2">3</ref> shows the result of decomposition of an image texture to analyze and extract the diagonal details, the vertical details, the horizontal details and finally the description.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Image analysis by color histogram</head><p>For a monochrome image, the histogram is defined as a discrete function that maps each intensity value the number of pixels taking this value. The determination of the histogram is made by counting the number of intensity for each pixel of the image. The quantification, which includes several intensity values in one class can better visualize the distribution of image intensities. Our job is to build a histogram of a color image in the RGB space, the red, green and blue. Each component is quantized into eight intervals. In each interval of each Red, green and blue component; we calculate the number of pixels normal- </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Principal component analysis and signature extraction</head><p>The principal component analysis ( P CA), developed in France in the 1960s by JP.Benzcri is an exploratory statistical method used to describe a wide array of data type individuals / variables. When individuals are described with 5 large numbers of variables, no simple graphical representation allows to visualize the point cloud formed by the data.</p><p>The PCA provides a representation in a space of reduced size, thereby allowing to highlight any structures in the data. For this, we look for subspaces where the projection of the cloud deforms the least possible initial cloud.</p><p>Applying the P CA to the descriptors, previously computed, A signal f (x), that includes all the characteristic values, is obtained. This signal is then subjected to an automatic thresholding (equation 2 ) to the transformed into a binary signature C(x) (equation 3).</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="5,275.64,597.56,204.99,29.03">M f = m n=1 f (x)<label>(2)</label></formula><p>In this way each image is represented by a binary code which is stored in a database for later use in the research phase. </p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="6,232.56,331.80,248.06,21.02">f (x) = C(x) = 1 if f (x) &gt;= M f C(x) = 1 if f (x) &lt; M f<label>(3)</label></formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Estimate similarities between codes and search relevant images</head><p>Once the signatures are extracted, we must think of a technique that quantifies the distance between them, in order to identify similar images. The bit-wise comparison of each two image codes A and B each detail is given by the normalization of the Hamming distance (HD) <ref type="bibr" coords="6,325.08,445.84,15.60,8.74" target="#b15">[16]</ref> defined as following:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="6,259.44,471.76,221.18,23.09">HD = 1 N A(k) ⊗ B(k)<label>(4)</label></formula><p>With ⊗ is the boolean operator ( XOR) described by the equation 5 follows</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="6,274.56,536.64,206.06,16.65">a ⊗ b = ab + ab<label>(5)</label></formula><p>The probability that two bits of arbitrary code images are equal or not, worth P = 0.5. When the majority of codes A(j) and B(j) are equal , is therefore in the case where the two codes compared are equivalent. In the opposite case, the two codes are different. Generally, when HD tends to zero it is called relevant images.</p><p>Our group submitted just one run in your rst participation in the ImageCLEF Plant task 2014. In this paper we described a plant species retrieval model based on a extraction of unique signature for each image in collection. This signature is composed by Haar and Harris features.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments and Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Evaluation Metric</head><p>The metric evaluation S was related to the rank of the correct species in the list of retrieved species as follows <ref type="bibr" coords="7,265.69,175.84,14.69,8.74" target="#b16">[17]</ref>:</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="7,233.88,197.00,246.74,29.99">S = 1 U U u=1 1 P u Pu p=1 1 N u,p Nu,p n=1 S u,p,n<label>(6)</label></formula><p>Where U :is the number of users. P u : number of individual plants observed by the u th user. N u,p : number of pictures taken from the p th plant observed by the u th user. S u,p,n : score between 1 and 0 equals to the inverse of the rank of the correct species (for the n th picture taken from the p th plant observed by the u th user).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">The Results</head><p>IVprocessing team has submitted a single automatic run to the multi-image plant observation queries. In this run, we extracted visual descriptors from images, used texture, color and interest points model for generating the feature vectors.</p><p>The result is showed in Table <ref type="table" coords="7,266.04,385.84,3.90,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. At a closer look, the score values of our results are rather low. We cannot fully explain the failure with these plant image as there were no indications for the weak performance during the training stage. One reasonable interpretation of the results is that the conducted learning runs led to an over-fitting. A total of 10 participating groups submitted 27 runs focusing on plant observations. 6 teams submitted 14 complementary runs on images in ImageCLEF 2014. The following graphic shows the scores obtained on the main task on multi-image plant observation queries. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>We presented in this paper a research method by which the content is based on extracting a signature for a given image. This signature is composed by a set of descriptors, such as the analysis of the histogram of the color image, the extraction of the interest points and Haar wavelet. This signature undergoes a step dimensionality reduction by PCA method. An experimental study on ImageCLEF 2014 showed the effectiveness of our descriptors.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,239.52,374.01,136.35,7.89"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Diagram of indexing steps</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,146.52,301.65,322.18,7.89;4,263.79,125.89,87.32,144.12"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. Figure showing the detection of points of interest by the Harris detector</figDesc><graphic coords="4,263.79,125.89,87.32,144.12" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="5,134.76,333.81,345.91,7.89;5,134.76,344.76,232.35,7.86"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3. Decomposition of the image using the Haar wavelet, (a) image description, (b) horizontal details, (c) vertical details, (d) diagonal details</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="6,176.88,280.65,261.38,7.89;6,191.39,160.39,103.12,69.02"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4. An example of color histogram applied to an RGB image</figDesc><graphic coords="6,191.39,160.39,103.12,69.02" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4" coords="8,250.20,309.21,114.89,7.89;8,341.89,116.79,111.12,177.92"><head>Fig. 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Fig. 5. Scores for Plant task</figDesc><graphic coords="8,341.89,116.79,111.12,177.92" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="7,209.16,465.21,194.20,39.93"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Results for the run in plant collection</figDesc><table coords="7,209.16,485.97,193.86,19.17"><row><cell>Run name</cell><cell cols="2">Retrieval type Score</cell></row><row><cell>IV Processing Run 1</cell><cell>Visual</cell><cell>0,043</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.88,491.28,337.74,7.86;8,151.56,502.20,329.00,7.86;8,151.56,513.12,328.94,7.86;8,151.56,524.16,329.04,7.86;8,151.56,535.08,55.60,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,261.81,513.12,214.41,7.86">Query by image and video content: The qbic system</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Myron</forename><surname>Flickner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Harpreet</forename><surname>Sawhney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Wayne</forename><surname>Niblack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Ashley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Qian</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Byron</forename><surname>Dom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Monika</forename><surname>Gorkani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jim</forename><surname>Hafner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Denis</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Dragutin</forename><surname>Petkovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Steele</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Yanker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995-09">September 1995</date>
			<publisher>IEEE Computer Society Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="32" />
			<pubPlace>Los Alamitos, CA, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.88,546.60,337.62,7.86;8,151.56,557.52,328.86,7.86;8,151.56,568.56,328.83,7.86;8,151.56,579.48,84.25,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,361.21,546.60,119.29,7.86;8,151.56,557.52,328.86,7.86;8,151.56,568.56,74.69,7.86">Content-based image retrieval approach for biometric security using colour, texture and shape features controlled by fuzzy heuristics</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Kashif</forename><surname>Iqbal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Odetayo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Anne</forename><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-07">July 2012</date>
			<publisher>Academic Press, Inc</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1258" to="1277" />
			<pubPlace>Orlando, FL, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.88,591.00,337.73,7.86;8,151.56,601.92,328.95,7.86;8,151.56,612.84,83.83,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,296.28,591.00,184.34,7.86;8,151.56,601.92,276.54,7.86">Frip: a region-based image retrieval tool using automatic image segmentation and stepwise boolean and matching</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Byoungchul</forename><surname>Ko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hyeran</forename><surname>Byun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="113" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.88,624.36,337.56,7.86;8,151.56,635.10,226.88,8.26" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,363.22,624.36,117.22,7.86;8,151.56,635.40,97.33,7.86">Caractérisation d&apos;une région d&apos;intérêt dans les images</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Yves</forename><surname>Caron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Pascal</forename><surname>Makris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nicole</forename><surname>Vincent</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,268.92,635.10,16.86,8.26">EGC</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="462" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,142.88,646.80,337.65,7.86;8,151.56,657.84,231.13,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="8,445.79,646.80,34.74,7.86;8,151.56,657.84,201.87,7.86">Retin: A content-based image indexing and retrieval system</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Fournier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Cord</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Philipp-Foliguet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Cergy Pontoise Cedex</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,142.88,120.72,337.60,7.86;9,151.56,131.34,328.98,8.26;9,151.56,142.26,328.85,8.26;9,151.56,153.60,328.90,7.86;9,151.56,164.52,41.91,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,332.53,120.72,147.95,7.86;9,151.56,131.64,248.99,7.86">Les filtres de Hermite et de Gabor donnent-ils des modles quivalents du systme visuel humain?</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Carlos</forename><surname>Rivero-Moreno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Stphane</forename><surname>Bres</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,420.24,131.34,60.30,8.26;9,151.56,142.26,277.55,8.26">ORASIS 2003, Journes francophones des jeunes chercheurs en vision par ordinateur</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-05">May 2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="423" to="432" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Article apparu en confrence nationale avec actes de congrs et comit de lecture</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,142.88,175.14,337.76,8.26;9,151.56,186.18,161.18,8.26" xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,228.96,175.14,251.68,8.26;9,151.56,186.18,82.87,8.26">Indexation et recherche d&apos;images par fusion d&apos;informations textuelles et visuelles</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sabrina</forename><surname>Tollari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">PhD thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,142.88,197.40,337.75,7.86;9,151.56,208.32,251.44,7.86" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,312.58,197.40,168.05,7.86;9,151.56,208.32,108.32,7.86">Comparison and optimization of methods of color image quantization</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jean</forename><surname>Pierre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Braquelaire</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Luc</forename><surname>Brun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1048" to="1051" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,142.88,219.36,337.61,7.86;9,151.56,230.28,328.82,7.86;9,151.56,240.90,137.35,8.26" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,416.40,219.36,64.09,7.86;9,151.56,230.28,324.90,7.86">Rétro-ingénierie des bases de données relationnelles : approche basée sur l&apos;analyse de formulaires</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mimoun</forename><surname>Malki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Madjid</forename><surname>Ayache</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mustapha</forename><surname>Kamal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Rahmouni</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,163.08,240.90,42.91,8.26">INFORSID</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,142.55,252.24,337.86,7.86;9,151.56,263.16,329.16,7.86;9,151.56,274.08,168.53,7.86" xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,398.14,252.24,82.26,7.86;9,151.56,263.16,329.16,7.86;9,151.56,274.08,48.42,7.86">Recherche par similarités dans les bases de données multidimensionnelles: panorama des techniques d&apos;indexation</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sid-Ahmed</forename><surname>Berrani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Laurent</forename><surname>Amsaleg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Gros</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="44" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,142.55,285.00,337.98,7.86;9,151.56,295.74,298.28,8.26" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,392.76,285.00,87.77,7.86;9,151.56,296.04,158.22,7.86">Vectorisation des processus d&apos;appariement document-requête</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Vincent</forename><surname>Claveau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Romain</forename><surname>Tavenard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Laurent</forename><surname>Amsaleg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,329.64,295.74,27.83,8.26">CORIA</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="324" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,142.55,306.96,337.82,7.86;9,151.56,317.58,195.68,8.26" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,218.29,306.96,262.08,7.86;9,151.56,317.88,55.68,7.86">Vectorisation du modèle d&apos;appariement pour la recherche d&apos;images par le contenu</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hanen</forename><surname>Karamti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,227.04,317.58,27.83,8.26">CORIA</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="335" to="340" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,142.55,328.62,337.86,8.26;9,151.56,339.54,229.15,8.26" xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,288.71,328.92,150.67,7.86">A combined corner and edge detector</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Stephens</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,459.60,328.62,20.81,8.26;9,151.56,339.54,137.75,8.26">Proc. of Fourth Alvey Vision Conference</title>
		<meeting>of Fourth Alvey Vision Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="151" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,142.55,350.76,337.79,7.86;9,151.56,361.80,328.76,7.86;9,151.56,372.72,230.09,7.86" xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,364.08,350.76,116.25,7.86;9,151.56,361.80,212.12,7.86">Haar wavelet based processor scheme for image coding with low circuit complexity</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Javier</forename><surname>Díaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Angel</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Burón</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">José</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Solana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-03">March 2007</date>
			<publisher>Pergamon Press, Inc</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="126" />
			<pubPlace>Tarrytown, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,142.55,383.64,337.86,7.86;9,151.56,394.38,328.81,8.26;9,151.56,405.30,183.08,8.26" xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,323.75,383.64,152.44,7.86">Differential invariants for color images</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Montesinos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Gouet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Deriche</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,164.40,394.38,79.38,8.26;9,278.63,394.38,201.74,8.26;9,151.56,405.30,8.26,8.26">Proceedings. Fourteenth International Conference on</title>
		<meeting>Fourteenth International Conference on</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998-08">1998. Aug 1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="838" to="840" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Pattern Recognition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,142.55,416.52,337.98,7.86;9,151.56,427.26,328.93,8.26;9,151.56,438.18,292.49,8.26" xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,410.74,416.52,69.78,7.86;9,151.56,427.56,167.57,7.86">A new scheme of signature extarction for iris authentication</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Akrout</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Khanfir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kallel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Benamar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Ben Amor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,337.44,427.26,114.49,8.26;9,151.56,438.18,191.13,8.26">SSD &apos;09. 6th International Multi-Conference on</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009-03">2009. March 2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Systems, Signals and Devices</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,142.55,449.40,337.97,7.86;9,151.56,460.44,296.20,7.86" xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,295.94,460.44,127.83,7.86">Lifeclef plant identification task</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Hervé</forename><surname>Goëau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alexis</forename><surname>Joly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Bonnet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jean-François</forename><surname>Molino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Barthélémy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nozha</forename><surname>Boujemaa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
