<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,142.31,165.85,308.69,15.12;1,258.71,187.76,75.89,15.12">Entity List Completion Using Set Expansion Techniques</title>
				<funder ref="#_DYbHsPH">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="2011-02-28">February 28, 2011</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,179.68,220.25,73.57,10.48"><forename type="first">Bhavana</forename><surname>Dalvi</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,262.27,220.25,65.19,10.48"><forename type="first">Jamie</forename><surname>Callan</surname></persName>
							<email>callan@cs.cmu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,336.56,220.25,77.07,10.48"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
							<email>wcohen@cs.cmu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,142.31,165.85,308.69,15.12;1,258.71,187.76,75.89,15.12">Entity List Completion Using Set Expansion Techniques</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2011-02-28">February 28, 2011</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">506813EE857B0FAF111BB41F2792DDEE</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Set expansion refers to expanding a partial set of "seed" objects into a more complete set. In this paper, we focus on relation and list extraction techniques to perform Entity List Completion task through a two stage retrieval process. First stage takes given query entity and target entity examples as seeds and does set expansion. In second stage, only those candidates who have valid URI in Billion Triple dataset are ranked according to type match with given types. First stage of this system focuses on the recall while second stage tries to improve precision of the outputted list. We submitted the results on the Web as well as ClueWeb09 corpus.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Entity List Completion task is a pilot task in TREC entity track, introduced this year to create a corpus for evaluation of semantic search systems. The motivation of this task is to complete a list of entities which have a particular relation with query entity. Also, they have to be located in the Semantic Web. For this year's task is based on Billion Triple Challenge 2009 dataset. Unlike main task in Entity Track where entities are represented by the homepage of the entity in Clueweb dataset, here they are represented using a Uniform Resource Identifier(URI) within the LOD. The task of Entity List Completion is defined as follow. Given a query entity, by its URI, the type of target entity, nature of their relation, as well as few examples of target entities, find remaining entities that are related to query entity, of target type, which are part of LOD.</p><p>In TREC 2009, many successful systems used DBpedia and Freebase ontologies to answer entity track queries. So we tried using the knowledge base developed at CMU by Read The Web group <ref type="bibr" coords="1,328.21,636.24,9.96,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. Read The Web group used coupled semi-supervised learning for doing ontology driven information extraction <ref type="bibr" coords="1,145.21,660.15,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. The knowledge base currently contains 440K beliefs and most of them are popular facts frequently found on the Web. When we tried to answer Entity Finding Task queries with this knowledge base, coverage was low. This might be because the query entities are less popular ones in the Web corpus. We also worked on a corpus of noun-phrase pairs data extracted by shallow parsing the  <ref type="bibr" coords="2,295.40,278.99,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. We found that coverage of queries was still low on this data. This was because these noun-pairs were capturing the occurrences of noun-phrases which occur in sentences separated by context string. The queries in this track are such that most of the answer entities occur on homepage of query entity or some page linked to homepage. Hence any approach which tries to find the query entity and target entity separated by a context will fail.</p><p>In this paper we apply set expansion technique for the Entity List completion task. This technique is based on the assumption that the target entities occur together in structured webpages, and have similar character patterns around them. It then leverages such co-occurring patterns to suggest entities similar to given set of seed entities. To solve the Entity List Completion task, we proposed a two stage approach. First stage uses the list extraction technique called "Set Expansion for Any Language (SEAL)" which takes given query entity and examples of target entities as seeds and generates a list of candidate entities to complete the list. In the second stage, we rank these entities according to type match with given allowed target types. Section 2 describes SEAL system. Section 3 describes our two stage retrieval process. Submitted runs are discussed in Section 4. Section 5 gives conclusion and Future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Set Expansion for Any Language (SEAL)</head><p>Set expansion refers to expanding a partial set of "seed" objects into a more complete set. Table <ref type="table" coords="2,214.75,560.91,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows the examples of SEAL's input/output. e.g. given two names of Reality TV shows, SEAL finds other reality TV shows.</p><p>The SEAL system <ref type="bibr" coords="2,226.06,584.82,10.52,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref> has three components: the Fetcher, the Extractor, and the Ranker. The Fetcher fetches web pages from the World Wide Web. The URLs to crawl are decided based on top results provided by the Search engine, when queried for concatenation of seeds. Given the seed entities and the webpages on which they co-occur, the Extractor learns wrappers(regular expressions surrounding the seed entities) for each page, and then applies those wrappers, to extract more candidate entities that can be part of list of seeds. The last stage of set expansion process, comprises of the Ranker which builds a graph, and then ranks the extracted mentions globally based on the weights computed in the graph walk.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,172.12,704.37,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_0">1</ref> describes the above process pictorially. This system is modular, SEAL has already shown promising results when used in conjunction with Ephyra System for the task of list question answering task (TREC 2006-07) <ref type="bibr" coords="3,124.80,376.42,9.96,8.74" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. Iterative SEAL <ref type="bibr" coords="3,211.79,376.42,10.52,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref> is an extension of the SEAL system which enables us to provide many seeds as input, and system iteratively chooses small number of them at a time and does set expansion. It also enables to feed the high score candidates at the end of iteration 1 to act as seeds for iteration 2, leading to a bootstrapping process.</p><p>SEAL defines a wrapper as a pair of maximally-long left and right context strings (l; r) that bracket at least one occurrence of every seed on a web page. Since longer strings are better, they have defined a ranking algorithm called Wrapper Length which works as follows : score(x) = j extracts x (length(w j )) where w j is the jth wrapper composed of a pair of left and right contextual strings, and the function length returns the sum of the character lengths of those pair of strings in w j . This heuristic is based on the assumption that an item should have a high score if it is extracted by many long wrappers. This simple ranking function worked very well with iterative SEAL <ref type="bibr" coords="3,405.60,555.75,9.96,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. The same algorithm can be extended for extracting binary relations. To do this task we need a third type of context, called the middle context that occurs between the left and right contexts of a wrapper for separating any two items. The same algorithm as before can be applied, except that a seed instance in the algorithm is now a seed instance pair bracketing some middle context (i.e. "s1 &lt;middle-context&gt; s2 ").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Two Stage Retrieval Process</head><p>In this section we describe in detail our two stage retrieval process for the ELC task. In the first stage we use the SEAL system for set expansion. SEAL is capable of handling relation instances. So we first feed {query entity, target entity} Second stage deals with type-checking and ranking. We used the Billion triple index <ref type="bibr" coords="4,179.59,457.93,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. For each entity in the candidate list produced by first stage, we do a lookup in Billion Triple Index. For each query, the index returns multiple URIs. We extracted the type fields in the webpages corresponding to top URIs. ELC task specifies two fields target type dbpedia and target entity. For many queries target type dbpedia indicates more specific type (e.g. Scientist) than target entity (e.g. Person). We first try to match target type dbpedia, if not then target entity. This step assigns type score to candidate URI. A type score of 2 is assigned for target type dbpedia match, 1 for target entity match and 0 for no type match but a valid URI. Candidate entities for which no URI was found are removed from the set. At this stage we have candidate tuples {entity name, URI, type score, SEAL score}. We rank the entities first by type score and then resolve the collisions using SEAL score. These entities are then outputted in the TREC result format.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experiments and Submitted Runs</head><p>SEAL has an interface for querying the Google API to collect the documents in which seeds co-occur. We implemented another interface to query the Clueweb index <ref type="bibr" coords="4,151.06,680.07,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. We presented two runs for the ELC task. Run-1 was using the Google API and Run-2 was using Clueweb API. Since Clueweb is a subset of actual web, SEAL could not answer 2 queries which were answered using Google API.  2 gives the detailed statistics about how many queries were answered in each run and number of URIs that matched the given target type. Table <ref type="table" coords="5,421.27,545.11,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_3">3</ref> describes the number of target entities the system generated per query in each of the runs. Table <ref type="table" coords="5,152.98,569.02,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_4">4</ref> shows the overall performance of both runs using two metrics, Mean Average Precision(MAP) and R-precision. When we manually checked the answers and evaluation done for each query, we found that our method fails to find correct URIs for many result entities. E.g. for query-4 ("Professional sports teams in Philadelphia") our system could find the sports team names : Soul, Phantoms, Phillies, Eagles etc. but it does not return correct URIs. We need more sophisticated URI finding algorithm to fix this problem. In queries like query-17 ("Chefs with a show on the Food Network"), where SEAL relation extraction failed, and we used SEAL list extraction, we got the target entities which were not relevant to the query entity as per the given description.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,172.49,700.53,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_2">3</ref> shows the performance comparison of all the participating runs for this task. Our system did not not perform well when compared to other participants. This evaluation helped us understand two improvements that can be done in our system : (1) Improve relation extraction method by using query description and (2) Devise better method for finding entity URI. We believe that these two changes will improve MAP and R-precision of our system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusions and Future Work</head><p>We developed a two stage retrieval process to answer entity list completion queries. First stage focused on improving recall by doing set expansion on query entity and examples of target entity. Second stage improves precision by checking the type of candidates found in first stage and ranking the results by type score and a SEAL generated score. Our system needs better relation extraction and URI finding methods to perform reasonably well on this task. In future we are want to focus on three aspects of the system : 1) Devise better method of finding the correct URI, given name of a target-entity. 2) Extend SEAL to make use of the relation description given in the query. If our system can learn wrappers taking into account the kind of relation we want to learn then it will definitely improve accuracy of list extraction. 3) Study the relation of entities appearing on homepage of the query entity and how to define/extract such relations.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,212.06,260.91,165.87,8.74;3,146.66,125.80,300.00,120.00"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Flow chart of SEAL System</figDesc><graphic coords="3,146.66,125.80,300.00,120.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="4,195.69,318.51,198.61,8.74;4,198.56,125.80,196.20,177.60"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Flow chart of our two-stage System</figDesc><graphic coords="4,198.56,125.80,196.20,177.60" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="5,166.31,501.33,257.37,8.74;5,211.66,366.22,170.00,120.00"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Performance comparison of all participating runs</figDesc><graphic coords="5,211.66,366.22,170.00,120.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,124.80,127.76,280.75,159.97"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>SEAL input/output examples valid sentences from Clueweb dataset</figDesc><table coords="2,187.76,127.76,217.79,105.18"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Country names Reality TV shows</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>India</cell><cell>Amazing Race</cell></row><row><cell>Input seeds</cell><cell>China</cell><cell>Survivor</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Canada</cell><cell>...</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Japan</cell><cell>Big Brother</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>France</cell><cell>The Mole</cell></row><row><cell>Output</cell><cell>Brazil</cell><cell>The Apprentice</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Australia</cell><cell>Project Runway</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Germany</cell><cell>...</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,444.44,703.98,24.07,8.74"><head>Table Run -</head><label>Run</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="5,166.71,127.76,259.89,68.91"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">1 Run-2</cell></row><row><cell>#Queries answered (Total 14)</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>9</cell></row><row><cell>#Queries answered by relation extraction</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>4</cell></row><row><cell>#Queries answered by list extraction</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>5</cell></row><row><cell>#URIs that matched target type dbpedia</cell><cell>412</cell><cell>406</cell></row><row><cell>#URIs that matched target entity</cell><cell>56</cell><cell>64</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="5,135.61,209.80,322.10,53.77"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Overall statistics about two runs</figDesc><table coords="5,135.61,230.52,322.10,33.05"><row><cell cols="2">Queryid 1 2 3 4 5</cell><cell>6</cell><cell cols="2">7 11 12</cell><cell cols="2">15 16 17 19 20</cell></row><row><cell>Run-1</cell><cell cols="5">4 0 0 6 0 19 81 31 95 100</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1 39 92</cell></row><row><cell>Run-2</cell><cell cols="3">4 0 0 6 0 97 22</cell><cell>0 96</cell><cell>58</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1 94 92</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="5,146.84,276.69,296.31,55.71"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Number of target entities outputted by each run per query</figDesc><table coords="5,233.05,299.35,127.22,33.05"><row><cell>Run</cell><cell cols="2">MAP R-precision</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Run-1 0.0228</cell><cell>0.0274</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Run-2 0.0755</cell><cell>0.0494</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="5,196.12,345.52,197.75,8.74"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Overall performance of the two runs</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work was supported by the <rs type="grantName">Google Research Grant</rs>. Any opinions, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in this material are those of the authors and do not necessarily reflect the views of the sponsors.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_DYbHsPH">
					<orgName type="grant-name">Google Research Grant</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,140.30,476.77,328.21,9.02;6,140.30,489.45,118.83,8.30" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Balog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://zookst1.science.uva.nl:8888/btc-webapp-0.1/btc" />
		<title level="m" coord="6,190.58,476.77,82.72,8.74">Billion triple index</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,140.30,507.70,328.21,9.02;6,140.30,520.38,55.07,8.30" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Callan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://boston.lti.cs.cmu.edu/Data/clueweb09/" />
		<title level="m" coord="6,185.73,507.70,96.98,8.74">The clueweb09 dataset</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,140.30,538.63,328.21,9.02;6,140.30,551.31,274.75,8.30" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Callan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://boston.lti.cs.cmu.edu:8085/clueweb09/search/cata_english/lemur.cgi" />
		<title level="m" coord="6,187.03,538.63,163.04,8.74">Search clueweb09 category a -english</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,140.30,569.56,328.22,8.74;6,140.30,581.52,328.22,8.74;6,140.30,593.47,60.79,8.74" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,184.78,581.52,264.05,8.74">Coupled semi-supervised learning for information extraction</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Carlson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Betteridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hruschka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jr</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,140.30,593.47,27.82,8.74">WSDM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,140.30,612.45,295.53,9.02" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://rtw.ml.cmu.edu/rtw/" />
		<title level="m" coord="6,196.19,612.45,92.28,8.74">Read the web project</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,140.30,631.42,328.21,8.74;6,140.30,643.38,202.70,8.74" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,293.45,631.42,175.06,8.74;6,140.30,643.38,124.72,8.74">Language-independent set expansion of named entities using the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,286.80,643.38,24.15,8.74">ICDM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,140.30,662.35,328.22,8.74;6,140.30,674.31,135.95,8.74" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,288.31,662.35,180.21,8.74;6,140.30,674.31,57.96,8.74">Iterative set expansion of named entities using the web</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,220.05,674.31,24.15,8.74">ICDM</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,140.30,693.28,328.21,8.74;6,140.30,705.24,245.30,8.74" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,405.89,693.28,62.62,8.74;6,140.30,705.24,158.97,8.74">Automatic set expansion for list question answering</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Schlaefer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Nyberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,320.72,705.24,32.39,8.74">EMNLP</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
