<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,100.47,160.66,411.06,15.15">York University at TREC 2010: Chemical Track</title>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council</orgName>
					<orgName type="abbreviated">NSERC</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,211.49,194.56,52.49,8.74"><forename type="first">Jiashu</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Information Retrieval and Knowledge Managment Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">York University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Toronto</settlement>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,274.54,194.56,63.65,8.74"><forename type="first">Xiangji</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<email>jhuang@yorku.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Information Retrieval and Knowledge Managment Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">York University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Toronto</settlement>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,348.75,194.56,40.96,8.74"><forename type="first">Zheng</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
							<email>yezheng@yorku.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Information Retrieval and Knowledge Managment Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">York University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Toronto</settlement>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Information Retrieval Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Dalian University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,100.47,160.66,411.06,15.15">York University at TREC 2010: Chemical Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">12BAAE240D1F8AB0474808AABF64228E</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Chemical Information Retrieval</term>
					<term>Patent</term>
					<term>BM25</term>
					<term>DFR</term>
					<term>Language Model</term>
					<term>QRocDFR</term>
					<term>RM3</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We participated two chemical information retrieval tasks, Technology Survey (TS) task and Prior Art (PA) task in TREC 2010 chemical track. We aim to discover extra relevant chemical compounds for a given query. We investigate various basic retrieval models as well as corresponding Pseudo Relevance Feedback(PRF) models in chemical experiments. In order to eliminate low quality feedback documents, QRocDFR, an early work of York University, is introduced to consider the quality of each feedback chemical document. Further analysis could be made when we were able to reach the evaluation results.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This is the second year that TREC chemical track has been carried out. This paper describes the work done by members at York University in Canada for the TREC 2010 chemical track, which continues our work in the TREC 2009 chemical track <ref type="bibr" coords="1,328.03,486.02,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. We participated in both the Technology Survey (TS) and the Prior Art (PA) retrieval tasks. Our goal of participating in this year's TREC Chemical track is to evaluate Information Retrieval (IR) models and their term weighting functions in the chemical domain, and to address the challenges in searching large-scale chemical and patent documents.</p><p>The TREC 2010 chemical track data collection is very similar to the one of 2009, but larger. Same as in 2009, the test corpus used in this year's chemical track also consists of two types of documents, chemical patents and chemical articles. There are 1.3 million patents covering patents in the chemical field until 2009, and 181,076 scientific articles from: The Royal Society of Chemistry, PubMed Central, Hindawi Publishing, International Union of Crystallography, Oxford Publishing and Molecular Diversity Preservation International. In addition to last year's plain XML format, TREC 2010 chemical track contains images and chemical structure information (in the form of CDX or MOL files). Our work focuses on retrieval using plain XML chemical documents.</p><p>The TREC 2010 Chemical Track contains two ad-hoc retrieval tasks: Technology Survey and Prior Art. The TS task contains 30 short topics, which are generated with the help of human experts. The PA task contains 1000 long automatically generated topics, each of which is a full patent. The aim of this task is to find relevant patents with respect to a set of 1,000 existing patents. The results were assessed based on existing citations from the 1,000 patents and their family members. There is also a subtask using title and claim only and a smaller set of topics including 100 patents.</p><p>The remainder of this paper is organized as follows. In Section 2, we describe three most popular basic retrieval models. In Section 3, we introduce Pseudo Relevance Feedback (PRF) models: QRocDFR based on DFR, and RM3 based on KL-divergance retrieval model. In Section 4, we test the introduced models on both TS and PA task in chemical track.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Basic Retrieval Models</head><p>The retrieval documents are ranked in the order of their probabilities of relevance to the query. Search term is assigned weight based on its within-document term frequency and query term frequency. We used three well-known basic retrieval models, BM25 <ref type="bibr" coords="2,316.22,214.46,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, DFR <ref type="bibr" coords="2,356.64,214.46,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, and KL-divergence retrieval model <ref type="bibr" coords="2,90.00,226.41,10.52,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref> in this year's chemical track.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">BM25</head><p>In BM25, search term is assigned weight based on its within-document term frequency and query term frequency <ref type="bibr" coords="2,158.97,284.65,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. The corresponding weighting function is as follows.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,141.04,315.03,380.96,49.83">w = (k 1 + 1) * tf K + tf * log (r + 0.5)/(R -r + 0.5) (n -r + 0.5)/(N -n -R + r + 0.5) * (k 3 + 1 ) * qtf k 3 + qtf ⊕ k 2 * nq * (avdl -dl ) (avdl + dl )<label>(1)</label></formula><p>where w is the weight of a query term, N is the number of indexed documents in the collection, n is the number of documents containing a specific term, R is the number of documents known to be relevant to a specific topic, r is the number of relevant documents containing the term, tf is withindocument term frequency, qtf is within-query term frequency, dl is the length of the document, avdl is the average document length, nq is the number of query terms, the k i s are tuning constants (which depend on the database and possibly on the nature of the queries and are empirically determined), K equals to k 1 * ((1 -b) + b * dl/avdl), and ⊕ indicates that its following component is added only once per document, rather than for each term. In our experiments, the values of k 1 , k 2 , k 3 and b are set to be 1.2, 0, 8 and 0.75 respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">DFR</head><p>Divergence from Randomness (DFR) is a componential framework that measures the relevance of documents following the probabilistic paradigm <ref type="bibr" coords="2,295.40,530.37,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. In the DFR framework, the weight of a document d for a given query term t is given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,220.28,566.23,297.47,9.65">ω(d, t) = qtw(t) * IG * (-log 2 P rob(tf )) (<label>2</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,517.75,566.23,4.24,8.74">)</formula><p>where IG is the information gain, which is given by a conditional probability of success of encountering a further token of a given word in a given document on the basis of the statistics on the retrieved set. P rob(tf ) is the probability of observing the document d given tf occurrences of the query term t. -log2P rob(tf ) measures the amount of information that term t carries in d. qtw is the query term weight component, which measures the importance of individual query terms. In the DFR framework, the query term weight is given by:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,269.75,664.37,252.26,23.23">qtw(t) = qtf (t) qtf max<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where qtf (t) is the query term frequency of t, namely the number of occurrences of t in the query. qtf max is the maximum query term frequency in the query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">KL-divergence Retrieval Model</head><p>In KL-divergence retrieval model, the query and document are represented as language models <ref type="bibr" coords="3,508.72,142.21,9.96,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p><p>The Kullback-Leibler divergence between the query language model θ Q and the document language model θ D is defined as</p><formula xml:id="formula_4" coords="3,201.28,196.51,320.72,38.07">D(θ Q |θ D ) = Σ w P (w|θ Q )log P (w|θ Q ) P (w|θ D ) = -Σ w P (w|θ Q )logP (w|θ D ) + cons(q) (4)</formula><p>where cons(q) is a document-independent constant that can be dropped, since it does not affect the ranking of documents.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Relevance Feedback</head><p>In Chemical IR, it shows that specialized relevance feedback models are needed. Chemical compounds are complicated and consisting more than one chemical elements. Chemical compounds can be molecular compounds held together by covalent bonds, salts held together by ionic bonds, inter-metallic compounds held together by metallic bonds, or complexes held together by coordinate covalent bonds. Either way, a chemical compound is related to a serious of chemical reactions, chemical elements, and other chemical compounds. Due to the large amount of chemical terms, it is impossible for human beings to gather all the related terms together for any given chemical compound. Therefore, we introduce two relevance feedback weighting models in this section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Relevance Feedback under DFR framework: QRocDFR</head><p>QRocDFR <ref type="bibr" coords="3,139.55,443.63,10.52,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref> was an earlier work of York University, it updates the query term weight component of the DFR framework by considering an expansion terms importance in the pseudo relevance set, has the follows steps:</p><p>QRocDFR:</p><p>(1) For a given query, performs the first-pass retrieval and considers the R highest ranked documents as the pseudo feedback set DR (2) Assigns an expansion weight w(t, DR) = Σ d R ∈D R w(t, dR) to each term t in DR (3) The T most weighted expansion terms are added to the query, using updating formula</p><formula xml:id="formula_5" coords="3,149.26,547.82,201.66,34.76">Q1 = α * Q0 + β * Σr∈R r * q(dr ) R Figure 1: QRocDFR</formula><p>In step (2), the expansion weight w(t, D R ) is the mean of the expansion weights in each individual feedback document d R . Document ranking scores from the first pass retrieval is applied to compute the expansion weight w(t, D R ).</p><p>In step (3), the quality of each feedback document are considered. It is shown that the retrieval performance will be degraded by the low-quality feedback documents, when the feedback document set size is large <ref type="bibr" coords="3,156.64,667.49,9.96,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. QRocDFR, a quality-biased pseudo relevance feedback (PRF) method, promotes expansion terms in the high-quality documents, and penalizes those in the low-quality documents.</p><formula xml:id="formula_6" coords="3,90.00,689.65,128.61,14.38">Q 1 = α * Q 0 + β * Σ r∈R r * q(dr) R</formula><p>is a quality-baised factor, where q(d r ) is the quality score of feedback document d r in the R highest ranked documents in the first-pass retrieval. The document quality score is given by the sum of the expansion weight of the original query as q(d r ) = t∈Q w(t, d r ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Relevance Feedback under LM framework: Relevance Model</head><p>The essential issue in the KL-divergance retrieval model is to estimate θ Q and θ D . In general, a feedback language model θ F is derived to smooth θ Q <ref type="bibr" coords="4,325.26,154.17,9.96,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. The updated query language model is as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7" coords="4,246.55,178.08,275.45,9.65">θ Q = (1 -α) * θ Q + α * θ F<label>(5)</label></formula><p>Relevance model is a representative and state-of-the-art approach for estimating query language models within language modeling framework <ref type="bibr" coords="4,294.49,207.97,9.96,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. Relevance models do not explicitly model the relevant or pseudo-relevant document. Instead,they model a more generalized notion of relevance R. The formula of RM1 is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8" coords="4,229.72,243.83,292.28,10.27">p(w|R) ∝ Σ D p(w|θ D )p(θ D )p(Q|θ D )<label>(6)</label></formula><p>The relevance model p(w|R) is often used to estimate the feedback model θ F , and then interpolated with the original query model θ Q in order to improve its estimation. The interpolated version of relevance model is called RM3.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Experimental Results</head><p>Our experiments were conducted on a double-processor server which has 2 Intel(R) Quad 2.66GHz CPU and 4G memory. York University submitted eight automatic runs in total for the 2010 TREC Chemical track, including seven TS task runs, and one PA task run. For TS task, we did experiments on the basic retrieval weighting models and also their relevance feedback versions. Due to the limitation of number of submissions, we only submitted runs with empirical optimal parameters. The overview of the experimental settings of our submitted runs are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,460.42,400.22,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. For PA task, the keywords within a query and extracted the top keywords for further retrieval were ranked <ref type="bibr" coords="4,143.75,611.51,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. We use a part of BM25 as weighting function, in order to consider both the frequency of the keyword in the query and its effect on the whole collection. ŵ = log (r + 0.5)/(R -r + 0.5) (n -r + 0.5)/(N -n -R + r + 0.5)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Run</head><formula xml:id="formula_9" coords="4,371.87,643.89,150.13,23.23">* (k 3 + 1 ) * qtf k 3 + qtf<label>(7)</label></formula><p>The parameters are the same as described in Function 1. There are two parts of Function 7, where the first part is calculated based on the term frequency on the whole collection and the second part is calculated based on the term frequency on the query. The top keywords are therefore extracted for retrieval. The retrieval models and their performance is shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,434.26,709.71,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. We can see that using both title and claim can achieve better performance than using title only. Using PRF model, QEAdap, can further improve the performance. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,90.00,431.36,432.00,164.97"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Information of Submitted TS runsDue to the reason that the organizers have not finished evaluation of TREC 2010 Chemical Track TS task, we are not able to show or analyze the results currently. Besides the official runs, we also conducted more experiment, we can further analyze the details after the evaluation is done.</figDesc><table coords="4,96.97,431.36,418.06,87.37"><row><cell></cell><cell>Model</cell><cell>Parameter Settings</cell><cell>Decription</cell></row><row><cell>york09ca02</cell><cell>BM25</cell><cell>b=0.3, k1=0.12, k3=1000</cell><cell>Title</cell></row><row><cell>york09ca03</cell><cell>LM</cell><cell>µ = 500</cell><cell>Title</cell></row><row><cell>york09ca05</cell><cell>DFR</cell><cell>Parameter Free</cell><cell>Title</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">york09ca06 QRocDFR Doc No.=20, Expansion Term No.=30, Parameter= 0.7</cell><cell>Title</cell></row><row><cell>york09ca07</cell><cell>BM25</cell><cell>b=0.3, k1=0.12, k3=1000</cell><cell>Title &amp; Chemical</cell></row><row><cell>york09ca08</cell><cell>LM</cell><cell>µ = 500</cell><cell>Title &amp; Chemical</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">york09ca09 QRocDFR Doc No.=20, Expansion Term No.=30, Parameter= 0.7 Title &amp; Chemical</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="5,90.00,166.06,399.15,127.59"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>MAP for PA runs 5 Acknowledgements</figDesc><table coords="5,122.85,166.06,366.30,53.29"><row><cell>Model</cell><cell>Parameter Settings</cell><cell>Description</cell><cell>MAP</cell></row><row><cell>DLM</cell><cell>µ = 1000</cell><cell>Title</cell><cell>0.0136</cell></row><row><cell>DLM</cell><cell>µ = 1000</cell><cell cols="2">Title &amp; Claim (top 40 words for query) 0.0269</cell></row><row><cell>DPH</cell><cell>Parameter Free</cell><cell>Title &amp; Claim (top 50)</cell><cell>0.0320</cell></row><row><cell>DPH &amp; QEAdap</cell><cell>Parameter Free</cell><cell>Title &amp; Claim (top 50)</cell><cell>0.0339</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>This research is supported in part by the research grant from the <rs type="funder">Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council (NSERC) of Canada</rs>. We would also like to thank <rs type="person">Michael Siu</rs> at <rs type="affiliation">Vice-President Research Office of York University</rs> for his support and advice.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,389.86,403.07,8.74" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Z</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009. 2009</date>
			<publisher>Chemical Track</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,408.92,416.51,8.74;5,105.50,420.87,337.69,8.74" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Beaulieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gatford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="5,496.26,408.92,25.74,8.74;5,105.50,420.87,250.61,8.74">Okapi at TREC-5. Proceedings of 5th Text REtrieval Conference</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996. 1996</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="166" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,439.93,416.50,8.74;5,105.50,451.89,334.04,8.74" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,153.11,439.93,363.99,8.74">Probabilistic models for information retrieval based on divergence from randomness</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Amati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Department of Computing Science, University of Glasgow</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">PhD thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,470.95,416.50,8.74;5,105.50,482.91,416.50,8.74;5,105.50,494.86,416.51,8.74;5,105.50,506.82,60.88,8.74" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,196.51,470.95,325.49,8.74;5,105.50,482.91,81.20,8.74">Document language models, query models, and risk minimization for information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lfferty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,212.70,482.91,309.29,8.74;5,105.50,494.86,285.79,8.74">SIGIR 01: Proceedings of the 24th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">111119</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,525.88,416.50,8.74;5,105.50,537.83,182.74,8.74" xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>He</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="5,344.99,525.88,177.01,8.74;5,105.50,537.83,150.48,8.74">Revisiting Rocchios Relevance Feedback Algorithm for Probabilistic Models</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,556.89,416.50,8.74;5,105.50,568.85,416.50,8.74;5,105.50,580.80,197.04,8.74" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,202.01,556.89,319.99,8.74;5,105.50,568.85,34.67,8.74">Model-based feedback in the language modeling approach to information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>La?erty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,165.37,568.85,356.62,8.74;5,105.50,580.80,100.74,8.74">CIKM 01: Proceedings of the tenth international conference on Information and knowledge management</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">403410</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,599.86,416.50,8.74;5,105.50,611.82,416.51,8.74;5,105.50,623.77,59.22,8.74" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,231.74,599.86,145.50,8.74">Relevance-based language models</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Lavrenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,386.09,599.86,135.91,8.74;5,105.50,611.82,395.98,8.74">Proceedings of the 24th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 24th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="127" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,642.83,416.50,8.74;5,105.50,654.79,166.54,8.74" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,161.38,642.83,249.06,8.74">A Probabilistic Approach to Automatic Keyword Indexing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Harter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,417.56,642.83,104.44,8.74;5,105.50,654.79,136.17,8.74">Journal of the American Society for Information Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1975">1975</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,673.85,306.85,8.74" xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://chem.sis.nlm.nih.gov/chemidplus/" />
		<title level="m" coord="5,105.50,673.85,56.41,8.74">ChemID plus</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.48,692.91,199.66,8.74" xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/" />
		<title level="m" coord="5,110.48,692.91,40.32,8.74">PubChem</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.48,711.97,411.52,8.74;5,105.50,723.93,311.47,8.74" xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,372.31,711.97,149.69,8.74;5,105.50,723.93,247.75,8.74">Applying Data Mining to Pseudo-Relevance Feedback for High Performance Text Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>An</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Poon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<publisher>ICDM</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
