<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.00,77.49,291.16,16.71;1,72.00,95.69,148.81,10.70">Authorship Verification Based on CoSENT Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2023</title>
				<funder ref="#_BhDXGDc">
					<orgName type="full">National Social Science Foundation of China</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,75.00,121.23,76.74,11.62"><forename type="first">Zhaohao</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<email>zhaohaohuang6@gmail.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,163.56,121.23,54.76,11.62"><forename type="first">Leilei</forename><surname>Kong</surname></persName>
							<email>kongleilei@fosu.edu.cn</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,233.28,121.23,72.84,11.62"><forename type="first">Mingjie</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<email>mingjiehuang007@163.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Foshan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Foshan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">CLEF</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2023</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.00,77.49,291.16,16.71;1,72.00,95.69,148.81,10.70">Authorship Verification Based on CoSENT Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2023</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">202AB33738E7FFA8A288A1491D0886B4</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T16:35+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Authorship Verification</term>
					<term>Data optimization</term>
					<term>Feature-based</term>
					<term>CoSENT 1</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Authorship verification is the task of determining whether the authorship of texts is the same based on stylistic features. In this paper, we propose two different approaches to the author attribution task. The first approach employs a positive-example-based data optimization approach to reorganize the training dataset. The second method uses CoSENT, a featurebased text classification method, to accomplish the task of authorship verification. This method enables the model to have a better ability to identify whether sentence pairs are similar or dissimilar.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>The authorship verification task is to determine whether two texts are written by the same author by analyzing various characteristics and styles of texts. By utilizing effective authorship verification techniques, we can identify authors in literature, law, journalism, and other fields, thereby helping to solve important tasks such as the authenticity of texts, copyright issues, and the identification of forged documents. This paper presents our approach for the authorship verification task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,469.68,414.77,12.92,10.70" target="#b0">[1]</ref> on PAN 2023. This task is an open-set validation task, and the test dataset contains authors who were not seen in the training dataset, so writing style models built for the authors or topics of the training dataset are not supported in the open-set validation task.</p><p>Our idea is to encode text information, get text features, and judge whether two texts are the same author by comparing the similarity of features. In order to make the model better classify texts, the characteristic text matching method CoSENT <ref type="bibr" coords="1,278.28,490.73,12.92,10.70" target="#b1">[2]</ref> is used to expand the distance of feature vectors of dissimilar texts and reduce the distance of feature vectors of similar texts. In this task, the lack of enough labeled data to train the language model is also a problem to be solved. We try to expand the training set data by restructuring text sentence pairs from the official training set data. Then use the pre-trained language model BERT <ref type="bibr" coords="1,226.56,541.37,12.92,10.70" target="#b2">[3]</ref> to complete the author verification task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Datasets</head><p>The training dataset provided by the PAN@CLEF 2023 organization <ref type="bibr" coords="1,421.80,611.69,12.92,10.70" target="#b3">[4]</ref> consists of crossdiscourse types of authorship verification cases using the following discourse types (DT): essays, emails, interviews, and speech transcriptions. Among the four DTs, essays and emails belong to the written discourse, and interviews and speech transcriptions belong to the spoken discourse. The dataset includes texts from approximately 56 authors who are native English speakers and have similar ages ranging from 18 to 22. The topic of the text samples is not limited or constrained. The total number of text pairs in the dataset provided by PAN@CLEF 2023 is 8,836. Each problem is composed of two texts belonging to two different DTs. All text pairs contain 886 texts from different authors. The number distribution of different discourse types is shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,423.00,112.85,4.14,10.70" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p><p>Since the text length of texts of emails and interviews can be very small, each text belonging to these DTs is actually a concatenation of different messages. We use the &lt;new&gt; tag to denote the boundaries of original texts. New lines within a text are denoted with the &lt;nl&gt;tag. In addition, authorspecific and topic-specific information, e.g., named entities, has been replaced with corresponding tags. In spoken discourse types, additional tags are used to indicate nonverbal vocalizations (e.g., cough, laugh). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data preprocessing</head><p>For deep learning methods, the more text data, the more text features the language model can learn. Of the 8,836 text pairs in the original training dataset, there are only 886 distinct texts. We try to use these different texts to scramble and combine them into a more extensive data set for model training. We combine two groups of texts belonging to the same author into a positive pair, and the total number of positive pairs is 6,945. In order to keep the ratio of positive and negative samples at 1:1, each of the 886 different texts in the original training dataset is combined with any text of other authors to form a negative pair, and each text is randomly combined with 8 negative pairs. There are a total of 7088 negative sentence pairs. A total of 14033 positive and negative sentence pairs are shuffled and divided into 75% training set and 25% test set, as shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,419.64,515.81,4.14,10.70" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Model settings</head><p>In this paper, we choose to use a feature-based text-matching approach for this task. The Bert model is fine-tuned during the training phase using the expanded training dataset. In the prediction stage, we send the text1 and text2 of the text pair separately to the pre-trained language model, bert, where the text is encoded respectively and the cosine similarity is calculated. Finally, whether the cosine similarity is greater than 0.5 is used as the classification standard for the sentence pair. The overall structure of the model is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,289.20,734.45,4.14,10.70" target="#fig_0">1</ref>.</p><p>We hope to improve the classification ability of the model. The work of Su <ref type="bibr" coords="2,421.56,747.05,12.92,10.70" target="#b1">[2]</ref> suggests that a new loss function is proposed, which improves the model's ability to identify similar text and distinguish dissimilar text to a certain extent. We record pos  as the set of all positive sample pairs and neg  as the set of all negative sample pairs.</p><p>In fact, we hope that for any positive sample pair   pos   j , i and negative sample</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,72.00,118.54,434.99,49.90">pair   neg l   , k , both have cos , &gt; cos ,<label>(1)</label></formula><p>Where i u , j u , k u , l u are their respective sentence vectors. Here we only hope that the similarity of positive sample pairs is greater than that of negative sample pairs, and it is up to the model to decide how much larger it is. The loss function is shown in formula <ref type="bibr" coords="3,372.00,215.33,11.70,10.70" target="#b1">(2)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,166.08,252.93,340.91,27.50">log 1 + , ∈Ω , , ∈Ω cos , -cos ,<label>(2)</label></formula><p>λ is a hyperparameter, and we set it to 20 in this experiment. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Experiment setting</head><p>In this work, BERTBASE (L=12, H=768, A=12, Total Parameters=110M) is chosen as the pretrained model size, and we use Pytorch to construct BERT and fully connected network classification model. Our hyperparameters are set as follows: the batch size is 16, the maximum sequence length is 512, the initial learning rate is set to 1e-5, and 20 epochs are trained. Each training is optimized with AdamW, and the warm-up rate is set to 0.1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5.</head><p>Evaluation and results</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.">Evaluation</head><p>To evaluate the proposed models, we use the TIRA <ref type="bibr" coords="3,314.64,757.13,12.92,10.70" target="#b4">[5]</ref> evaluation tool with the following metrics: AUC: The area-under-the-curve (ROC) score F1-score: F1 score is the harmonic mean between precision and recall <ref type="bibr" coords="4,408.96,100.13,11.70,10.70" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. c@1: rewards systems that leave complicated problems unanswered <ref type="bibr" coords="4,399.24,112.85,11.79,10.70" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. F_0.5u: A measure that puts more emphasis on deciding same-author cases correctly <ref type="bibr" coords="4,472.92,125.45,11.70,10.70" target="#b7">[8]</ref>.</p><p>Brier: The complement of the Brier score for evaluating the goodness of (binary) probabilistic Classifiers <ref type="bibr" coords="4,121.20,150.77,11.70,10.70" target="#b8">[9]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.">Results</head><p>We test the performance of our model on a new reorganized test set and test our model on the PAN23 authorship verification test dataset.The test results are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,419.52,218.69,4.14,10.70" target="#tab_2">3</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusion</head><p>In this paper, we present our approach to authorship verification on PAN 2022. We re-pair each dissimilar sentence in the training dataset into a new larger training dataset. By augmenting the dataset in this way, we hope the model can learn more about the similarities between texts by the same author and the differences between texts by different authors. In addition, we also introduced a special loss function in the model to make the model better learn the similarity and difference information between sentence pairs. Then use the pre-trained language model BERT to extract text features and calculate sentence cosine similarity to judge whether they are from the same author.</p><p>From the results, the method does not perform well on open datasets with unknown authors. In the follow-up work, we should use more effective methods to enhance the data and improve the classification ability of the model in the open set.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,72.00,541.25,204.96,10.93;3,220.56,320.40,167.28,204.60"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Architecture diagram for our model.</figDesc><graphic coords="3,220.56,320.40,167.28,204.60" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,72.00,214.60,360.00,184.20"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc>The number distribution of different discourse types.</figDesc><table coords="2,72.00,244.01,360.00,154.78"><row><cell></cell><cell>Type</cell><cell>Quantity</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Essays</cell><cell>93</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Emails</cell><cell>450</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Interviews</cell><cell>275</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Speech transcriptions</cell><cell>68</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Overall</cell><cell>886</cell></row><row><cell>3.</cell><cell>Method</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>3.1.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="2,72.00,541.72,424.92,67.11"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>The partition of the training dataset of PAN 2023 into a new training dataset and test dataset.</figDesc><table coords="2,85.80,570.04,411.12,38.79"><row><cell>dataset</cell><cell>proportion</cell><cell>number of text pairs</cell></row><row><cell>New training dataset on PAN23</cell><cell>75%</cell><cell>10524</cell></row><row><cell>New test dataset on PAN23</cell><cell>25%</cell><cell>3509</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="4,72.00,245.20,451.02,136.06"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>The experimental results of the Cosent method on the new test dataset on PAN23 and the true test dataset on PAN23.</figDesc><table coords="4,80.16,286.72,431.05,94.54"><row><cell>Test datasets</cell><cell>AUC</cell><cell>c@1</cell><cell>f_05_u</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>Brier</cell><cell>Overall</cell></row><row><cell>New test dataset on PAN23</cell><cell>0.935</cell><cell>0.935</cell><cell>0.925</cell><cell>0.938</cell><cell>0.935</cell><cell>0.934</cell></row><row><cell>PAN23</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>authorship verification test</cell><cell>0.563</cell><cell>0.563</cell><cell>0.55</cell><cell>0.511</cell><cell>0.563</cell><cell>0.55</cell></row><row><cell>dataset</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work is supported by the <rs type="funder">National Social Science Foundation of China</rs> (No. <rs type="grantNumber">22BTQ101</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_BhDXGDc">
					<idno type="grant-number">22BTQ101</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,108.00,698.33,414.96,10.70;4,108.00,710.93,415.08,10.70;4,108.00,723.65,414.96,10.70;4,108.00,736.25,69.60,10.70" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,143.04,710.93,264.34,10.70">Overview of the Authorship Verification Task at PAN 2023</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kredens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pęzik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bevendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="CEUR-WS.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,427.56,710.93,95.53,10.70;4,108.00,723.65,348.78,10.70">CLEF 2023 Labs and Workshops, Notebook Papers. Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>CLEF</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2023. 2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.00,74.93,415.08,10.70;5,108.00,87.53,177.59,10.70" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,138.60,74.93,349.77,10.70">CoSENT (I): A more efficient sentence vector scheme than Sentence-BERT</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Su</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://spaces.ac.cn/archives/8847" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.00,100.13,414.96,10.70;5,108.00,112.85,415.05,10.70;5,108.00,125.45,264.24,10.70" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,313.80,112.85,186.03,10.70">Scikit-learn: Machine learning in python</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Pedregosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Varoquaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gramfort</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Thirion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Grisel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Blondel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Prettenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Weiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Dubourg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,509.52,112.85,13.53,10.70;5,108.00,125.45,166.20,10.70">the Journal of machine Learning research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2825" to="2830" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.00,138.17,415.08,10.70;5,108.00,150.77,414.96,10.70;5,108.00,163.37,415.02,10.70;5,108.00,176.09,415.08,10.70;5,108.00,188.69,415.08,10.70;5,108.00,201.41,415.08,10.70;5,108.00,214.01,415.05,10.70;5,108.00,226.73,414.96,10.70;5,108.00,239.33,77.52,10.70" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,407.88,163.37,115.14,10.70;5,108.00,176.09,415.08,10.70;5,108.00,188.69,151.44,10.70">Overview of PAN 2023: Authorship Verification, Multi-Author Writing Style Analysis, Profiling Cryptocurrency Influencers, and Trigger Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bevendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Borrego-Obrador</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chinea-Ríos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Franco-Salvador</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fröbe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kredens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mayerl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pęzik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wolska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Zangerle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,108.00,214.01,415.05,10.70;5,108.00,226.73,314.30,10.70">Experimental IR Meets Multilinguality, Multimodality, and Interaction. Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Arampatzis</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kanoulas</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tsikrika</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Vrochidis</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Giachanou</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Aliannejadi</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vlachos</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Faggioli</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Thessalonikki, Greece</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023. 2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.60,251.93,417.48,10.70;5,108.00,264.65,415.08,10.70;5,108.00,277.25,414.96,10.70;5,108.00,289.97,415.08,10.70;5,108.00,302.57,415.02,10.70;5,108.00,315.17,40.68,10.70" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,241.20,264.65,281.88,10.70;5,108.00,277.25,19.86,10.70">Continuous Integration for Reproducible Shared Tasks with TIRA</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Fröbe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kolyada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Grahm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Elstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Loebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,277.80,289.97,245.28,10.70;5,108.00,302.57,196.64,10.70">Advances in Information Retrieval. 45th European Conference on IR Research (ECIR 2023)</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Goeuriot</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Crestani</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Maistro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Joho</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gurrin</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><surname>Kruschwitz</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Caputo</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg New York</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="236" to="241" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.00,327.89,414.96,10.70;5,108.00,340.49,415.05,10.70;5,108.00,353.21,264.24,10.70" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,313.80,340.49,186.03,10.70">Scikit-learn: Machine learning in python</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Pedregosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Varoquaux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Gramfort</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Michel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Thirion</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Grisel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Blondel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Prettenhofer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Weiss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Dubourg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,509.52,340.49,13.53,10.70;5,108.00,353.21,166.20,10.70">the Journal of machine Learning research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2825" to="2830" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.00,365.81,313.40,10.70" xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Peñas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rodrigo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="5,207.60,365.81,181.77,10.70">A simple measure to assess non-response</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.00,378.53,415.02,10.70;5,108.00,391.13,415.04,10.70;5,108.00,403.73,415.02,10.70;5,108.00,416.45,120.96,10.70" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,328.68,378.53,174.98,10.70">Generalizing unmasking for short texts</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bevendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,108.00,391.13,415.04,10.70;5,108.00,403.73,273.63,10.70">Proceedings of the 2019 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2019 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="654" to="659" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Long and Short Papers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.00,429.05,414.96,10.70;5,108.00,441.77,132.61,10.70" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,204.84,429.05,270.67,10.70">Verification of forecasts expressed in terms of probability</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Brier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,485.04,429.05,37.92,10.70;5,108.00,441.77,67.62,10.70">Monthly weather review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="3" />
			<date type="published" when="1950">1950</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
