<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,89.29,84.74,410.93,15.42;1,89.29,106.66,269.21,15.42;1,89.29,129.00,157.29,11.96">Profiling Cryptocurrency Influencers With Few-shot Learning via Contrastive Learning Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2023</title>
				<funder ref="#_gsPMrnh">
					<orgName type="full">Natural Science Foundation of Guangdong Province, China</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,89.29,154.90,54.11,11.96"><forename type="first">Zengyao</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Foshan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Foshan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,153.61,154.90,76.49,11.96"><forename type="first">Zhongyuan</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
							<email>hanzhongyuan@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Foshan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Foshan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,247.36,154.90,40.62,11.96"><forename type="first">Jiyin</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
							<email>caijiyin0904@163.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Foshan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Foshan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,298.85,154.90,68.42,11.96"><forename type="first">Zhijian</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Foshan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Foshan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,379.28,154.90,77.95,11.96"><forename type="first">Shaohua</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Foshan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Foshan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,89.29,168.85,55.48,11.96"><forename type="first">Leilei</forename><surname>Kong</surname></persName>
							<email>kongleilei@fosu.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Foshan University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Foshan</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,89.29,84.74,410.93,15.42;1,89.29,106.66,269.21,15.42;1,89.29,129.00,157.29,11.96">Profiling Cryptocurrency Influencers With Few-shot Learning via Contrastive Learning Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2023</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<idno type="ISSN">1613-0073</idno>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">BCAC473E257A9C899B671249E2BCCDE6</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T16:35+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>contrastive learning</term>
					<term>few-shot learning</term>
					<term>profiling cryptocurrency influencers</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We proposed a novel approach that leverages embedding augmentation based on contrastive learning to address the issue of few-shot learning in the task of analyzing cryptocurrency influencers.This representation learning technique enables the model to better distinguish between similar and dissimilar samples, thereby enhancing generalization in few-shot tasks.In our method, we treat sentences with the same label within a batch as positive samples while considering sentences with different labels as negative samples. We conduct additional pre-training to enhance the embedding representation capabilities of the encoder. Subsequently, we fine-tuned the model and used it for classification. Our method achieved the 4th official ranking on the official test dataset for this evaluation.The experimental results serve as compelling evidence of the effectiveness and utility of a contrastive learning-based approach in addressing the few-shot problem in analyzing cryptocurrency influencers. By employing this innovative method, we are able to effectively tackle the challenges associated with analyzing cryptocurrency influencers with limited labelled data.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Cryptocurrencies have gained significant popularity in recent years <ref type="bibr" coords="1,405.46,457.29,11.59,10.91" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, with social media playing a crucial role in shaping public perceptions and influencing investment decisions. Understanding the characteristics and behaviours of cryptocurrency influencers on social media platforms can provide valuable insights for various stakeholders, including investors, researchers, and policymakers <ref type="bibr" coords="1,226.69,511.49,11.36,10.91" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,240.77,511.49,7.57,10.91" target="#b2">3]</ref>.</p><p>In this study, we present a contrastive learning-based approach to address the PAN at CLEF 2023 task: Profiling Cryptocurrency Influencers with Few-shot Learning. The task comprises three sub-tasks, each targeting a specific aspect of cryptocurrency influencers. The first sub-task focuses on low-resource influencer profiling, with the objective of categorizing influencers into distinct classes based on their impact and reach. The second sub-task centres around low-resource influencer interest identification, aiming to classify influencers' interests based on their Twitter posts. The third sub-task revolves around identifying influencers' intent in a low-resource context, where the goal is to discern the underlying purpose behind their tweets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Related Work</head><p>The PAN committee organizing has initiated the Profiling task annually from 2013 to 2022. The PAN author profiling task spanned from 2013 to 2016 with the primary goal of determining the gender and age distribution of authors based on their documents <ref type="bibr" coords="2,374.17,199.79,11.23,10.91" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,388.04,199.79,7.42,10.91" target="#b4">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,398.10,199.79,7.42,10.91" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,408.16,199.79,7.49,10.91" target="#b6">7]</ref>. The following year, the PAN challenge expanded its scope beyond gender detection and incorporated language diversity identification as well <ref type="bibr" coords="2,221.64,226.89,11.28,10.91" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. In 2018, the task adopted a multimodal approach by providing participants with both textual and image data to detect the author's gender <ref type="bibr" coords="2,422.53,240.44,11.34,10.91" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. As the number of social media users surged in 2019, the PAN author profiling task shifted its focus to Twitter. In this instance, the objective involved not only bot detection but also the identification of gender among human authors <ref type="bibr" coords="2,228.81,281.08,16.40,10.91" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. Subsequently, the tasks in 2020, 2021, and 2022 revolved around identifying propagators of Twitter fake news, hate speech, and stereotype dissemination, respectively <ref type="bibr" coords="2,145.59,308.18,16.43,10.91" target="#b10">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,164.75,308.18,12.32,10.91" target="#b11">12]</ref>.</p><p>Before 2018, researchers primarily focused on discussing text preprocessing and feature extraction methods for traditional classifiers. However, starting in 2018, there has been a shift towards the adoption of new deep-learning algorithms. With the introduction of the Transformer model <ref type="bibr" coords="2,177.61,362.38,16.23,10.91" target="#b12">[13]</ref>, an increasing number of teams have opted to utilize the BERT model for author profiling tasks.</p><p>In the profiling task of the previous year, the team that achieved the top ranking employed a fusion model technique. They employed three distinct loss functions to fine-tune the Bertweet model and incorporated a CNN model based on BERT features. Additionally, they utilized soft voting to combine the predictions from these models, resulting in the highest performance. There are other teams that have also achieved remarkable results using ensemble models.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Model</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Our Method</head><p>For this task, we propose a supervised contrastive learning method inspired by Simcse <ref type="bibr" coords="2,484.12,523.27,18.83,10.91" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. The method revolves around constructing groups of three sentences denoted as G = (x, x+, x-), where x represents the source sample, x+ denotes the positive sample with the same label, and x-represents the negative sample with a different label. During batch training, apart from using x-from the sentence group G1 as a negative sample, negative samples from other groups Gi (i!=1) within the same batch are also employed for training.</p><p>In figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,144.03,604.56,3.81,10.91" target="#fig_0">1</ref>, the subscript of S represents the category of the sentence. The purple line represents the source sample and the positive sample, where both samples belong to the same class label. Our objective is to minimize the semantic distance between them. In contrast, the green line represents the source sample and the negative sample, where these two samples have different class labels. Our objective is to maximize the semantic distance between them. In the  The training progress at this stage is evaluated using the Spearman coefficient, and the model with the highest coefficient is selected and further fine-tuned.</p><p>In the 4-classification task, Our goal is to obtain the feature space distribution shown in the right half of Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,177.29,572.41,5.14,10.91" target="#fig_0">1</ref> for the model. The samples from the same class exhibit close proximity, while samples from different classes are well-separated with significant distances between them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Classifier</head><p>We selected the RoBERTa model and the BERTweet model as our baseline models. To serve as classifiers for prediction, we augmented the models with dropout and linear layers. Following the contrastive learning-based method described above, we conducted further pre-training of the baseline models. Subsequently, we connected the pre-trained models to a classifier for fine-tuning, ultimately obtaining the final model. The model architecture is illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,89.29,114.06,3.74,10.91" target="#fig_1">2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Experiment</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Dataset</head><p>This year's Pan evaluation task is a monolingual few-shot task aimed at identifying cryptocurrency influencers on Twitter. The task consists of three subtasks. Subtask 1: The training set for this subtask consists of five labels, with 32 users per label. Each label has a maximum of ten English tweets, resulting in a total of 160 users. The test set contains 220 users, with a maximum of 10 tweets per user. Subtask 2: This subtask includes five labels, with 64 users per label. Each label has one English tweet. The test set consists of 402 users, with one tweet per user. Subtask 3: This subtask involves four labels, with 64 users per label. Each label has one English tweet. The test set comprises 292 users, with one tweet per user. To process these data, we apply different processing strategies to each subtask as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="4,107.28,327.56,151.71,10.91">• Base Scheme 1(subtask 1)</formula><p>Text splicing (multiple tweets from the same user are spliced, when a tweet exceeds 510 lengths, it will be spliced into a new one) Multiple line breaks are replaced with one, and multiple spaces are also replaced with one Convert emoticons to English text • Base Scheme 2 (subtask 2, subtask3)</p><p>Multiple line breaks are replaced with one, and multiple spaces are also replaced with one Convert emoticons to English text • Addtional Scheme 1 (all subtasks)</p><p>Note $ and # (add currency to vocabulary) • Addtional Scheme 2 (subtask2, subtask3)</p><p>Pairwise combination with label text for data augmentationStyle of author name (chinese)</p><p>We perform various experiments by combining fundamental strategies with additional strategies, and we will analyze the specific results in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Experimental setting</head><p>In order to train the model and evaluate its effectiveness, a 5-fold cross-validation method was employed during the training phase. The optimal hyperparameters that were found are shown in table 1. In this experiment, the models we ultimately submitted were obtained by fine-tuning the hyperparameters in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,225.11,610.09,3.79,10.91" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. Additionally, during the fine-tuning stage of the pre-trained model, we utilized cross-entropy as the loss function for model. The entire experiment was conducted using the PyTorch framework. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Result</head><p>This section introduces the experimental results.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="5,127.07,329.01,5.08,10.91">2</ref> exhibits the outcomes obtained through the utilization of 5-fold cross-validation on the training dataset of subtask 1, along with the results obtained on the test dataset. The model we finally submitted was trained using the contrastive learning method, and it achieved a score of 55.1, placing us in the 7th position.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="5,128.11,383.21,5.17,10.91">3</ref> showcases the results and test set outcomes derived from 5-fold cross-validation performed on the training set of subtask 2. In addition to using contrastive learning, we also conducted experiments using AWP adversarial training and the combination strategy. For the final model submission, we included both the contrastive learning model and an ensemble model that combines all three methods. As shown in the figure, the contrastive learning model achieved a higher score compared to the ensemble model. Based on our score, we ultimately ranked 5th in this subtask.</p><p>In Table <ref type="table" coords="5,140.99,478.05,3.81,10.91">4</ref>, you can find the results and test set outcomes obtained through 5-fold crossvalidation on the training set of subtask 3.Regarding subtask 3, our submitted model utilized the same approach as for subtask 2, and the experimental results ultimately demonstrated that using the contrastive learning method alone outperformed the performance of the ensemble model. In subtask 3, we ultimately achieved 11th place. Our speculation is that there may be a conflict between adversarial training and contrastive learning methods, leading to the observed decrease in model performance. Our next step will be to investigate the underlying reasons behind this discrepancy to understand the root cause.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.">Conclusion</head><p>To address the task of analyzing cryptocurrency influencers proposed by PAN2023, we propose in this paper an approach of contrastively learned fusion models. Additionally, we also explored the performance of adversarial training in this task. We discovered that there may be a certain</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,89.29,275.16,177.82,8.93;3,130.96,84.19,333.36,178.40"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Contrastive Learning Framework</figDesc><graphic coords="3,130.96,84.19,333.36,178.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,89.29,480.62,171.43,8.93;3,193.47,302.01,208.35,166.04"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: BERT-based model architecture</figDesc><graphic coords="3,193.47,302.01,208.35,166.04" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,88.99,90.49,402.87,173.95"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="5,88.99,102.49,402.87,161.95"><row><cell cols="2">Hyperparameter Settings</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Model</cell><cell>lr</cell><cell cols="3">Batch size Epoch Optimizer</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Scheduler</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Bertweet-base 2e-5</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>AdamW</cell><cell cols="4">get_linear_schedule_with_warmup</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Roberta-base 5e-5</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>50</cell><cell>AdamW</cell><cell cols="4">get_linear_schedule_with_warmup</cell></row><row><cell>Table 2</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="6">Comparison of Macro-F1 between Different Models of Subtask1</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Model</cell><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>Avg</cell><cell>Test</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Bertweet-base</cell><cell cols="6">50.2857 54.7403 55.1313 47.6398 48.5000 51.2594</cell><cell>/</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Roberta-base</cell><cell cols="6">59.3073 51.2732 57.8632 53.2467 59.8787 56.3138</cell><cell>/</cell></row><row><cell cols="9">Bertweet-base + CL 60.0733 53.3427 59.7034 56.2397 60.5312 57.9781 55.1</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="7.">Acknowledgments</head><p>This work is supported by the <rs type="funder">Natural Science Foundation of Guangdong Province, China</rs> (No.<rs type="grantNumber">2022A1515011544</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_gsPMrnh">
					<idno type="grant-number">2022A1515011544</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" />			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,112.66,532.74,393.61,10.91;6,112.66,546.29,393.33,10.91;6,112.66,559.83,393.33,10.91;6,112.66,573.38,200.44,10.91" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,295.55,532.74,210.72,10.91;6,112.66,546.29,216.46,10.91">Cryptocurrency bubble detection: A new stock market dataset, financial task &amp; hyperbolic models</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sawhney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mittal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,351.29,546.29,154.70,10.91;6,112.66,559.83,393.33,10.91;6,112.66,573.38,102.30,10.91">Proceedings of the 2022 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</title>
		<meeting>the 2022 Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics: Human Language Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5531" to="5545" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,112.66,586.93,393.61,10.91;6,112.66,600.48,394.53,10.91;6,112.66,614.03,103.95,10.91" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,395.79,586.93,110.48,10.91;6,112.66,600.48,214.49,10.91">Profiling cryptocurrency influencers with few shot learning at pan 2023</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chinea-Rios</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Borrego-Obrador</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Franco-Salvador</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,356.02,600.48,145.80,10.91">CLEF 2022 Labs and Workshops</title>
		<title level="s" coord="6,112.66,614.03,73.93,10.91">Notebook Papers</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,112.66,627.58,393.33,10.91;6,112.39,641.13,393.60,10.91;6,112.66,654.68,395.01,10.91;6,112.66,668.23,38.81,10.91" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,357.60,627.58,148.39,10.91;6,112.39,641.13,393.60,10.91;6,112.66,654.68,72.97,10.91">Overview of pan 2023: Authorship verification, multi-author writing style analysis, profiling cryptocurrency influencers, and trigger detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bevendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chinea-Ríos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Franco-Salvador</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,208.71,654.68,209.48,10.91">European Conference on Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="518" to="526" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,112.66,86.97,394.61,10.91;7,112.66,100.52,394.52,10.91;7,112.66,114.06,80.57,10.91" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,274.79,86.97,213.08,10.91">Overview of the author profiling task at pan 2013</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koppel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,112.66,100.52,353.25,10.91">CLEF conference on multilingual and multimodal information access evaluation</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CELCT</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="352" to="365" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,112.66,127.61,394.53,10.91;7,112.66,141.16,394.52,10.91;7,112.66,154.71,65.36,10.91" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,270.90,127.61,231.84,10.91">Overview of the 2nd author profiling task at pan 2014</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Chugur</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,127.22,141.16,287.66,10.91">CLEF 2014 Evaluation Labs and Workshop Working Notes Papers</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Sheffield, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="30" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,112.66,168.26,393.33,10.91;7,112.66,181.81,130.57,10.91" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="7,287.48,168.26,218.51,10.91;7,112.66,181.81,18.15,10.91">Overview of the 3rd author profiling task at pan 2015</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<publisher>CLEF</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,112.66,195.36,393.33,10.91;7,112.66,208.91,393.33,10.91;7,112.66,222.46,373.68,10.91" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,291.95,195.36,214.04,10.91;7,112.66,208.91,132.53,10.91">Overview of the 4th author profiling task at pan 2016: cross-genre evaluations</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Verhoeven</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,270.42,208.91,235.56,10.91;7,112.66,222.46,18.22,10.91">Working Notes Papers of the CLEF 2016 Evaluation Labs</title>
		<title level="s" coord="7,138.16,222.46,134.97,10.91">CEUR Workshop Proceedings/</title>
		<editor>et al.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="750" to="784" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,112.66,236.01,393.33,10.91;7,112.66,249.56,393.32,10.91;7,112.66,263.11,105.38,10.91" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,287.59,236.01,218.40,10.91;7,112.66,249.56,259.06,10.91">Overview of the 5th author profiling task at pan 2017: Gender and language variety identification in twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,379.68,249.56,126.30,10.91;7,112.66,263.11,24.17,10.91">Working notes papers of the CLEF</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1613" to="0073" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,112.66,276.66,393.60,10.91;7,112.66,290.20,393.33,10.91;7,112.66,303.75,80.02,10.91" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,323.01,276.66,183.26,10.91;7,112.66,290.20,253.32,10.91">Overview of the 6th author profiling task at pan 2018: multimodal gender identification in twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Montes-Y Gómez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,375.55,290.20,130.43,10.91;7,112.66,303.75,24.17,10.91">Working notes papers of the CLEF</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="38" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,112.66,317.30,393.53,10.91;7,112.66,330.85,393.97,10.91;7,112.41,344.40,18.52,10.91" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,199.19,317.30,307.00,10.91;7,112.66,330.85,246.35,10.91">Overview of the 7th author profiling task at pan 2019: bots and gender profiling in twitter, Working notes papers of the CLEF</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,385.11,330.85,68.12,10.91">evaluation labs</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2380</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,112.66,357.95,393.61,10.91;7,112.66,371.50,394.52,10.91;7,112.39,385.05,243.38,10.91" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,326.99,357.95,179.28,10.91;7,112.66,371.50,236.46,10.91">Overview of the 8th author profiling task at pan 2020: Profiling fake news spreaders on twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Giachanou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">H H</forename><surname>Ghanem</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,371.95,371.50,130.46,10.91">CEUR workshop proceedings</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Sun SITE Central Europe</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2696</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,112.66,398.60,393.33,10.91;7,112.66,412.15,394.53,10.91;7,112.66,425.70,393.33,10.91;7,112.66,439.25,172.59,10.91" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,409.53,398.60,96.45,10.91;7,112.66,412.15,159.08,10.91">Profiling hate speech spreaders on twitter task at pan 2021</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">L D L</forename><surname>Peña-Sarracén</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Chulvi-Ferriols</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,294.50,412.15,212.69,10.91;7,112.66,425.70,207.00,10.91">Proceedings of the Working Notes of CLEF 2021, Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<meeting>the Working Notes of CLEF 2021, Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum<address><addrLine>Bucharest, Romania</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CEUR</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">September 21st to 24th, 2021. 2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1772" to="1789" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,112.66,452.79,393.32,10.91;7,112.66,466.34,186.38,10.91" xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,300.44,452.79,109.45,10.91">Attention is all you need</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vaswani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Shazeer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Parmar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="7,418.64,452.79,87.34,10.91;7,112.66,466.34,141.59,10.91">Advances in neural information processing systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="7,112.66,479.89,394.62,10.91;7,112.66,493.44,394.53,10.91;7,112.66,506.99,90.72,10.91" xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="7,222.23,479.89,264.64,10.91">Simcse: Simple contrastive learning of sentence embeddings</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="7,112.66,493.44,390.05,10.91">Proceedings of the 2021 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</title>
		<meeting>the 2021 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6894" to="6910" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
