<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.02,75.32,440.05,17.04;1,72.02,96.08,82.27,17.04;1,72.02,115.96,148.95,9.94">A Multi-Feature Custom Classification Approach to Authorship Verification Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2023</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,72.02,141.46,62.88,10.80"><forename type="first">Riya</forename><surname>Sanjesh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Presidency University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ittagallpura, Bengaluru</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,164.30,141.46,81.01,10.80"><forename type="first">Alamelu</forename><surname>Mangai</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Presidency University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ittagallpura, Bengaluru</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.02,75.32,440.05,17.04;1,72.02,96.08,82.27,17.04;1,72.02,115.96,148.95,9.94">A Multi-Feature Custom Classification Approach to Authorship Verification Notebook for PAN at CLEF 2023</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">B7941969B54E3B87872506ED4F4215FC</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T16:35+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Authorship Verification</term>
					<term>PAN 2023</term>
					<term>Multi-Feature extraction</term>
					<term>Stylometric Features</term>
					<term>Cosine Similarity</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>PAN 2023 conducted Cross Discourse Authorship Verification task to evaluate the systems that identify if a pair of text was authored by the same person. This paper talks about our approach towards this task. We used multiple stylometric features such as character n-grams, POS tags, character and word count etc. to represent the texts. The predictions were done using a custom classifier which uses cosine similarities between the text of an author and the input pair of texts. This submission of ours achieved the AUC of 0.985 on the training data set.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="594.96" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="594.96" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="594.96" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="594.96" lry="842.04"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="594.96" lry="842.04"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Authorship Verification task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,214.25,382.89,12.00,9.94" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,228.89,382.89,9.20,9.94" target="#b1">2]</ref> is being conducted by PAN at CLEF since 2013 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,453.34,382.89,12.00,9.94" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,467.86,382.89,8.28,9.94" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,478.66,382.89,8.28,9.94" target="#b4">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,489.58,382.89,8.28,9.94" target="#b5">6,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,500.38,382.89,8.28,9.94" target="#b6">7,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,511.18,382.89,8.01,9.94" target="#b7">8]</ref>. This task aims to determine if a pair of text has been written by the same author. In this paper we introduce our work on Cross-Discourse Type Authorship Verification task in PAN at CLEF 2023 <ref type="bibr" coords="1,507.58,408.09,11.71,9.94" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. In this edition of the Authorship Verification task the focus was on cross discourse type authorship verification where both written and spoken languages were represented in the set of discourse types.</p><p>In our proposed system we introduced a multi-feature extraction and transformation to represent the texts and a custom classifier based on cosine similarities to make the predictions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Proposed Approach</head><p>In this section we talk about the data set used and describe our approach in detail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Data set</head><p>PAN 2023 Cross Discourse Authorship Verification task provided training (calibration) and test data set to train and evaluate the submitted tasks. The data consists of pairs of texts (both in English) from two different discourse types and given a unique identifier. The structure of both training and test data set is the same. The training data contains 8836 pairs along with the metadata on the discourse type for each pair of text. We divided this dataset into two partsone for training purpose and the other for validating the proposed model. The ratio between the training and validation set was 80 -20. Table <ref type="table" coords="1,517.52,637.44,5.52,9.94" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows the breakdown of the data sets. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.">Proposed System</head><p>To train the system we used 3 stages through which we pass the texts. The first stage preprocesses the texts using NLTK packages to extract the tokens and POS tags. This stage is followed by Feature extraction which extracts different types of features described in the next sub section. Once the texts are transformed and fitted into the model we move to the next stage where we measure the cosine similarities of the pairs of texts and with the text of individual authors. We believe that if a pair of text was written by a single author then both these text should be similar to the other texts written by that author and not just similar to each other. Due to this reason we combined all the texts written by an author into a single text for this comparison. This data is further taken through a custom classifier to come up with best configuration to predict the outcomes. All these stages are described in the below sections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.1.">Preprocessing and Feature Extraction</head><p>All the text from a single author is clubbed together into a single document. These documents are further passed to the following stages. The first stage of our proposed systems consists of a preprocessor and a multi-feature transformation to extract different types of features from the input text. The preprocessor uses NLTK Treebank Word Tokenizer to tokenize the text and NLTK's POS tagger to POS tag.</p><p>We used multiple features which are extracted from the input data set. Some of these features are adopted from <ref type="bibr" coords="2,134.62,437.13,18.48,9.94" target="#b9">[10]</ref> and some of them also described in Writeprints feature set <ref type="bibr" coords="2,420.02,437.13,17.05,9.94" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. Following are the features that we used:</p><p> TFIDF for character n-grams where n is between 1-6  TFIDF for n-grams of POS tags where n is between 1-3  TFIDF for n-grams of POS tag chunks where n is between 1-3  TFIDF for punctuation marks used in the text  Frequency of stop words  Count of characters in the text  Count of words in the text  Average character counts per word  Ratio of hapax-legomenon and dis-legomenon</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2.">Training the classifiers</head><p>We worked on two different classifiers with slight differences. The motivation behind the second classifier was to understand the impact of leaving some the problems unanswered in the borderline cases. Below we describe each one of them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2.2.1.">Classifier 1</head><p>Our custom classifier calculates the similarities of each pair of texts among themselves as well as with the individual authors' texts. This gives us three values for each author and pair of texts. For example, consider a case with three authors, A, B, C and a pair of text, say x1 and x2. Our classifier calculates the similarities between x1 and x2, A and x1, A and x2, B and x1, B and x2, C and x1 and C and x2 as shown in the Table <ref type="table" coords="3,201.24,87.04,4.17,9.94" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. This is repeated for each pair of text. For calculating the similarities we use cosine similarity. </p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="3,112.22,182.06,353.20,37.92">A-&gt;x1 A-&gt;x2 x1-&gt;x2 B B-&gt;x1 B-&gt;x2 x1-&gt;x2 C C-&gt;x1 C-&gt;x2 x1-&gt;x2</formula><p>For each pair of text we get the number of rows in the above table, equal to the number of authors in the input data set. We believe that all these three values are important and due to this our classifier tries to maximize these values. To achieve this, we identify a row which has the max value for the summation of all three distances, for each input text pair. We store all three values of such a row, let's say, s1, s2 and s3. Now we calculate a cutoff value for each column based on these values and a threshold value as mentioned below:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="3,244.01,326.50,270.74,37.99">cutoff1 = thr * s1 (1) cutoff2 = thr * s2 (2) cutoff3 = thr * s3<label>(3)</label></formula><p>where, thr is the threshold value. The purpose of the cutoff is to find out how far ahead are the best values for the cosine similarities from the rest of the values (cosine similarities of the pair of the text and the text from other authors).</p><p>In the next step, we try to find all rows for a pair with values above the cutoff values. If we get exactly one such row, we predict the pair written by the same author. In all other cases we predict the authors of the pair to be different.</p><p>This process is repeated for threshold values ranging from 0.2 to 1 to identify the value that gives us the best values for our predictions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.1.1.">Classifier 2</head><p>Classifier 2 is exactly the same as the classifier 1 with just one difference in the prediction. Classifier 2 leaves the problem unanswered if we get exactly two rows above the cutoff values. Classifier 1 in this case, predicts the authors of the pair to be different.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1.2.">Evaluation and Results</head><p>PAN 2023 evaluation set is used to evaluate the model. This evaluation uses 5 metrics against which the submissions are compared and ranked. While training our proposed model we used the 'overall' score which is the mean of all the 5 metrics used by the evaluator. Table <ref type="table" coords="3,406.01,647.28,5.52,9.94" target="#tab_2">3</ref> shows the results of our training runs for different threshold values ranging from 0.2 to 0.95 at step size of 0.05. We further tried to fine tune the threshold value by repeating the training process for threshold values ranging from 0.65 to 0.8 and step size of 0.01 and best value for threshold was chosen to be 0.69 which resulted in the best overall score of 0.785. We took this threshold and used it for the run of our system on the validation data set. Table <ref type="table" coords="4,248.67,314.47,5.52,9.94" target="#tab_3">4</ref> shows the overall score on both training and validation data sets. The proposed system with Classifier 1 (calm-lyrics) and Classifier 2 (null-midpoint) were then submitted on TIRA Platform <ref type="bibr" coords="4,201.34,450.21,18.51,9.94" target="#b11">[12]</ref> for PAN 2023 Cross Discourse Authorship Verification task <ref type="foot" coords="4,488.26,449.04,3.48,6.26" target="#foot_0">2</ref> and Table <ref type="table" coords="4,99.86,462.81,5.52,9.94" target="#tab_4">5</ref> shows the scores for the 5 metrics when the system was run on the training data provided by the platform. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Conclusion</head><p>The proposed system performed fairly in PAN 2023 Cross Discourse Authorship Verification task on the training data set. Although Classifier 2 got a slightly better C@1 and F1 score as it leaves some of the problems unanswered but the overall score was same as that of the classifier 1. As a future work we would like to look at the multi-feature key extraction more closely and analyse the impact of different combinations of features. We would also like to look at how we can improve our predictions when the authors of the test data set are unknown.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,72.02,74.06,394.02,55.08"><head>Table 1</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="2,72.02,87.50,394.02,41.64"><row><cell>Training and Validation data set sizes</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Training Set</cell><cell>Validation Set</cell></row><row><cell>Number of pairs</cell><cell>7068</cell><cell>1768</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="3,72.02,124.70,441.22,68.40"><head>Table 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="3,72.02,138.14,441.22,54.96"><row><cell>Cosine Similarities</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Author</cell><cell>Distance of x1 to Author</cell><cell>Distance of x2 to</cell><cell>Distance between x1 and x2</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Author</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>A</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="3,72.02,684.84,347.41,81.96"><head>Table 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="3,72.02,698.28,347.41,68.52"><row><cell>Various threshold values and corresponding overall score</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Threshold</cell><cell>Overall Score</cell></row><row><cell>0.2</cell><cell>0.677</cell></row><row><cell>0.25</cell><cell>0.677</cell></row><row><cell>0.3</cell><cell>0.677</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="4,72.02,352.13,427.25,69.98"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Results of our system on the training and validation data sets at threshold 0.69</figDesc><table coords="4,129.50,381.19,369.77,40.92"><row><cell>Classifier</cell><cell>Training set</cell><cell>Validation set</cell></row><row><cell>Classifier 1</cell><cell>0.785</cell><cell>0.763</cell></row><row><cell>Classifier 2</cell><cell>0.786</cell><cell>0.763</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="4,72.02,500.35,432.83,69.85"><head>Table 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Results from PAN 2023 Cross Discourse Authorship Verification 1</figDesc><table coords="4,85.82,529.54,419.03,40.66"><row><cell>Classifier</cell><cell>AUC</cell><cell>C@1</cell><cell>F_05_U</cell><cell>F1</cell><cell>Brier</cell><cell>Overall</cell></row><row><cell>classifier 1</cell><cell>0.985</cell><cell>0.781</cell><cell>0.745</cell><cell>0.815</cell><cell>0.847</cell><cell>0.835</cell></row><row><cell>classifier 2</cell><cell>0.984</cell><cell>0.783</cell><cell>0.742</cell><cell>0.82</cell><cell>0.845</cell><cell>0.835</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_0" coords="4,76.58,762.63,208.63,7.24"><p>https://pan.webis.de/clef23/pan23-web/author-identification.html</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.02,105.52,415.07,9.94;5,108.02,118.12,414.73,9.94;5,108.02,130.84,362.95,9.94" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,252.93,105.52,270.16,9.94;5,108.02,118.12,30.64,9.94">Taveer: an interpretable topic-agnostic authorship verification method</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Halvani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Graner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Regev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,353.10,118.12,169.65,9.94;5,108.02,130.84,228.11,9.94">ARES 2020: The 15th International Conference on Availability, Reliability and Security</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Volkamer</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Wressnegger</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="41" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.02,143.44,415.03,9.94;5,108.02,156.16,334.76,9.94" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,217.43,143.44,238.03,9.94">Improving author verification based on topic modeling</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Potha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,462.88,143.44,60.17,9.94;5,108.02,156.16,233.52,9.94">Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1074" to="1088" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.02,168.76,414.72,9.94;5,108.02,181.48,415.09,9.94;5,108.02,194.08,414.99,9.94;5,108.02,206.68,414.81,9.94;5,108.02,219.40,415.06,9.94;5,108.02,232.03,415.18,9.94;5,108.02,244.75,187.44,9.94" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,264.93,194.08,258.08,9.94;5,108.02,206.68,278.57,9.94">Overview of PAN 2022: AuthorshipVerification, Profiling Irony and Stereotype Spreaders, and Style Change Detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bevendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Chulvi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Fersini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kestemont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kredens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mayerl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ortega-Bueno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pezik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Rangel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wolska</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Zangerle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,223.37,232.03,299.84,9.94;5,108.02,244.75,85.33,9.94">Proceedings of theThirteenth International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Cedeno</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">D S</forename><surname>Martino</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Esposti</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Sebastiani</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Pasi</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hanbury</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Faggioli</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>theThirteenth International Conference of the CLEF Association (CLEF</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022. 2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.02,257.35,414.71,9.94;5,108.02,269.95,415.17,9.94;5,108.02,282.67,342.62,9.94" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,137.16,269.95,264.31,9.94">Overview of the Authorship Verification Task at PAN</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kestemont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kredens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pezik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Heini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bevendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="CEUR-WS.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,411.02,269.95,112.18,9.94;5,108.02,282.67,232.54,9.94">Working Notes of CLEF 2022 -Conference and Labs of the Evaluation Forum</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022. 2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.02,295.27,414.79,9.94;5,108.02,307.99,415.13,9.94;5,108.02,320.59,414.74,9.94;5,108.02,333.19,415.04,9.94;5,108.02,345.91,147.03,9.94" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,377.32,307.99,145.83,9.94;5,108.02,320.59,195.05,9.94">Overview of the Cross-Domain Authorship Verification Task at PAN 2020</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Kestemont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Enrique</forename><surname>Manjavacas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ilia</forename><surname>Markov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Janek</forename><surname>Bevendorff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Matti</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Efstathios</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="CEUR-WS.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,277.25,333.19,154.65,9.94">CLEF 2020 Labs and Workshops</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Linda</forename><surname>Cappellato</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carsten</forename><surname>Eickhoff</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aurélie</forename><surname>Névéol</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-09">September 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Notebook Papers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.02,358.51,414.84,9.94;5,108.02,371.23,415.03,9.94;5,108.02,383.85,415.16,9.94;5,108.02,396.45,415.05,9.94;5,108.02,409.17,26.51,9.94" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,202.88,371.23,320.17,9.94;5,108.02,383.85,213.14,9.94">Overview of the author identification task at PAN-2018: cross-domain authorship attribution and style change detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kestemont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Tschuggnall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Daelemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Specht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,340.09,383.85,183.09,9.94;5,108.02,396.45,69.54,9.94">Working Notes Papers of the CLEF 2018 Evaluation Labs</title>
		<editor>et al.</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Avignon, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-09-10">2018. September 10-14, 2018/Cappellato</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="25" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.02,421.77,414.81,9.94;5,108.02,434.49,415.05,9.94;5,108.02,447.09,414.83,9.94;5,108.02,459.69,415.11,9.94;5,108.02,472.41,249.00,9.94" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,417.54,434.49,105.53,9.94;5,108.02,447.09,125.13,9.94">Overview of the Author Identification Task at PAN</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Efstathios</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Walter</forename><surname>Daelemans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Verhoeven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Juola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Sanchez-Perez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alberto</forename><surname>Barrón-Cedeño</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,209.10,459.69,249.91,9.94">Working Notes Papers of the CLEF 2014 Evaluation Labs</title>
		<title level="s" coord="5,120.01,472.41,155.22,9.94">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Linda</forename><surname>Cappellato</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>Ferro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Halvey</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wessel</forename><surname>Kraaij</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-09">2014. September 2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1180</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,108.02,485.01,414.71,9.94;5,108.02,497.73,415.11,9.94;5,108.02,510.22,415.04,10.05;5,108.02,523.05,66.95,9.94" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,290.80,485.01,231.93,9.94;5,108.02,497.73,19.87,9.94">Overview of the Author Identification Task at PAN 2013</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Juola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Efstathios</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="CEUR-WS.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,397.27,497.73,125.86,9.94;5,108.02,510.22,175.00,10.05">CLEF 2013 Evaluation Labs and Workshop -Working Notes Papers</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pamela</forename><surname>Forner</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roberto</forename><surname>Navigli</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Tufis</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Valencia, Spain</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-09">23-26 September. September 2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,112.58,535.68,410.53,9.94;5,112.58,548.28,410.56,9.94;5,112.58,561.00,94.43,9.94" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,423.22,535.68,99.89,9.94;5,112.58,548.28,139.40,9.94">Cross-Discourse Type Authorship Verification at PAN</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Rosso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Efstathios</forename><surname>Stamatatos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Benno</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="-WS.org" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,295.27,548.28,142.78,9.94">CLEF 2023 Labs and Workshops</title>
		<title level="s" coord="5,445.51,548.28,77.63,9.94;5,112.58,561.00,23.20,9.94">Notebook Papers, CEUR</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023. 2023</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,112.58,573.60,410.50,9.94;5,112.58,586.32,410.62,9.94;5,112.58,598.92,22.08,9.94" xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,308.89,573.60,214.19,9.94;5,112.58,586.32,410.62,9.94">Feature Vector Difference based Neural Network and Logistic Regression Models for Authorship Verification&quot; Notebook for PAN at CLEF</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Janith</forename><surname>Weerasinghe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Rachel</forename><surname>Greenstadt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,112.58,611.52,410.54,9.94;5,112.58,624.24,410.18,9.94;5,112.58,636.84,51.24,9.94" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,222.91,611.52,300.21,9.94;5,112.58,624.24,166.52,9.94">Writeprints: A stylometric approach to identity-level identification and similarity detection in cyberspace</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">.</forename><surname>Abbasi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,287.02,624.24,193.74,9.94">ACM Transactions on Information Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2008-01">01 2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,112.58,649.56,410.57,9.94;5,112.58,662.16,410.57,9.94;5,112.58,674.76,82.71,9.94" xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,169.94,662.16,289.35,9.94">Continuous Integration for Reproducible Shared Tasks with TIRA</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Froebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Wiegmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kolyada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Grahm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Elstner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Loebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Potthast</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2023">2023</date>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="241" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
