<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,156.20,116.95,302.95,12.62;1,146.41,134.89,322.53,12.62">Scalewelis: a Scalable Query-based Faceted Search System on Top of SPARQL Endpoints</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,225.06,172.56,75.86,8.74"><forename type="first">Joris</forename><surname>Guyonvarch</surname></persName>
							<email>joris.guyonvarch@gmail.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">IRISA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Université de Rennes</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1 ; Campus de Beaulieu</addrLine>
									<postCode>35042</postCode>
									<settlement>Rennes cedex</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,323.63,172.56,66.67,8.74"><forename type="first">Sébastien</forename><surname>Ferré</surname></persName>
							<email>ferre@irisa.fr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">IRISA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Université de Rennes</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1 ; Campus de Beaulieu</addrLine>
									<postCode>35042</postCode>
									<settlement>Rennes cedex</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,156.20,116.95,302.95,12.62;1,146.41,134.89,322.53,12.62">Scalewelis: a Scalable Query-based Faceted Search System on Top of SPARQL Endpoints</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">7D0237D6F331D8C3DACC3492893E2C7A</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:34+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper overviews the participation of Scalewelis in the QALD-3 open challenge. Scalewelis is a Faceted Search system. Faceted Search systems refine the result set at each navigation step. In Scalewelis, refinements are syntactic operations that modify the user query. Scalewelis uses the Semantic Web standards (URI, RDF, SPARQL) and connects to SPARQL endpoints.</p><p>1 Scalewelis has been implemented as a Web application and is available at: http://lisfs2008.irisa.fr/scalewelis/</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.276" lry="841.89"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>We participated with Scalewelis in the question answering task of the QALD-3 open challenge for DBpedia. This task was about answering a hundred questions formulated in several languages. The answer could be given either as a SPARQL query or directly as a list of results. SPARQL is a very expressive language that is based on graph patterns and relational algebra but it requires an important background for those who want to use it. We discuss two alternatives to SPARQL that are Question Answering and Faceted Search.</p><p>Question Answering (QA) gives answers to natural questions or keywords rather than from formal queries. For example, Querix <ref type="bibr" coords="1,371.11,460.58,10.52,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref> asks for users to write full English questions and, then, there is a dialog between Querix and users that clarifies ambiguities. However, question answering does not prevent dead ends, i.e. empty results.</p><p>Faceted Search guides users with feedback. The result set is incrementally refined by the selection of facets. A facet selection always leads to non-empty results, so that there are no dead ends. For example, VisiNav <ref type="bibr" coords="1,407.87,532.31,10.52,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref> is a set-based Faceted Search system that applies operations to the result set. gFacet <ref type="bibr" coords="1,450.99,544.27,10.52,8.74" target="#b4">[5]</ref> is a graph-based Faceted Search system that applies operations to the result graph. Sewelis [2] is a query-based Faceted Search system that applies operations to the query.</p><p>Scalewelis 1 is inspired from Sewelis. Sewelis manages its own data structures and does not scale to large datasets such as DBpedia. On the contrary, Scalewelis connects to SPARQL endpoints and uses partial result sets in order to scale to large datasets. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Approach</head><p>Query-based Faceted Search allows for more expressive search than traditional set-based Faceted Search. In Sewelis and Scalewelis, facets are query elements and selecting a facet adds it to the search query. Only valid facets are provided, so that navigation is safe: there are no dead ends. Facets are computed from the results of the previous query. Scalewelis uses only a subset of those results. In experiments on datasets of up to 15 millions triples, automatically generated with the Berlin SPARQL Benchmark <ref type="bibr" coords="2,279.08,561.04,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, the partial computation of facets required far less time than the complete computation. Moreover, it nonetheless gave all the facets in most cases <ref type="bibr" coords="2,240.98,584.95,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. At the initial step, Scalewelis retrieves all classes in the dataset (Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,468.97,597.34,3.87,8.74">1</ref>). Properties can be computed in a similar manner but are not in the current implementation for efficiency reasons. In the next steps, partial results and facets are computed with four successive SPARQL queries (Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,392.85,633.20,3.87,8.74">2</ref>). Query 1 retrieves the first 1,000 results matching &lt;Pattern&gt;, which is the SPARQL graph pattern translated from the user query. Queries 1, 2, and 3 incorporate those results in order to retrieve the facets for the current query, using the VALUES construct of SPARQL. Query 2 retrieves the types of the results, i.e. classes. Query 3 retrieves the properties linking from the results. Query 4 retrieves the property linking to the results, i.e. inverse properties. Finally, the selection of a facet by the user modifies the query so that it is more constrained but is ensured to return results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Resources</head><p>Regarding the QALD-3 open challenge, Scalewelis was connected to the standard DBpedia SPARQL endpoint because response times of the provided endpoint were too long for effective use. The process is intrinsically interactive and we acted as the user. We answered 70 questions out of 99, requiring a few minutes per question (human and machine time). Two kinds of questions were not addressed. Firstly, questions involving quantities (such as Which German cities have more than 250000 inhabitants?) because filters and aggregations are not yet implemented in Scalewelis. Secondly, questions for which facets were not found by the user. In general, it was unclear whether those facets were not listed (due to partial results) or whether the user was not knowledgeable enough to identify the right facet (for example Give me all B-sides of the Ramones.).</p><p>One of the question in the challenge is Which films starring Clint Eastwood did he direct himself ?. We explain how we answered this question with Scalewelis. At the initialization step, the user filtered the list of classes with the word film. The selection of the class a dbo:Film led to the query What is a dbo:Film?. At this step, there are property facets and the selection of has dbo:starring and has dbo:director led to the query What is a dbo:Film and has dbo:starring a thing and has dbo:director a thing?. Finally, the selection of the result Clint Eastwood at the two undefined element represented by a thing led to the final user query: What is a dbo:Film and has dbo:starring dbr:Clint Eastwood and has dbo:director dbr:Clint Eastwood?.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>Scalewelis ranked third out of six candidates with 32 correct answers plus 1 partial answer. Scalewelis was theoretically able to correctly answer the 70 questions the user chose to answer, but he failed to answer 37 of them because incorrect facets were chosen.</p><p>1. Firstly, English is not the mother tongue of the user so that incorrect facets were used because of misunderstandings. 2. Secondly, the user had sometimes the choice between two facets differing only by their namespace, for example DBpedia ontology and infobox properties. 3. Thirdly, the standard DBpedia SPARQL endpoint to which Scalewelis was connected sometimes gave different results compared to the provided SPARQL endpoint.</p><p>Scalewelis can be improved in several ways. First, there are missing functionalities from SPARQL such as comparisons or aggregations. Second, the partial computation of results and facets entails a bias in the search, because the first results returned by SPARQL may not form a representative sample of all results. Third, Scalewelis could take advantage of the DBpedia ontology to further improve scalability, and to display facets as class/property hierarchies.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="2,207.74,158.75,199.87,7.89;2,134.77,179.57,276.28,7.86;2,134.77,199.15,145.93,7.47;2,148.89,210.11,42.37,7.47;2,134.77,221.07,56.49,7.47;2,134.77,239.35,244.17,7.86;2,134.77,258.93,141.22,7.47;2,148.89,269.88,150.63,7.47;2,148.89,280.84,84.73,7.47;2,134.77,299.13,258.05,7.86;2,134.77,318.70,136.51,7.47;2,148.89,329.66,150.63,7.47;2,148.89,340.62,84.73,7.47;2,134.77,358.90,289.69,7.86;2,134.77,378.48,150.64,7.47;2,148.89,389.44,150.63,7.47;2,148.89,400.40,98.85,7.47"><head>Fig. 1 .Query 1 :Query 4 :Fig. 2 .</head><label>1142</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Computation of classes at the initial step. Query 1: Computation of the partial results, limited to 1,000 entities SELECT DISTINCT ?result WHERE { &lt;Pattern&gt; } LIMIT 1000 Query 2: Computation of class facets from the partial results SELECT DISTINCT ?class WHERE { VALUES (?result) {res1 ... resN} ?result a ?class } Query 3: Computation of property facets from the partial results SELECT DISTINCT ?prop WHERE { VALUES (?result) {res1 ... resN} ?result ?prop [] } Query 4: Computation of inverse property facets from the partial results SELECT DISTINCT ?invProp WHERE { VALUES (?result) {res1 ... resN} [] ?invProp ?result }</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.35,259.15,342.24,7.86;4,146.91,270.11,275.44,7.86" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,240.71,259.15,131.65,7.86">The Berlin SPARQL Benchmark</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bizer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Schultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,380.86,259.15,99.73,7.86;4,146.91,270.11,203.25,7.86">International Journal on Semantic Web and Information Systems (IJSWIS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,146.91,281.07,333.69,7.86;4,146.91,292.03,165.03,7.86" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,249.83,281.07,230.77,7.86;4,146.91,292.03,51.83,7.86">Reconciling faceted search and query languages for the semantic web</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ferré</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,206.36,292.03,28.80,7.86">IJMSO</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="54" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.35,302.99,342.24,7.86;4,146.91,313.95,333.68,7.86;4,146.91,324.90,55.97,7.86" xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Guyonvarch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ferré</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ducassé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="4,307.72,302.99,172.87,7.86;4,146.91,313.95,265.58,7.86">Scalable query-based faceted search on top of SPARQL endpoints for guided and expressive semantic search</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>IRISA</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">research report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.35,335.86,342.24,7.86;4,146.91,346.82,105.47,7.86" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,190.95,335.86,254.71,7.86">VisiNav: A system for visual search and navigation on web data</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Harth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,452.57,335.86,28.02,7.86;4,146.91,346.82,19.46,7.86">J. Web Sem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="348" to="354" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.35,357.78,342.25,7.86;4,146.91,368.74,333.68,7.86;4,146.91,379.70,62.50,7.86" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,266.16,357.78,210.64,7.86">Facet Graphs: Complex semantic querying made easy</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Heim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Ertl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ziegler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,229.85,368.74,41.56,7.86">ESWC (1)</title>
		<title level="s" coord="4,333.27,368.74,143.35,7.86">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<editor>et al, L.A.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="288" to="302" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="4,138.35,390.66,342.24,7.86;4,146.91,401.62,333.68,7.86;4,146.91,412.58,42.50,7.86" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,271.84,390.66,208.75,7.86;4,146.91,401.62,232.78,7.86">Evaluating the usability of natural language query languages and interfaces to semantic web knowledge bases</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kaufmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bernstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="4,386.61,401.62,50.64,7.86">J. Web Sem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="377" to="393" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
