<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.80,83.76,464.13,15.48">From Blogs to News: Identifying Hot Topics in the Blogosphere</title>
				<funder ref="#_VmxCD5E">
					<orgName type="full">Netherlands Organisation for Scientific Research (NWO)</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_AZKmDy7 #_wq9wcz8 #_APugKG2 #_E2DqnBu #_BxMvx7p">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_V6nWj4p">
					<orgName type="full">Dutch and Flemish Governments</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,154.67,116.28,97.60,10.75"><forename type="first">Wouter</forename><surname>Weerkamp</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">ISLA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,267.21,116.28,82.71,10.75"><forename type="first">Manos</forename><surname>Tsagkias</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">ISLA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,364.86,116.28,90.19,10.75"><forename type="first">Maarten</forename><surname>De Rijke</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">ISLA</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Amsterdam</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,72.80,83.76,464.13,15.48">From Blogs to News: Identifying Hot Topics in the Blogosphere</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">3A00E6321829E5163C60267323C69403</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We describe the participation of the University of Amsterdam's ILPS group in the blog track at TREC 2009. We focus on the top stories identification task, and take an approach that does not require the headlines of top stories to be known beforehand. We explore the feasibility of a so-called blogs to news approach: given a date and a set of blog posts, identify the main topics for that date. This approach is more general than just finding top stories, but it can still be applied to the task of headline ranking. Results show that this general approach, applied to the task at hand, is among the top performing approaches in this year's TREC.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This year's Blog track consisted of two tasks: top stories identification and faceted blog distillation. The latter task is very similar to the "regular" blog distillation task that ran during the previous two TREC years <ref type="bibr" coords="1,206.97,427.36,65.61,8.64">(2007 and 2008)</ref>, except for the addition of "facets" (e.g. in-depth, opinionated, or personal). Because of the similarity between the faceted blog distillation task and previous tasks, we felt that our focus should be on the new top stories task, and we therefore dedicated most of our time and effort to submitting to the top stories identification task.</p><p>The second task, top stories identification, is new; the goal is to identify top stories for a given day using information from the blogosphere, and provide a listing of blog posts that support the selection of a top story. The underlying scenario is one of a news provider (in possession of news headlines) trying to rank these headlines based on what people write about news stories in their blogs. For the identification part, it calls for an approach described in the following steps:</p><p>1. construct a "query" from headline; 2. limit results to the given date; 3. count the number of relevant posts; 4. rank headlines based on these counts.</p><p>The steps above reveal two limitations: (i) headlines are needed in advance, and (ii) topics from the blogosphere can only emerge when they are about news events reported by mainstream media. In an effort to alleviate these limitations, we take on the task from a different angle:</p><p>1. observe posts from the given date;</p><p>2. see what differentiates these posts from previous posts; 3. display the emerging topics; 4. rank headlines by their similarity to the emerging topics.</p><p>Although the algorithm can stop one step short, the last step is designated to provide compatibility with the task at hand. In our participation we investigate the potential of both approaches and report on initial evaluation of the results. For the second step of the top stories identification task, namely, to provide evidence for the importance of a headline, we chose to select the top blog posts ranked by the number of their respective comments.</p><p>In the remainder of this paper we first describe the data and preprocessing for both tasks (Section 2), then, we introduce our top stories identification approaches (Section 3). We report on the performance of the submitted runs, and perform some additional analysis in Sections 4 and 5. Finally, we report on some initial conclusions for this year's Blog track participation in Section 6.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Data and Preprocessing</head><p>The dataset provided by TREC is the new Blogs08 collection; the collection consists of a crawl of feeds, permalinks, and homepages of 1,303,520 blogs during early 2008-early 2009. This crawl results in a total of 28,488,766 blogs posts (or permalinks). In our experiments we only used feed data, that is, the textual content of blog posts distributed by feeds (e.g. RSS) and ignored the permalinks. Two main reasons underly this decision: (i) the tasks (and especially the top stories task) are precision-oriented and benefit from a very clean collection; and (ii) using feed data requires almost no preprocessing of the data (e.g. no html-removal, etc.). Extracting posts from the feed data gave us a coverage of 97.7% <ref type="bibr" coords="1,346.37,698.87,114.63,8.64">(27,833,965 posts extracted)</ref>. As a second preprocessing step we perform language detection and remove all non-English blog posts from our corpus , leaving us with 16,869,555 blogs posts . We construct two indexes, one based on the full content of blog posts and one on only the blog post titles. Additional to the indexing, we extract features that can prove useful in both tasks. Extracted features are: number of comments, post length, number of spelling errors, number of shouted words, number of emoticons, and ratio of first person pronouns.</p><p>Part of the top stories task is a collection of 102,812 news headlines from the New York Times. We created a separate index of this collection, resulting in an average news headline length of 11 words. Finally, we have 55 dates designating the topics for the top stories task.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Significance testing</head><p>Throughout the paper we use a two-tailed paired t-test to test for significant differences between runs. We report on significant increases (or drops) for p &lt; 0.01 using (and ) and for p &lt; 0.05 using (and ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Approaches</head><p>As explained in the introduction, we contrast two main approaches in identifying top stories: (i) starting from the news headlines, or (ii) starting from the blog posts. In our participation we explore the potential of both approaches and compare their results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">News to Blogs</head><p>Given the scenario where news headlines are known beforehand, they can be used as starting points for identifying top stories on a given date. As explained before, this scenario is limited, but definitely worth investigating. Our is approach is as follows: we want to estimate the probability of a news headline given a date, and rank news headlines based on this probability. We use an expert finding model from <ref type="bibr" coords="2,278.51,507.77,9.59,8.64;2,53.80,519.72,63.58,8.64">Balog et al. (2006)</ref> (more specific Model 2) and modify it to fit the data at hand. Although the model allows us to explicitly define a post's importance for a given date, we assume all posts to be equi-important (i.e., the probability of the post given the date is uniform).</p><p>We run the approach on both a post index (run IlpsTSHlP) and a title-only index (run IlpsTSHlT). The reason for using the title-only index is that we expect bloggers to use important (news) terms in their post titles, so that matching the headline to the title would result in acceptable rankings as well.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Blogs to News</head><p>Following the second scenario where the news headlines are unknown, we need to extract information from the blog posts without any prior knowledge of what is in the news. To this end, we take the top 5,000 blog posts from a given date, ordered by their respective number of comments. We then combine these posts and identify distinguishing terms between them and a background corpus. The background corpus consists of the remainder of the blog posts. These steps (covering steps 1 and 2 from the introduction) result in a set of weighted terms, where the weight indicates a term's "distinctiveness" for the given date. Based on co-occurrence statistics, the terms are clustered, leaving us with the topics that emerge from the blog posts. Up to here our approach is general as no news headlines are required. An example of the generated output, is shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,475.15,188.78,3.74,8.64" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Terms</head><p>News event To use this approach for the task at hand, we need a way of matching the extracted information to the news headlines. We index the news headlines and use the extracted term clusters to query the headline index. Headlines are ranked based on the distinctiveness of the terms, and if more than one headline matches a query, we select a maximum of 10 headlines for this "topic".</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,324.09,230.96,24.90,8.64">ledger</formula><p>As with the previous approach, we run this on both a post index (IlpsTSExP) and a title-only index (IlpsTSExT). Here, we expect the title-only representation to contain less noise (less indistinctive terms) and therefore be able to better get the important terms on top.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results</head><p>The results of our submitted runs are displayed in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,541.25,591.27,3.74,8.64">2</ref>.</p><p>The top two lines represent the two approaches on the post index and the lower two lines on the title-only index. The first observation is that the blogs to news approach significantly outperforms the news to blogs approach on all metrics and for both indexes. Looking at each approach individually, we see that for the news to blogs approach the difference between the two indexes is not significant. For the blogs to news approach the performance of the post index is significantly better than the title-only index for MAP and MRR.</p><p>Comparing </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Analysis</head><p>We perform some initial analysis on our submissions, and do so in three ways: (i) looking at the ordering before sampling blog posts, (ii) exploring how large our sample of blog posts should be, and (iii) detailing two dates for which our approach either works well or does not. As detailed in Section 3, the blogs to news approach depends on a sample of blog posts for a given date. Sampling these posts from the set of posts for a day can be done in various ways; in our baseline we order posts by the number of comments they receive, and take the top 5,000 posts for a day. We now look at the influence of other orderings (length of a post, and random sampling), and the influence of different sample sizes. To start with the first question, Table <ref type="table" coords="3,287.92,603.23,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_2">4</ref> shows the results of the three ways of ordering posts before selecting them.</p><p>The results show that ordering by post length can lead to improved early precision, but does hurt MAP slightly. Choosing a (reasonable) way of ordering improves over selecting just random posts as sample. Now we shift to the size of the sample: Here we experiment with three different sample sizes to show how this influences the results. Note that we are not looking for an optimal value, but merely want to see the behavior of our approach. Table <ref type="table" coords="3,522.54,166.93,4.98,8.64">5</ref> shows the results for using ordering on comments, and taking the top 500, 5,000, and 50,000 posts.</p><p>Sample size MAP P5 MRR 500 0.0418 0.1709 0.3057 5,000 0.1354 0.2655 0.4271 50,000 0.1050 0.2145 0.4057 Table <ref type="table" coords="3,379.75,281.57,3.88,8.64">5</ref>: Results of various sample sizes.</p><p>We can tell from the results that it is probably better to take a larger sample than a smaller one: Results drop significantly going from 5,000 to only 500 posts. If we take more posts into account, we also observe a drop in performance, but not as big as when going down in sample size. Further research is required on how we can determine the optimal number of posts in our sample.</p><p>Finally, we look at two dates for which our approach showed either good or bad performance: First is topic 30, August 8, 2008. Table <ref type="table" coords="3,412.48,413.09,4.98,8.64" target="#tab_3">6</ref> shows the extracted topics on the left, and the headlines that where matched against this topic (and judged relevant) on the right. Similarly, we list the data for topic 19 <ref type="bibr" coords="3,365.79,448.96,62.26,8.64">(May 12, 2008)</ref> in Table <ref type="table" coords="3,465.16,448.96,3.74,8.64" target="#tab_4">7</ref>.</p><p>From these two topics we can conclude three things: (i) our approach works well for major events in the news (Georgia-Russia conflict, opening of Olympics), but also for smaller, more local events (Brett Favre joining the New York Jets), (ii) the output generated by the approach is usable in more settings than just headline ranking, and (iii) topics that come up are not always news related (Mother's Day).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Conclusions</head><p>This year we focused on the new top stories identification task: use the blogosphere to rank news headlines. We follow two general approaches: news to blogs, and blogs to news. The former starts from the news headlines, uses them as queries, and ranks these queries according to the headline likelihood. The latter is more general and tries to identify topics that emerge from the blogosphere. It is only in the final step that this approach tries to link these topics to news headline (by using the topics as a query against a headline index). In our experiments, the blogs to news approach that is independent of a given day's news headlines outperforms the news to blogs approach on all reported metrics and the difference in performance is measured statistically significant. Other participants in the blog track however, showed that the news to blogs approach can be successful as well.</p><p>Further exploration of the system parameters revealed that using a title-only representation of blog posts does not lead to improvement, neither on recall-based metrics (as expected) nor on precision-based metrics. Both, the ordering of blog posts before selection and the sample size, make a difference in performance of the blogs to news approach. Finally, the examples show that our approach can (i) identify major and minor news events using blog posts, (ii) construct output that is more general than just headlines, and (iii) identify hot topics that are not news related.</p><p>Future work focuses on exploring the optimal sample size of blog posts, applying more elaborate models to the top stories identification task and see how we can use additional (external) information to identify emerging topics, or use explicit links and references to news events for this task.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,316.81,230.96,239.10,154.10"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Example of top emerging terms (left) and related news events (right) for January 22, 2008.</figDesc><table coords="2,324.09,230.96,224.56,107.33"><row><cell>heath actor</cell><cell cols="2">Actor Heath Ledger dies</cell></row><row><cell>roe abortion</cell><cell cols="2">Roe v. Wade case on</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">abortion; March for Life</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>2008</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>romney mitt huckabee</cell><cell>Republican</cell><cell>primaries</cell></row><row><cell>thompson gop ...</cell><cell>2008</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="3">luther martin king african dr Martin Luther King Day</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>2008</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="2,373.68,710.82,182.24,8.64"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>results to other participants in the blog track, Results of our best run, the best run at TREC 2009, and the median of all participants.</figDesc><table coords="3,53.80,58.19,239.10,304.01"><row><cell cols="2">Approach MAP</cell><cell>P5</cell><cell>MRR</cell><cell>RunID</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">b-to-n (p) 0.1354</cell><cell>0.2655</cell><cell>0.4271</cell><cell>IlpsTSExP</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">n-to-b (p) 0.0083</cell><cell>0.0291</cell><cell>0.1119</cell><cell>IlpsTSHlP</cell></row><row><cell>b-to-n (t)</cell><cell>0.0756</cell><cell>0.2036</cell><cell>0.2670</cell><cell>IlpsTSExT</cell></row><row><cell>n-to-b (t)</cell><cell>0.0085</cell><cell>0.0545</cell><cell>0.0958</cell><cell>IlpsTSHlT</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Table 2: Results of our submitted runs of top stories identifi-</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">cation task for the blogs to news (b-to-n) and news to blogs</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">(n-to-b) approaches on a (p)ost index or (t)itle index.</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">we are in the top 3 performing runs on all reported metrics</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">(MAP, P5, and MRR). Table 3 shows the results of our best</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">run compared to the best run at TREC 2009, and the median</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">of all participants. Interesting to see is that the two other top</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">performing runs at TREC used our news to blog approach,</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">which indicates that our run of this type could still improve.</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Nevertheless, our more general approach is reasonably close</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">to the best news to blogs runs, while maintaining its general</cell></row><row><cell>nature.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Run</cell><cell></cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>P5</cell><cell>MRR</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">Best (uogTr) 0.1862 0.3236 0.5390</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Median</cell><cell cols="2">0.0445 -</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">b-to-n (p)</cell><cell cols="3">0.1354 0.2655 0.4271</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="3,316.81,58.19,239.10,86.31"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Results of various ways of ordering posts before selecting them.</figDesc><table coords="3,355.05,58.19,162.62,49.50"><row><cell>Ordering</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>P5</cell><cell>MRR</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Comments 0.1354 0.2655 0.4271</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">Post length 0.1145 0.2982 0.4959</cell></row><row><cell>Random</cell><cell cols="3">0.1041 0.2327 0.3892</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="4,59.78,59.80,500.67,263.27"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Example of top emerging terms (left) and judged relevant headlines (right) for August 8, 2008.</figDesc><table coords="4,59.78,59.80,500.67,263.27"><row><cell>Terms</cell><cell></cell><cell>Relevant headlines</cell></row><row><cell>ossetia georgian georgia russia russian</cell><cell></cell><cell>Russia and Georgia clash over breakaway region</cell></row><row><cell>conflict region troops</cell><cell></cell><cell>Georgian troops enter breakaway enclave in region's fiercest fighting in years</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>From Green Bay to Broadway: Favre is a Jet</cell></row><row><cell>favre jets</cell><cell></cell><cell>Sports of the times; In Favre the Jets have a tiger by the tail</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Jets 24, Browns 20; As Favre sits, another Brett is impressive</cell></row><row><cell>edwards affair hunter abc elizabeth</cell><cell></cell><cell>Edwards admits to affair in 2006</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">olympics beijing olympic athletes ceremony</cell><cell>Games open in a new China, dazzling an age of new media</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">china opening sports chinese games coverage Olympic message to some in Beijing is "please leave"</cell></row><row><cell>Terms</cell><cell cols="2">Relevant headlines</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">mothers moms mother mommy recipe -flowers dish egg garden sauce mom ...</cell></row><row><cell>nba</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>hezbollah</cell><cell cols="2">Hezbollah begins to withdraw gunmen in Beirut after 4 days of street battles</cell></row><row><cell>earthquake</cell><cell>-</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="4,101.38,349.24,406.96,8.64"><head>Table 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Example of top emerging terms (left) and judged relevant headlines (right) for May 12, 2008.</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0" coords="4,316.81,435.18,239.10,8.64;4,326.78,447.14,229.14,8.64;4,326.78,458.91,40.67,8.59"><p>Balog, K., Azzopardi, L., and de Rijke, M. (2006). Formal models for expert finding in enterprise corpora. In SIGIR'06.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="7">Acknowledgments</head><p>This research was supported by the <rs type="projectName">DuOMAn</rs> project carried out within the <rs type="programName">STEVIN programme</rs> which is funded by the <rs type="funder">Dutch and Flemish Governments</rs> (http://www. stevin-tst.org) under project number <rs type="grantNumber">STE-09-12</rs>, and by the <rs type="funder">Netherlands Organisation for Scientific Research (NWO)</rs> under project numbers <rs type="grantNumber">640. 001.501</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">640.002.501</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">612.066.-512</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">612.061.814</rs>, <rs type="grantNumber">612.061.815</rs>, and <rs type="grantNumber">640.004.802</rs>,</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_V6nWj4p">
					<idno type="grant-number">STE-09-12</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">DuOMAn</orgName>
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">STEVIN programme</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_VmxCD5E">
					<idno type="grant-number">640. 001.501</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_AZKmDy7">
					<idno type="grant-number">640.002.501</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_wq9wcz8">
					<idno type="grant-number">612.066.-512</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_APugKG2">
					<idno type="grant-number">612.061.814</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_E2DqnBu">
					<idno type="grant-number">612.061.815</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_BxMvx7p">
					<idno type="grant-number">640.004.802</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
