<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,116.02,148.86,370.97,15.15">IIIT-H at ImageCLEF Wikipedia MM 2009</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,250.39,182.75,102.23,8.74"><forename type="first">Srinivasarao</forename><surname>Vundavalli</surname></persName>
							<email>srinivasarao@research.iiit.ac.in</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">International Institute of Information Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>500032</postCode>
									<settlement>Hyderabad</settlement>
									<region>Andhra Pradesh</region>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,116.02,148.86,370.97,15.15">IIIT-H at ImageCLEF Wikipedia MM 2009</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">FE305628647825F87CA9C073B16322CE</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:21+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.3 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: H.3.1 Content Analysis and Indexing</term>
					<term>H.3.3 Information Search and Retrieval</term>
					<term>H.3.4 Systems and Software</term>
					<term>H.3.7 Digital Libraries TF-IDF, Information Retrieval, Image Retrieval, Vector Space Model, Boolean Model</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper, we describe the IIITH retrieval system used for the ImageCLEF Wikipedia MM task. The system automatically ranks the most similar images to a given textual query. The system preprocesses the data set in order to remove the non-informative terms. For each query, the system finds a ranked list of its most similar images using the textual information only.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>ImageCLEFs WikipediaMM uses image collection created and employed by the INEX competition <ref type="bibr" coords="1,90.00,510.53,9.97,8.74">[1]</ref>. This image collection contains approximately 150,000 images that cover diverse topics of interest. These images are associated with unstructured and noisy textual annotations in English. There are 75 topics as the query to be searched on the collection. Each topic consists of textual data (and/or sample images and/or concepts) describing a users (multimedia) information need. These data are given as the XML files in each one there is image textual information such as image title, image concept, image location path and a short text which describes the desired results, i.e it explains what could be the relevant result and what is the irrelevant results. The aim of this task is to try to find as many relevant images as possible from the Wikipedia image collection for a given textual-and/or-visual query.</p><p>Section 2 describes the models we used in our experiments, in section 3 we show the results we obtained and finally section 4 concludes the notes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Models</head><p>Our system uses a combination of the Vector Space Model (VSM) of Information Retrieval and the Boolean model to determine how relevant a given Document is to a User's query. In general, the idea behind the VSM is the more times a query term appears in a document relative to the number of times the term appears in all the documents in the collection, the more relevant that document is to the query. It uses the Boolean model to first narrow down the documents that need to be scored based on the use of boolean logic in the Query specification.</p><p>The score is calculated based on TF-IDF model <ref type="bibr" coords="2,309.08,112.02,13.19,8.74" target="#b0">[2]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Term Frequency-Inverse Document Frequency Model</head><p>In the TF-IDF model <ref type="bibr" coords="2,189.34,158.30,9.97,8.74" target="#b0">[2]</ref>, each document in the collection and a query are represented by their associated vector of the length of the vocabulary.</p><p>tf (t in d) correlates to the term's frequency, defined as the number of times term t appears in the currently scored document d. Documents that have more occurrences of a given term receive a higher score. The default computation of tf (t in d) in our system is sq.rt(f requency). idf (t) stands for Inverse Document Frequency. This value correlates to the inverse of docF req (the number of documents in which the term t appears). This means rarer terms give higher contribution to the total score. The default computation of idf (t) in our system is 1+log(numDocs/(docF req+ 1))</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Vector Space Model(VSM)</head><p>In a Vector Space Model <ref type="bibr" coords="2,191.28,300.22,13.13,8.74" target="#b1">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,204.42,300.22,8.76,8.74" target="#b2">4]</ref>, a document is represented as a vector. Each dimension corresponds to a separate term. If a term occurs in the document, its value in the vector is non-zero. Several different ways of computing these values, also known as (term) weights, have been developed. One of the best known schemes is tf-idf weighting <ref type="bibr" coords="2,282.30,336.08,12.64,8.74" target="#b0">[2]</ref>.</p><p>The score of query q for document d correlates to the cosine-distance or dot-product between document and query vectors. A document whose vector is closer to the query vector in that model is scored higher. The scoring we used was the lucene[5] scoring.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Runs and Results</head><p>By using the image's filename and the text associated with the image, we submitted one run based on the models described in the previous section.</p><p>The results for the wikipediaMM task have been computed with the trec eval tool (version 8.1). The submitted runs have been corrected (where necessary) so as to correpond to valid runs in the correct TREC format. The following corrections have been made:</p><p>• The runs comply with the TREC fomat as specified in the submission guidelines for the task • When a topic contains an image example that is part of the wikipediaMM collection, this image is removed from the retrieval results, i.e., we are seeking relevant images that the users are not familiar with (as they are with the images they provided as examples).</p><p>• When an image is retrieved more than once for a given topic, only its highest ranking for that topic is kept and the rest are removed (and the ranks in the retrieval results are appropriately fixed).</p><p>• Ensure that each of the submitted runs has a unique name.</p><p>The interpolated recall precision averages are shown in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,382.10,621.98,3.88,8.74">1</ref>, and the summary statistics for the runs sorted by MAP are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="2,301.02,633.94,3.88,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Run</head><p>Modality Topic Fields FB/QE MAP P@10 P@20 Rprec. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Bpref</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusion</head><p>In this working note, we presented a retrieval system which automatically ranks the most similar images to a given textual query. The system preprocesses the data set in order to remove the noninformative terms. For each query, the system finds a ranked list of its most similar images using the textual information only. Even though our system did not perform well, we are happy that we participated in the ImageCLEF WikipediaMM task and are looking forward to ImageCLEF2009.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" coords="3,104.94,108.86,425.20,283.47"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="3,104.94,108.86,425.20,283.47" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="2,95.98,657.59,488.06,88.78"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Retrieval Results</figDesc><table coords="2,458.69,657.59,125.34,44.60"><row><cell>Number of</cell><cell cols="2">Number</cell></row><row><cell>retrieved</cell><cell>of</cell><cell>relevat</cell></row><row><cell>documents</cell><cell cols="2">retrieved</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">documents</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="3,106.05,562.81,406.94,8.74;3,114.91,574.76,286.48,8.74" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,295.90,562.81,217.10,8.74;3,114.91,574.76,26.42,8.74">Term-weighting approaches in automatic text retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Gerard</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="3,149.53,574.76,179.36,8.74">Information Processing and Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="513" to="523" />
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,106.05,594.69,406.95,8.74;3,114.91,606.64,262.76,8.74" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,308.80,594.69,195.13,8.74">A Vector Space Model for Automatic Indexing</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Salton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="3,114.91,606.64,124.39,8.74">Communications of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">613620</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1975">1975</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="3,106.05,626.57,406.94,8.74;3,114.91,638.52,258.34,8.74" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="3,254.39,626.57,233.68,8.74">A General Language Model for Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="3,497.92,626.57,15.07,8.74;3,114.91,638.52,213.74,8.74">Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="279" to="280" />
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
