<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,153.96,148.72,295.12,15.51;1,125.78,170.63,351.59,15.51;1,142.87,192.56,317.32,15.51">Fraunhofer FIRST&apos;s Submission to ImageCLEF2009 Photo Annotation Task: Non-sparse Multiple Kernel Learning</title>
				<funder ref="#_ctXm59p">
					<orgName type="full">Federal Ministry of Economics and Technology of Germany</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,217.83,226.36,75.06,9.62"><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Binder</surname></persName>
							<email>alexander.binder@first.fraunhofer.de23</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Fraunhofer Institute FIRST</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Kekuléstr. 7</addrLine>
									<postCode>12489</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,300.79,226.36,84.40,9.62"><forename type="first">Motoaki</forename><surname>Kawanabe</surname></persName>
							<email>motoaki.kawanabe@first.fraunhofer.de23</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Fraunhofer Institute FIRST</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Kekuléstr. 7</addrLine>
									<postCode>12489</postCode>
									<settlement>Berlin</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,153.96,148.72,295.12,15.51;1,125.78,170.63,351.59,15.51;1,142.87,192.56,317.32,15.51">Fraunhofer FIRST&apos;s Submission to ImageCLEF2009 Photo Annotation Task: Non-sparse Multiple Kernel Learning</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">8EAED61ED09CD05D525882823EDA5AF4</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:20+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>I.4 [Image Processing and Computer Vision]: I.4.8 Scene Analysis</term>
					<term>I.4.9 Image Representation</term>
					<term>I.5 [Pattern Recognition]: I.5.2 Design Methodology</term>
					<term>I.5.4 Applications Measurement, Performance, Experimentation ImageCLEF2009, Photo Annotation, Support Vector Machine, Multiple Kernel Learning, Spatial Pyramid Representation, Bag of Words</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In order to achieve good performance in image annotation tasks, it is necessary to combine information from various image features. In our submission, we applied the nonsparse multiple kernel learning for feature combination proposed by Kloft et al.(2009)   to the ImageCLEF2009 photo annotation data. Since some of the concepts of the Im-ageCLEF task are rather abstract, we conjectured that color histograms are informative for some categories such as sky and snow. Therefore we tried pyramid histograms of pixel colors. Since the images are not aligned, we sorted histograms at different places, when computing similarity of two images. Short description of our methods will be presented and obtained results will be discussed in this manuscript.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Recent research results show that combining information from various image features is inevitable to achieve good performance in image annotation tasks. With the support vector machine (SVM), this is implemented by mixing kernels (similarities between images) constructed from different image descriptors with appropriate weights. For instance, the average kernel with uniform weights or the optimal kernel trained by multiple kernel learning (MKL) have been used so far. Recently, <ref type="bibr" coords="1,90.00,702.51,77.31,9.62">Kloft et al.(2009)</ref> proposed the non-sparse MKL with L p -regularizer, which bridges the abovementioned two extremes, i.e. the average kernel SVM and the standard MKL. The non-sparse MKL is successfully applied to object classification tasks; it could outperform the two baseline methods by optimizing the tuning parameter p ≥ 1 through cross validation. In our submission, we applied the novel technique for feature combination to ImageCLEF2009 photo annotation data based on bag-of-words <ref type="bibr" coords="2,189.76,123.75,10.52,9.62" target="#b1">[2]</ref> over SIFT features which is similar to a subset of the Pascal VOC 2008 winners <ref type="bibr" coords="2,126.94,135.70,15.50,9.62" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,146.08,135.70,7.76,9.62" target="#b2">3]</ref> submission. Furthermore, we tested sorted pyramid kernel with color histograms which will be explained in Section 2.1.1.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Experiment Description</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Features</head><p>We computed SIFT features <ref type="bibr" coords="2,220.10,222.52,10.52,9.62" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,234.79,222.52,7.75,9.62" target="#b6">7]</ref> on a dense grid of step size six over the color channels red, green, blue, normalized red, normalized green, normalized blue, opponent color 1, opponent color2, normalized opponent color 1,normalized opponent color 2, grey. We used radii 4,8,12,16 for the SIFT feature supports.</p><p>For the bag of words models we combined the color channels into the following five sets: grey, red-green-blue, normalized red-green-blue, opponent color 1 -opponent color2. The bag of words prototypes have been obtained using kmeans clustering with 800000 SIFT features randomly sampled from 3000 files. The number of prototypes was fixed to 4000 for each of the five channel combinations. Finally we computed the bag of words for image tilings 1x1, 2x2 and 3x1 in the sense of spatial pyrmaid levels <ref type="bibr" coords="2,230.90,330.12,10.52,9.62" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,245.91,330.12,7.01,9.62" target="#b0">1]</ref>. This results in 12 features of which we applied in each learning setting at most eleven due to 32 bit memory restrictions. Furthermore we employed pyramid histograms over color intensities features based on the color channels grey, opponent color 1,opponent color 2, green and blue. We chose the number of bins per pyramid cell to be ten.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.1">Modifications of pyramid histograms over color intensities</head><p>In order to improve the information content of the spatial pyramids for pyramid histograms over color intensities (PHoCol), we sorted the cells within a pyramid level according to the slant of the histogram. This reflects the notion that an image patch having high intensities in a certain colour channel results in an intensity histogram slanted towards higher intensities. The slant was determined via the entropy of the accumulated histogram of a histogram:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,166.67,476.60,269.65,27.17">a(h) i = k≤i h k , a(h) i = a(h) i k a(h) k , sl(h) = i -a(h) i ln(a(h) i )</formula><p>In addition to that we included the difference between sort costs in the kernel. Algebraically a sort cost is just a mapping of the sort permutation of a pyramid level into the real numbers. In our specific case we resorted to</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="2,221.44,558.96,160.12,20.88">sc(π) = C k max(v(π(k)) -v(k), 0)</formula><p>where v(i) is the height of the cell with index i with C being chosen so that the sort cost is upperbounded by one and lies at a similar scale compared to the χ 2 -distance. The intuition behind such a sort cost is to punish large changes of the vertical position of an image patch associated to a pyramid cell caused by sorting compared to the unsorted pyramid. This sort cost is obviously invariant to changes in horizontal position of pyramid cells. The sort cost modified kernel is a product of the χ 2 -Kernel and a gaussian kernel over the difference of the sortcosts between two features</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="2,202.12,679.41,198.75,11.94">k(x, y) = exp(-σ(d χ 2 (h x , h y ) + (sc x -sc y ) 2 ))</formula><p>. While it would be straightforward to replace this fixed weight kernel modification by an linearized MKL-approach, we omitted it due to 32 bit memory restrictions. We also experimented with an alternative formulation</p><formula xml:id="formula_3" coords="2,197.69,743.80,207.61,11.94">k(x, y) = exp(-σ(d χ 2 (h x , h y )(1 + (sc x -sc y ) 2 ))</formula><p>for which the kernel property is not proven which however turned out to be nonnegative definite.</p><p>In the end we computed these features using tilings 4x4, no sorting, 3x1, sorted with sort cost, 16x16, sorted without sort cost over color channels noted above. While we do not regard such features as good standalone features, we realized their speed and potential value for contributing to some classifiers of the 53 classes in a proper MKL-procedure. We had low structured concepts with high variance in mind like sky, water, portrait, daytime.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Kernels</head><p>We used the χ 2 -Kernel with the exception of pyramid histograms over color intensities. All kernels have been normalized.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Experiments</head><p>We used support vector machines with average kernels, sparse L 1 -MKL, and the recently developed general non-sparse L p -MKL <ref type="bibr" coords="3,214.88,288.03,9.96,9.62" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. The regularization parameter was fixed to one.</p><p>We submitted one single kernel result, namely phows over red-green-blue with 1x1 tiling as an early fallback, furthermore we submitted for each binary classifier the single best support vector learning algorithm measured by AP/AUC and FRR rate score over ten-fold crossvalidation (L p -joint) using which generates three additional submissions A) eleven bag of words kernels, namely red-green-blue, normalized red-green-blue and grey, all tilings, and opponent color 1 -opponent color2, 1x1 and 3x1 tiling.</p><p>B) nine bag of words kernels, namely red-green-blue, normalized red-green-blue and grey, all tilings, C) 10 kernels, namely bag of words red-green-blue, all tilings, grey 1x1 tiling, PHoCol over green and blue channels 4x4,3x1,16x16 tilings (various sort strategies) D) eleven kernels, namely bag of words red-green-blue and grey, all tilings, opponent color 1opponent color2 and normalized opponent color 1 -opponent color2, both with 1x1 tiling, PHoCol over grey channels 4x4,3x1,16x16 tilings (various sort strategies) E) 10 kernels, namely bag of words red-green-blue, all tilings, grey 1x1 tiling, PHoCol over opponent color 1 and 2 channels 4x4,3x1,16x16 tilings (various sort strategies)</p><p>We used for the standard SVM and the L p -MKL code from the shogun toolbox <ref type="bibr" coords="3,455.47,527.14,10.52,9.62" target="#b8">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="3,469.31,527.14,7.01,9.62" target="#b7">8]</ref>.</p><p>The experiments were conducted with C++-code on an Opteron-Cluster running on a 32 bit Linux which implied a hard limit for memory usage of 3GB. On average we used 20 CPUs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Conclusion</head><p>On average combinations of only Bag of words features perform best. There exists classes for which adding the low level color descriptors improves performance. Since each binary classifier can be selected separately based on crossvalidation error adding the color features improves the final submission. By comparing the results from A and B versus C, D, and E one can clearly observe overfitting. In our point of view it comes from noisy feature extraction in connection with small sample sizes for many of the smaller concept classes. We doubt that the applied features permit a Bayes Error close to zero. In that sense there is still a need for better feature extraction despite the success story of Bag of Words representations.</p><p>Below are AP and AUC scores over 5-fold crossvalidation, the result of the best method is marked bold. For multiclass subproblems we computed for each method the average score over the subproblem and marked the subproblem in total bold. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>AP / methods</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A+avg</head></div>		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>This work was supported in part by <rs type="funder">Federal Ministry of Economics and Technology of Germany</rs> under the project <rs type="projectName">THESEUS</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">01MQ07018</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_ctXm59p">
					<idno type="grant-number">01MQ07018</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">THESEUS</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="10,110.48,196.91,402.51,9.62;10,110.47,208.86,402.51,9.62;10,110.47,220.81,186.70,9.62" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,359.23,196.91,153.76,9.62;10,110.47,208.86,63.93,9.62">Representing shape with a spatial pyramid kernel</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Bosch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Zisserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Xavier</forename><surname>Muñoz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,195.11,208.86,317.88,9.62;10,110.47,220.81,88.57,9.62">Proceedings of the 6th ACM international conference on Image and video retrieval (CIVR &apos;07)</title>
		<meeting>the 6th ACM international conference on Image and video retrieval (CIVR &apos;07)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="401" to="408" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,110.48,240.74,402.53,9.62;10,110.47,252.69,402.51,9.62;10,110.47,264.65,89.53,9.62" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,302.82,240.74,191.92,9.62">Visual categorization with bags of keypoints</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Csurka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Bray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dance</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,110.47,252.69,273.24,9.62">Workshop on Statistical Learning in Computer Vision, ECCV</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Prague, Czech Republic</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004-05">May 2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,110.48,284.58,81.06,9.62;10,208.46,284.58,78.14,9.62;10,303.53,284.58,110.71,9.62;10,431.16,284.58,48.95,9.62;10,497.02,284.58,16.06,9.62;10,110.47,296.53,71.23,9.62;10,219.04,296.53,293.94,9.62;10,110.47,308.48,49.79,9.62;10,186.98,308.48,34.56,9.62;10,295.59,308.48,217.31,9.62;10,110.47,320.44,160.88,9.62" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,219.04,296.53,259.64,9.62">The PASCAL Visual Object Classes Challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Everingham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Van Gool</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K I</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Winn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Zisserman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.pascal-network.org/challenges/VOC/voc2008/workshop/index.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,116.01,308.48,44.25,9.62;10,186.98,308.48,30.24,9.62">VOC2008) Results</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008. 2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,110.48,340.37,402.54,9.62;10,110.47,352.32,402.52,9.62;10,110.47,364.27,74.82,9.62" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,396.42,340.37,116.60,9.62;10,110.47,352.32,33.48,9.62">Non-sparse multiple kernel learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Marius</forename><surname>Kloft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ulf</forename><surname>Brefeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Pavel</forename><surname>Laskov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sören</forename><surname>Sonnenburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,179.25,352.32,333.74,9.62;10,110.47,364.27,70.38,9.62">Abstract of the NIPS workshop on Kernel Learning: Automatic Selection of Optimal Kernels</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,110.48,384.20,402.58,9.62;10,110.47,396.16,402.52,9.62;10,110.47,408.11,402.53,9.62;10,110.47,420.06,222.03,9.62" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,363.91,384.20,149.15,9.62;10,110.47,396.16,252.19,9.62">Beyond bags of features: Spatial pyramid matching for recognizing natural scene categories</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Svetlana</forename><surname>Lazebnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Cordelia</forename><surname>Schmid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jean</forename><surname>Ponce</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="10,383.59,396.16,129.41,9.62;10,110.47,408.11,398.51,9.62">Proceedings of the 2006 IEEE Computer Society Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR &apos;06)</title>
		<meeting>the 2006 IEEE Computer Society Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR &apos;06)<address><addrLine>New York, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2169" to="2178" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,110.48,439.99,402.52,9.62;10,110.47,451.95,213.34,9.62" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,190.29,439.99,252.63,9.62">Distinctive image features from scale-invariant keypoints</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Lowe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="10,456.08,439.99,56.93,9.62;10,110.47,451.95,121.47,9.62">International Journal of Computer Vision</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,110.48,471.87,402.53,9.62;10,110.47,483.83,388.81,9.62" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,309.77,471.87,199.07,9.62">A performance evaluation of local descriptors</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Krystian</forename><surname>Mikolajczyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Cordelia</forename><surname>Schmid</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="10,110.47,483.83,277.42,9.62">IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis &amp; Machine Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1615" to="1630" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,110.48,503.75,309.56,9.62" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sonnenburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.shogun-toolbox.org/" />
		<title level="m" coord="10,180.55,503.75,85.29,9.62">The shogun toolbox</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,110.48,523.68,402.53,9.62;10,110.48,535.63,269.08,9.62" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,357.21,523.68,151.61,9.62">Large scale multiple kernel learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sonnenburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Rätsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Schäfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Schölkopf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="10,110.48,535.63,166.58,9.62">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1531" to="1565" />
			<date type="published" when="2006-07">07 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="10,110.48,555.56,402.51,9.62;10,110.48,567.51,402.53,9.62;10,110.48,579.47,54.36,9.62" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="10,348.78,555.56,164.21,9.62;10,110.48,567.51,91.52,9.62">Evaluating color descriptors for object and scene recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">E A</forename><surname>Van De Sande</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Gevers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">G M</forename><surname>Snoek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="10,210.16,567.51,283.57,9.62">IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>in press</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
