<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,100.78,148.86,401.44,15.15;1,282.13,170.78,38.75,15.15">CWI at the photo retrieval task of ImageCLEF 2009</title>
				<funder ref="#_rCHjSma">
					<orgName type="full">European Commission</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">European Union</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,212.49,204.67,80.64,8.74"><forename type="first">Theodora</forename><surname>Tsikrika</surname></persName>
							<email>theodora.tsikrika@cwi.nl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">CWI</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Amsterdam</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,315.82,204.67,74.68,8.74"><forename type="first">Arjen</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>De Vries</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">CWI</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Amsterdam</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,100.78,148.86,401.44,15.15;1,282.13,170.78,38.75,15.15">CWI at the photo retrieval task of ImageCLEF 2009</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">580ED4D1BA35F0BA750FF6BF23C1F03F</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:21+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.3 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: H.3.1 Content Analysis and Indexing</term>
					<term>H.3.3 Information Search and Retrieval</term>
					<term>H.3.4 Systems and Software</term>
					<term>H.3.7 Digital Libraries</term>
					<term>H.2.3 [Database Managment]: Languages-Query Languages Measurement, Performance, Experimentation Image retrieval, diversity, clickthrough data, search logs, implicit feedback</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>CWI's experiments investigate the usefulness of clickthrough data for improving the diversity of image retrieval results. We use the search logs provided to us by Belga to find relevant images; we consider that these correspond to images clicked for queries exactly matching or best matching a topic's title and cluster titles. To reduce the noise, we also filter these results and only consider those clicked images that are also retrieved by a text-based approach that uses the image captions. To promote diversity, we interleave the images retrieved in the previous step for each of the cluster titles (and also the title). However, given that the clickthrough data available to us cover only a small part of the collection used in the photo retrieval task, our experimental results are inconclusive, although they do provide indications on the reliability of using image search clickthrough data to identify relevant images.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>CWI participated in the photo retrieval task at ImageCLEF 2009 in the context of the research activities of the VITALAS<ref type="foot" coords="1,203.49,632.79,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref> (Video and image Indexing and reTrievAl in the LArge Scale) project. One of the research directions investigated in this project is the usefulness of users' implicit feedback <ref type="bibr" coords="1,130.48,658.28,9.96,8.74" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, in particular users' clickthrough data collected in search interaction logs, in a variety of applications, such as image annotation <ref type="bibr" coords="1,279.84,670.23,14.61,8.74" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. In VITALAS, the necessary resources for such experiments, i.e., the image collection and clickthrough data generated from users' interactions with this collection, have been made available by Belga News Agency<ref type="foot" coords="1,406.57,692.57,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_1">2</ref> , a picture portal that provides access to photographic images covering a broad domain. Given that this year's photo retrieval ImageCLEF task also uses images from the same content provider <ref type="bibr" coords="1,412.48,718.05,14.61,8.74" target="#b9">[10]</ref>, we were motivated to participate in this task and examine whether clickthrough data could be a useful source of evidence for improving the diversity of image retrieval results. Since this additional resource is not available to the participants of the photo retrieval task (only to VITALAS partners), the main aim of our participation has been to contribute retrieval results to the generation of the pools for the development of this test collection, and then to also examine how the effectiveness of our search log-based approaches compares to the more expensive clustering methods typically employed in such a task <ref type="bibr" coords="2,195.19,183.75,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Section 2 presents the employed approaches that combine textual and search log-based evidence, Section 3 discusses the experimental results achieved by the officially submitted runs, and Section 4 concludes this paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Approach</head><p>Clickthrough data consist of the queries submitted by the users of a retrieval system, together with the documents in the retrieval results that these users selected to click on in response to their queries. Such implicit feedback is considered to "weakly" indicate the relevance of the document to the query for which it was clicked <ref type="bibr" coords="2,237.52,298.29,9.96,8.74" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Using clickthrough data as a source of evidence of relevance is particularly attractive since they can be gathered in large quantities without any major effort on the part of content owners and without any explicit user intervention. Their major shortcoming, on the other hand, is that they are sparse, since they only cover the part of the collection that has been previously accessed, and potentially noisy. In the context of an image retrieval task that aims to promote diversity in the top n ranks, image search clickthrough data have the potential to minimise the tradeoff between precision and diversity, since they are both quite reliable as relevance assessments (even over 80% in some cases <ref type="bibr" coords="2,277.64,381.98,14.77,8.74" target="#b10">[11]</ref>), and they also include many query variations <ref type="bibr" coords="2,502.49,381.98,10.51,8.74" target="#b8">[9]</ref> that could be used to reflect the different topical facets of an information need.</p><p>The simplest approach to find relevant images using clickthrough data is to consider the images clicked for queries exactly matching the title (T) or the cluster title(s) (CT) of a topic (see the overview of the photo retrieval task <ref type="bibr" coords="2,283.85,429.80,15.50,8.74" target="#b9">[10]</ref> for details on the topic format and other aspects of the test collection). Given though that users with the same or similar information needs may submit different textual queries, an exact match approach may not be able to produce results for some of these topics; therefore, methods with less stringent matching criteria are also needed. To this end, we also employ approaches that consider as relevant those images clicked for queries that best match the title or the cluster title(s) of a topic. In particular, we find for each of these topic fields the images clicked for their best matching query which we consider to be the top ranking query using the NLLR (normalized log-likelihood ratio) retrieval model <ref type="bibr" coords="2,411.07,513.49,9.97,8.74" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, a simple derivation of a language model with linear interpolation smoothing <ref type="bibr" coords="2,344.83,525.44,10.52,8.74" target="#b3">[4]</ref> that produces log-linear scores. In summary, we construct, for each field of each topic (i.e., the topic's title T and each of its cluster titles CT i , i = 0, 1, ..., m), a list of images clicked for its exactly matching query and a list of images clicked for its best matching query, and we rank the images within each individual list by their click count; that means that for each topic we construct 2 * (1 + m) ranked image lists.</p><p>To eliminate some of the false positives in these search log-based rankings, i.e., images that have been clicked without being relevant to the submitted query, we also take into account the textual evidence in the form of captions that accompany the images in the collection. We index the images in the collection using their captions, after applying stemming and stopword removal. We use the title field of each topic as the query and NLLR as the retrieval model to produce a top 1000 ranking. Then, by keeping in the search log-based rankings generated in the previous steps only the images that also appear in the top 1000 text-based ranking, a potentially less noisy result is produced for each of the considered topic fields.</p><p>To promote diversity among the top ranked retrieval results, we simply interleave the images in the lists produced for each topic in the previous steps, i.e., either the lists containing the images clicked for the query exactly matching each of the cluster titles and/or the title of the topic, or the lists containing the images clicked for the query best matching each of the cluster titles and/or the title of the topic, or the lists containing the images that both were clicked for the query exactly matching each of the cluster titles and/or the title of the topic and also appear in the top 1000 text-based retrieval results.</p><p>The approaches described above are listed below in a more succinct form (the ones marked by an asterirk (*) correspond to runs officially submitted to the task):</p><p>1. cwi1 T TXT: Images clicked for the query exactly matching the title.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">cwi2 CT TXT:</head><p>Interleave the m lists of images clicked for the queries exactly matching each of the cluster titles.</p><p>3. cwi3 TCT TXT*: Interleave the m + 1 lists of images clicked for the queries exactly matching the title and each of the cluster titles.</p><p>4. cwi4 T TXT: Images clicked for the query best matching the title.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">cwi5 CT TXT:</head><p>Interleave the m lists of images clicked for the queries best matching each of the cluster titles.</p><p>6. cwi6 TCT TXT*: Interleave the m+1 lists of images clicked for the queries best matching the title and each of the cluster titles.</p><p>7. cwi7 T TXT: Images retrieved in the top 1000 of a text-based approach and also clicked for the query exactly matching the title.</p><p>8. cwi8 CT TXT*: Interleave the m lists that contain images retrieved in the top 1000 of a text-based approach and also clicked for the queries exactly matching each of the cluster titles.</p><p>9. cwi9 TCT TXT*: Interleave the m + 1 lists that contain images retrieved in the top 1000 of a text-based approach and also clicked for the queries exactly matching the title and each of the cluster titles.</p><p>The approaches presented thus far find the relevant images in the search logs by considering those previously clicked for a query that matches a topic field, while, for the promotion of diversity, they require that the different topical facets of an information need, corresponding to the different clusters of a topic in the photo retrieval task, are known in advance. We also investigate an approach that does not require the availability of such information<ref type="foot" coords="3,384.08,489.03,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_2">3</ref> . This approach, denoted as cwi10 T TXT*, first finds the queries for which the images retrieved in the top 1000 by the text-based approach have been previously clicked. Then the images clicked for each these queries are found in the clickthrough data, ranked by their click count, and approach cwi2 CT TXT is applied with each of these queries treated as a cluster title.</p><p>The clickthrough data used in our experiments have been extracted from Belga search logs that correspond to a 15-month period (June-September 2007 and January-December 2008). However, these data cover a time period that it is slightly different to the time period within which the Belga images that comprise the ImageCLEF photo collection have been made available online to the Belga users. Therefore, these logs do not record many of the interactions with these particular images and thus are quite sparse with respect to this dataset. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,399.72,610.15,4.98,8.74" target="#fig_1">2</ref> presents, for each topic, the images that have been previously clicked for the topic's title and cluster titles (both the total number of clicked images and also those that also belong to the top 1000 retrieved using the text-based approach). For 11 out of the 50 topics, there are no clicked images for queries exactly matching either the title or the cluster title(s), whereas for 8 more topics, there is no overlap between the clicked images found and those retrieved in the top 1000 by the text-based approach.</p><p>Overall, the number of images found in the search logs for this data set is very low (even less than 10 in many cases), which makes it very difficult to evaluate the usefulness of the proposed approaches. Nevertheless, we decided to submit our runs so as to get an indication of their effectiveness. However, to ensure that we submit a sufficient number of results for each of the Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,120.92,327.87,3.88,8.74">1</ref>: The number of images that have been previously clicked for each topic's title and cluster titles (both the total number of clicked images and also those that also belong to the top 1000 retrieved using the text-based approach). topics, we append to each ranking the top 100 images retrieved by the text-based approach (taking care to remove from these top 100 those already retrieved by the search log-based approaches).</p><p>We conducted our experiments using PF/Tijah </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="4,117.13,522.61,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_0">1</ref> presents the results of our official submissions. Out of the 5 submitted runs, the effectiveness of the 4 best performing ones is comparable, whereas run cwi10 T TXT is not very effective as it is probably affected by topic drift. The mean P@10 and P@20 of the 4 best performing runs is around 0.75 over the 50 topics and also over each of the two subsets. This indicates that both the search log-based and the text-based approach, and in particular their combination (i.e., runs cwi9 TCT TXT and cwi8 CT TXT ) are effective in identifying relevant images. A further examination of the P@10 values achieved by the best performing cwi9 TCT TXT for each of the topics (as these P@10 values are plotted against the number of top ranked images that have also been previously clicked in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,237.71,618.26,4.43,8.74">3</ref>) indicates that the majority of topics (35/50) perform better than the mean P@10 (the median P@10 is 0.8). Figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,336.19,630.21,4.98,8.74">3</ref> further indicates the high reliability of clicks as relevance assessments.</p><p>Regarding the diversity of the retrieval results, our 4 best performing runs manage to retrieve, in the top 10 ranks, images belonging to at least half of the different topical facets that have been considered in the evaluation. The results regarding the CR@10 are slightly better in the second part of the topics (topics 26-50). Given that these topics do not contain cluster titles and thus all the approaches that rely only on them do not produce any results and simply consider the top 100 images retrieved by the text-based approach that have been appended, these results indicate that this text-only approach and also the images clicked for the title achieve quite a high diversity. However, a per-topic analysis of the CR@10 (and F-measure) values is required so as to reach more reliable conclusions.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Conclusions</head><p>We investigated the effectiveness of employing clickthrough data to improve the diversity among the top ranked retrieval results. Unfortunately the Belga search logs available to us at the time of submission cover only a really small part of the image collection used in the photo retrieval task. This renders our experimental results inconclusive, although they do indicate the reliability of using image search clickthrough data as relevance assessments. We are currently performing further experiments using an additional sample of Belga search logs and are also exploring approaches to deal more effectively with the sparseness of clickthrough data. In the future, we also aim to apply more principled approaches in the diversification of image retrieval results.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="4,307.88,406.50,3.97,6.12;4,315.05,408.07,197.95,8.74;4,90.00,420.03,423.00,8.74;4,90.00,431.98,222.65,8.74;4,312.65,430.41,3.97,6.12;4,317.12,431.98,195.88,8.74;4,90.00,443.94,423.01,8.74;4,90.00,455.89,294.89,8.74;4,384.90,454.32,3.97,6.12;4,393.22,455.89,119.78,8.74;4,90.00,467.85,111.56,8.74"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>4 [5], a research project run by the University of Twente, which aims at creating a flexible environment for setting up search systems. PF/Tijah is part of the open source release of MonetDB/XQuery 5 , which is being developed in cooperation with CWI, Amsterdam and the University of München. PF/Tijah combines database and Information Retrieval technologies by integrating the PathFinder (PF) XQuery 6 compiler<ref type="bibr" coords="4,434.19,455.89,10.52,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref> with the Tijah XML retrieval system<ref type="bibr" coords="4,188.28,467.85,9.96,8.74" target="#b7">[8]</ref>.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="5,90.00,628.67,422.99,8.74;5,90.00,640.63,420.82,8.74;5,189.57,452.67,220.54,160.89"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: P@10 values for run cwi9 TCT TXT plotted against the number of images that have been previously clicked and are also retrieved in the top 1000 of the text-based NLLR approach.</figDesc><graphic coords="5,189.57,452.67,220.54,160.89" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="5,90.00,176.72,423.00,249.98"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Results for the CWI official submissions to the photo retrieval task at ImageCLEF 2009.</figDesc><table coords="5,95.98,188.42,410.77,238.28"><row><cell>overall</cell><cell cols="2">relative</cell><cell>run</cell><cell cols="6">F-measure CR@10 CR@20 P@10 P@20 rel ∧ retr</cell></row><row><cell>rank</cell><cell>rank</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="5">All Topics (relative ranking among modality TXT)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>33</cell><cell>11</cell><cell cols="2">CWI9 TCT TXT</cell><cell>0.6467</cell><cell>0.5607</cell><cell>0.6355</cell><cell>0.76</cell><cell>0.78</cell><cell>3914</cell></row><row><cell>42</cell><cell>18</cell><cell cols="2">CWI3 TCT TXT</cell><cell>0.6301</cell><cell>0.5639</cell><cell>0.6292</cell><cell>0.71</cell><cell>0.74</cell><cell>4179</cell></row><row><cell>45</cell><cell>20</cell><cell cols="2">CWI8 CT TXT</cell><cell>0.6217</cell><cell>0.5250</cell><cell>0.6305</cell><cell>0.76</cell><cell>0.78</cell><cell>3834</cell></row><row><cell>53</cell><cell>24</cell><cell cols="2">CWI6 TCT TXT</cell><cell>0.6033</cell><cell>0.5027</cell><cell>0.6140</cell><cell>0.75</cell><cell>0.78</cell><cell>3738</cell></row><row><cell>73</cell><cell>38</cell><cell cols="2">CWI10 T TXT</cell><cell>0.4445</cell><cell>0.4854</cell><cell>0.5787</cell><cell>0.41</cell><cell>0.40</cell><cell>7105</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="5">Topics 1-25 (relative ranking among all runs)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>33</cell><cell>46</cell><cell cols="2">CWI9 TCT TXT</cell><cell>0.6255</cell><cell>0.5296</cell><cell>0.6292</cell><cell>0.76</cell><cell>0.78</cell><cell>1992</cell></row><row><cell>42</cell><cell>48</cell><cell cols="2">CWI3 TCT TXT</cell><cell>0.6216</cell><cell>0.5515</cell><cell>0.6242</cell><cell>0.71</cell><cell>0.74</cell><cell>2229</cell></row><row><cell>45</cell><cell>53</cell><cell cols="2">CWI8 CT TXT</cell><cell>0.6017</cell><cell>0.4962</cell><cell>0.6159</cell><cell>0.76</cell><cell>0.77</cell><cell>1965</cell></row><row><cell>53</cell><cell>61</cell><cell cols="2">CWI6 TCT TXT</cell><cell>0.5633</cell><cell>0.4518</cell><cell>0.5828</cell><cell>0.75</cell><cell>0.77</cell><cell>1868</cell></row><row><cell>73</cell><cell>73</cell><cell cols="2">CWI10 T TXT</cell><cell>0.4455</cell><cell>0.4794</cell><cell>0.5813</cell><cell>0.42</cell><cell>0.40</cell><cell>3879</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="5">Topics 26-50 (relative ranking among all runs)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>33</cell><cell>21</cell><cell cols="2">CWI9 TCT TXT</cell><cell>0.6670</cell><cell>0.5918</cell><cell>0.6418</cell><cell>0.76</cell><cell>0.78</cell><cell>1922</cell></row><row><cell>53</cell><cell>40</cell><cell cols="2">CWI6 TCT TXT</cell><cell>0.6407</cell><cell>0.5537</cell><cell>0.6451</cell><cell>0.76</cell><cell>0.78</cell><cell>1870</cell></row><row><cell>45</cell><cell>41</cell><cell cols="2">CWI8 CT TXT</cell><cell>0.6407</cell><cell>0.5537</cell><cell>0.6451</cell><cell>0.76</cell><cell>0.78</cell><cell>1869</cell></row><row><cell>42</cell><cell>42</cell><cell cols="2">CWI3 TCT TXT</cell><cell>0.6385</cell><cell>0.5762</cell><cell>0.6342</cell><cell>0.72</cell><cell>0.73</cell><cell>1950</cell></row><row><cell>73</cell><cell>69</cell><cell cols="2">CWI10 T TXT</cell><cell>0.4434</cell><cell>0.4914</cell><cell>0.5761</cell><cell>0.40</cell><cell>0.41</cell><cell>3226</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="1,105.24,738.07,105.85,6.64"><p>http://vitalas.ercim.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="1,105.24,747.58,84.68,6.64"><p>http://www.belga.be/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="3,105.24,736.68,407.75,6.99;3,90.00,746.14,304.32,6.99"><p>This is actually one of the objectives examined in the context of this task, since only half of the 50 available topics contain cluster information, whereas the other half only contain a title<ref type="bibr" coords="3,378.80,746.14,12.41,6.99" target="#b9">[10]</ref>.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_3" coords="4,105.24,721.44,152.43,6.64"><p>http://dbappl.cs.utwente.nl/pftijah/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="5" xml:id="foot_4" coords="4,105.24,730.95,186.30,6.64"><p>http://www.sourceforge.net/projects/monetdb/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="6" xml:id="foot_5" coords="4,105.24,740.45,118.55,6.64"><p>http://www.w3.org/TR/xquery/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="5">Acknowledgements</head><p>This material is based on work supported by the <rs type="funder">European Union</rs> via the <rs type="funder">European Commission</rs> project <rs type="projectName">VITALAS</rs> (contract no. <rs type="grantNumber">045389</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_rCHjSma">
					<idno type="grant-number">045389</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">VITALAS</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="6,110.48,268.27,402.51,8.74;6,110.48,280.23,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,292.18,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,304.14,256.38,8.74" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,360.11,268.27,152.89,8.74;6,110.48,280.23,141.20,8.74">Overview of the ImageCLEFphoto 2008 photographic retrieval task</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Arni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sanderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grubinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,275.18,280.23,237.82,8.74;6,110.48,292.18,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,304.14,22.68,8.74">Advances in Multilingual and Multimodal Information Retrieval: Proceedings of the 9th Workshop of the Cross-Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2008)</title>
		<title level="s" coord="6,141.01,304.14,152.88,8.74">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,110.48,322.78,402.51,8.74;6,110.48,334.74,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,346.69,386.62,8.74" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,490.03,322.78,22.96,8.74;6,110.48,334.74,305.41,8.74">Mon-etDB/XQuery: a fast XQuery processor powered by a relational engine</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Boncz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Grust</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Van Keulen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Manegold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Rittinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Teubner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,435.91,334.74,77.08,8.74;6,110.48,346.69,287.72,8.74">Proceedings of the ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data</title>
		<meeting>the ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="479" to="490" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,110.48,365.34,402.51,8.74;6,110.48,377.29,402.51,8.74;6,110.48,389.25,135.63,8.74" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,246.85,365.34,144.22,8.74">Random walks on the click graph</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Craswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Szummer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,412.78,365.34,100.22,8.74;6,110.48,377.29,402.51,8.74;6,110.48,389.25,37.33,8.74">Proceedings of the 30th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</title>
		<meeting>the 30th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="239" to="246" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,110.48,407.90,402.53,8.74;6,110.48,419.85,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,431.81,402.53,8.74;6,110.48,443.76,65.37,8.74" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,177.26,407.90,313.68,8.74">A linguistically motivated probabilistic model of information retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hiemstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,110.48,419.85,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,431.81,100.28,8.74">Proceedings of the 2nd European Conference on Research and Advanced Technology for Digital Libraries (ECDL 1998)</title>
		<title level="s" coord="6,287.89,431.81,152.42,8.74">Lecture Notes in Computer Science</title>
		<meeting>the 2nd European Conference on Research and Advanced Technology for Digital Libraries (ECDL 1998)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1513</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="569" to="584" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,110.48,462.41,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,474.36,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,486.32,357.64,8.74" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,327.64,462.41,185.36,8.74;6,110.48,474.36,27.85,8.74">PF/Tijah: text search in an XML database system</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hiemstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Rode</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Van Os</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Flokstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,160.55,474.36,352.45,8.74;6,110.48,486.32,234.28,8.74">Proceedings of the 2nd International Workshop on Open Source Information Retrieval (OSIR) (held in conjunction with SIGIR 2006)</title>
		<meeting>the 2nd International Workshop on Open Source Information Retrieval (OSIR) (held in conjunction with SIGIR 2006)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006-08">August 2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12" to="17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,110.48,504.96,402.51,8.74;6,110.48,516.92,113.77,8.74" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,214.10,504.96,263.23,8.74">Implicit feedback for inferring user preference: A bibliography</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Teevan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,484.74,504.96,28.26,8.74;6,110.48,516.92,26.08,8.74">SIGIR Forum</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,110.48,535.56,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,547.52,313.47,8.74" xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="6,161.82,535.56,259.21,8.74">Variations on Language Modeling for Information Retrieval</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Kraaij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Centre for Telematics and Information Technology, University of Twente</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">PhD thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,110.48,566.17,402.51,8.74;6,110.48,578.12,329.06,8.74" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,429.50,566.17,83.50,8.74;6,110.48,578.12,135.36,8.74">TIJAH: Embracing IR Methods in XML Databases</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>List</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mihajlović</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Ramírez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Vries</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hiemstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Blok</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="6,254.95,578.12,92.98,8.74">Information Retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="547" to="570" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,110.48,596.77,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,608.72,402.51,8.74;6,110.48,620.68,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,632.63,367.32,8.74" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,317.06,596.77,195.94,8.74;6,110.48,608.72,51.64,8.74">Development of a collection to support diversity analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Paramita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sanderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,182.95,608.72,330.04,8.74;6,110.48,620.68,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,632.63,336.78,8.74">Proceedings of the Workshop on Redundancy, Diversity, and Interdependent Document Relevance (IDR 2009) -held at the 32nd Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR 2009)</title>
		<meeting>the Workshop on Redundancy, Diversity, and Interdependent Document Relevance (IDR 2009) -held at the 32nd Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR 2009)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,110.47,651.28,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,663.23,285.03,8.74" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,320.74,651.28,192.26,8.74;6,110.48,663.23,120.75,8.74">Diversity in photo retrieval: overview of the ImageCLEFphoto task 2009</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Paramita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sanderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,252.63,663.23,112.23,8.74">CLEF working notes 2009</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,110.47,681.88,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,693.83,375.08,8.74" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,233.87,681.88,275.02,8.74">Evaluating implicit judgements from image search interactions</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ashman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,122.93,693.83,265.84,8.74">Proceedings of the Web Science Conference: Society On-Line</title>
		<meeting>the Web Science Conference: Society On-Line<address><addrLine>WebSci</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009. 2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="6,110.47,712.48,402.53,8.74;6,110.48,724.43,402.52,8.74;6,110.48,736.39,128.78,8.74" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="6,354.72,712.48,158.29,8.74;6,110.48,724.43,17.71,8.74">Image annotation using clickthrough data</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tsikrika</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Diou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>De Vries</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Delopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="6,149.68,724.43,363.32,8.74;6,110.48,736.39,98.23,8.74">Proceedings of the 8th International Conference on Content-based Image and Video Retrieval (CIVR 2009)</title>
		<meeting>the 8th International Conference on Content-based Image and Video Retrieval (CIVR 2009)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
