<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,185.41,146.21,232.15,18.08">SINAI at ImagePhoto 2009</title>
				<funder ref="#_MPuhnjU">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_XTsEHkm">
					<orgName type="full">Regional Government of Andaluca (Spain)</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_f4qc8Tm">
					<orgName type="full">Spanish Government</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,114.68,181.27,103.03,10.46"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computers Department. SINAI Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,225.87,181.27,80.31,10.46"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Díaz-Galiano</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computers Department. SINAI Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,314.08,181.27,71.68,10.46"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Montejo-Raez</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computers Department. SINAI Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,393.91,181.27,94.41,10.46"><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Martín-Valdivia</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computers Department. SINAI Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Jaén</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,185.41,146.21,232.15,18.08">SINAI at ImagePhoto 2009</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">E0B76E6E62C55DA19D8CC1DE323E4E07</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:20+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.3 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: H.3.1 Content Analysis and Indexing</term>
					<term>H.3.3 Information Search and Retrieval</term>
					<term>H.3.4 Systems and Software</term>
					<term>H.3.7 Digital Libraries</term>
					<term>H.2.3 [Database Management]: Languages-English Measurement, Performance, Experimentation Text retrieval, Indexing, Clustering, PRF</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper presents the fourth participation of the SINAI group, University of Jaén, in the Photo Retrieval task at Image CLEF 2009. Our system uses only the text of the queries, and a clustering system (based on kmeans) that combines different approaches based on a different use of the cluster data of the queries. The official results shown that the combination between the title of each query and the other titles of the clusters obtain our best performance and that our clustering system did not work well.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>In this paper we describe our approach to the ImagePhoto 2009 evaluation campaign at CLEF, over the new collection, which contains 498,920 images from Belga News Agency. Given a monolingual English query the goal of the ImagePhoto task is to find as many relevant images as possible from an image collection <ref type="bibr" coords="1,171.36,575.24,11.62,10.46" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p><p>In 2008 this task took a different approach to evaluate the image clustering. This year the organizers give special value to the diversity of results. Given a query the goal is to retrieve a relevant set of images at the top of a ranked list. Text and visual information can be used to improve the retrieval methods, and the main evaluation points are the use of pseudo-relevant feedback (PRF), query expansion, IR systems with different weighting functions and clustering or filtering methods applied over the cluster terms. Our system makes use of text information, not visual information, to improve the retrieval methods. This year, a new method has been implemented to cluster images.</p><p>The following section describes the queries built and the new algorithm of clustering. In Section 3 we explain the experiment carried out. Finally, the obtained results and conclusions are presented in Section 4.</p><p>In our system we have used an automatic modality, without user interaction, with English text information (not visual information). The English collection documents have been preprocessed as usual (English stopwords removal and the Porter's stemmer <ref type="bibr" coords="2,365.26,156.27,13.58,10.46" target="#b1">[2]</ref>). Then, it has been indexed using as Information Retrieval (IR) system Lemur<ref type="foot" coords="2,308.80,167.15,3.97,7.32" target="#foot_0">1</ref> .</p><p>Past campaigns our adhoc system worked with different IR systems, and test different approaches, such as combination of retrieved lists or fusion of a filtering method that used some clusters terms. The precision results obtained were very similar to different languages <ref type="bibr" coords="2,469.77,204.09,13.16,10.46" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,486.92,204.09,7.01,10.46" target="#b3">4]</ref>. In 2007, a simple combination method with both IR results was developed, and the evaluation of the combined list of relevant documents fix the parameter that weight each list in 0.8 for Lemur documents and 0.2 for Jirs documents. Using the same combination parameters the main objective in 2008 has been to improve the basic case with different combinations of methods and the application of a filter with the cluster term, a similar filtering method is applied in our system that works with geographical information <ref type="bibr" coords="2,268.00,275.82,12.79,10.46" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. In 2008 the use of the cluster term was oriented in a filtering way, and after the retrieval process the documents or passages marked as relevant are filtered <ref type="bibr" coords="2,119.17,299.73,10.94,10.46" target="#b5">[6]</ref>.</p><p>The weighting function of the IR system is a parameter changed to test previous results and based on them we have used Okapi. The use of Psedo-Relevance Feedback (PRF) to improve the retrieval process is not conclusive, but in general the precision is increased in past experiments, so it is always used with Lemur. The blind feedback algorithm is based on the probabilistic term relevance weighting formula developed by Robertson and Sparck Jones <ref type="bibr" coords="2,395.23,359.50,12.43,10.46" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p><p>The evolution of our system introduces a clustering module, based on the algorithm kmeans, and the creation of the final topics using the information of the title and the clusters terms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Building the queries</head><p>The first module of our system uses the data of the title and the cluster title, in some cases, and combines them to obtain the final topics. These topics, in a second step, are run over the IR system, and a final list of relevant documents is obtained.</p><p>The following four sets of topics have been built for these experimentation:</p><p>1. In the baseline case only the title of the query is used against the index of the IR system.</p><p>2. Each final topic is a combination between the query title and the title of the last cluster.</p><p>3. Each final topic is a combination between the query title and the other words of each cluster.</p><p>The figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,153.12,549.25,4.98,10.46" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows a general scheme of the system developed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Clustering subsystem</head><p>It has been found that the variability of top results in a list of documents retrieved as answer to a query, the performance of the retrieval systems increases too, being in some cases more desirable to have less but more varied items in this list <ref type="bibr" coords="2,299.23,619.44,9.96,10.46" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. In order to increase variability, a clustering system has been applied. This has also been used in other systems with the same aim <ref type="bibr" coords="2,476.77,631.39,9.96,10.46" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. The idea behind is rather simple: re-arrange most relevant documents so that documents belonging to different clusters are promoted to the top of the list.</p><p>We have applied kmeans on each list returned by the Lemur IR system. For this, Rapid Miner tool was used<ref type="foot" coords="2,150.02,678.14,3.97,7.32" target="#foot_1">2</ref> . The clustering algorithm has tried to group these results, without any concern on ranking, into 4 different groups. The number of groups has been stablished at this value as documents in the training set have this average number of clusters specified in their metadata. Once each of the documents in the list has been labeled to its resulting cluster index, the list has been reordered according to the described principle: we fill the list by alternating documents from different clusters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Experiments description</head><p>The data set contains 498,920 images from Belga News Agency, an image search engine for news photographs. Each photograph will be up to a maximum of 512 pixels in either width or height, accompanied by a caption composed of English text up to a few sentences in length. Different to the data last year, captions are provided without a specific format to increase the challenges to participants. Caption might contain date and place where image was captured.</p><p>The topics statements include a query title with few words, and some cluster titles and descriptions, to promote the diversity of the final results, as appear in the Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,440.01,527.46,3.87,10.46" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. In our system descriptions are not used. 2.</p><p>(2) SINAI2 -title and final cluster. This experiment combines the query title with the title of the final that appear in the topics file. Lemur also uses Okapi as weighting function and PRF.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>3.</head><p>(3) SINAI3 -title and all clusters. This experiment combines the query title with all the words that appear in the titles of all the clusters. Lemur also uses Okapi as weighting function and PRF.</p><p>4. (4) SINAI4 -clustering. The query title and each cluster title (except the last one that combines all) are run against the index generated by the IR system. Several lists of relevant documents are retrieved, and the clustering module combines them to obtain the final list of relevant documents. The aim of this experiment is to increment the diversity of the retrieved results using a clustering algorithm.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Results and Discussion</head><p>The data set of the collection has been indexed using Lemur 3 IR system, by applying Okapi weighing function and using Pseudo-Relevance Feedback (PRF). We have used only textual information in English. We have experimented with different kinds of cluster combination. However, as we can see in Table <ref type="table" coords="4,117.08,507.12,3.87,10.46" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, the application of clustering does not improve the results greatly. In fact, only in the run used SINAI3 the query the original title and the titles of all the clusters overcomes the baseline case SINAI1 that only uses the original title. Unfortunately, the experiment SINAI4 that applies our clustering and fusion approach has achieved the worst results. Thus, the obtained results show that it is necessary to continue investigating the clustering methodology. In addition, the use of visual information could improve the final system.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,153.85,117.46,295.29,10.46;3,113.53,128.93,372.49,226.70"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: General scheme of the SINAI system at ImagePhoto 2009</figDesc><graphic coords="3,113.53,128.93,372.49,226.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="3,209.43,570.18,184.14,10.46;3,188.21,581.62,226.53,141.70"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: ImagePhoto 2009: query sample</figDesc><graphic coords="3,188.21,581.62,226.53,141.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,141.11,368.54,347.58,113.17"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Table 1 shows the results obtained in our four experiments submitted this year. SINAI experiment results</figDesc><table coords="4,149.71,391.20,303.57,58.67"><row><cell>Experiment</cell><cell>Rank</cell><cell>CR10</cell><cell>P10</cell><cell>MAP</cell><cell>F-measure</cell></row><row><cell>sinai1 T TXT</cell><cell>58</cell><cell>0.4580</cell><cell>0.796</cell><cell>0.4454</cell><cell>0.5814</cell></row><row><cell>sinai2 TCT TXT</cell><cell>70</cell><cell>0.3798</cell><cell>58</cell><cell>0.3286</cell><cell>0.4590</cell></row><row><cell>sinai3 TCT TXT</cell><cell>44</cell><cell cols="3">0.5210 0.778 0.4567</cell><cell>0.6241</cell></row><row><cell>sinai4 TCT TXT</cell><cell>72</cell><cell>0.4356</cell><cell>0.474</cell><cell>0.2233</cell><cell>0.4540</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,105.24,722.38,166.11,8.37"><p>Available at http://www.lemurproject.org/</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="2,105.24,731.89,116.01,8.37"><p>Available at http://rapid-i.com</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="5">Acknowledgements</head><p>This work has been supported by the <rs type="funder">Regional Government of Andaluca (Spain)</rs> under excellence project <rs type="projectName">GeOasis</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">P08-41999</rs>), the <rs type="funder">Spanish Government</rs> under project <rs type="projectName">Text-Mess TIMOM</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">TIN2006-15265-C06-03</rs>) and the local project <rs type="grantNumber">RFC/PP2008/UJA-08-16-14</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_XTsEHkm">
					<idno type="grant-number">P08-41999</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">GeOasis</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_f4qc8Tm">
					<idno type="grant-number">TIN2006-15265-C06-03</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">Text-Mess TIMOM</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_MPuhnjU">
					<idno type="grant-number">RFC/PP2008/UJA-08-16-14</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="4,105.50,700.33,407.51,10.46;4,105.50,712.28,338.58,10.46" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="4,313.34,700.33,199.67,10.46;4,105.50,712.28,100.51,10.46">Diversity in photo retrieval: overview of the ImageCLEFPhoto task</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Paramita</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sanderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Clough</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="4,235.34,712.28,111.92,10.46">CLEF working notes 2009</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Corfu, Greece</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009. 2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,110.53,407.51,10.46;5,105.50,122.49,129.01,10.46" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,171.03,110.53,143.71,10.46">An algorithm for suffix stripping</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Porter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,336.14,110.53,145.31,10.46">Readings in information retrieval</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="316" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,142.41,407.51,10.46;5,105.50,154.37,407.51,10.46;5,105.50,166.33,149.19,10.46" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,194.24,154.37,118.31,10.46">SINAI at ImageCLEF 2006</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Díaz-Galiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Martín-Valdivia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Montejo-Raez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ureña-López</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,333.31,154.37,179.70,10.46;5,105.50,166.33,118.75,10.46">Proceedings of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</title>
		<meeting>the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2006)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,186.26,407.51,10.46;5,105.50,198.21,407.51,10.46;5,105.50,210.16,149.19,10.46" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,194.24,198.21,118.31,10.46">SINAI at ImageCLEF 2007</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Díaz-Galiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Martín-Valdivia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Montejo-Raez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ureña-López</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,333.31,198.21,179.70,10.46;5,105.50,210.16,118.75,10.46">Proceedings of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2007)</title>
		<meeting>the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2007)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,230.09,407.50,10.46;5,105.50,242.04,407.51,10.46;5,105.50,253.99,196.65,10.46" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,105.50,242.04,75.53,10.46">GEOUJA System</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Perea-Ortega</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>García-Vega</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Montejo-Raez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,379.57,242.04,133.44,10.46;5,105.50,253.99,106.86,10.46">Proceedings of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum</title>
		<meeting>the Cross Language Evaluation Forum<address><addrLine>CLEF</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007. 2007. 2007</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Jaén at GEOCLEF</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,273.92,407.51,10.46;5,105.50,285.88,407.50,10.46;5,105.50,297.84,52.58,10.46" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,105.50,285.88,117.88,10.46">SINAI at ImageCLEF 2008</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Díaz-Galiano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>García-Cumbreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Martín-Valdivia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ureña-López</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,243.87,285.88,269.13,10.46;5,105.50,297.84,22.14,10.46">Proceedings of the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2008)</title>
		<meeting>the Cross Language Evaluation Forum (CLEF 2008)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,317.76,407.50,10.46;5,105.50,329.72,210.13,10.46" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,282.21,317.76,158.96,10.46">Relevance weighting of search terms</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">Sparck</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,449.92,317.76,63.09,10.46;5,105.50,329.72,179.83,10.46">Journal of the American Society for Information Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1976">1976</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,349.64,407.51,10.46;5,105.50,361.60,407.50,10.46;5,105.50,373.55,342.97,10.46" xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,216.04,349.64,296.97,10.46;5,105.50,361.60,29.23,10.46">Less is more: probabilistic models for retrieving fewer relevant documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Karger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,143.23,361.60,369.77,10.46;5,105.50,373.55,219.51,10.46">SIGIR &apos;06: Proceedings of the 29th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Seattle, Washington</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.50,393.47,407.51,10.46;5,105.50,405.43,407.51,10.46;5,105.50,417.39,332.98,10.46" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,475.78,393.47,37.22,10.46;5,105.50,405.43,262.69,10.46">Crossing textual and visual content in different application scenarios</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ah-Pine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bressan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Clinchant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Csurka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Hoppenot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Renders</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="5,376.45,405.43,103.95,10.46">Multimedia Tools Appl</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1380-7501</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="56" />
			<publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,110.48,437.32,402.53,10.46;5,105.50,449.27,407.51,10.46;5,105.50,461.22,169.25,10.46" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,326.68,437.32,186.34,10.46;5,105.50,449.27,252.91,10.46">Using Ontology Dimensions and Negative Expansion to solve Precise Queries in CLEF Medical Task</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Chevallet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Radhouani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,366.38,449.27,146.63,10.46;5,105.50,461.22,41.16,10.46">Working Notes of the 2005 CLEF Workshop</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Vienna, Austria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-09">Sep, 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
