<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,185.88,90.21,240.27,15.39">TREC 2007 Spam Track Overview</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,254.04,125.62,103.76,10.86"><forename type="first">Gordon</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Cormack</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Waterloo</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Waterloo</settlement>
									<region>Ontario</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,185.88,90.21,240.27,15.39">TREC 2007 Spam Track Overview</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">DAA24C6947415427185B00D29DFFF291</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>TREC's Spam Track uses a standard testing framework that presents a set of chronologically ordered email messages a spam filter for classification. In the filtering task, the messages are presented one at at time to the filter, which yields a binary judgment (spam or ham [i.e. non-spam]) which is compared to a humanadjudicated gold standard. The filter also yields a spamminess score, intended to reflect the likelihood that the classified message is spam, which is the subject of post-hoc ROC (Receiver Operating Characteristic) analysis. Four different forms of user feedback are modeled: with immediate feedback the gold standard for each message is communicated to the filter immediately following classification; with delayed feedback the gold standard is communicated to the filter sometime later (or potentially never), so as to model a user reading email from time to time and perhaps not diligently reporting the filter's errors; with partial feedback the gold standard for only a subset of email recipients is transmitted to the filter, so as to model the case of some users never reporting filter errors; with active on-line learning (suggested by D. Sculley from Tufts University <ref type="bibr" coords="1,120.01,353.97,15.49,9.96" target="#b10">[11]</ref>) the filter is allowed to request immediate feedback for a certain quota of messages which is considerably smaller than the total number. Two test corpora -email messages plus gold standard judgments -were used to evaluate subject filters. One public corpus (trec07p) was distributed to participants, who ran their filters on the corpora using a track-supplied toolkit implementing the framework and the four kinds of feedback. One private corpus (MrX 3) was not distributed to participants; rather, participants submitted filter implementations that were run, using the toolkit, on the private data. Twelve groups participated in the track, each submitting up to four filters for evaluation in each of the four feedback modes (immediate; delayed; partial; active).</p><p>Task guidelines and tools may be found on the web at http://plg.uwaterloo.ca/˜gvcormac/spam/ .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.1">Filtering -Immediate Feedback</head><p>The immediate feedback filtering task is identical to the TREC 2005 and TREC 2006 (immediate) tasks <ref type="bibr" coords="1,72.00,516.81,10.57,9.96" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,86.40,516.81,6.97,9.96" target="#b4">5]</ref>. A chronological sequence of messages is presented to the filter using a standard interface. The the filter classifies each message in turn as either spam or ham, also computes a spamminess score indicating its confidence that the message is spam. The test setup simulates an ideal user who communicates the correct (gold standard) classification to the filter for each message immediately after the filter classifies it. Participants were supplied with tools, sample filters, and sample corpora (including the TREC 2005 and TREC 2006 public corpora) for training and development. Filters were evaluated on the two new corpora developed for TREC 2007.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2">Filtering -Delayed Feedback</head><p>Real user's don't immediately report the correct classification to filters. They read their email, typically in batches, some time after it is classified. Last year (TREC 2006) the delayed learning task sought to simulate user behavior by withholding feedback for some random number of messages after which feedback was given; this delay followed by feedback was repeated in several cycles. This year (TREC 2007) the track seeks instead to measure the effect of delay. To this end, immediate feedback is given for the first several thousand messages (10,000 for trec07p; 20,000 for MrX 3) after which no feedback at all is given. Thus, the majority of the corpus is classified with no feedback and the cumulative effect of delay may be evaluated by examining the learning curve.</p><p>Participants trained on the TREC 2006 corpus. While the 2007 guidelines specified that feedback might never be given, they did not specify the exact nature of the task. It was anticipated that the delayed feedback task would be more difficult for the filters, and that filter performance would degrade during the interval for which no feedback was given. It was anticipated that participants might be able to harness information from unlabeled messages (the ones for which feedback was not given) to improve performance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.3">Partial Feedback</head><p>Partial feedback is a variant on delayed feedback effected with exactly the same tools. As for "delayed feedback" the feedback was in fact either given immediately or not at all. In this case, however, the messages for which feedback was given were those sent to a subset of the recipients in the corpus; that is, the filter was trained on some users' messages but asked to classify every users' messages. Partial feedback was used only for the trec07p corpus, as it contained email addressed to many recipients. It was not applicable to MrX 3, being a single-user corpus.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.4">The On-line Active Learning Task</head><p>For the on-line task, filters were passed an additional parameter -the quota of messages for which feedback could be requested -and were expected to return an additional result -to request or decline feedback for each message classified. Filters that were unaware of these parameters were assumed to request feedback for each message classified until the quota was exhausted; thus the default behavior was identical to the delayed feedback task. However, filters were able to decline feedback for some messages (presumably those whose classification the filter found unimportant) in order to preserve quota so as to be able to request feedback for later messages.</p><p>A naive solution to this problem would be to have the filter make a label request for every message. This would request labels and train normally for the first N messages, where N is the initial quota, and then would not update for the remainder of the run. The testing jig is backward compatible with filters from prior years by making the naive approach the default method if no label request is specified. This allows prior filters to run on this task without modification.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Evaluation Measures</head><p>We used the same evaluation measures developed for TREC 2005. The tables and figures in this overview report Receiver Operating Characteristic (ROC) Curves, as well as 1 -ROCA(%) -the area above the ROC curve, indicating the probability that a random spam message will receive a lower spamminess score than a random ham message.</p><p>The appendix contains detailed summary reports for each participant run, including ROC curves, 1-ROCA%, and the following statistics. The ham misclassification percentage (hm% ) is the fraction of all ham classified as spam; the spam misclassification percentage (sm% ) is the fraction of all spam classified as ham.</p><p>There is a natural tension between ham and spam misclassification percentages. A filter may improve one at the expense of the other. Most filters, either internally or externally, compute a spamminess score that reflects the filter's estimate of the likelihood that a message is spam. This score is compared against some fixed threshold t to determine the ham/spam classification. Increasing t reduces hm% while increasing sm% and vice versa. Given the score for each message, it is possible to compute sm% as a function of hm% (that is, sm% when t is adjusted to as to achieve a specific hm% ) or vice versa. The graphical representation of this function is a Receiver Operating Characteristic (ROC) curve; alternatively a recall-fallout curve. The area under the ROC curve is a cumulative measure of the effectiveness of the filter over all possible values. ROC area also has a probabilistic interpretation: the probability that a random ham will receive a lower score than a random spam. For consistency with hm% and sm%, which measure failure rather than effectiveness, spam track reports the area above the ROC curve, as a percentage ( (1 -ROCA)% ). The appendix further reports sm% when the threshold is adjusted to achieve several specific levels of hm%, and vice versa. A single quality measure, based only on the filter's binary ham/spam classifications, is nonetheless desirable. To this end, the appendix reports logistic average misclassification percentage (lam% ) defined as lam% = logit -1 ( logit(hm%)+logit (sm%)  odds of ham and spam misclassification, converted back to a proportion<ref type="foot" coords="3,384.12,51.53,3.97,6.97" target="#foot_1">1</ref> . This measure imposes no a priori relative importance on ham or spam misclassification, and rewards equally a fixed-factor improvement in the odds of either. For each measure and each corpus, the appendix reports 95% confidence limits computed using a bootstrap method <ref type="bibr" coords="3,108.48,103.65,10.57,9.96" target="#b3">[4]</ref> under the assumption that the test corpus was randomly selected from some source population with the same characteristics.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Spam Filter Evaluation Tool Kit</head><p>All filter evaluations were performed using the TREC Spam Filter Evaluation Toolkit, developed for this purpose. The toolkit is free software and is readily portable. Participants were required to provide filter implementations for Linux or Windows implementing five commandline operations mandated by the toolkit:</p><p>• initialize -creates any files or servers necessary for the operation of the filter • classify message [quota] -returns ham/spam classification and spamminess score for message. <ref type="bibr" coords="3,510.49,259.65,29.46,9.96">[quota]</ref> is used only in active learning feedback.</p><p>• train ham message -informs filter of correct (ham) classification for previously classified message</p><p>• train spam message -informs filter of correct (spam) classification for previously classified message</p><p>• finalize -removes any files or servers created by the filter.</p><p>Track guidelines prohibited filters from using network resources, and constrained temporary disk storage (1 GB), RAM (1 GB), and run-time (2 sec/message, amortized). These limits were enforced incrementally, so that individual long-running filters were granted more than 2 seconds provided the overall average time was less than 2 second per query plus one minute to facilitate start-up. The toolkit takes as input a test corpus consisting of a set of email messages, one per file, and an index file indicating the chronological sequence and gold-standard judgments for the messages. It calls on the filter to classify each message in turn, records the result, and at some time later (perhaps immediately, perhaps never, and perhaps only on request of the filter) communicates the gold standard judgment to the filter. The recorded results are post-processed by an evaluation component supplied with the toolkit. This component computes statistics, confidence intervals, and graphs summarizing the filter's performance. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Public Corpus -trec07p</head><p>The public corpus contains all the messages delivered to a particular server from April 8 through July 6, 2007. The server contains many accounts that have fallen into disuse but continue to receive a lot of spam. To these accounts were added a number of "honeypot" accounts published on the web and used to sign up for a number of services -some legitimate and some not. Several services were canceled and several "opt-out" links from spam messages were clicked. All messages were adjudicated using the methodology developed for previous spam tracks. <ref type="bibr" coords="4,174.12,76.77,10.45,9.96" target="#b5">[6]</ref> This corpus is the first TREC public corpus that contains exclusively ham and spam sent to the same server within the same time period. The messages were unaltered except for a few systematic substitutions of names.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Private Corpus -MrX3</head><p>The Twelve groups participated in the TREC 2007 spam track. Each participant submitted up to four filter implementations for evaluation on the private corpora; in addition, each participant ran the same filters on the public corpora, which were made available following filter submission. All test runs are labeled with an identifier whose prefix indicates the group and filter priority and whose suffix indicates the corpus to which the filter is applied. Table <ref type="table" coords="4,189.86,604.89,4.98,9.96" target="#tab_1">2</ref> shows the identifier prefix for each submitted filter. All test runs have a suffix indicating the corpus and task, detailed in figure <ref type="figure" coords="4,287.81,616.89,4.98,9.96">3</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">Results</head><p>Figures  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">Conclusions</head><p>Once again, the general performance of filters has improved over previous techniques. Support vector machines <ref type="bibr" coords="7,101.64,633.09,15.49,9.96" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="7,120.36,633.09,7.81,9.96" target="#b8">9]</ref> and logistic regression <ref type="bibr" coords="7,230.65,633.09,9.91,9.96" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, specifically engineered for spam filtering, show exceptionally strong performance. Delayed and partial feedback degrade filter performance; at the time of writing we are unaware of any special methods used by participants mitigate this degradation <ref type="bibr" coords="7,376.94,656.97,14.60,9.96" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. The learning curves do not show substantial de-learning as delay increases. The best-performing techniques for active learning use techniques akin to "uncertainty scheduling" <ref type="bibr" coords="7,512.44,683.85,15.49,9.96" target="#b11">[12]</ref> in which feedback is requested only for those messages whose score is near the filter's threshold. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">Epilogue</head><p>In each of the three years that TREC has hosted the spam track, new techniques have dominated the previous state of the art. In TREC 2005, sequential compression models showed outstanding performance <ref type="bibr" coords="8,72.00,549.33,10.57,9.96" target="#b1">[2]</ref> -much better than that achieved by commonly deployed "Bayesian" filters. In TREC 2006, OSBF-Lua achieved dominance through Orthogonal Sparse Bigrams and iterative training <ref type="bibr" coords="8,427.82,561.33,10.00,9.96" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. This year, SVM and logistic regression methods -based on character features -were for the first time shown to be superior for spam.</p><p>CEAS 2008, the Conference on Email and Anti-Spam (www.ceas.cc) will host a laboratory evaluation modeled after the spam track. In addition, CEAS will run the Live Challenge -a real-time version of the task using a live email feed rather than an archival corpus. Other evaluation efforts -and their results -are compared and contrasted with the spam track in a recent survey <ref type="bibr" coords="8,357.60,635.97,10.00,9.96" target="#b7">[8]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9">Acknowledgments</head><p>The author thanks D. Sculley for suggesting the active feedback task and making the necessary modifications to the spam filter evaluation toolkit.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="3,72.00,502.60,467.96,138.53"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Corpus StatisticsFor TREC 2007, we used one public corpus and one private corpus with a total of 237,394 messages (see table1).</figDesc><table coords="3,72.00,502.60,310.62,82.13"><row><cell>4 Test Corpora</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Ham</cell><cell>Spam</cell><cell>Total</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">trec07p 25220 50199</cell><cell>75419</cell></row><row><cell>MrX3</cell><cell cols="3">8082 153893 161975</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell cols="3">33302 204092 237394</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1" coords="4,72.00,152.97,468.20,371.52"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>MrX3 corpus was derived from the same source as the MrX and MrX2 corpora used for TREC 2006 and TREC 2006 respectively. All of X's email from December 2006 through July 11, 2007 was used. The proportion of spam has grown substantially since 2005 2 ; Ham volume was insubstantially different. Participant filters</figDesc><table coords="4,72.00,210.28,380.39,314.21"><row><cell>5 Spam Track Participation</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Group</cell><cell></cell><cell>Filter Prefix</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications kid</cell></row><row><cell>Fudan University-WIM Lab</cell><cell></cell><cell>fdw</cell></row><row><cell>Heilongjiang Institute of Technology</cell><cell></cell><cell>hit</cell></row><row><cell>Indiana University</cell><cell></cell><cell>iub</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">International Institute of Information Technology</cell><cell>III</cell></row><row><cell>Jozef Stefan Institute</cell><cell></cell><cell>ijs</cell></row><row><cell>Mitsubishi Electric Research Labs</cell><cell></cell><cell>crm</cell></row><row><cell>National University of Defense Technology</cell><cell></cell><cell>ndt</cell></row><row><cell>Shanghai Jiao Tong University</cell><cell></cell><cell>sjt</cell></row><row><cell>South China University of Technology</cell><cell></cell><cell>scu</cell></row><row><cell>Tufts University</cell><cell></cell><cell>tft</cell></row><row><cell>University of Waterloo</cell><cell></cell><cell>wat</cell></row><row><cell>Corpus / Task</cell><cell cols="2">Filter Suffix</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">trec07p / immediate feedback pf</cell></row><row><cell>trec07p / delayed feedback</cell><cell>pd</cell></row><row><cell>trec07p / partial feedback</cell><cell>pp</cell></row><row><cell>trec07p / active feedback</cell><cell>p1000</cell></row><row><cell>MrX3 / immediate feedback</cell><cell>x3f</cell></row><row><cell>MrX3 /delayed feedback</cell><cell>x3d</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="4,253.80,535.89,104.37,9.96"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Run-id suffixes</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="7,72.00,516.09,468.03,54.24"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Summary 1-ROCA (%) -trec07p Public Corpus participant is shown in the figures; tables 4 and 5 show 1-ROCA% for all feedback regimens on trec07p and MrX3 respectively. Full details for all runs are given in the notebook appendix.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="8,175.80,53.57,260.24,424.60"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Summary 1-ROCA (%) -MrX3 Private Corpus</figDesc><table coords="8,175.80,53.57,260.24,401.89"><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Immediate feed.</cell><cell cols="2">Delayed feed.</cell></row><row><cell>Rank</cell><cell>run tag</cell><cell>1-ROCA(%)</cell><cell>run tag</cell><cell>1-ROCA(%)</cell></row><row><cell>1</cell><cell>tftS3Fx3f</cell><cell>0.0042</cell><cell>tftS3Fx3d</cell><cell>0.0568</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>tftS2Fx3f</cell><cell>0.0054</cell><cell>tftS2Fx3d</cell><cell>0.0683</cell></row><row><cell>3</cell><cell>wat3x3f</cell><cell>0.0076</cell><cell>tftS1Fx3d</cell><cell>0.0685</cell></row><row><cell>4</cell><cell>wat1x3f</cell><cell>0.0096</cell><cell>fdw1x3d</cell><cell>0.0747</cell></row><row><cell>5</cell><cell>wat4x3f</cell><cell>0.0096</cell><cell>fdw2x3d</cell><cell>0.0751</cell></row><row><cell>6</cell><cell>fdw2x3f</cell><cell>0.0147</cell><cell>wat3x3d</cell><cell>0.0787</cell></row><row><cell>7</cell><cell>fdw3x3f</cell><cell>0.0154</cell><cell>wat1x3d</cell><cell>0.0896</cell></row><row><cell>8</cell><cell>fdw1x3f</cell><cell>0.0155</cell><cell>fdw3x3d</cell><cell>0.1062</cell></row><row><cell>9</cell><cell>tftS1Fx3f</cell><cell>0.0166</cell><cell>fdw4x3d</cell><cell>0.1258</cell></row><row><cell>10</cell><cell>wat2x3f</cell><cell>0.0219</cell><cell>crm1x3d</cell><cell>0.2079</cell></row><row><cell>11</cell><cell>ijsdctx3f</cell><cell>0.0229</cell><cell>wat2x3d</cell><cell>0.2512</cell></row><row><cell>12</cell><cell>fdw4x3f</cell><cell>0.0255</cell><cell>ijsctwx3d</cell><cell>0.2830</cell></row><row><cell>13</cell><cell>ijsdcwx3f</cell><cell>0.0281</cell><cell>ijsppmx3d</cell><cell>0.3055</cell></row><row><cell>14</cell><cell>osbfx3f</cell><cell>0.0281</cell><cell>crm2x3d</cell><cell>0.3811</cell></row><row><cell>15</cell><cell>ijsctwx3f</cell><cell>0.0392</cell><cell>ijsdcwx3d</cell><cell>0.5036</cell></row><row><cell>16</cell><cell>ijsppmx3f</cell><cell>0.0397</cell><cell>ijsdctx3d</cell><cell>0.5288</cell></row><row><cell>17</cell><cell>crm1x3f</cell><cell>0.0543</cell><cell>crm4x3d</cell><cell>0.7589</cell></row><row><cell>18</cell><cell>hitSPAM1hpex3f</cell><cell>0.0650</cell><cell>sjtWinnowx3d</cell><cell>0.9674</cell></row><row><cell>19</cell><cell>hitSPAM2chix3f</cell><cell>0.1032</cell><cell>ndtEx3d</cell><cell>2.2840</cell></row><row><cell>20</cell><cell>crm4x3f</cell><cell>0.1145</cell><cell>crm3x3d</cell><cell>2.5169</cell></row><row><cell>21</cell><cell>crm2x3f</cell><cell>0.1296</cell><cell>kid0x3d</cell><cell>2.5383</cell></row><row><cell>22</cell><cell>sjtWinnowx3f</cell><cell>0.1666</cell><cell>ndtDx3d</cell><cell>4.6920</cell></row><row><cell>23</cell><cell>sjtMulti1x3f</cell><cell>0.3413</cell><cell>sjtMulti1x3d</cell><cell>5.0656</cell></row><row><cell>24</cell><cell>crm3x3f</cell><cell>0.9476</cell><cell>ndtAx3d</cell><cell>5.3401</cell></row><row><cell>25</cell><cell>IIITx3f</cell><cell>1.0234</cell><cell>sjtBayesx3d</cell><cell>28.7693</cell></row><row><cell>26</cell><cell>kidult0x3f</cell><cell>1.0313</cell><cell>IIITx3d</cell><cell>49.9682</cell></row><row><cell>27</cell><cell>ndtDx3f</cell><cell>1.3985</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>28</cell><cell>sjtBayesx3f</cell><cell>2.0811</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>29</cell><cell>ndtAx3f</cell><cell>2.4078</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>30</cell><cell>scut2x3f</cell><cell>4.7596</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>31</cell><cell>iube5c6x3f</cell><cell>19.0336</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row><row><cell>32</cell><cell>hitSPAM3bayx3f</cell><cell>49.9682</cell><cell>-</cell><cell>-</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,196.20,721.89,103.35,9.96;2,313.08,720.56,4.52,6.26;2,300.72,727.49,29.24,6.97;2,331.08,721.89,208.90,9.96"><p>) where logit(x) = log( x 100%-x ). That is, lam% is the geometric mean of the</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_1" coords="3,87.24,726.14,452.62,7.61;3,72.00,735.99,126.51,7.24"><p>For small values, odds and proportion are essentially equal. Therefore lam% shares much with the geometric mean average precision used in the robust track.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_2" coords="4,87.24,720.87,452.66,7.24;4,72.00,730.35,157.58,7.24"><p>Note that the MrX and MrX3 corpora include all email delivered during a particular time period, MrX2 was sampled so as to yield the same ham:spam ratio as MrX.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="9,92.52,77.73,447.51,9.96;9,92.52,89.61,384.04,9.96" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,138.72,77.73,396.10,9.96">OSBF-Lua -A Text Classification Module for Lua The Importance of the Training Method</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Assis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,104.88,89.61,221.29,9.96">Fifteenth Text REtrieval Conference (TREC-2006)</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>NIST</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,92.52,109.53,447.45,9.96;9,92.52,121.53,446.41,9.96" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,451.68,109.53,88.29,9.96;9,92.52,121.53,152.49,9.96">Spam filtering using statistical data compression models</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bratko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Cormack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Filipič</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lynam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Zupan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="9,254.16,121.53,168.30,9.96">Journal of Machine Learning Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2673" to="2698" />
			<date type="published" when="2006-12">Dec (2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,92.52,141.45,447.39,9.96;9,92.52,153.45,26.77,9.96" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,165.12,141.45,137.08,9.96">Trec 2005 spam track overview</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cormack</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,327.00,141.45,119.45,9.96">Proceedings of TREC 2005</title>
		<meeting>TREC 2005<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,92.52,173.37,447.30,9.96;9,92.52,185.25,89.30,9.96" xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,162.36,173.37,237.63,9.96">Statistical precision of information retrieval evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cormack</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,422.16,173.37,117.66,9.96">Proceedings of SIGIR 2006</title>
		<meeting>SIGIR 2006<address><addrLine>Seattle, WA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,92.52,205.17,447.39,9.96;9,92.52,217.17,26.77,9.96" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,165.12,205.17,137.08,9.96">Trec 2006 spam track overview</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cormack</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,327.00,205.17,119.45,9.96">Proceedings of TREC 2006</title>
		<meeting>TREC 2006<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,92.52,237.09,447.52,9.96;9,92.52,249.09,351.39,9.96" xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,249.60,237.09,148.21,9.96">Spam Corpus Creation for TREC</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cormack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Lynam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,425.64,237.09,114.40,9.96;9,92.52,249.09,222.71,9.96">Proceedings of the Second Conference on Email and Anti-Spam (CEAS-2005)</title>
		<meeting>the Second Conference on Email and Anti-Spam (CEAS-2005)<address><addrLine>Mountain View, CA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,92.52,269.01,447.29,9.96;9,92.52,280.89,116.80,9.96" xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,174.60,269.01,229.86,9.96">Waterloo participation in the TREC 2007 spam track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Cormack</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,424.08,269.01,115.73,9.96">Proceedings of TREC 2007</title>
		<meeting>TREC 2007<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,92.52,300.81,331.70,9.96" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="9,176.28,300.81,186.32,9.96">Email Spam Filtering: A systematic review</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Cormack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,92.52,320.85,447.50,9.96;9,92.52,332.73,409.48,9.96" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,375.00,320.85,165.02,9.96;9,92.52,332.73,149.65,9.96">Three non-Bayesian methods of spam filtration: CRM114 at TREC 2007</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Langeway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Yerazunis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,263.40,332.73,116.93,9.96">Proceedings of TREC 2007</title>
		<meeting>TREC 2007<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,92.52,352.65,447.29,9.96;9,92.52,364.65,79.59,9.96" xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,266.88,352.65,200.68,9.96">Semi-supervised spam filtering: does it work?</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mojdeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Cormack</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,487.44,352.65,52.37,9.96">SIGIR 2008</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Singapore</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,92.52,384.57,447.29,9.96;9,92.52,396.45,258.50,9.96" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,159.48,384.57,301.40,9.96">Online active learning methods for fast label-efficient spam filtering</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sculley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,485.28,384.57,54.53,9.96;9,92.52,396.45,189.23,9.96">CEAS 2007: Fourth Conference on Email and AntiSpam</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-08">August 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="9,92.52,416.49,447.53,9.96;9,92.52,428.37,238.60,9.96" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="9,273.36,416.49,247.02,9.96">Relaxed online SVMs in the TREC spam filtering track</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sculley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Wachman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="9,92.52,428.37,116.93,9.96">Proceedings of TREC 2007</title>
		<meeting>TREC 2007<address><addrLine>Gaithersburg, MD</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
