<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,170.05,137.95,289.90,15.12">Overview of the TREC 2011 Entity Track</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,195.15,170.43,79.88,10.48"><forename type="first">Krisztian</forename><surname>Balog</surname></persName>
							<email>krisztian.balog@idi.ntnu.no</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,370.93,170.43,84.38,10.48"><forename type="first">Pavel</forename><surname>Serdyukov</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">NTNU</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Trondheim</settlement>
									<country key="NO">Norway</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<address>
									<settlement>Yandex</settlement>
									<country key="RU">Russia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Arjen P. de Vries CWI</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,170.05,137.95,289.90,15.12">Overview of the TREC 2011 Entity Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">8B58BEA62C911C3FAA4133DDE96CCCBB</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-08-05T15:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="612.0" lry="792.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>The TREC Entity track aimed to build test collections to evaluate entity-oriented search on Web data. In 2011, the track worked with two corpora: the ClueWeb 2009 web corpus and the new Sindice-2011 dataset <ref type="bibr" coords="1,220.96,333.24,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p><p>Motivated by observations from the 2010 Entity track, we made the following changes in the track setup for 2011. In the REF task, we focused on modifications to simplify the evaluation and to improve cross-system comparison: (1) only primary homepages are accepted, i.e., relevance is binary; <ref type="bibr" coords="1,154.26,381.06,12.73,8.74" target="#b1">(2)</ref> for each answer, a (single) supporting document is required; (3) target type is not limited anymore; (4) groups that generate results using Web Search Engines are required to submit an obligatory run, using the Lemur ClueWeb Online Query Service.</p><p>The main change regarding the LOD task is the use of the Sindice-2011 corpus, an improved and larger Semantic Web crawl, replacing the BTC-2009 collection used in 2010: <ref type="bibr" coords="1,462.93,428.88,12.73,8.74" target="#b0">(1)</ref> the target corpus is a larger and more representative LOD crawl; <ref type="bibr" coords="1,350.09,440.83,12.73,8.74" target="#b1">(2)</ref> examples are not mapped manually to LOD, but given as ClueWeb document identifiers.</p><p>Finally, we introduced a new pilot task, REF-LOD, to explore the differences between ranking web data and ranking semantic web data, possibly enabling deeper investigations into connecting Semantic Web data with the 'real' web. We basically repeated the REF task, but requested results identified by their LOD URIs instead of their homepages. One of the goals of this task was to gain more insights in entity representation, and specifically investigate how often entities that are not represented on the web with their own homepage are represented as entities in LOD.</p><p>In the remainder of the paper we first detail the setup of each task. We present the results collected in this year's track participation, and summarize the approaches applied. The paper concludes with a brief discussion of the problems faced by the track, and the way forward.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">Tasks</head><p>The third edition of the Entity track featured two main tasks and a pilot task; all are variations of the related entity finding problem, but differ in how the input is formulated (i.e., whether example entities are available), in the data collections used, and in the means of entity identification. The tasks are summarized in   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Main task 1: Related Entity Finding</head><p>The Related Entity Finding (REF) task is defined as follows:</p><p>Given an input entity, by its name and homepage, the type of the target entity, as well as the nature of their relation, described in free text, find related entities that are of target type, standing in the required relation to the input entity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.1">Input</head><p>For each request (query) the following information is provided:</p><p>• Input entity, defined by its name and homepage (ClueWeb ID)</p><p>• Type of the target entity</p><p>• Narrative (describing the nature of the relation in free text) An example information need, "manufacturers of vehicles used by UPS" is formulated as follows: &lt;query&gt; &lt;num&gt;80&lt;/num&gt; &lt;entity_name&gt;United Parcel Service (UPS)&lt;/entity_name&gt; &lt;entity_URL&gt;clueweb09-en0014-05-00600&lt;/entity_URL&gt; &lt;target_entity&gt;manufacturer&lt;/target_entity&gt; &lt;narrative&gt;manufacturers of vehicles used by UPS&lt;/narrative&gt; &lt;/query&gt; A key change to last year's setup is that target entity types are not limited anymore to the four high-level entity types (person, organization, location, product). The target type is extracted from the narrative and is always given in singular form.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.2">Output</head><p>• For each query, participants may return up to 100 answers (related entities). Each query must have at least one entity retrieved for it.</p><p>• For each answer entity a single homepage and a single supporting document must be returned; optionally, the name of the entity may also be returned.</p><p>• Participating teams may submit up to four runs, at least one of which will be judged.</p><p>• Groups that generate results using Web Search Engines are required to submit an obligatory run, using the Lemur ClueWeb Online Query Service,<ref type="foot" coords="2,388.39,647.02,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_0">1</ref> to ensure reproducibility.</p><p>New in 2011 that we require a single supporting document for each answer and that Web Search Engines may not be used unless submitting a corresponding run using a common ClueWeb API.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.3">Data collection</head><p>The document collection is the English portion of ClueWeb, comprising of approximately 500 million pages.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.4">Topics and assessments</head><p>Both topic development and relevance assessments were performed by NIST. For the 2011 edition of the track 50 new REF topics have been created. The evaluation methodology differs from what was originally set out in the guidelines. In particular, runs are evaluated using standard trec eval and supporting documents are not incorporated into the evaluation. The judgments come from two sources: answers found by the assessors during topic development and pooled results from participants (pooled down to depth 30). Although not used in the scoring, a judgment file with the assessments of supporting documents and name correctness has also been made available.</p><p>The main evaluation measure we use is Mean Average Precision (MAP). We also report on R-Precision (precision at rank R).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Related Entity Finding, LOD-variant</head><p>In this pilot we investigate using Linked Open Data (LOD) URIs instead of homepages for entity identification. The task and the topics are the same as for the main REF task. The LOD crawl used is the Sindice-2011 data set; see Section 2.3.3 for details.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Entity List Completion</head><p>Entity List Completion (ELC) addresses essentially the same task as REF does: finding entities that are engaged in a specific relation with an input entity. There are two main differences to REF:</p><p>• Entities are not represented by their homepages, but by a unique URI (from a specific collection, a sample of the Linked Open Data cloud).<ref type="foot" coords="3,364.32,453.97,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_1">2</ref> </p><p>• A number of entity homepages (i.e., ClueWeb docIDs) are made available as part of the topic definition, as examples of known relevant answers.</p><p>The ELC task then is defined as follows:</p><p>Given an information need and a list of known relevant entity homepages, return a list of relevant entity URIs from a specific collection of Linked Open Data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.1">Input</head><p>For each request (query) the following information is provided:</p><p>• Input entity, defined by its name, homepage (ClueWeb docID), and one or more LOD URIs</p><p>• Type of the target entity (defined using the DBpedia Ontology<ref type="foot" coords="3,407.79,633.75,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_2">3</ref> )</p><p>• Narrative (describing the nature of the relation in free text) </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.2">Output</head><p>• For each query, participants may return up to 100 answers (related entities). Each query must have at least one entity retrieved for it.</p><p>• For each answer entity a single URI must be returned; optionally, the name of the entity may also be returned.</p><p>• Participating teams may submit up to four runs, at least one of which will be judged.</p><p>• Groups that generate results using Web Search Engines are required to submit an obligatory run, using the Lemur ClueWeb Online Query Service, to ensure reproducibility.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.3">Data collection</head><p>Last year we used the Billion Triple Challenge (BTC) collection as a sample of Linked Open Data (LOD), and found that it did not contain many of the entities targeted by the topics. Galway. The collection is derived from data collected by the Sindice semantic search engine and is designed specifically for supporting research in the domain of web entity retrieval. It also comes with a set of tools to help researchers work with the data set <ref type="bibr" coords="5,431.24,306.98,9.96,8.74" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. The collection is available at http://data.sindice.com/trec2011/.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.4">Topics and assessments</head><p>We created the ELC 2011 topic set based on the REF 2010 topics, where known relevant answers serve as examples. Target types have manually been mapped to the DBpedia ontology. Note that the input entity and example entities are not mapped to LOD. Looking them up in the LOD crawl is now part of the task. URIs of example entities may also be returned as answers but these are worth less credit than finding new entities. Relevance is binary, but a distinction is made between returning examples and new entities; the main metric is NDCG. Relevance assessments are collected using community judging, the assessment procedure is underway.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Results</head><p>Ten groups submitted a total of 37 runs. Table <ref type="table" coords="5,317.16,501.67,4.98,8.74" target="#tab_4">2</ref> lists the participating groups.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">REF task</head><p>Four teams submitted a total of 12 runs for the REF task; the results are shown in Table <ref type="table" coords="5,501.49,547.95,3.87,8.74" target="#tab_5">3</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">REF-LOD task</head><p>Since only a single team has submitted runs, this task did not result in reusable assessments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">ELC task</head><p>Results for the ELC task are not yet available at the time of writing this paper. We are planning to report on the results and evaluation in a separate publication at a suitable venue. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RunID</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">Approaches</head><p>The following are descriptions of the approaches taken by the different groups. These paragraphs were contributed by participants (edited slightly for better presentation) and are meant to be a road map to their papers. Note that not all participants provided us with their summary.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">REF task</head><p>This year the PRIS group paid more attention to mining entities and homepages. Mappings between queries and categories in Wikipedia are established. Then a new entity lexicon with richer types is built for entity extraction. Besides the Document-Centered Model (DCM), which is the basic entity ranking model referred in previous reports, a keyword-entity distance algorithm is merged for entity ranking. Another improvement is a detailed analysis of homepage identification and ranking.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">REF-LOD (pilot) task</head><p>The group CARD from UALR incorporated a novel technique by leveraging network mining algorithms to rank answer entities. A multi-modal network was derived from related documents of a query so that entity-entity and entity-sentence relationships sustain. The relationships were carried forward from the HTML tree parser; this biases the entities in the same HTML tree node to rank high because of its neighborhood. Sentence nodes in the network were weighted by averaging its neighbor sentence nodes; further, the entities are ranked by highly weighted sentence nodes in the node's neighborhood. The sentence node with high weight among an entity's neighbors is the evidence to say that the entity is a right answer for the query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">ELC task</head><p>The Universitas Indonesia group has experimented with several combined approaches to search the entity candidates, i.e., by resolving the linguistic relation of the given entity, query expansion by example to broaden the retrieval results, and an ontology approach to identify the named entity from the search result snippets and to retrieve the candidate entity. At the end, they perform the phrase-based search mechanism in the Sindice dump collection to retrieve specific URIs for the final entity list. The group has developed a system architecture consisting of query processing, entity recognition and retrieval, and URI's identification component. They have demonstrated that frequency-based entity scoring, combined with a lightweight linguistic and ontology processing, can be used to finding new entities to complete a given list of related entities for the ELC 2011 task.</p><p>Team Commit addressed the ELC task using two techniques, one that retrieves entities based on terms in triples associated with each entity (text based approach). The other technique uses link overlap between example entities and entities in the LOD cloud (link based approach). The coverage of these techniques is increased by extracting candidate entities from homepages of source entities. Pages are selected based on their coverage of example entities. Next, candidates are mapped to URIs in the LOD cloud and reranked with the link based approach or by a combination of the text and link based approaches.</p><p>The Sindice team investigated in their submitted approach the concept of context. The context is defined as a document, which is a collection of entities. A document is composed of a central entity, with "surrounding" entities providing contextual information. The ranking algorithm consists in assigning a score to each entity in the document. Then each score is combined into a document score. The entity with the highest resulting score is returned as the central entity of the document. The user is then provided with a ranked list of central entities.</p><p>The PRIS group focuses on analysis of entity association and ranking. In order to establish entity associations, two novel statistics, Entity Activation Force (EAF) and entity affinity measure, are proposed. After an entity network is built, the entity list can be partly completed by neighbor entities of the given known ones. The final ranking is a combined Document-Centered Model (DCM) and entity affinity measure. Other approaches are similar to the REF task.</p><p>The LIA group proposed to rank candidate entities according to the similarity score between the context of their occurrences and the context of the occurrences of the examples. It used coocurrences of candidate entities and of examples in support documents (from which the candidate entities were extracted) and tables and lists found in source entity's homepage. According to the "distributional hypothesis," LIA proposed to estimate this similarity by comparing snippets relative to candidate entities (retrieved by querying a Web search engine) to snippets retrieved from examples.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Summary</head><p>The third edition of the Entity track featured two main tasks: Related Entity Finding (REF) and Entity List Completion (ELC). Entity 2011 also featured a pilot task, aiming to get more insight in the question whether semantic web resources would address the problem of entity representation better than our previous 'an entity has a homepage' assumption.</p><p>Unfortunately, instead of attaining a healthy growth in participation when compared to 2010, we attracted only a handful of participants; especially the REF task has been disappointing. Also, judging from an informal analysis of the results submitted we estimate that the pools are not of great quality. It is unclear why the track has been less successful than before-maybe teams thought that handling ClueWeb A was too challenging, or our requirement of a non-web run (for reasons of comparison) was perceived as too much effort; maybe the deadlines fell earlier than anticipated, or, researchers may simply have moved on to studying other problems.</p><p>As a consequence, we decided to put the track on hold for 2012. New ideas and tasks for a possible future continuation of the track are being discussed on the track's mailing list<ref type="foot" coords="7,485.91,632.46,3.97,6.12" target="#foot_3">4</ref> and at the Entity-Oriented Search (EOS) workshop series <ref type="bibr" coords="7,331.33,645.99,9.96,8.74" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="1,269.79,662.97,24.07,8.74"><head>Table</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="1,108.00,662.97,414.00,20.69"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>. Changes to last years edition are discussed in the description of the corresponding task. Tasks at Entity 2011.</figDesc><table coords="2,403.34,99.47,55.40,8.74"><row><cell>Collection(s)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3" coords="4,108.00,101.06,414.00,391.30"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>• A set of example entities, each defined by one or more ClueWeb09 docIDs (and the corresponding URLs) and optionally one or more names.Changed since last year that neither the input entity nor examples (known relevant) entities are mapped manually to LOD, only ClueWeb IDs and the corresponding URLs are provided.</figDesc><table coords="4,108.00,132.94,414.00,327.82"><row><cell>An example information need, "Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC)" is</cell></row><row><cell>formulated as follows:</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;query&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;num&gt;22&lt;/num&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;entity_name&gt;Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries</cell></row><row><cell>(OPEC)&lt;/entity_name&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;entity_homepage id="clueweb09-en0010-21-28880"&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>http://www.opec.com/&lt;/entity_homepage&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;target_entity&gt;location&lt;/target_entity&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;target_type_dbpedia&gt;Country&lt;/target_type_dbpedia&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;narrative&gt;Find countries that are members of OPEC</cell></row><row><cell>(the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries).&lt;/narrative&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;examples&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;entity&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;homepage id="clueweb09-en0002-20-01948"&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>http://english.mofa.gov.qa/index.cfm&lt;/homepage&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;homepage id="clueweb09-en0002-74-29899"&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>http://portal.www.gov.qa/wps/portal/&lt;/homepage&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;name&gt;qatar&lt;/name&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;/entity&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;entity&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;homepage id="clueweb09-en0127-57-06714"&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>http://en.iran.ir/&lt;/homepage&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;name&gt;iran&lt;/name&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;/entity&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;/examples&gt;</cell></row><row><cell>&lt;/query&gt;</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4" coords="4,108.00,679.79,414.00,20.69"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Groups participated in Entity 2011.</figDesc><table coords="5,123.15,99.47,27.77,8.74"><row><cell>Group</cell></row></table><note coords="4,502.57,679.79,19.43,8.74;4,108.00,691.75,414.00,8.74"><p>This year we introduced a new collection, Sindice-2011, created by the Sindice team from DERI, NUI</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5" coords="6,163.25,99.47,303.50,184.42"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Results for the REF task. Runs are ordered by MAP scores.</figDesc><table coords="6,217.01,99.47,195.98,152.60"><row><cell></cell><cell>Type</cell><cell>MAP R-Prec</cell></row><row><cell>PRISREF1</cell><cell>manual</cell><cell>0.2509 0.2908</cell></row><row><cell>PRISREF3</cell><cell>manual</cell><cell>0.2450 0.2750</cell></row><row><cell>PRISREF4</cell><cell>manual</cell><cell>0.2448 0.2823</cell></row><row><cell>PRISREF2</cell><cell>manual</cell><cell>0.2329 0.2620</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">TongKeyEN2 manual</cell><cell>0.1266 0.1984</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">TongKeyEN2 automatic 0.1209 0.1972</cell></row><row><cell>WhuRun1</cell><cell>manual</cell><cell>0.0063 0.0176</cell></row><row><cell>WhuRun2</cell><cell>manual</cell><cell>0.0050 0.0229</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">ICSTmaxSni automatic 0.0004 0.0015</cell></row><row><cell>ICSTmaxAll</cell><cell cols="2">automatic 0.0000 0.0000</cell></row><row><cell>ICSTaveSni</cell><cell cols="2">automatic 0.0000 0.0000</cell></row><row><cell>ICSTaveAll</cell><cell cols="2">automatic 0.0000 0.0000</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0" coords="2,123.24,697.20,237.12,6.64"><p>http://lemurproject.org/clueweb09.php/index.php#Services</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2" xml:id="foot_1" coords="3,123.24,674.73,398.75,6.99;3,108.00,684.19,229.93,6.99"><p>We acknowledge that Web of Data would be a more appropriate name for what we refer to as LOD. However, in order to not to confuse participants, we keep LOD for now.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3" xml:id="foot_2" coords="3,123.24,694.27,135.50,6.64"><p>http://wiki.dbpedia.org/Ontology</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4" xml:id="foot_3" coords="7,123.24,666.05,182.57,6.64"><p>http://groups.google.com/group/trec-entity/</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="8,123.50,122.88,398.51,8.74;8,123.50,134.84,344.77,8.74" xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Balog</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>De Vries</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Serdyukov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J.-R</forename><surname>Wen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="8,372.95,122.88,149.05,8.74;8,123.50,134.84,210.71,8.74">The First International Workshop on Entity-Oriented Search (EOS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011-12">December 2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="43" to="50" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SIGIR Forum</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="8,123.50,154.76,398.50,8.74;8,123.50,166.72,398.51,8.74;8,123.50,178.67,249.40,8.74" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="8,504.84,154.76,17.16,8.74;8,123.50,166.72,296.76,8.74">The Sindice-2011 dataset for entity-oriented search in the web of data</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Campinas</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">EOS</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ceccarelli</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">EOS</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Perry</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">EOS</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Delbru</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">EOS</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Balog</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">EOS</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Tummarello</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">EOS</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="8,433.65,166.72,88.35,8.74;8,123.50,178.67,160.69,8.74">In 1st International Workshop on Entity-Oriented Search</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="26" to="32" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
