<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,261.11,146.21,245.30,18.08">at CLEF 2007 Ad-Hoc Track</title>
				<funder ref="#_w8CJ3TU">
					<orgName type="full">Ministry of Education of the Czech Republic</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_uA6npkB">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,236.51,178.75,51.95,12.98"><forename type="first">Pavel</forename><surname>Češka</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName coords="1,311.14,181.27,55.36,10.46"><forename type="first">Pavel</forename><surname>Pecina</surname></persName>
							<email>pecina@ufal.mff.cuni.cz</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Charles University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Formal and Applied Linguistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Charles University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>118 00</postCode>
									<settlement>Praha 1</settlement>
									<country key="CZ">Czech Republic</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,261.11,146.21,245.30,18.08">at CLEF 2007 Ad-Hoc Track</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">76B148C4F28549BC53EF07CEF770AD33</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.2452/413-AH:</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:15+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.3 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: H.3.1 Content Analysis and Indexing</term>
					<term>H.3.3 Information Search and Retrieval</term>
					<term>H.3.4 Systems and Software</term>
					<term>H.3.7 Digital Libraries Measurement, Performance, Experimentation Ad-Hoc Retrieval</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In this paper we describe retrieval experiments performed at Charles University in Prague for participation in the CLEF 2007 Ad-Hoc track. We focused on the Czech monolingual task and used the LEMUR toolkit as the retrieval system. Our results demonstrate that for Czech as a highly inflectional language, lemmatization significantly improves retrieval results and manually created queries are only slightly better than queries automatically generated from topic specifications.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>This work represents the first participation of Charles University in the CLEF evaluation campaign. Our research is focused on Czech monolingual tasks and application of advanced language processing tools developed at our university -namely a morphological analyser and tagger. We also attempt to compare systems with manually and automatically created queries. For the Ad-Hoc track we submitted four experiments (runs): Prague01, Prague02, Prague03, and Prague04. Our main goal were to study influence of lemmatization and whether manual query construction can bring additional performance improvement. Similar experiments were performed also for the CLEF 2007 Cross-Language Speech Retrieval track.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">System Description</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Retrieval model</head><p>Being novices in the field of information retrieval we decided to use a freely available retrieval toolkit instead of developing our own. The final choice was the LEMUR toolkit [5] and its Indri retrieval model <ref type="bibr" coords="1,160.89,720.26,9.96,10.46">[3]</ref>. It is based on a combination of language modeling and inference network retrieval. It has been popular among CLEF participant in recent years and was found effective for a wide range of retrieval tasks.</p><p>An inference network (also known as a Bayesian network) consists of a document node, smoothing parameters nodes, model nodes, representation nodes, belief nodes, and information need nodes connected by edges representing independence assumptions over random variables. The document node represents documents as binary vectors where each position represents presence or absence of a certain feature of the text. The model nodes correspond to different representations of the same document (e. g. pseudo-documents made up from all titles, bodies, etc.). The representation concept nodes are related to the features extracted from the document representation. The belief nodes are used to combine probabilities of different representations, other beliefs, etc. A detailed description can be found in <ref type="bibr" coords="2,212.40,206.18,9.96,10.46" target="#b3">[6]</ref>.</p><p>To improve retrieval results, we used Indri's pseudo-relevance feedback which is an adaption of Lawrenko's relevance models <ref type="bibr" coords="2,228.66,230.09,9.96,10.46" target="#b2">[4]</ref>. The basic idea behind these models is to combine the original query with a query constructed from top ranked documents of the original query.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Morphological tagging and lemmatization</head><p>State-of-the-art retrieval systems usually include at least some basic linguistically-motivated preprocessing of the documents and queries such as stemming and stopword removal. Czech is a morphologically complex language and there is no easy way how to determine stems and their endings as it can be done in English and other languages. Stemming in Czech is not sufficient and should be replaced by a proper lemmatization (substituting each word by its base form -the lemma) which involves determining the part of speech of all words. In our experiments, we employed the Czech morphological analyzer and tagger developed at Charles University <ref type="bibr" coords="2,458.25,360.05,9.96,10.46" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" coords="2,474.47,360.05,10.52,10.46" target="#b1">[2]</ref> which assigns a disambiguated lemma and a morphological tag to each word. Its accuracy is around 95%. An example of its output for one word ("serious" in English) is following:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="2,160.28,405.74,282.31,9.41">&lt;f&gt;závažných&lt;MDl src="a"&gt;závažný&lt;MDt src="a"&gt;AAIP2----1A----</formula><p>The tag &lt;f&gt; is followed by the original word form, tag &lt;MDl&gt; is followed by the lemma, and the tag &lt;MDt&gt; separates a 15-position morphological category (the first position represents the partof-speech; A stands for an adjective). Lemmatization was employed in all our experiments except Prague03. In Prague01, both original word forms and lemmas were used for indexing (in two separate model representations).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Stopword list construction</head><p>We used two approaches to construct the stopword lists for our experiments. The first was based on frequency of word occurrences in the collection, the latter on part-of-speech of words. In the first three experiments (Prague01-03), we removed 40 most frequented words (separately from the original and lemmatized text) from the documents and the queries. In the fourth experiment (Prague04), we removed all words tagged as pronouns, prepositions, conjunctions, particles, interjections, and unknown words (mostly typos) and kept only open-class words.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Automatic query construction</head><p>Automatically created queries were constructed from the &lt;title&gt; and &lt;description&gt; fields of the topic specifications only. The text was simply concatenated and processed by the analyzer and tagger. A combination of the original and lemmatized query was used in the first experiment (Prague01). Lemmatized queries containing only nouns, adjectives, numerals, adverbs and verbs were created for the fourth experiment (Prague04).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Example</head><p>Step 1. The original title and description (topic 10.2452/413-AH: Reducing Diabetes Risk): &lt;title&gt;Snižování rizika onemocnění cukrovkou&lt;/title&gt; &lt;desc&gt;Najděte dokumenty zmiňující faktory, které snižují riziko onemocnění cukrovkou. &lt;/desc&gt;</p><p>Step 2. Concatenation: Snižování rizika onemocnění cukrovkou. Najděte dokumenty zmiňující faktory, které snižují riziko onemocnění cukrovkou.</p><p>Step 3. Lemmatization: Step 5. Prague04 query:</p><p>#combine(snižování riziko onemocnéní cukrovka zmiňující faktor snižovat riziko onemocnéní cukrovka)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.5">Manual query construction</head><p>The queries in two of our experiments were created manually. In Prague02 they were constructed from lemmas (to match the lemmatized documents) and their synonyms and in Prague03 with the use of "stems" and wildcard operators to cover all possible word forms (documents indexed in the original forms).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Example</head><p>Step 1. The original title and description (topic 10.2452/413-AH: Reducing Diabetes Risk): &lt;title&gt;Snižování rizika onemocnění cukrovkou&lt;/title&gt; &lt;desc&gt;Najděte dokumenty zmiňující faktory, které snižují riziko onemocnění cukrovkou. &lt;/desc&gt;</p><p>Step 2. The Prague02 query based on lemmas (the operator #combine() combines beliefs of the nested operators, operator #syn() represets synonymic line of equal expressions and operator #2() represents ordered window with width 2 words):</p><p>#combine(#syn(diabetes cukrovka úplavice) #2(snížení riziko) prevence)</p><p>Step 3. The Prague03 query with wildcard operators (which can be used as a suffix only).</p><p>#combine(diabet* cukrovk* úplavic* sníž* rizik* preven*)</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,90.00,229.94,407.73,9.41;3,90.01,240.90,89.39,9.41;3,90.00,261.97,423.01,10.46;3,90.00,273.92,221.18,10.46;3,90.01,295.70,418.77,9.41;3,90.00,306.66,357.61,9.41;3,90.01,317.61,381.12,9.41;3,90.00,328.58,395.26,9.41;3,90.01,339.53,367.01,9.41;3,90.00,350.49,79.99,9.41"><head>Step 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>snižování riziko onemocnění cukrovka najít dokument zmiňovat faktor který snižit riziko onemocnění cukrovka Prague01 query (original word forms plus lemmas; the suffixes .(orig) and .(lemma) reffer to the corresponding model representations): #combine(snižování.(orig) rizika.(orig) onemocnéní.(orig) cukrovkou.(orig) najdéte.(orig) dokumenty.(orig) zmiňující.(orig) faktory.(orig) které.(orig) snižují.(orig) riziko.(orig) onemocnéní.(orig) cukrovkou.(orig) snižování.(lemma) riziko.(lemma) onemocnéní.(lemma) cukrovka.(lemma) najít.(lemma) dokument.(lemma) zmiňující.(lemma) faktor.(lemma) kter.(lemma) snižovat.(lemma) riziko.(lemma) onemocnéní.(lemma) cukrovka.(lemma))</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>This work has been supported by the <rs type="funder">Ministry of Education of the Czech Republic</rs>, projects <rs type="grantNumber">MSM 0021620838</rs> and #<rs type="grantNumber">1P05ME786</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_w8CJ3TU">
					<idno type="grant-number">MSM 0021620838</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_uA6npkB">
					<idno type="grant-number">1P05ME786</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In terms of Mean Average Precision, the best score was achieved in experiment Prague01. Indexing both original word forms and lemmas in combination with automatically generated queries seems to be a reasonable way how to build a retrieval system. In terms of other performance measures, the scores of Prague02 are slightly better but this is probably due to the use of synonyms in the manually created queries -not in the manual approach itself.</p><p>By comparing scores of Prague03 with results of Prague01 and Prague02 we can confirm that lemmatization is quite useful for searching in highly flectional languages such a Czech and can not be fully substituted by stemming.</p><p>The last lesson we learned is that using extensive stopword lists based on part-of-speech can seriously harm the performance of a retrieval system as can bee seen on the results of experiment Prague04.</p><p>We found these results quite encouraging and motivating for our future work.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.49,303.76,407.52,10.46;5,105.50,315.71,407.50,10.46;5,105.50,327.67,150.82,10.46" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,281.99,303.76,231.02,10.46;5,105.50,315.71,205.97,10.46">Tagging Inflective Languages: Prediction of Morphological Categories for a Rich, Structured Tagset</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Hajič</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Barbora</forename><surname>Vidová-Hladká</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,332.83,315.71,180.17,10.46;5,105.50,327.67,36.10,10.46">Proceedings of the Conference COLING -ACL &apos;98</title>
		<meeting>the Conference COLING -ACL &apos;98<address><addrLine>Montreal, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.49,347.59,407.51,10.46;5,105.50,359.54,152.46,10.46" xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Hajič</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m" coord="5,156.51,347.59,356.49,10.46;5,105.50,359.54,84.85,10.46">Disambiguation of Rich Inflection (Computational Morphology of Czech). Nakladatelství Karolinum</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Prague</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.49,399.40,407.52,10.46;5,105.50,411.35,407.50,10.46;5,105.50,423.31,284.30,10.46" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="5,274.86,399.40,144.15,10.46">Relevance based language models</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Lavrenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">Bruce</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="5,440.94,399.40,72.07,10.46;5,105.50,411.35,407.50,10.46;5,105.50,423.31,101.65,10.46">SIGIR &apos;01: Proceedings of the 24th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="5,105.49,463.16,407.52,10.46;5,105.50,475.12,406.16,10.46" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="5,347.32,463.16,165.70,10.46;5,105.50,475.12,198.09,10.46">Indri: A language-model based search engine for complex queries (extended version)</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Strohman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Metzler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Turtle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Croft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>IR-407</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>CIIR, UMass</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
