<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,166.08,149.02,270.71,15.49">The XLDB Group at GeoCLEF 2005</title>
				<funder ref="#_cdRvMEF #_aHgWWem">
					<orgName type="full">Portuguese Fundação para a Ciência e Tecnologia</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_qDUKSKe">
					<orgName type="full">FCT</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,111.00,182.90,55.91,8.97"><forename type="first">Nuno</forename><surname>Cardoso</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Grupo XLDB -Departamento de Informática Faculdade de Ciências</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade de Lisboa {ncardoso</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>bmartins, mchaves</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,173.67,182.90,98.30,8.97"><roleName>Marcirio</roleName><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Grupo XLDB -Departamento de Informática Faculdade de Ciências</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade de Lisboa {ncardoso</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>bmartins, mchaves</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,274.25,182.90,60.34,8.97"><forename type="first">Silveira</forename><surname>Chaves</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Grupo XLDB -Departamento de Informática Faculdade de Ciências</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade de Lisboa {ncardoso</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>bmartins, mchaves</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,341.49,182.90,75.14,8.97"><forename type="first">Leonardo</forename><surname>Andrade</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Grupo XLDB -Departamento de Informática Faculdade de Ciências</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade de Lisboa {ncardoso</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>bmartins, mchaves</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName coords="1,435.69,182.90,55.99,8.97"><forename type="first">Mário</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Grupo XLDB -Departamento de Informática Faculdade de Ciências</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Universidade de Lisboa {ncardoso</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>bmartins, mchaves</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main" coord="1,166.08,149.02,270.71,15.49">The XLDB Group at GeoCLEF 2005</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">AC362BBD6447C6C4DFEA5AE0B362B0ED</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-06-26T15:08+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.3 [Information Storage and Retrieval]: H.3.1 Content Analysis and Indexing; H.3.3 Information Search and Retrieval Measurement</term>
					<term>Experimentation</term>
					<term>Design Geographic Information Retrieval</term>
					<term>Text Mining</term>
					<term>Evaluation</term>
					<term>CLEF</term>
					<term>GeoCLEF</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes our participation at the GeoCLEF 2005 task. We detail the main software components of our Geo-IR system, its adaptation for the participation at GeoCLEF and discuss the obtained results. The software architecture includes a geographic knowledge base, a text mining tool for geo-referencing documents, and a geo-ranking component to re-rank the results of a standard IR index according to geo-scopes. Evaluation shows that ranking with geographic scopes is heavily dependent on the information loaded in the knowledge base and on the ranking algorithm involved, requiring more than the correct assignment of a geo-scope to each document.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<facsimile>
		<surface n="1" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="2" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="3" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="4" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="5" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="6" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="7" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="8" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="9" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="10" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="11" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="12" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="13" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
		<surface n="14" ulx="0.0" uly="0.0" lrx="595.0" lry="842.0"/>
	</facsimile>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">Introduction</head><p>Over the past two years, the XLDB Group has been developing and operated tumba!, a search engine for the Portuguese community, publicly available at http://www.tumba.pt <ref type="bibr" coords="1,367.91,583.46,15.24,8.97" target="#b17">[18]</ref>. Tumba! is a testbed for several data management, information retrieval and data mining research efforts. We are currently extending it to handle geographic searches, under the GREASE (Geographical REAsoning for Search Engines) project.</p><p>GREASE researches methods, algorithms and software architecture for geographical information retrieval (Geo-IR) from the web <ref type="bibr" coords="1,218.88,631.34,10.78,8.97" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="1,233.50,631.34,11.86,8.97" target="#b18">19]</ref>. Some of the specific challenges are: 1) building geographical ontologies to assist Geo-IR; 2) extracting geographical references from text; 3) assigning geographical scopes to documents; 4) ranking documents according to geographical relevance.</p><p>GeoTumba, a location-aware search engine handling concept@location queries, is a prototype system developed in the context of GREASE.</p><p>Last year, the XLDB Group made its debut participation in CLEF, using tumba! at the monolingual ad hoc Portuguese retrieval task <ref type="bibr" coords="1,222.45,702.98,10.60,8.97" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. This year, along with a second participation in the ad hoc task, we also entered the GeoCLEF task, to evaluate the work done so far on GeoTumba. Our intent was to obtain results that could provide interesting insights on the validity of our approaches. In order to build a system configuration that would enable us to generate the runs, we made significant adaptations to GeoTumba, Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,247.05,290.30,3.90,8.97">1</ref>: The Geographic IR architecture including using global geographic information instead of just focusing on the Portuguese territory, and replacing the ranking component (which is still under development) by a simpler scheme.</p><p>The rest of the paper is organized as follows: Section 2 describes GeoTumba and the software configuration that was assembled for our participation at GeoCLEF. Section 3 outlines our evaluation goals and the submitted runs. Section 4 presents an analysis on the obtained results, and finally, Section 5 draws conclusions and directions for future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">The Geographic IR system</head><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="2,118.65,447.98,5.03,8.97">1</ref> shows the architecture of the current Geo-IR system prototype. Information is processed in three phases:</p><p>Data loading: web pages are harvested into a repository by a crawling module. The geographic knowledge of GeoTumba is collected into GKB (Geographic Knowledge Base) <ref type="bibr" coords="2,396.53,491.90,10.78,8.97" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,410.78,491.90,7.27,8.97" target="#b3">4]</ref>. GKB can be queried interactively to retrieve data about a geographic name or a relationship about two geographic features. It can also be used to create geographic ontologies.</p><p>Indexing and Mining: the geographic ontology is used by CaGE, a text mining module for recognizing geographical references and assigning documents with a corresponding geo-scope <ref type="bibr" coords="2,451.24,547.58,15.69,8.97" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="2,470.29,547.58,11.86,8.97" target="#b10">11]</ref>. Once the scopes are assigned to documents, we create indexes for a fast retrieval of web documents. The indexing software of tumba! is being enhanced for indexing the geographic scopes information. Term indexes are created from the repository data to handle the concept part of the queries, while the location part is used as a key for fast access to documents through the scopes indexes.</p><p>Geo-Retrieval: in the last phase, the indexes and repositories previously created are accessed to generate the result sets that match users' queries, ranked according to geographic criteria.</p><p>In the rest of this Section, we describe the main modules, namely GKB and CaGE. The Section ends with a description of the software configuration that we assembled to create the runs submitted to Geo-CLEF.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">GKB</head><p>Geographic knowledge is collected into a common knowledge repository, the GKB. Its purpose is both to provide a common place for integrating data from multiple external sources under a common schema, and to support mechanisms for exporting geographic knowledge to be used by other components. The geographical information in GKB includes names for places and other geographical features, information types (e.g. city, street, etc.), ontological relationships between the features, demographics data and geographic codes, such as postal codes.</p><p>We have developed two GKB instances: the first has detailed information about the main Portuguese territory; the second, holds information about the main regions, countries, cities and places around the world in four different languages: Portuguese (PT), Spanish (ES), English (EN) and German (DE). While the first was created to support the GeoTumba service for Portugal, the latter is simply intended for validation of the GeoTumba software, through experiments with annotated multilingual corpora and Geo-IR evaluations covering other parts of the world, such as GeoCLEF.</p><p>GKB models geographic information as typed features and relationships. Figure <ref type="figure" coords="3,433.89,403.82,5.03,8.97" target="#fig_0">2</ref> shows the feature types for geo-administrative and geo-physical domains data and their relationships as defined for the created world ontology. The main feature type is ISO-3166-1, which encompasses countries and territories. The feature types Region, ISO-3166-2, Agglomeration, City-Capital, Place and Administrative Division have a 'PartOf' relationship with ISO-3166-1.</p><p>The relationship between ISO-3166-1 and Region feature types is bidirectional, that is, a feature of type ISO-3166-1 can be part of a Region (Nicaragua is part of Latin America) or a Region can be part of a ISO-3166-1 feature (Siberia is part of Russia). The geo-administrative information is related to the geophysical information through the feature types ISO-3166-1 and Region. An instance of an ISO-3166-1 can be part of River, Continent or Lake, or it may be adjacent to a Sea, River or Lake.</p><p>The geographic ontology of the world was built from two public information sources:</p><p>Wikipedia: on-line encyclopaedia <ref type="bibr" coords="3,232.18,541.34,15.33,8.97">[21]</ref>. We used its name definitions of countries and their capitals in the four supported languages. We also collected all the geo-physical names information from this source. Names are defined in accordance to standards ISO-3166-1 and ISO-3166-2 (http://www. iso.org/iso/en/prods-services/iso3166ma/02iso-3166-code-lists/list-en1.html).</p><p>World Gazetteer: information about the largest cities and agglomerations around the world <ref type="bibr" coords="3,473.69,596.18,15.24,8.97">[22]</ref>. We selected those with population above 100,000.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" coords="3,129.69,626.18,5.03,8.97" target="#tab_0">1</ref> shows some statistics for the world ontology used in GeoCLEF. The majority of the relationships are of the PartOf type, while Equivalence and Adjacency relationships are much less frequent. There are 12,283 features, and 7,970 of them have a population associated. Most of the features are provided by the World Gazetteer. Only relationship types PartOf and Adjacency are used to connect all features.</p><p>It is worth mentioning that the features ISO-3166-1 contain preferred and alternative names, which includes the adjectives of the countries (e.g. Brazilian, Australian or Finnish). We loaded the preferred and alternative names in the four supported languages, while the adjectives were only loaded for the English and German languages.</p><p>For some types, the number of described features (number of Seas, Lakes and Regions) is much smaller than in reality because they weren't available in the information sources. We decided to add some features  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">CaGE</head><p>CaGE is a text mining module specifically developed to infer the geographic context from collections of documents, based on the geographic knowledge presented in a OWL ontology generated by GKB. The main assumption of CaGE is that although each document can have several different geographic scopes (for instance, a news article covering several events in different places), we take the simplistic approach of associating each document to a single scope, or none if the assignment can not be made within a certain confidence level. This is similar to the "one sense per discourse" assumption, taken in many recognition and disambiguation systems <ref type="bibr" coords="5,203.62,418.34,10.60,8.97" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. Resources can nonetheless be characterized according to different degrees of locality, whether they are likely to be of interest to a geographically broad audience, or to relatively narrow regions. Our scopes can be seen as a sub-region hierarchy, where broad regions are detailed in their constituent locations. The process of geo-referencing the textual documents is performed in two stages:</p><p>1. Identify the geographical references present in the document's text and weight them according to frequency.</p><p>2. Assign a corresponding geographical scope to each document according to the geographical references, their frequency, and the relationships among them.</p><p>The geographical references are handled through a named-entity recognition (NER) procedure particularly tailored to recognize and disambiguate geographical concepts over the text. Although NER is a familiar task in Information Extraction <ref type="bibr" coords="5,250.16,574.34,15.33,8.97" target="#b16">[17]</ref>, this work advances the state of the art by presenting a specific adaptation strategy to the domain of multilingual geographical references. Besides recognizing place names, we try to normalize them in a way that specifically describes or even uniquely identifies the place in question, disambiguating them with respect to their specific type (e.g. city) and grounding them with features from the geographical ontology.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" coords="5,134.37,634.10,5.03,8.97" target="#fig_1">3</ref> illustrates the geographical NER and disambiguation stage. It follows the traditional NER architecture by combining lexical resources with shallow processing operations. We have four processing steps:</p><p>Pre-processing: this step essentially performs text tokenisation. A language guesser is run on the document's text and this is the starting point for the following processing operations <ref type="bibr" coords="5,434.28,690.50,15.33,8.97" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. The identified textual segments are split into their constituent word n-grams, by moving a window over each text segment and taking all possible consecutive word sequences.</p><p>Named-entity identification: involves the detection of all possible n-grams that are likely to belong to a geographical reference. An initial identification applies language-specific patterns which combine  place names from the geographical ontology and context expressions, with and without capitalization (i.e. "city of Lisbon" or "Lisbon metropolitan area"). Table <ref type="table" coords="6,349.52,385.46,5.03,8.97" target="#tab_2">2</ref> illustrates some of these expressions for English, and equivalents are used for the German language. Next, n-grams that are likely to contain more than one named-entity are detected and attachment problems are resolved. Finally, membership in exclusion lists is used to discard very frequent words that, despite having a geographical connotation, are more frequently used in other contexts (e.g. brand names or proper names).</p><p>Named-entity disambiguation: named-entity identification is not sufficient by itself to derive the meaning of expressions, as many named-entities remain ambiguous. This stage addresses this issue, aiming to find the correct meaning for the expressions recognized. Classification rules, built on the same expressions that are used to recognize entities, are first employed to solve the simple cases (e.g. in "city of X", we know X is a city and not some other geographical feature). Ontology based classification uses the feature types and other contiguity measures to guess the correct type for a given reference (i.e. a one referent per discourse assumption, so that place names throughout the same paragraph refer to the same or to geographically related locations). Finally, we compare slight word variations (i.e. one different character, one extra character or one less character) against references already disambiguated.</p><p>Generation of feature lists: this stage simply consists in listing the geographical references recognized in the text, together with their frequency and an association to the corresponding feature at the geographical ontology. In the cases not covered by the disambiguation heuristics, we use the associations to the several different possible concepts at the ontology, and some ambiguity problems can therefore persist at the end of this process.</p><p>In the scope assignment stage, besides the ambiguity problems which may still persist after the first stage, different (sometimes conflicting) geographical expressions may be associated with the same document. More than simply counting the most frequent references, we need to combine the available information and disambiguate further among the different possible scope assignments that can be made for each document. This is the idea behind the scope assignment approach, which relies on the existence of a graph where the particular relationships between geographical concepts are specified. The geographical ontology provides the needed information. We convert it to a graph representation, weighting different semantic relationships (edges) according to their importance (i.e., equivalence relationships are more important than hierarchical relationships, which in turn are more important than adjacency relationships) and weighting different geographical concepts (nodes) according to the feature weights computed at the previous step (see Figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,118.53,124.10,3.63,8.97">4</ref>). Figure <ref type="figure" coords="7,255.81,297.26,3.90,8.97">4</ref>: Geographic concepts graph Importance scores are then calculated for all the nodes in the graph. In the end, we select the highest ranked node as the scope for the document. For the computation of importance scores, we use a variation of the popular PageRank ranking algorithm <ref type="bibr" coords="7,268.10,355.10,15.33,8.97" target="#b15">[16]</ref>. PageRank determines the importance of a vertex using the collective knowledge expressed in the entire graph, recursively computing importance using the idea of voting. The higher the number of votes (e.g. graph links) that are cast to a vertex, the higher its importance. Moreover, the importance of the vertex casting the vote determines the importance of the vote itself. There is a considerable amount of work focusing on all aspects of PageRank, namely stability, convergence speed, memory consumption, and the connectivity matrix properties <ref type="bibr" coords="7,363.12,414.86,10.60,8.97" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. By using this formulation we can leverage on all these previous studies.</p><p>PageRank is traditionally computed through iterative solution methods. Formally, let G = (V, E) be a directed graph with the set of nodes V and the set of edges E, where E is a subset of V * V . For a given node V i , let In(V i ) ⊂ V be the set of nodes that point to it, and let Out(V i ) ⊂ V be the set of nodes that V i points to. The values w i j correspond to weights given to the edges connecting nodes V i and V j , and s i correspond to weights given to each node V i (the source strengths). Below we show the formula for graph-based ranking that takes into account edge and node weights when computing the score associated with a node in the graph. The ranking score of a node V i is defined as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0" coords="7,202.08,528.46,198.84,19.41">S(V i ) = (1 -d)s i + d * ∑ V j εIn(V i ) w i j ∑ v k εOut(V j ) w jk S(V j )</formula><p>The parameter d is a damping factor set to 0.85, integrating into the model the probability of jumping from a given node to another random node in the graph (e.g. having a document associated with a completely different feature than the ones we were able to extracted from it).</p><p>The source strengths s i should be positive and satisfy the following condition:</p><formula xml:id="formula_1" coords="7,265.44,614.25,72.23,15.53">|In(V i )| = ∑ |V | j=1 s i .</formula><p>After a score is computed for each feature from the ontology, we select the most probable scope for the document, by taking the highest scoring feature, or none if all features are scored below a given threshold. The general procedure goes as follows:</p><p>1. Normalize the ranking scores obtained through the graph ranking algorithm.</p><p>2. If there are no features with a weight above the threshold, then no scope is selected.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>3.</head><p>From the set of features with the highest weight above the threshold: (a) If there is only one, return it as the scope for the document.</p><p>(b) If there is more than one feature, but one of them corresponds to a generally broader concept in the ontology, return this broader feature as the scope.</p><p>(c) If there is more than one feature, but they all have a common direct broader feature in the ontology, select this broader feature as the scope.</p><p>(d) If there is more than one feature and no common direct broader concept exists, use demographics data to select the scope corresponding to the highest populated geographical region.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Ranking documents with geo-scopes</head><p>In GeoTumba, we use geo-scopes to create new indexes supporting fast searches. The indexes integrate seamlessly with classic IR document weighting algorithms (TF × IDF, BM25, PageRank). For geographic ranking, a key concept is geo-scope similarity metrics <ref type="bibr" coords="8,308.02,250.94,15.33,8.97" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. Geographic similarity can be computed using the following criteria:</p><p>Relative position of geo-scopes on the concepts graph: two scopes may be equivalent, one may contain the other, they may overlap or may be adjacent to each other. We can say that document D 1 is more similar to query Q than D 2 if the area of overlap between the geo-scopes of D 1 and Q is larger than the area of overlap between D 2 and Q.</p><p>Geometric proximity of geo-scopes: assuming that the similarity between two geo-scopes is inversely proportional to the distance between them, we can use Euclidean distance, travel time on the public transportation network or other source of data related to physical proximity to compute similarity as the distance between the centroids of two scopes.</p><p>Graph-based distances: the relative location of nodes representing scopes on the geographic concepts graph can be used to define a semantic similarity metric between scopes <ref type="bibr" coords="8,403.94,408.38,10.60,8.97" target="#b8">[9]</ref>.</p><p>Importance of scopes: the total population or economic importance of the geographic entity represented by a scope can be used as criteria for weighting the relative power of a scope.</p><p>As we put emphasis on geographic reasoning rather than on geometric reasoning, the indexes used for geographic ranking on GeoTumba only have information about the similarity values between any pair of scopes, with little or no spatial information.</p><p>The best strategies for efficiently organising this information for fast access are still in debate. We are presently pondering strategies for fusing various similarity metrics in a global GeoTumba ranking function. As a result, we decided to participate in GeoCLEF with a system software configuration that does not use the geographic indexes, but still ranks documents according to geographic criteria.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Software Configuration used to create the GeoCLEF Runs</head><p>In our GeoCLEF experiments, we used QuerCol, a query expansion component to generate queries from the CLEF supplied topics (more details about the query generation process are presented in a separate text describing our participation in the CLEF 2005 ad hoc task <ref type="bibr" coords="8,330.57,605.06,10.50,8.97" target="#b0">[1]</ref>). QuerCol provides multiple strategies to generate queries from topic data to be submitted to search engines. For GeoCLEF, we used in some runs the location part of the topics as additional query terms. For bilingual runs, we asked our colleagues from the Braga node of Linguateca to translate the topics, using the same method as in our submission to the ad hoc bilingual subtasks.</p><p>For generating the runs submitted to GeoCLEF, we assembled along with QuerCol a modified retrieval system from our existing software. The changes made to GeoTumba include:</p><p>• Replacement of the web crawler by a custom loader already used in previous evaluations, to bring the GeoCLEF newswire text collections into the repository. We also used the language information provided with the document collection metadata and turned off the language guesser of CaGE.</p><p>• Development of a simple alternative scope assignment algorithm, that consists in simply selecting the most frequent geographical reference as the scope of a document. We were interested in comparing the graph-ranking method for assigning geographical scopes to documents against this baseline approach.</p><p>• Implementation of a geo-ranking function which does not use geographic indexes. Ranking was computed in two stages: first, we ranked documents using the classic IR approach, with a simplified version of the BM25 function that only uses the term index (this function was also used in the CLEF 2005 ad hoc task participation). Then, we ranked the documents in the obtained result set with a geographic similarity function. The final ranking corresponds to the set of documents containing the terms on the query, ordered by a composite key having the geographic rank followed by the non-geographic rank.</p><p>The geographic similarity metric that we used in GeoCLEF is defined on a scopes tree extracted from the geographic concepts graph built from the geographic ontology. The scopes tree contains the nodes of the graph and the edges defining partOf relationships among the nodes. In this tree, we define i) depth(X) as the count of edges between node X and the root of the tree; ii) ancestor(X,Y ) = true if X is on the path of Y to the root node of the tree; and iii) T D, tree depth, the maximum depth() of any node on the tree.</p><p>Given a query Q, a geo-scope Scope Q and a result set with documents D 1 , ..., D n , each with a Scope D i or NULL scope assigned, the geographic similarity GS(Q, D i ) is obtained as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2" coords="9,102.00,364.68,397.89,63.01">GS(Q, D i ) =          0 i f Scope Q = Scope D i depth(Scope Q ) -depth(Scope D i ) i f ancestor(Scope Q , Scope D i ) = true n × TD + depth(Scope D i ) -depth(Scope Q ) i f ancestor(Scope D i , Scope Q ) = true 2 × n × TD otherwise</formula><p>The definition above means that the geographic similarity ranking function first ranks all the documents with the same scope as the query, then those with a narrower scope than the query, and then those with a wider scope. Finally, documents with NULL scopes or scopes that can not be defined as strictly narrow or wider than the scope of the query are ranked last.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">Runs Description and Evaluation Goals</head><p>Our goals for participating in GeoCLEF were: Scope ranking: measure how the ranking with the geo-scopes assigned to documents improves Geo-IR results, in comparison to include location terms in the query strings, using geographic terms as common terms, a common practice for narrowing geographic searches (e.g. 'restaurant london') <ref type="bibr" coords="9,501.69,566.90,10.78,8.97" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" coords="9,114.96,578.90,11.86,8.97" target="#b13">14]</ref>.</p><p>Scope assigning: when using geo-scopes, compare the graph-based algorithm against the simple scope assignment algorithm that selects the most frequent geographic entity in texts.</p><p>Expansion of location terms: when not using geo-scopes, measure the contribution of the expansion of geographic terms in queries to improve searches.</p><p>Topic translation: observe the performance of Portuguese to English bilingual runs. Our efforts were focused towards the English monolingual subtask. The bilingual runs obtained provide initial results on the performance of the machine translation system being developed by the Linguateca group at Braga, Portugal. There was no interest in creating runs derived from manual queries for this subtask.</p><p>We submitted six runs for the English monolingual subtask, four runs for the German monolingual subtask, and four runs for the Portuguese to English bilingual subtask <ref type="bibr" coords="9,354.76,730.34,15.33,8.97" target="#b19">[20]</ref>. Table <ref type="table" coords="9,401.26,730.34,5.03,8.97">3</ref> summarizes the submitted runs. Below, we describe the creation procedures and observations intended for each of the submitted runs: the obtained results are presented in average precision vs. interpolated recall charts, in Figures <ref type="figure" coords="11,481.47,134.42,5.03,8.97">5</ref> and<ref type="figure" coords="11,507.47,134.42,5.03,8.97">6</ref> (English and German monolingual subtasks), and in Figure <ref type="figure" coords="11,327.91,146.30,5.03,8.97" target="#fig_3">7</ref> (Portuguese to English bilingual subtask). Scope ranking: comparing no-scope runs vs. scope-aware runs, we observe that the runs with location terms inserted in the fully automatic query (AutMandTDL) ended with better precision than the runs with geographic scope ranking (TDGKBm3 and TDGKBm4). We didn't expect this behaviour, as our Geo-IR is able to retrieve relevant documents to a given scope without its name on the query. A more detailed analysis of the qrels shows that this happened because both the geo-ranking method and the ontology data revealed some limitations.</p><p>Scope assigning: comparing the graph-based vs. the most frequent geographical reference algorithms used to assign scopes to documents, the method based on the graph ranking algorithm (TDGKBm3) achieved higher precision than the alternative method of assigning the most frequent geographic reference as the document's scope (like the TDGKBm4 runs). Scrutinizing the results, we can see that CaGE normally assigned the same scopes that an human would infer if he only had the same geographic knowledge passed on the world ontology.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Expansion of location terms:</head><p>We can observe that the runs based on manual queries with expanded location terms (i.e. the ManTDL runs) obtained higher precision than the AutMandTDL runs. This reinforces our belief that relevant documents often do not contain explicitly the terms from the desired location. A Geo-IR system should consider the relationships between geographical concepts in order to retrieve relevant documents to a given location, even if they do not contain the location terms. However, the CaGE graph-ranking algorithm did not obtained better results than the runs created by using only location names and a standard text search (AutMandTDL). As scopes seemed to be correctly assigned, we suspect the result was due to the used ontology and geographic ranking function.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Topic translation:</head><p>The English monolingual runs exhibit better results than the bilingual runs. This was due to the quality of the topic translation, which faced some difficulties. Detailed description of these problems are included in the ad hoc participation paper <ref type="bibr" coords="12,338.13,492.26,10.60,8.97" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. This wasn't too obvious on the ManTD runs (they showed a similar performance), as they were created from query strings with few terms selected from the topic.</p><p>The analysis of the topic qrels shows that 61% of the relevant documents have been assigned to an unrelated or unknown scope. We realized that sub-optimal results are caused by the geographic ranking strategy adopted, and the lack of relationships in the ontology. For example, we have 'Glasgow' as part of 'United Kingdom', and 'United Kingdom' as part of 'Europe'. Yet, the record 'Scotland' was associated to 'United Kingdom', and thus our geo-ranking module did not have a path from 'Glasgow' and 'Scotland' on the scopes tree.</p><p>Further analysis also revealed that we could have profited from using the Adjacency relationships on the geographic similarity metric, as we couldn't associate documents with assigned scopes like Russia or Azerbai jan to regions like Siberia or Caspian Sea.</p><p>These facts had a noticeable impact on the TDGKBm3 and TDGKBm4 runs, meaning that we can't make an overall evaluation of our Geo-IR, compared to the AutMandTDL and ManTDL runs, at this point.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">Conclusion</head><p>For our participation at the GeoCLEF evaluation campaign, we adapted software from a geographical web search engine currently under development at our group. Our approach is based on a two stage process, in which geographical references in the text are recognized and a geographic scope is afterwards computed for each document. A central component of the whole process is a geographical ontology, acting as the source of geographical names and relationships.</p><p>Although our scope assignment algorithm has shown to be better than a simple baseline of selecting the scopes according to the most frequent geographical references, retrieving documents using scopes was no better than the simple inclusion of the topic locations as additional terms to a standard text search. Our evaluation of the qrels has shown that the lack of information about some of the geographic concepts and their relationship to other concepts on the ontology that we built was the cause for very poor performance in a considerable number of topics. This shows that the success of our approach strongly depends on the amount and quality of geographic knowledge that is provided to the system. However, we suspect that if too much detailed geographic information is provided, performance will also become sub-optimal.</p><p>A similar resource to GKB is the Getty Thesaurus of Geographic Names (TGN) <ref type="bibr" coords="13,445.70,231.62,15.33,8.97" target="#b14">[15]</ref>, which is a structured vocabulary including names and associated information about both current and historical places around the globe. The focus of TGN records are places, each identified by a unique numeric ID. Linked to the place's records are names (historical names, common alternative names and names in different languages), place types (e.g., inhabited place and state capital), place's parent or position in the hierarchy, other relationships, geographic coordinates, notes and the data sources. There may be multiple broader contexts, making the TGN poly-hierarchical. In addition to the hierarchical relationships, the TGN has equivalent and associative relationships, similar to the GKB structure. We believe that the number of features in GKB is enough to assign the geographic scope to each document. We wanted to experiment this assumption with other gazetteers, and we planned to generate runs using TGN to compare the results to the ones obtained with GKB, but we did not receive it in time to be used at GeoCLEF.</p><p>As future work, in addition to improving the scope assignment algorithm and experimenting with more comprehensive ontologies, we plan to devise and evaluate better geographic ranking functions, capable of geographically ranking documents even in the absence of geographic knowledge about terms of the query location part or in documents, and making better use of the geographic scopes.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0" coords="3,148.20,266.06,306.26,8.97;3,112.44,109.02,378.00,142.00"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Feature types and their relationships in the world ontology of GKB</figDesc><graphic coords="3,112.44,109.02,378.00,142.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1" coords="5,144.72,286.94,313.16,8.97"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: The geographical named-entity recognition and disambiguation step.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2" coords="11,115.80,343.46,371.22,8.97"><head>Figure 5 :Figure 6 :</head><label>56</label><figDesc>Figure 5: Results of the XLDB group on the English monolingual subtask of GeoCLEF 2005</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3" coords="12,94.80,278.90,413.18,8.97"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: Results of the XLDB group on the Portuguese to English bilingual subtask of GeoCLEF 2005</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0" coords="4,90.00,110.90,422.63,619.05"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc></figDesc><table coords="4,158.64,110.90,286.10,543.45"><row><cell cols="2">Geographic Administrative Domain</cell></row><row><cell>Number of features by types</cell><cell>Value</cell></row><row><cell>ISO-3166-1 (4 languages)</cell><cell>239</cell></row><row><cell>ISO-3166-2 (in English)</cell><cell>3,979</cell></row><row><cell>Agglomeration (in English)</cell><cell>751</cell></row><row><cell>Place (in English)</cell><cell>3,968</cell></row><row><cell>Administrative Division (in English)</cell><cell>3,111</cell></row><row><cell>City-Capital (4 languages)</cell><cell>233</cell></row><row><cell>Regions (4 languages)</cell><cell>2</cell></row><row><cell>Total number of features</cell><cell>12,283</cell></row><row><cell>features of population</cell><cell>7,970 (64,88%)</cell></row><row><cell>Features from Wikipedia</cell><cell>4,453 (36,25%)</cell></row><row><cell>Features from World Gazetteer</cell><cell>7,830 (63,75%)</cell></row><row><cell>Relationships PartOf</cell><cell>11,995</cell></row><row><cell>Relationships Equivalence</cell><cell>2,501</cell></row><row><cell>Total number of relationships</cell><cell>14,496</cell></row><row><cell>Geographic Physical Domain</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Number of features by types</cell><cell>Value</cell></row><row><cell>Planet (4 languages)</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Continent (4 languages)</cell><cell>7</cell></row><row><cell>Sea (4 languages)</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Lake (4 languages)</cell><cell>1</cell></row><row><cell>Total number of features</cell><cell>10</cell></row><row><cell>Features from Wikipedia</cell><cell>10 (100%)</cell></row><row><cell>Relationships PartOf</cell><cell>9</cell></row><row><cell>Total number of relationships</cell><cell>9</cell></row><row><cell>Inter-Domain Relationships</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Statistic</cell><cell>Value</cell></row><row><cell>Relationships PartOf</cell><cell>241</cell></row><row><cell>Relationships adjacency</cell><cell>13</cell></row><row><cell>Total number of relationships</cell><cell>254</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Total number of features</cell><cell>12,293</cell></row><row><cell>Total number of relationships</cell><cell>14,759</cell></row><row><cell>PartOf relationships</cell><cell>12,245 (82,97%)</cell></row><row><cell>Equivalence relationships</cell><cell>2,501(16,95%)</cell></row><row><cell>Adjacency relationships</cell><cell>13 (0.08%)</cell></row><row><cell>Avg. broader features per feature</cell><cell>1.07</cell></row><row><cell>Avg. narrower features per feature</cell><cell>475.44</cell></row><row><cell>Avg. equivalent features per feature with equivalent</cell><cell>3.82</cell></row><row><cell>Avg. adjacent features per feature with adjacent</cell><cell>6.5</cell></row><row><cell>Features without ancestors</cell><cell>1(0.00%)</cell></row><row><cell>Features without descendants</cell><cell>12,045 (97,98%)</cell></row><row><cell>Features without equivalent</cell><cell>11,819 (96,14%)</cell></row><row><cell>Features without adjacent</cell><cell>12,291 (99,99%)</cell></row></table><note coords="4,233.37,666.98,171.53,8.97;4,90.00,708.98,422.63,8.97;4,90.00,720.98,373.10,8.97"><p>Descriptive statistics of the world ontology manually to GKB, because some of the GeoCLEF topics included place names like the North Sea, Caspian Sea and Siberia, which are not present on the information sources used to create the ontology.</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2" coords="6,156.96,331.70,288.83,8.97"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Expressions used for recognizing geographical concepts in text.</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head n="6">Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank <rs type="person">Andreas Wichert</rs>, for the manual creation of the German queries and insight on certain aspects on diacritics expansions on German texts, and <rs type="person">Alberto Simões</rs>, for the translation of the topics.</p><p>Thanks to all the tumba! developers and <rs type="projectName">GREASE</rs> project participants. This work was financed by the <rs type="funder">Portuguese Fundação para a Ciência e Tecnologia</rs> through grant <rs type="grantNumber">POSI / PLP / 43931 / 2001</rs> (Linguateca) and by grant <rs type="grantNumber">POSI / SRI / 40193 / 2001</rs> (<rs type="projectName">GREASE</rs>). <rs type="person">Bruno Martins</rs> is supported by <rs type="funder">FCT</rs> through grant <rs type="grantNumber">SFRH-BD-10757-2002</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_cdRvMEF">
					<idno type="grant-number">POSI / PLP / 43931 / 2001</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">GREASE</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funded-project" xml:id="_aHgWWem">
					<idno type="grant-number">POSI / SRI / 40193 / 2001</idno>
					<orgName type="project" subtype="full">GREASE</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_qDUKSKe">
					<idno type="grant-number">SFRH-BD-10757-2002</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>'ManTD': this run was generated as an intermediary step for the construction of the ManT DL, T DGKBm3 and T DGKBm4 runs. It provides a comparative baseline for the other submissions. We created manual queries to generate these runs, using terms from the topics's titles and descriptions, avoiding narrative terms and all related geographic terms. We did not include any location names or adjectives from the topics titles in the queries. We expanded morphologically the terms, and combined them using 'AND' and 'OR' logic operators into a single query line. As our baseline runs, the goal was to maximize recall. Precision was expected to suffer due to the lack of geographic terms on these baseline runs. These runs have a label which ends with 'ManT D' (MANual query, Title + Description).</p><p>'ManTDL': this run was meant to measure the efficiency of a simple geographical IR technique, which consists in restricting the search to documents containing the geographical location terms provided in the topics, expanding also the geographical names in order to account for equivalent names and spatial operators. We wanted to measure how efficient this technique is for restraining document scopes, hence we created these runs by inserting the scope(s) location(s) from the topic to the manual query from the 'ManT D' runs.</p><p>When the topic location scope implicitly embraces a group of countries, we extended it to the country level. For example, in the topic with the North Sea scope, the generated query string included terms like North, Sea, England and Denmark. In the case of topics with important spatial relation (e.g. South-West of Scotland), we expanded the scope in a similar way for each location found on the narrative, like Ayr and Glasgow on the example above (notice that this was the only information used from the narratives, regarding all query strings). These runs have a label which ends with 'ManT DL' (MANual query, Title + Description + Location).</p><p>'TDGKBm3 and TDGKBm4': in this run, we intended to measure the efficiency of our text mining software for assigning documents with a corresponding geographical scope, as described in Section 2. Runs labeled with 'T DGKBm3' mark the PageRank-like scope assignment, and the labels 'T DGKBm4' mark the most frequent geographic entity as the scope's document.</p><p>We did not submit mandatory runs for the German monolingual task, because QuerCol couldn't handle the agglutinated concepts in the topic titles properly. We found no interest in submitting these runs as the German language specificities were outside the scope of our participation in GeoCLEF.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct coords="13,111.59,570.62,401.05,8.97;13,111.60,582.62,401.07,8.97;13,111.60,594.50,153.76,8.97" xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="13,406.79,570.62,105.85,8.97;13,111.60,582.62,130.89,8.97">The XLDB Group participation at CLEF 2005 ad hoc task</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nuno</forename><surname>Cardoso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Leonardo</forename><surname>Andrade</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Alberto</forename><surname>Simões</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mário</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="13,330.59,582.62,177.41,8.97">Working Notes for the CLEF 2005 Workshop</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Wien, Austria</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-09-23">21-23 September 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="13,111.59,614.42,400.97,8.97;13,111.60,626.42,347.70,8.97" xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="13,318.83,614.42,112.11,8.97">The XLDB Group at CLEF</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nuno</forename><surname>Cardoso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mário</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><surname>Costa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="13,139.41,626.42,176.33,8.97">Working Notes for the CLEF 2004 Workshop</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Bath, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004-09">2004. 15-17 September 2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="13,111.59,646.34,401.07,8.97;13,111.60,658.22,103.08,8.97;13,214.80,656.38,3.72,6.64;13,222.24,658.22,290.54,8.97;13,111.60,670.22,57.15,8.97" xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="13,330.35,646.34,182.31,8.97;13,111.60,658.22,71.51,8.97">A Geographic Knowledge Base for Semantic Web Applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Marcirio</forename><surname>Chaves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mário</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="13,204.62,658.22,10.06,8.97;13,214.80,656.38,3.72,6.64;13,222.24,658.22,194.18,8.97">20 o Simpósio Brasileiro de Banco de Dados -SBBD</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Uberlândia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-10-07">3rd -7th October 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="13,111.59,690.14,400.96,8.97;13,111.60,702.14,193.58,8.97" xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="13,362.85,690.14,145.34,8.97">GKB -Geographic Knowledge Base</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Silveira</forename><surname>Marcirio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mário</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Chaves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>DI/FCUL TR 5-12</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-06">June 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="13,111.59,722.06,401.14,8.97;13,111.60,733.94,190.28,8.97" xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="13,281.04,722.06,93.52,8.97">One sense per discourse</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Gale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Church</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Yarowsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="13,391.65,722.06,121.07,8.97;13,111.60,733.94,160.69,8.97">Proceedings of the 4th DARPA Speech and Natural Language Workshop</title>
		<meeting>the 4th DARPA Speech and Natural Language Workshop</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.59,112.10,320.95,8.97" xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://xldb.di.fc.ul.pt/index.php?page=GREASE" />
		<title level="m" coord="14,111.59,112.10,63.42,8.97">GREASE home</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.59,132.02,401.04,8.97;14,111.60,144.02,257.55,8.97" xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="14,228.33,132.02,163.77,8.97">Experiments with PageRank computation</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ashraf</forename><surname>Khalil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Yong</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>603</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004-12">December 2004</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Computer Science department at Indiana University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.59,163.94,400.92,8.97;14,111.60,175.94,163.24,8.97" xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="14,183.02,163.94,258.12,8.97">Analysing search engine queries for the use of geographic terms</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Janet</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kohler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-09">September 2003</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Sheffield</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Master&apos;s thesis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.59,195.86,401.05,8.97;14,111.60,207.74,401.17,8.97;14,111.60,219.74,122.08,8.97" xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="14,305.27,195.86,207.36,8.97;14,111.60,207.74,191.78,8.97">An approach for measuring semantic similarity between words using multiple information sources</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Yuhua</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Zuhair</forename><surname>Bandar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mclean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j" coord="14,311.64,207.74,201.13,8.97;14,111.60,219.74,28.93,8.97">IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="871" to="882" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.58,239.66,401.04,8.97;14,111.60,251.66,100.77,8.97" xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="14,249.07,239.66,263.54,8.97">Geographical named entity recognition and disambiguation in web</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mário</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>to appear</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.58,271.58,401.27,8.97;14,111.60,283.46,364.49,8.97" xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="14,251.95,271.58,256.30,8.97">A graph-based ranking algorithm for geo-referencing documents</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mário</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="14,122.39,283.46,324.30,8.97">Proceedings of ICDM-05, the 5th IEEE International Conference on Data Mining</title>
		<meeting>ICDM-05, the 5th IEEE International Conference on Data Mining</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.58,303.38,401.03,8.97;14,111.60,315.38,337.49,8.97" xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="14,335.23,303.38,160.65,8.97">Indexing and ranking in Geo-IR systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mário</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Leonardo</forename><surname>Andrade</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="14,111.60,315.38,248.72,8.97">Workshop on Geographical Information Retrieval, CIKM 2005</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-11-04">November 4th 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.58,335.30,401.10,8.97;14,111.60,347.30,401.18,8.97;14,111.60,359.18,22.64,8.97" xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="14,249.08,335.30,153.16,8.97">Language identification in Web pages</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mário</forename><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="14,424.56,335.30,88.11,8.97;14,111.60,347.30,45.09,8.97;14,311.41,347.30,196.67,8.97">the 20th ACM Symposium on Applied Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of ACM-SAC-DE-05</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.58,379.10,401.13,8.97;14,111.60,391.10,400.95,8.97;14,111.60,402.98,65.42,8.97" xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="14,259.63,379.10,172.59,8.97">A Statistical Study of the WPT 03 Corpus</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Mário</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>DI/FCUL TR-04-1</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004-04">April 2004</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Departamento de Informática da Faculdade de Ciências da Universidade de Lisboa</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.58,422.90,400.40,8.97;14,111.60,435.43,133.87,7.83" xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://www.getty.edu/research/conducting_research/vocabularies/tgn/" />
		<title level="m" coord="14,111.58,422.90,156.29,8.97">Getty Thesaurus of Geographic Names</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.58,454.82,401.18,8.97;14,111.60,466.82,401.32,8.97;14,111.60,478.70,131.70,8.97" xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main" coord="14,396.13,454.82,116.63,8.97;14,111.60,466.82,124.93,8.97">The PageRank citation ranking: Bringing order to the Web</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><surname>Page</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Sergey</forename><surname>Brin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Rajeev</forename><surname>Motwani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Terry</forename><surname>Winograd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>SIDL-WP-1999-0120</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999-11">November 1999</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Stanford Digital Library</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
	<note>Working Paper</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.58,498.62,400.97,8.97;14,111.60,510.62,401.02,8.97;14,111.60,522.62,401.36,8.97;14,111.60,534.50,103.88,8.97" xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="14,324.00,498.62,188.55,8.97;14,111.60,510.62,198.61,8.97">Introduction to the CoNLL-2003 shared task: Language-Independent Named Entity Recognition</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Tjong</forename><surname>Kim Sang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Erik</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Fien</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Meulder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="14,111.60,522.62,329.55,8.97">Proceedings of CoNLL-2003, the 7th Conference on Natural Language Learning</title>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Walter</forename><surname>Daelemans</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Miles</forename><surname>Osborne</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>CoNLL-2003, the 7th Conference on Natural Language Learning<address><addrLine>Edmonton, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="142" to="147" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.58,554.42,401.18,8.97;14,111.60,566.42,401.25,8.97;14,111.60,578.42,53.93,8.97" xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="14,173.32,554.42,184.61,8.97">The Case for a Portuguese Web Search Engine</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mário</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="14,376.37,554.42,136.39,8.97;14,111.60,566.42,198.07,8.97">Proceedings of ICWI-03, the 2003 IADIS International Conference on WWW/Internet</title>
		<meeting>ICWI-03, the 2003 IADIS International Conference on WWW/Internet<address><addrLine>Algarve, Portugal</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IADIS</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003-11-08">5-8 November 2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="411" to="418" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.58,598.34,401.04,8.97;14,111.60,610.22,401.14,8.97;14,111.60,622.22,64.95,8.97" xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main" coord="14,465.28,598.34,47.34,8.97;14,111.60,610.22,138.39,8.97">Adding Geographic Scopes to Web Resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mário</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Silva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Marcirio</forename><surname>Martins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Nuno</forename><surname>Chaves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><forename type="first">Ana</forename><forename type="middle">Paula</forename><surname>Cardoso</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName coords=""><surname>Afonso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" coord="14,257.70,610.22,210.04,8.97">CEUS -Computers, Environment and Urban Systems</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>accepted for publication</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct coords="14,111.58,642.14,388.23,8.97" xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="http://ir.shef.ac.uk/geoclef2005/task_description.html" />
		<title level="m" coord="14,111.58,642.14,104.93,8.97">GeoCLEF task description</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
